,gnihton fo lluf dna gib oot
,larutannu saw tI
,emit a ta sruoh rof nur ot detaerc ,selcsum lufrewop
.NGISLLAC htiw ,REDAER yb uoy rof daer ,floWrecilpS yb
.seye yrotaderp ,live esoht
,thgit mih gnidloh llits smra tlef eh
”.ti nwo I dna stsixe tserof eht ylno dneterp adnik I
,gnitlem saw ydob sih ni elcsum yreve
,oN“ .decniw reppoC
,noziroh eht morf pu gnikop nageb noom eht fo pit ehT
,erac t’ndid eh tuB
.gniws lluf koot tfihs eht erofeb tuo dehguoc eh drow lanif ehT ”!NUR“  .emit s’tI
.drow yreve otno gnignah ,ylregae deddon renneT
ria eht otni pu hgih deraos ti sa dehctaw htob
gninrom txen eht pu ekow eh emit eht yB
!haey ,naem I ,oN“
,deohce reppoC ”.yadnuS
”.ecalp siht ekil t’nod uoy fi yrros m’I-I ?ko uoy erA !suseJ“
,kcap sih htiw derahs eh emoh roodtuo larur eht devol eH
.dloc gninnur doolb
.revo dna revo gninrut ,htoob eht revo
.gnihtaerb ypsar ,peeD
.ti leef dluoc reppoC tub ,weiv fo tuo
,diuqil toh erom nehT
.snaej sih fo tekcop eht morf retrauq a dellup renneT
meht denepo eh nehw niap enasni eht etipsed taht erus ,seye sih gnisolc nageb eh
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,gnitfihs ,gnignarraer
,éuqsir os gnihtyna enod reven dah eh llits
.etsat eht ni gnilever ,gniht eht
”.doog sdnuos keew txen emit emas ,haeY“
,pirg eciv sti desaeler waj s’reppoC
,htap eht nwod detnirps eh sa mih ediug teef sih tel tsuj eH
!laed gib on yllaer ,eivom a thguac dna ni deyats I !haey hO“
.gniht eno tsuj mih gnillet
”!evaeL .tsuj esaelP“
.thgil gniyd eht ni ksab selcsum sih gnittel ,cirbaf evitcirtser eht morf ydob sih gnieerf
,mrof sih egnarraer ot llA
.meht woleb erugif llams eht fo mra eht ni deirub
.gnigdub erew rehtien
.noom lluf a fo wolg elap eht ni detanimulli
.yks eht ni peed nwod knas nus remmus eht sa
.revoc ylidaer t’ndluoc yeht gnihtyna t’nsaw ti ,llib eht ta dekool htob yehT  .detsisni reppoC
,erew sgniht
tub sekatsim eht eteled ot gniyrt no desucof eH
,maes eht ta tilps stnap siH
.pleh dluoc ohw ,enoyna
?setunim erom wef a yats uoy t’nac ,naem I“
,yb desluper yllacitengam demees sevlow nwot a ni gnivil neeb dah renneT
,lortnoc esol t’ndluoc eh tub ,lufniap os saw tI
.ekal llams a no gniredrob
.retaw gnilppir eht ffo tcelfer ot thgil fo stnilg nedlog esuac ot hguone hgih tsuj llits saw thgilnus eht
,dnop egral a fo tnorf ni gnidnats ,porctuo ykcor llams a fo pot no gnidnats saw eH
.lanoitidart erom saw eh hguohtla
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,denrub ti ,truh tI
.noom eht ,nehT .noziroh eht dniheb dehsinav nus eht sa laruttug erom gnitteg eciov
.elbissop sa noos sa evael ot gnitnaw
,kcor dloc a eb ot desoppus saw ti rO
.dekcol enohp ,liaf ,liaf ,liaF
?thgir reppoC s’tI
,bmun tnew lla ti ylnedduS
.ecalp ni mih ezorf dnuos a neht
.nwo sih ni wap s’flow rehto eht depsalc eh erofeb ,dnoces a rof detatiseh eH
.ecivres on saw ereht tuB
.seenk dna sdnah sih no drawrof gnilwarc nageb dna hcamots sih otno flesmih deppilf eH
!no evots eht tfel eh ,eugor rieht tuohtiw tsol eb dluow maet dnd sih ,llits od ot hcum os dah eH
,sehtolc tseb sih gniraew saw eH
,ni pu nworg dah eh emoh yrtnuoc llud eht naht efil fo lluf dna tnarbiv erom hcum os saw ti ,hguoht nwot eht devol renneT
”.gniteem ssenisub tnatropmi na togrof I
.tiag lamron sih nwod wols elbaredisnoc ot gnideen etipsed
.enin enin enin enin enin enin enin ,enin ,enin
.esuoh sih dnuora sdoow eht ni kcab saw eh enigami tsomla dluoc eh
,ydob eritne sih hguorht dewolf niap toh etihw
.meht rof nabru oot neeb evah thgim ti
tuc hserf a tsniaga drah desserp eson tew mraw a tlef eh
,sgnaf s’flow eht fo ezis eht ta deirrow elttil a
.wap sih morf deppord enohp eht
,dertah tnatsni ro
,deifirroh saw renneT
,kcab sih no tnap saw od dluoc renneT lla tuB
.etad eht fo setunim wef tsal eht ruovas ot gnihsiw tub
.pirt ssenisub a rof ni dellac tog rehtaf ym tub ,htron sruoh wef a tops a evah I
.ecalp otni gnippans ,on
,mih gnillac saw ti
,enil eert eht evoba tuo gnikop daeh lufituaeb reh fo pit eht
.daeh sih ni flesmih gnikcik
,eno rehtona evah dluoc yeht erus saw eH
ylhsipeehs yawa dekool sevlow htoB
!gnihtemos togrof I haeY
.mra sih otni gniggid swalc tlef eH
.mra sih ni seguog peed eht morf gninrub selcsum
mmmmH“ .hgis a tuo tel renneT
!snaeJ .rallod ythgiE“
dah eh ,htap niam eht ffo teg ot dah eH
.elbativeni eht pots ot tpmetta lanif eno ni pu mra sih desiar dna seye sih desolc eH
,tca fo tros emos saw siht fi wonk t’ndid eh
?gnorw s’tahW“ ”!ON
,truh tI .yawa teg ot
.ecaf sih otno nwod gnippird
.mrof gnignahc s’ydob sih fo revir eht ni
,ylsuovren dehgual renneT
.flow gnirewoc eht ot thgir liart doolb eht dewollof dah reppoC flesti dellac ecno taht gniht ehT
.etiruovaf sih saw ti ,sliat dekcip syawla reppoC ”!sliaT“ .dednamed renneT ”!llaC“
,daeherof sih nwod gninnur diuqil mraw
.yzzuf dna ,mraw gnihtemos dehcuot wap sih tub
;daeha deppets reppoC
.rennid morf flow taht ot txen yllufepoH
gnippat tpek eh dna
.gnikaerb saw mih ni enob yreve
,sehtolc sih rednu gnidih neeb dah flow eht ydob ralucsum eht gniees etah t’ndid osla eh tub
.egnahc tsrif eht fo noitsuahxe erup gnivael
.esolc siht erew yeht elihw ton ,tey ton
.remrof eht detaerc owt eht
,rewol knus nioc eht sa dehctaw htob yehT
.kcohs ni tsol dnim
.laiceps eb ot tsrif eht detnaw eh tub
,seciov fo sdnasuoht gnitaerc
.egailof thgil eht hguorht yks thgin eht ta pu derats eH .gnippots neht
,dne dipar a ot emac yawdaeh ehT
,meg neddih a fo tib elttil a si eno siht tub ,ytic eht dnuora skrap wef a s’ereht ,haeY“
,enod tuoba saw renneT
.srettat ot gnippir trihs deppir ydaerla
”?gniod uoy era tahW“
.enohp sih tuo gnillup ,tekcop sih otni dehcaer wap gnikahs A
.demlehwrevo elttil a gnileef m’I nehw ereh ni sklaw ekat ot ekil I semitemos
daeh sih ni eciov a raeh tsomla dluoc eh
.gnol oot ,gnol os sgnaF
yojne esaelP  .yrrufos ro
slliks rotom enif sih fo mih gnippas saw kcohs eht ,hcum oot gnikahs erew sregnif sih
.thgirla eb dluow ti mih gnillet
.dnuorg eht ot dehsarc eh sa nwod edispu neht
tnirps ot mih desuac
,enoemos llac ot enohp sih tuo dellup eH
.egassam aps eltneg a ekil leef toof nekorb eht gnikam
,nioc eht ekil ,nehT
,kaeps ot dennuts oot llits ,nwod tas reppoC
.htap eht no knurt eert nellaf yltnecer a
.tsaeb eht fo smihw eht ot tsol eb dluow meht fo lla
,pets ni gniklaw saw reppoC
.emit nmad eht lla suoires erew ohw setamkcap sih lla morf ecap fo egnahc ecin a saw ti gnihtyna fi
.noisacco ffo eht no meht morf ecaps dedeen osla eh tub
,semit fo sdnasuoht retaw eht ffo gnitcelfer ,thgil wen eht
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna emit eerf sih ni gnitirw syojne ohw ,floWrecilpS yb
”?gnihtemos tegrof uoy diD
.drowssap sih ni gnipyt deirt eH
”?ti nees uoy evah ,eno flowerew wen ehT
,worros dna terger fo lluf
.woleb weiv eht sdrawot wob a htiw derutseg dna tsrif hguorht ekorb renneT
,ria eht hguorht welf eh sa syawedis og dlrow sih tlef eh dna krab dettor eht dekcik wap siH
”?keew txen emit emas ,oS“
,ssensuoicsnocnu fo etipser eht detnarg yllanif saw eH .gnisolc seye
,krap eht fo ezis reehs eht htiw dna ,thgil wol eht ni tub ,llew sdoow eht wenk eH ,od dluoc eh esle tahw wonk t’ndid eh ,nar renneT
.retaw eht ffo gnitcelfer thgil fo syar gniyd eht gnihctac hteet dna drawni delruc spiL
,mih morf ssorca gnittis flow deticxe eht dnim t’ndid reppoC
.flow gniripsrep won eht erussaer ot gniyrt ,yltneg wap s’reppoC dezeeuqs renneT
,erus ffo tup saw renneT
”…taht ti llac dluoc uoy haeY“
tlef eh sa srae gnignir sih ni deohce shtaerb deggar ,peed siH .oot sgnul
hteet eht rof sevlesmeht gnitah ,seye gnitaH
,seye citehtapmE
.seenk sih ,smraerof sih
”nettogroF eb ot tnatropmI ooT“
.riaf ,riaf s’taht hO“
,teef rieht no ykahs elttil a gnieb etipsed dna ,emit eht ta ni sknird evif ro ruof tuoba erew htoB
?ni uoy sgnirb tahw
yawa dehsaw erew sdnuow sih sa
,noisacco hcus eno saw sihT
”?ssenisub ylimaf fo tros emos ni krow uoy oS
,mra sih gnola nur eugnot hguor a tlef eH
reppoC ta kool ot weiv erutan eht morf yawa dekool renneT
,nwot ot wen er’uoy eliforp ruoy no dias tI
,dekan pirts ot sniap taerg koot eh
…evah I yas t’nac
.ydob sih gnirevoc thgil revlis
,tnemtnetnoc fo hgis a tuo tel eH
,dnim sih hguorht dehsalf sesucxe ynam oS
,revo gnikat ylwols gnignahc eht etipsed
,ti esolc ot wols oot saw eh tub ,nioc eht htiw detcennoc wap siH
.daeha pu thgir saw gniraelc ehT
,yawdaeh doog gnikam saw eH  .tsaf sa eciwt
.ti ees emoc ot ekil d’yeht fi ees ot flow regral eht ta dorp neve thgim eh
ytiniffaruf no
.taorht sih ni gniworg lworg eht revo elbidua ylerab erew sdrow s’reppoC ”!pir t’naC
”…noom ,ecin a ,a tahW“
yrots s’yadoT dna
.mih ot txen kcor eht no tser ot emoc wap sih gnittel
.detseggus renneT ”?pilF“
kcab sih otno mih gnillup ylhguor ,gel sih no pirg thgit a tlef eH
.seivom flowerew fo naf a gib oot ton yltsenoH
,etad siht no llew tnew sgniht fi ,lleH
,gninnips ,gninnips ,gninnips
.nur dna sredro s’flow eht egilbo ro
”…tops siht morf tesnus eht gnihctaw evol I
.yawa dna tuo teg ot revoc tcefrep eht neeb dah pirt ssenisub eht
.dereffo ylregae renneT ”!yap ll’I“
,sevael eht hguorht mih no nwod gnimaeb noom lluf
.denediw seye sih
,drah oot sserp ot gnitnaw ton ,edis sih ot kcab pord wap sih tel dah renneT
,tops eht ot tsomla erew yehT
,yawa dehcni renneT
,noitalpmetnoc ni pil rewol sih tib renneT .deksa reppoC
.revo saw gnineve eht erofeb og ot detnaw eh ecalp eno llits saw ereht
,noom eht leef dluoc eh tuB
.lwoh gnol a tuo gnittel
.emoh kcab srehto eht lla ot ffo flow gnihsulb ,retrohs eht wohs dluoc eh ebyam
.rennid gnirud gnol taht kool t’ndid yeht
”nettogroF eb ot tnatropmI ooT“ saw sihT
.dnuorg eht htiw stcapmi ynam eht morf skcarc bewredips ni derevoc ,derettahs saw neercs eht ,no ti denrut eH
,seye esoht ta pu gnirats
.kcen sih no eugnot s’etamkcap wen sih fo skcil gnirussaer ,mraw ,gnol eht saw derebmemer eh gniht tsal eht
?renneT uoy sekam taht emussa I
.derolpxe t’ndah eh strap llits erew ereht
.seye was dna nepo seye sih fo eno dekcarc yllacizziuq eH
,ytic eht tsuj ,aera eht ot wen yllaer ton naem I“
!emosewa s’taht hO“
!tuo uoy deksa I ,on ,oN“
,nepo kcab toohs seye sih edam lwoh gnicreip ehT
.deggurhs reppoC ”.pilF“
?yadnuS ,tiaW …yadnuS“
,deerga ylitsah renneT ”?tilpS“
.senob fo gnikcarc eht ,snaorg dna snaom deniap draeh eH .neve elbissopmi
.t’nsaw ti ,tey eid ot emit t’nsaw ti
”.ecalp siht morf yawa nur ot gniyrt s’enoyreve ,wonk I tahw morF
,gniworg ydob sih leef llits dluoc eH
.rab eht ta gnittis ,retto enol a fo kcab eht gnittih dna moor eht ssorca ti gnittaws daetsni
,revo ekat tcnitsni lavivrus dna yromem elcsum sih gnittel
,ybraen srehto yna ot tuo gnillaC
.enog lla saw ti erofeb yrruh ,ereh saw rennid
,peed oot htaerb t’ndid eh fI
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.kaeuqs thgil a tuo tel renneT
”!ti revoc dluohs I
,enog saw niap eht nooS
.sevael gnirevaw hguorht gnittilf nus yad-dim
.derepsihw reppoC ”?tilpS“
,skcor eht no revo deleek rennid morf flow dnik dna eniuneg ecno eht sa dehctaw eh
,ecnalg rehtona thguac eH
.rennid revo gnihgual elihw htiw sknird gnirahs saw eh eno eht fo seyE
.tnemtrapa moordeb eno sih ni reippah hcum saw eh
.sgnidnuorrus sih yb dezama tsomla saw reppoC
.taht sa tnatropmi sa gnihtemos nettogrof evah eh dluoc woh
!yeH“  floWrecilpS yb
.dnim sih ni etad eht no gnitanimur
”.mih rof og ot em deksa eh os ,desopsidni saw eH
,monev ekil ydob sih hguorht gnidaerps saw niap toh etihw eht ekil tlef ti wohemoS
.kcor etiruovaf sih no gnittis ydaerla saw renneT
.teb ot devol htob yeht tnerappa saw ti ,gnilbmag rof hcum gnieb ton etipsed
sgniht ,yadretsey gnilecnac tuoba yrroS
.swap rieht ni ecaf rieht gnidih
”!hguoht thginot tuo ti ekam htob dluoc ew dalg
.epoh mih evag neercs sih fo renroc pot eht ni srab esoht fo thgis eht ,erac t’ndid eH
,htap railimaf a gnola gniklaw saw renneT
thgirb eht fo espmilg a thguac eh litnu
”…ytic eht ni tsixe dluoc siht ekil ecalp a aedi on dah I“
,reppoc s’eman ,haeY“
,esitrepxe htiw nioc eht deppilf eh tub ,ylippols devom wap siH
,dnob tnatsni na rehtie detaerc taht sevlow tuoba gnihtemos saw erehT
.gnisluvnoc ylthgil nageb ydob sih sa daeh sih ni kcab dellor seye s’renneT
.enots hsurc ot hguone gnorts tsomla waj
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
”!nioc eht ekiL !looc os s’tahT
,sisylarap morf mih ekorb gniht lanif enO
.ecaf sih otno sraet gnippird
,sehtolc sih ffo gnikat trats dluohs eh fi
,krad gniog gnihtyreve tlef eh
,mih ot tuo gnillac lla
,revo saw ti wenk renneT
.ni shtaerb peed koot retsnom eht sa
,tnecs erup a hcus
,pu dekrej saw tI
.wam sih gninnur nageb eh erofeb htoob eht ta nwod tas neve ylerab dah eH
,krow htiw pu emac
,tuo dekrab reppoC ”.eniF .m’I .haeY“
.gniniag ylidaets saw mih dniheb gnihsarc dna gnippans eht tub
.ytic eht fo sllems eht yb delifednu
.ynapmoc eht gniyojne ,sknird dna rennid revo gniklat deunitnoc sevlow owt ehT
”…yadnuS retteb a rof deksa evah t’ndluoc I“
,gniog teg attog yllaer I
.tsrif ksa ot eno hcihw wonk t’ndid eh dna daeh sih ni dnuora gnicnuob erew snoitseuq ynam os
.gnicamirg ylivaeh won saw ohw
,wodniw llac ycnegreme eht denepo eH
”nettogroF eb ot tnatropmI ooT“ si
,pu dexim etad eht gnitteg rof flesmih gnikcik saw reppoC
,eid ot ydaer t’nsaw eh
,niap eht saw tlef eh gniht txen ehT
,etad siht no llew tnew sgniht fi ,llits tuB
.ria eht fo tuo nioc eht hctans ot tnew renneT
,tnemitnes ralimis a gnileef saw reppoC
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,erif no saw toof siH
”.hcamots ym rof hcum elttil a meht dnuof syawla ev’I
,ria gnidnuorrus eht lla ni gnikat ,htaerb peed a koot eH
.eert a tsniaga ydob derettab sih gninael dna htap niam eht ffo gnitteg ,no dehsup eh tub ,smra gnideelb sih otni gud trid eht
.kcab daeh sti deraer etteuohlis eht yaw eht yb ti gniyojne saw ti llet dluoc eH
dnim sih ni gnitarebrever sdrow eht gniraeh
ecnatsid ffo raf eht ni gnippans giwt a fo dnuos ehT
,yadot saw noom lluf eht wenk eH
,pu gnikool tpek tsuj eh
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,tuo denihw renneT ”…esaelp-lP“
.tsehc s’renneT otno slwoj s’retsnom eht morf nwod deppird avilas fo spord toH
.sdnilb sih hguorht gninihs thgil gninrom ,deb ni eb d’eh
.trid dna doolb fo xim dettam a saw ruf siH
.sgnaf fo gnihsang eht
,tnemssarrabme morf ylno toN