?gniyrt ton m’I kniht uoY“
.suoregnad gnihtyna swonk ehs esuaceb ti gniod ton s’ehs tub
.tcejbo ot ecnahc a dah hteS erofeb ti od ot tnew ehs neht dnA
,tnemom gnol a rof rehtohcae ta dekool htob yehT
,leef I woh s’taht taht“
,niallivrepus a m’I“ .denworf nitraM
?siht ,ytefas ruo fo ekas eht rof ,thgirlA“
”?dneirf lautum ruo morf draeh uoy evah“
.raja ylthgils dna dekcolnu rood sih dnuof eh
”droccA .sv dniwedarT“
,atnaS dessalgnus-
?em fo sekil eht htiw pu tup ot uoy yap yeht od“
,rednuht fo spalc owt fo dnuos eht htiW ”!ma I kniht I hO“
.thginot retfa noitpo na yllaer toN“
,hgual ot deirt dniwedarT
”.erofeb taht enod ev’yeht teB“
,taht enod ydaerla
,moor eht ssorca reep ot seotpit reh no tnew ehS
,tseug a ma I hcihw fo casedluc nabrubus a ni eucebrab draykcab a kcatta ot gniog ton m’I“ ,deffocs hteS
.eulc lanif eht eb ot tuo nrut lliw tahw dias yllatnedicca tsuj tnatsissa gnilbmub
”,yehT“ .dekrims hteS
.mih ediseb taes eht otni dils worc eht sa
.meht morf erutuf eht elgnatnesid ot gniyrt fi sa sreksihw sih hguorht sregnif nar xof ehT
.snoitatcepxe ym neve liaf ot yaw a dnuof snidalaP eht“
.mih pots ot gniyrt saw xof eht dna
.ecno rof pu tuhs hO“
taht yag s’eh esuac tsuJ“ ,desseug nitraM
,sbir desiurb no desserp segadnab eht sa decniw hteS
.taht od uoy tuoba woh ,os“
gnidloh saw hteS
”!rebmun sih em sevig eh taht ti tuoba yldneirf dna suoicarg os eb dna ezigolopa og ot deen I“
,deggurhs nitraM ”,knab a bor uoy emit txen uoy eeS“
!evael dna snoitalutargnoc yas tsuJ“ ”!oot ereh er’uoY“
”-tub ,edis ruoy no eb ot desoppus s’eh wonk I ,mih dnuora kcab ruoy hctaw uoY .lla si ,esolc teg ouQ suidatS tel t’nod I emit txeN
sa ffo saw trihs s’hteS
tsuj dna ,esolc seye sih tel yella eht ni xof ehT
,detpurretni nitraM ”,naem I ,oN“
”!kcirt ytrid a saw tahT“
,thguoht eh ,retteb gnikool saw worc ehT
”.eulav yratenom on fo noitatnemucod deniatnoc yldetroper dna ,spuorg tiforp-non dna
”!yas thgim eh gniht fo dnik eht s’tahw ,ekil ,kniht ot gniyrt tsuj
”?elbmarcs noitpecrep adnik emos ,naem uoy od tahW“
.esirnus fo yerg ylrae eht otni dehsinav dna
,thgir eht ot yawa dellorcs yltsom
”.tniop rieht ees nac I ,noonretfa lla uoy htiw laed ot tog ev’I fi dnA“
dias tsuj eh oS .tegrat eht neeb dah ohw ,os fi dna
,eromyna gnideelb t’nsaw eh esuaceb ebyaM .tnerehoc erom
slaudividni etavirp ot degnoleb
.thgil eht ffo kcilf ot tfardnwod lufrewop
,taes a koot ylimE sa eeffoc sih deppis hteS ”,lleW“
.retnuoc eht ta terref eht dellac
retsnoM ehT
,bulC sepA F-A-kciS“
”.suoregnad s’tI .dnatsrednu I os ,boj emas eht adnik
,tnedicca yb ti gniod ton s’ylimE“
”.reerac a erahs yeht nehw era selpuoc woh wonk uoY
.yella kcab sselthgil eht otni tuo deppets yeht nehw thgin llits saw ti
.no meht gnireehc ylsuocuar nemow eht dna
.teiuq mih peek ot ynomerec eht fo tser eht hguorht ti dleh dna
.ni llup dluoc srac ecilop eht erofeb tsuj
,hcihw ,cimaslab fo elttob eht rof retnuoc eht ta yug eht ksa ot dah I“
!sexob tisoped ytefas lareves morf stfeht tnerappa ta“
,hsarc niart tnatsid a ekil dnuos a htiw
”,did uoy teb I“
.detatiseh htob nitraM dna hteS
”?eb ot su tnaw uoy oD
,deirrow saw eciov s’nitraM
”?gniod I ma tahW“ .deppans hteS
”.yadot s’tahT .tihS“
.erew reve srednatsyb tneconni sa erawanu yllufssilb sa ,ragus repaehc
”-ni deppart er’uoy neht tuB“
”!syug uoy neewollah yppah hsogimO“ ”?tahw tuobA ?ohW“
esohw evitceted eivom eht ekil
“ naht erom yna daer ot deen t’ndid eno tub
”,pu eno taht gnirb t’ndid I“
yeht oiranecs esac tseb rO
tcaf ni od I esuaceB“
.pis rehtona koot nitraM
”!ereh owt uoy detivni I yhw gnirednow ylbaborp er’uoY“
”,rehtegot ti tup tsuj evah thgim I“
,niatpac ecaps dna noirutnec namor fo noitanibmoc emos
”,taht od ot desoppus ton er’eW“
dniwedarT“   yojne esaelP
taht sseug ot elba eb dluow dna
tuo siht gnirugif elihw hguorht enog ydaerla t’nevah I taht
”?ereh esle enoyna eb t’ndluow ereht wonk uoy d’woH“
”,t’nera erus eW“ .dias hteS
,yfiralc ot denetsah nitraM ”,gniyas ton m’I“
”!eb dluow uoy dias gocerp ruoy esuaceb tsuj em htiw kcuts er’uoy gnikniht uoy tnaw t’nod I ,naem I“
.gniht elohw siht tuobA .erusnu …neeb ev’I“
.taht rewsna ot woh wonk t’nod I“
”.sdneirf htiw ereh ni yllausu er’uoy“
.knird a gnitpecca morf yawa deihs dah sexelfer evitingocerp
.rof uoy deraperp yllatnem yeht tahw saw sihT
.gnihtyna daer ot deen t’ndid yllaer uoY
.gnisruc dna deliof ,yks eht otni ffo demrots
,elsia eht nwod gnihsur sdewylwen eht rof dedualppa yletilop
saw ti hgih os tsiaw a htiw sserd knip elap a gniraew saw ylimE
,gnitnar deunitnoc swen ehT
…was I tahw ,rehtegot
,efac llams eht ni vt eht denialpxe ”,delffab era eciloP“
”.yddaD rehtaeF dna ,hO .regaR s’lacsaP
s’tahT“ ”!?mih ot deklat uoY
”?eilemA …rof hciwdnas tnassiorc dalas eserpaC“ .ni demihc hteS
”?’si lla siht oreteh yldnalb woh‘ morf trapA“
,detrops adnerB eno eht sa ycnaf sa raen erehwon
”?huh ,srewop gnivah rof tiderc uoy evig neve t’nac yehT“
eht ot kcab teg nac ew rekciuq eht-“
”.teuquob eht hctac ’yllatnedicca‘
”?kniht syug uoy od tahW“
!hteS ,uoy nwonk ev’I sa gnol sa tsomla
.gniraew saw knumpihc tnecsevreffe eht retaews ylgu yletarebiled eht ro
…rednow I ,gocerp ym rof hcaer I emit yrevE“
”.ecurt eht rof hcum oS“
arait enotsenihr a erow ehS
dna cipot taht htiw enod ylluf won saw ylimE ”,oS“
.xofnogarD reppaD eht
.deffup erew kcen sih fo kcab eht nwod srehtaef eht
yas niatpac eht draeh tsuj ev’ohw sregnessap
,droccA dna dniwedarT dezingocer aera ytnuoc-irt eht ni enoyrevE
”.mrotsdniw kaerf a ni sevlesmeht nettalf
.thgil a no gninrut erofeb desolc erew sdnilb eht erus edam
dah mottob eht gnola rekcit swen suoires yrev ehT
knumpihc eht drawot nosinu deifirroh ni denrut seye rieht neht
,worbeye na desiar nitraM ”,hU“
tuo yaw sih no xob a barg ot depoows nialliv eht nehw dnA
”.srettel ruoy daer ot gnirehtob t’nera yeht nehw rO“
,dniwedarT lanimircrepus nwonk fo skramllah lareves syalpsid ni-kaerb eht
,sisemen a uoy sredisnoc ro ,uoy tsniaga segdurg yna tog s’ydoboN
dezilaer yeht nehw ezorf htob yehT
dellac atsirab emosdnah eht nehw
.ysub er’yeht“ ,delims ylimE ”,hO“
,deman ,terref emosdnah siht sa hcuS
I llit tsuJ“ .deffuh nitraM
”.enola gniddew s’adnerB dna tehC ot gniog kcus ll’tI …naem I“
ekil xof eht dna worc eht tfel ehS
”?etuc s’eh fi tuobA“
THGUORB ehs ohw was I ecnis ffo dna no gocerp ym gnirekcilf neeb ev’I
”.ti did tsuj eh ,saw ti tahw nialpxe t’ndid eH“
”,ti t’nsi
”…thginot erofeb adnerB ro tehC tem d’I fi desirprus erom eb ebyam d’I“ ”.nac I ?sey …oS
,rab elbissop tsewol ehT
ot desserdda saw egakcap ehT
”?lla retfa ,uoy saw taht oS“
…ni htob er’eW .sneppah tI“
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.noitca fo esruoc a no deerga yeht noissucsid retfa dna
,stseug ralucitrap reh htob
erofeb efac eht fo tuo tpews ehs dnA
,woble eht ni mih ekirts ot nworht neeb ydaerla dah afnot s’oreh eht
siht tuoba klat ot tnaw uoY“
”,thgirla eb tsum ti os ,dereffo saw ti nehw ssalg eht koot sexelfer gocerP“
.deerga dniwedarT
,nelarD yb uoy rof daer ,floWcaM boR yb
erofeb emit gnol a mih ta dekool nitraM
.nwod snidalaP eht gnirb ot eb dluow gniht cioreh eht ebyam
,swarts niht-oot dna stekcap ragus fo flehs elttil eht evoba neercs VT eht ta decnalg xof ehT .dias nitraM
,uoy evol I syas ti fI
.desu reven nitraM afos eht no lamina denethgirf a ekil deldduh
..xofnogarD reppaD eht
dna semutsoc paehc ni yb rednaw ot deunitnoc ytrap eht fo tser eht tuB
,retaews suoedih eht ni
”?deergA .evael ot reh sekat ti gnol revewoh
fi sa ,ylihtlaets
fo kcart tsol d’ehs dezilaer ehs nehw denrecnoc ylfeirb
:yldnoces dna ,enoyreve htiw sdneirf emoceb
”?yad lla dah evah elpoep eseht kaerb moorhtab tsrif eht tpurretni ot nosaer yna taht si tuB“
htaerw lerual nedlog citsalp eht rednu der dehsulb ecaf s’nitraM ”,kooL“
sih devirra d’eh nehw esuaceb ylno ton dna
,gnidliub eht otni edorts eh sa ylsuoretsiob dehgual ,niallivrepus suomafni eht ,dniwedarT
.desucofnu dna derettulf seye sih
”.netfo erom siht od dluohs eW“
”?reyrd riah rallod eerht
.gnihtyna swonk ehs ekil gnitca t’nsi erus ehS“
”?ot klat uoy d’ohW“
,niaga eciov sih deppord nitraM ”,si tniop ehT“
”.loohcs hgih ni ,epyt leber tnagorra eht rof tnew syawla uoy“
.hteS truh yllautca t’ndah eh depoh yllaer eH ”.CLL
”!enoZ thgiliwT eht morF !gnilreS doR m’I ,oN“
,delf tfihs dnoces eht sa decnuonna eh ”,elttil woH“
.kcab werd ,desuap
.detegdif nitraM ”.reh tuobA
”.siht ekil gnihtemos sllup ehs emit txen eht litnu tsael tA“
,worc a til dna ni deruop tI
…adnik emos htiw em tih eH
xof eht derepsihw ”,etal er’uoY“
,deppots eb regnol on nac nalp etamitlu esohw ,floWcaM boR yb
,tsaf oot detcaer droccA tuB
.egap yrruFoS sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna ,ahahawm
”!ynnuf era ynnuf era kniht dluohs ydobon sgniht fo tol a knihT“ ,kcab delworg nitraM
.moortser eht esu ot dah ehs decnuonna ylimE
,yawa ti nialpxe ot seirt ouQ suidatS rehtiE“
,taobefil a eganam ot woh tuo erugif nac uoy‘
.dekcatta tey t’ndah ti taht mrifnoc ot gniyrt fi sa
deffuts knumpihc ehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.elbmarcS noitpecreP
.t’nsi emit dnoces a ti gnioD“
.ecalp sih ekat ot delbmarcs dna nedrag kcab s’lepahc eht ot yaw sih deltsub
,flesruoy hciwdnas eht no ti tup annog ton er’uoy fI ?yllaer
’.ti diova ot od ot tahw dna ,eb ot gniog saw ytiruces eht lla erehw ecnavda ni
”!etuc ytterp s’eh ,dednim I taht toN
,elbat eht ot kcab yllufreehc dils ylimE ”!kcab m’I“
,tuo hcaer ot detrats nitraM
yawevird eht kcolb ot nac ados delpmurc a ekil drawkcab ti dessot dna
,htaerw eht ni sDEL derolocitlum
.ylrettib nitraM dias ”,sraey rof rehtohcae nwonk ev’ew ekil s’tI“
”!elohssa suoethgir-
,sehtolc fo stnuoma gnisaerced yldipar ni
taht tnemmoc did rohcna eht tuB .did reven yehT
”.ouQ suidatS“ ”?ria niht ,llew
.ylper dluoc meht fo rehtie
,rewsna ot ecnahc a dah nitraM erofeb kcab saw ylimE
…ebyaM“ ,dekrims dniwedarT ”?sloohcS
.yawyna stfig eht dedart yehT .nitraM dias
”!rosseforp egelloc taerg a eb d’uoy thguoht syawla I
,nwod gnittis neve tuohtiw moorhtab eht morf kcab ,dias ylimE ”,yrros OS m’I“ ”!deergA“
,dias d’eh tahw mih ot kcab detaeper hteS
noissucsid a gniria won saw hcihw ,margorp swen eht rednu elbat eht rof gnidaeh
erofeb ,delbuort dekool eh thguoht ehs
”?ytrap rolehcab eht ton ,ytrap etterolohcab eht ot seog eh naem t’ndluohs
”.ti revo tsrif ecaf llaf ot deganam llits yeht dna
.did ehs sa gnilbmurg ,seeffoc nwo rieht hcae meht dnah ot dah ehS
”?evisneffo saw ti ekil tlef eh ebyaM“
”?nitraM teem uoy did woh oS“
?eb ot tuo nrut ot gniog si siht part revetahw …fo tuo em gniklaw ti t’nsi yhW
,elbat eht ssorca worc eht ta denworf dna
”,swonk ehs hcum woh aedi on evah I“
.gniknird saw atnaS dias atiragram nezorf eht dna
.niaga enog saw ehs dnA
,tcaf ni ,erew yeht won
,moor eht fo dne rehto eht ta lwobhcnup eht yb gnidnats
.terref eht ta redluohs reh revo decnalg ehS
.taht dias dah nitraM duol woh
dna mih dniheb rood eht tuhs droccA
,rehtohcae htiw sdneirf eb
…t’ndluoc I dna ,gnorw tnew ytivarg
.tsrif rewsna ot rehto eht rof detiaw meht fo htob eht elihw hcuop keehc a otni hciwdnas eht fo flah hcae
,htuom sih ni sraeb ymmug fo lufdnah a deppop nitraM ”…lleW“
”,uoY“ ”!erutrot si sihT
.srewop evah I wonk t’nod“ ,denworf nitraM
s’ylimE fo mottob eht ot teg
.tesolc eht fo mottob eht ta devil
”.sey ,skrow gnicudortni woh si sihT“ ”.wonk uoy taht
,worc eht dehsuhs yltneg xof eht
,rac deromra na fo pot no gnithgif erew yeht ecnis
ot gniog t’nera seciffo naol yadyap fo niahc A
,ylluferac yrev ,dias nitraM ”,haeY“
,ytitnedi terces a gniniatniam ot desu gnol erew eh
smialc suomynona tnecer seined yllaiciffo snidalaP eht fo flaheb no tnemetats a ,swen rehto nI“
”?wonk uoy woh ksa yeht nehw dnA“
”,em llet ot evah t’nod uoY“
:yltsrif ,erew efil ni slaog owt reh taht wonk ot hguone gnol knumpihc elbisserperri eht nwonk htob d’yehT .t’nerew yehT
skool gnidart noonretfa eht fo tser eht tneps hteS dna eh dnA
”!dniwedarT ,hguone s’tahT“
”!rehtohcae ot decudortni erew uoy fo owt eht emit hgih saw ti thguoht I“
”!yhw wenk uoy fi derednow
.droccA oreh evarb eht htiw weivretni na teg ot eganam t’ndid thgin taht swen ehT
tsuj llits nac I tub“ ,dias hteS
,ecnelis eht ekorb yllanif nitraM
”-ti gniod si ehs yhw tuo erugif ew rekciuq ehT
”.od ot gniog er’uoy si ti revetahw ro“
”!uoy rof doog yllaer s’tI ?sniarg rehto ro taehw naht snietorp dna snimativ erom yaw uoy sevig aoniuq gnitae wonk uoy diD
”,sseug I ,detcartsid elttil a saw I“
”?gnola gnitteg owt uoy erA“
”,edis ym no etats ecnallievrus a fo secruoser eht lla
,rood eht rof dedaeh eh
.kcirt cigam a ekil noitasrevnoc otni kcab deppop ylimE
”!ecurt eht fo noisnetxe na si
!emutsoc taerg a s’taht ,hteS“
eb a yb nrow trihs naiiawah eht
.su ecudortni dnA
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”-aibohpomoh neve ebyam s’taht
.nwohs egatoof eht ni no gniog saw tahw wonk ot
.si siht revetahw gniod s’ehs yaw eht tuoba etarebiled gnihtemos yletinifed s’erehT .gniht
.etercnoc eht evoba teef net doog a teef
”.drah taht ton s’tI
,yluJ .rM ,werhS elbaematnU ,tnadeP noilimreV eht“
ohw nam a tuoba yrots a ot no gnivom
.seye sih dellor hteS
”.liof reve uoy semehcs esohw nosrep ylno eht m’I
.modnar ta gnitamilbus tsuj
”!hctiw dekciw elatyriaf a ton m’I
,dessorc smra ,yawa denrut nitraM
meht fo owt eht neht dna
”,esruoc fo ,ylimE detxeT“
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.esiwrehto mraf ycnerrucotpyrc a ni pu dniw ot gniog ylno s’tI
,doolb fo tol a tsoL
,s’nitraM tub tifeneb s’eno on rof denialpxe hteS
”?emehcs suoirafen fo dnik emos rof noitamrofni eht tiolpxe nac uoy oS ?yhW“ .deppans hteS
.dias ylimE ”,haey hO“
.rood eht drawot meht deirrac dna ,sexob lareves detfil
”!ytiruceS dnalemoH fo tnemtrapeD eht dellac eb ll’yeht ,lliw I ,haeY“
”,wonk uoy ,gnihtyna em ewo t’nod uoY“
.losarap ecal a gnilriwt dna
.retlehs gnikat ydaerla saw eh
sih dna ,eit ynniks dna tius bard denoihsaf dlo na gniraew saw eH
.teef ym ot lwarc ot deirt I nehw pu deparcs gnitteg ,sgniht otni gnihsarc ,seceip ot gniog erew em fo stib dilos eht nevE
.dekaeuqs ylimE ”!?teg uoy d’tahW“
”,saw ti esruoC“
”.pu kooL“ ”?woH ?tahW“
.enilefil a ot dah meht fo rehtie gniht tsesolc eht
,wonk t’nseod ehS .ecurt a sI
.noitartnecnoc sih fo tuo mih deltrats
?ylimE tuoba em nraw ti t’ndid yhw
hguorht teg dna lamron tca tsuj ew os
.gninrom yb niaga gnitareneger eb dluohs I“ ”?won tahW“
,ytiludercni emos htiw
”?teid wen a gniyrt er’uoy dias hteS“ ,ylkciuq thguoht nitraM ”…hU“
.snoziroh wen ot no sserp ot emit saw ti won tub
esuaceb ylbaborP
,nelarD yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
”?edart ot tnaw uoy fi revo mih llac dluoc I
”!gnihtyreve dna thgir liame sih dah ehs
”.siht troper nac I ,snidalaP ehT llet nac I“
.trapa gnillaf detrats I nehw yrruh a ni tfel eh
”.deneppah reven ti dneterp ,gur eht rednu ti peews tsuj ot yrt
.tuo uoy erugif ot gniyrt s’ydobon ,llet nac I sa raf sA .elpoep ksa
,ecnart eht fo tuo emac eh nehw dnA
.sevlesmeht rof srewop rieht esu ot desoppus t'nsaw oreh a tuB
.niap ni decamirg
,dluoc rehtie erofeB
”?mih detivni uoy erus er’uoY“
woh gnirongi ,dias ehs
.enog ydaerla saw ylimE sa
,gninael worc eht htiw nageb tI
.rehtaew mlac eht etipsed nwolbdniw wohemos emoceb evah ot demees
nem gnicnad eht erew ereht ,cisum duol dna sthgil eht morf trapA
”,orehrepus a er’uoY“
”droccA .sv dniwedarT“ saw sihT
.uoy no krow t’nseod noislupmoc ’rednerrus dna nwod dnats‘ sih fi tespu steg yltnerappa eH“
?detnaw uoy kniht I reyrd wolb levart taht htiw pu dnuow nitraM ekil skool tI“
.puc eht koot ehs nehw detcerroc yltneg knumpihc eht
?ot em detivni uoy ytrap a gnivah er’yeht yhw s’tahT“
.hteS ediseb hcuoc eht no taes a koot nitraM
.worbeye na desiar hteS ”?deksA“
,ylivaeh dehguoc ,rewsna ot detrats dniwedarT
,seye sih desolc eH .sisirC
”...ti ton s’taht ,on oN“
.talf eciov ,dias hteS
”,derujni gnitteg toN“
.worc eht dnuora gof laicifitra eht hguorht
fo ximer esuoh a fo dnuos tnatsid eht yb ylno dellif saw esuap ehT
!netfo erom meht od dluohs elpoeP
.seye sih dellor hteS ”.os esoppus I“
.sdneirf taerg eb ot gniog erew yeht
.uoy fo kniht ot hguone tnerehoc saw I erofeb saw ti gnol woh onnud I
,naem I ,sseug I“ ,dias nitraM
”!meht rof ma I yppah woh meht llet og ot evah I hsogimO“
”!niaga ecurt no era“
”.yrros ,etal oot hcuM“
skcart sti ffo rood leets detagurroc eht
…t’nera ew fi nevE
,dekaeuqs ylimE ”!haey ,hO“
”?llab-8 cigam a rof erised gninrub yna tog ev’uoy esoppus t’nod I“ .hteS deppans ”!ton esruoc fO“
ot noitisop otni su fo htob ro eno etalupinam ot yrt ot gniog s’ylimE .yllautca ,trap suoregnad eht eb annog s’noitpecer eht ,hO“
…tsuj ,taht gniyas em llits s’taht
tiftuo krad a ni erugif a nehw gniyalp ydaerla saw nagro ehT  …dekeep ylerab
”!?stsacerof rehtaew
sdneirf reh lla gnikam fo krow s’efil reh ta sseccus delellarapnu
.enohp reh ta ylevarg derats ylimE
,dnah sih koot eH
”?gniod s’ehs ’gniht siht‘ naem uoy od tahW“ .tfel dna
”?ydaerla elpoep eseht wonk t’nod yeht ekil skool ohw ereh esle enoyna ees uoy ,dnuora kooL
ro serugif ytirohtua evah yltcaxe t’nod I .tcaf ni ,did I“
”!gnihtyna deirt uoy ekil ton s’tI“
”?gniod owt uoy era woh
hcihw ,eit sih denethgiarts dna delbmurg worc eht
”?!degagne era adnerB dna tehC eveileb uoy nac“
esuaceb sotohp s’enoyreve ni saw enoyreve erus ekam dna
”!netfo erom siht od ot deen eW
”!kcab thgir eb ll’I dna sevlesruoy ecudortni owt uoy ,em s’taht ,hO“
”!desimorpmoc si ytitnedi ruoy fi ylimaf dna sdneirf ruoy gnitegrat snialliv evah ot gniog er’uoy fi sA“
.riahc gnidlof a ni deppart slatineg sih nettog dah
”,desserpmi m’I“ .hsaM
.nekcirts dekool ecaf s’ylimE
”.eb ot desoppus er’ew seimenehcra detah
yllausunu yrev tub
retaw ni nap gniyrf a ekil
ti laets ot gniyrt saw worc eht
eh sa neve ,gnilbmurg demuser hteS ”,ees t’nod I“
.gnorts saw ,lla retfa gniddew eht ot ti ekam dluow eh fi ees ot ,erutuf eht otni kool ot noitatpmet ehT
.emit gnol a ecnelis ni rehtohcae dleh setteuohlis owt ehT ”.sruoh xis ekil nI“
,detcerroc nitraM ”,yriaf dekciW“
.repsihw a dna lworg a neewteb erehwemos
,ti morf gnignah eceipeye DUH ekaf eht htiw
,ylsuovren dewehc
.ecrof evissecxe fo stnedicni pu gnirevoc fo nrettap a tuoba
,eciov sih fo tuo repmihw a peek ot thguof nitraM
wenK‘ ,etouq ,eh fi sa saw ti yas secruoS
,rehtegot taht od d’yeht larutan ylnO
.ria ot nrut ot etal oot
noitseuq lacirotehr reh gnirewsna rehtie fo daetsni
?puc eht fo sedis eht no seman eht daer uoy t’naC“
gnihtemos morf hsac fo tol a htiw yawa nettog wohemos
.dias meht fo eno
.sdneirf emoceb ot sdneirf reh lla ecrof
,skcolidlog sa sserd ot tnaem d’ehs fi tcefrep neeb ev'dluow taht giw a
”,yllautca ,ylimE s’tI“
.niaga dnuorg eht ot ylidob xob hcae erob scitaborca dna ,spmuj ,spilf fo seires htooms a dna
siht tnaw yllaer“
.sdaeh rieht evoba gniliec eht ot depat eoteltsim citsalp fo girps eht ot llaw eht pu
,tsael ta ,mih dekoops TAHT dnA“
,htap s’worc eht kcolb
evah t’ndid llab-8 ehT
,ylimE deerga ”,haeY“
tub ynit a esu ot
?gniddew eht kcatta tsuj ot em rof“
,pu thguorb neeb reven dah ti fi sa txen eht ot deppets
,otacsom gnilkraps dnarb-erots fo ssalg eht revo derewolg nitraM ”,eW“
”!gniod s’ylimE gniht siht fo tuO
”?nalp a deen ’eW‘ ?’eW‘“
,xof eht tsniaga kcab
fles uoy ,UOY ot ti od d’eh deirrow saw I“
,htiw mih tfel dah egnahcxe tfig eht hcstik ykcat eht
”.uoy ot yas ot gniog saw I tahw s’tahT“
.nialliv eht hcihw
”!ylsuoires ’ytitnedI terceS‘ ekat su fo emoS
taht tik dia tsrif etelpmoc ylevisserpmi na morf esle erehwyreve ylraen dna
’.dniF oT dooG sI naM draH A‘
,sregnif sih no ffo detnuoc worc eht
rewop sih ni hguone tnedifnoc saw worc eht litnu ereht gniniamer
,dias yllanif hteS
.ecnart evitingocerp sih otni deppils
,derevocsid noos ehs sa
.ti tuoba flesreh elbuort t’ndid ehs os
.maerc riah fo laed taerg a htiw kcab dekcils erew srehtaef
,tuc saw ekac eht emit eht yb deraeppaer d’yehT
dessih redluohs dna edis sih morf doolB
,moor eht dellif stsug tnelubruT
sihT“ ”?rednerrus a siht sI“
”.gnigaruocne gnihtoN“
.erongi ot ysae ti dnuof ylimE tub
ni ela regnig a ylno
emoh tog nitraM
.tixe sih edam eh erofeb lebal gnippihs eht ta ecnalg ot
d’ohw ,ylimE decnuonna
,sgniht eht wonk htob ew taht oS .rehtohcae oT
”.em no kcehc ot uoy dnes ot
”.ekulf a neeb ev’thgim efac eht ot su gniksA“ .delrans nitraM
”.rehtegot flesym llup
,niaga elpuoc yppah eht etalutargnoc ot revo htob meht gniltsub
.uoy knaht ,reerac ym no gnisucof neeb evah“ ,deffins hteS ”,I“
taht adnerB htiw dekcehc elbuod I“
”,llab-8 cigam A“
,dehsaelnu dniwedarT tsalb elag eht nees ydaerla dah sexelfer s’droccA esruoc fo tuB
tnemom a koot droccA
floWcaM boR yb ”droccA .sv
”!noitpecer eht ot pu nwohs tsuj ev’dluoc eW
.nwod tpael dna esiugsid sih edisa dessot eelf ot ton ’rekrow‘ ylno ehT
,hteS detnemmoc ”,kniht I“
,dellappa dekool hteS
”?eilemA …rof ahcoM etihW yrrebpsaR“
”!revo saw ti llit eciton neve t’ndid I dna krow ym edistuo thgir gnineppah saw taht eveileb t’nac I“
”.saw gnihtyna gnol woh llet ot draH
.thgis erutuf eht tog ev’uoY“ .deknilb hteS
.ria yduolc fo stsrub otni deraeppasid sdnah s’worc eht
,wenk ehs ,dah d’ehS
,yhw“ ,dehgual ylimE ”!sega
.cinap sih no nwod depmalc droccA
,tlusni na sa tnaem neeb dah taht fi erus t’nsaw nitraM ”.citehtaP
,nosmirc dehsulb ylimE
,ebyam lluf si radnelac laicos reh ,wonk t’nod I“
”-nehw decalpsim saw ti gniyas ,noitatnemucod ecudorp ot elbanu eb ot demialc yeht ,desserp nehW
”?ot pu s’ehs tahw tuo gnirugif kcul yna daH“
saw ylimE .nitraM deerga
”-loohcS yadnuS nairotciV a naht reicips gnihtyna emahsknik lliw yllaer sepyt oreh uoY !lausnesnoc lla
.moor siht ni noitasrevnoc a evah ot tluciffid saw tI
tsuj rof nitraM nwonk ev’I ,hO“
,deksa terref eht ”?yadot enola uoY“
em gnivig ton s’ti dna
,hciwdnas siht no cimaslab eht togrof yeht ,dnoces eno ,hO
”,ylimE no kcehc ytiruces noitamrofni na rof esabatad troppus snidalaP eht deireuq I“
tnemtneser fo lluf
dna niaga teef reh no saw ehs dnA
”?derujni gnitteG“ .hteS denaom
”.efil ni sgniht tnatropmi eht lla ssim lla su sekam msilatipaC“
.esrow saw retaews eht ,haey
”!retnec noitubirtsid siht tih d’uoy wenk I“
.sisemen ruoy gnieb rof ,em no ti nip ot yrt yeht rO
”!srewop gnivah ton ekil kool taht srewop evah ot teg t’nod su fo emos fi
…ecalp emos dedeeN“
”!ylsuoires ytitnedi terces ym ekat
,riahc sih ni thgiarts yllarutannu gnittis saw hteS
.taes reh otni kcab flesreh deppolp ehs sa gnas ylimE ”!kcaB“
.deksa nitraM ”?deneppah tahW“
htaeneb ytic eht ni tub
tsuj I ,gnihtyna deirt tsal ehs ecnis lausu naht regnol neeb s’tI“ ”!?WON
dias trihs-t reh dna
”,on ,ylralucitrap toN“
gnileef a dah ehS .odraudE
!wonk uoy ,sremotsuc eht rof tuo ti tup tsael ta neht
”.siht fo tuo teg ot GNIHTEMOS gniyrt m’I tsael tA“
deitpme stisopeD
,hguoc rehtona deganam ylno
…kniht d’ydobon
.roolf eht ot pird dluoc ti erofeb ria fo semulp ot denrut ti sa
,taerht yna rof deraperp eb ot deniart dah droccA tub
”,namowrehtO ,ainivaL ytterP ,eoD nhoJ“
”.epyt ym yllaer ton s’eh
d’eh fi sa ,pit hsac suoreneg a tfel
.detuohs xof eht
.yart draobdrac reh nwod tes ylimE
”.esoprup no od uoy gniht fo dnik eht t’nsi hcnul ot sesemen lautum gniksA
,drocer eht ffo ekops ohw sevitceted ot gnidroccA
!trap siht rof ereh su fo yna deen adnerB dna tehC yhw“
,dnoces a flah a rof gums dekool ylno hteS
,rac deromra na ekil
”.tnemegagne na ton ,gninetsirhc a saw taht dna“
.worc eht dekaorc
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”.sesu retteb hcum fo kniht nac I
”!gnihtyna ro snrecnoc ro skael yna dnif t’nac yeht nehw od yeht tahw tsuj s’taht erus m’I“
nehW…  ”...emoh daeh dluohs uoy kniht I .txet a tog I“
”?erawdrah retupmoc s’elpoep rehto laets ot gniyrt uoy no etartnecnoc ew nac
”?raelc si tsaoc eht llit ffo kaens“
.drows citsalp a no elppaenip fo knuhc a delapmi dah enoemos hcihw
.raeh ot ylimE rof wol oot ,delbmurg hteS
dna emit dna ,delley eH“
gnieelf fo daetsni mih rof rood eht denepo ylmlac ti tahT
,efiL fO yaW naciremA ruO
”.eludehcs fo daeha
.taerht a neve ro
”?reerac ruoy tuoba tahW“ ”.neetriht ta
,seirujni sih eraps ot sa os yltneg
sa desserd saw nitraM ”,oS“
”!noitautis esnet a si siht
saw ytimne derahs rieht taht tcaf eht ta
”…os ,uoy ecaf I nehw egde ylno ym yllaretil s’ti dna ,ti tsurt nac I ekil leef
.dnopser t’ndluoc eh dna sbmurc dna stunaep fo lluf saw htuom sih tub
,tsaf dna deggar saw htaerb s’worc eht
,lufetsatsid erom saw hcihw llet t’ndluoc hteS
.demuf dniwedarT
,fo tuo etareneger ot elba eb uoy t’ndluohS“
,ytilaturb namuhrepus s’taht ,tsinogatna na fo ytefas eht gnidragersid tsuj ton s’tahT“
yas ti did ron ”…lleW“
.xof eht ta yliraelb deknilb eH ”.em rof kool ot
!erehwyna ’tiL ’nitteG‘
”?gniknird eb uoy dluohS“
t’nod I neht dnA
”?uoy t’ndid ,siht ot pu reh tup uoY“ ’?thgir
”!tsieh lanimircrepus suoregn-
”…aciremA htuoS ni sremraf roop rof secirp doof rehgih ot sdael dnA“
.klawtac eht morf eciov a dellac
,ylkciuq ,kaeb s’worc eht fo edis eht dessik eh ”…dluoc ew tuB
”.ylsuoires ytitnedi terces ruoy ekat uoY“
.s’ylimE dehctam taht sarait enotsenihr erow meht fo lareveS
.rehto eht ta gniralg t’nsaw hcae fi sa kool ot gniyrt htob erew yeht
dna sregnif bmun morf xob eht deppord dniwedarT
”!ydaerla ti gniod era elpoeP
,oreh eht eb ot desoppus saw hcihw ,ssenkrad eht ni ,llet ot elbissopmi saw tI
,dekaeuqs ylimE ”!hsogimO“  ”.em llet uoy“
”!siht fo tuo teg ot nalp a deen eW ?esaelp ,sucof uoy dluoC“
”?saw I erehw ot revo gnimoc uoy fo daetsni ,uoy ot ereh revo emoc ot em tnaw ehs did yhw ,ekiL
,won thgir ot olleh yas ot dedeen ehs esle enoemos nees ydaerla dah ylimE tub ,derettum hteS
”?taht od I dluow yhW“
.snialliv ot sneppah tahw s’taht esuaceb gnirifkcab srewop nwo ruoy saw ti syas
,detanimulli ylerab saw yks ehT
,deksa nitraM ”,uoy diD“
”.ytitnedi terces a tuoba noitamrofni evitisnes evah thgim enoemos fi od uoy tahw si hcihW“ ,demuser nitraM
”.derif gnieb tuohtiw pots ot uoy llet t’nac eh nehw mih yfitcejbo ot riafnu ylpeed s’ti dna krow ta s’eh“
,sredluohs reh ot tsomla
,yawyna ,cimaslab eht tuoba elbuort yna t’nsaw yllaer ti mih dlot I
”!ecalp evres fles eht ta revo s’ti fi kcehc annog m’I
.cte ,lla retfa seoreh laer eht erew ohw ,srednopseR tsriF evarB ruo ekil tsuj
”!srossecorp fo tnempihs taht no sdnah ruoy gnitteg ton er’uoY“
,revo tsomla si hcnul ym tub“
fo ecioV ehT ot
.yawyna detlah nialliv eht tub
.deneppah evah tsum ti retfa keew a ylraen litnu detceted ton saw
yltcaxe t’ndluoc droccA
!?nemhcneh egadnob sih otni syug sehsawniarb ohw kcocaep ehT“
”?em dnif uoy did woH“
.tuo uoy dnuof s’nialliv A
taht dezilaer hteS dna
.gnicamirg ydaerla saw eh tub decamirg ev’dluow hteS
”?hctiw dekciw elatyriaf a ekiL
.uoy ot gnilwarc emac I ,derujni saw I nehw tahT“
”.snoitcejbo yna dah enoyna fi deksa ydaerla yehT“
,worc eht dnuora smra sih gnittup xof eht dna
”?wonk ehs seod hcum woh ,ylsuoireS“
.derettulf sdileye s’nitraM
.sevlesmeht ot tpek ohw tros eht ekil demees syawla dah htob yehT
!ytrap siht fo tuo toN“
dna eeffoc sih dehsinif hteS
.teef reh ot depmuj ylimE
.talf ylluferac eciov ,dias droccA
,ylteiuq ,dias hteS
…reh tcepxe t’ndiD
.did yeht tahw saw tahT
.ylrettib dehgual worc ehT
”?draeh uoy t’nevah
”.rehtegoT“ ”?tahw ew erA“ ”?ew era …tuB .onnud I ?elbatnuocca meht dloh ot yaw a dnif tsael tA
dehcnerw sdniw enacirruh nedduS
”!thgir os er’uoy hsogimhO“
”,thgis erutuf eht tog ev’uoY“ .elbat eht no
”?hguoht ,uoy erew erehw“
.niaga ti od ot tnew neht dna
,naM sexelfeR evitingocerP htiW ecnarT A otnI seoG ,yrros os m’I ,hO“
.erawa t’nerew uoy esac ni ,tneserp gniddew a meht thguob ydaerla eW“ .dekrims nitraM
.ti ekat em tel tsuj dluoc uoY“
.sraey ni esuoh ruoy edisni neeb s’uoy tub ydobon …snaeM“
.em llits si gocerp yM“
”.ylteiuq yreV .deksa I“
.ffo erew edisni sthgil ehT
?ynnuf si siht kniht I kniht uoY“ .dessih hteS
”.efaS uoY speeK ytitnedI terceS ruoY woH tuoba spiT lufpleH htiw telhpmap elttil a em tnes yeht“
.rehtegot krow tnatropmI
”?won thgir ,od ew od tahw“
”!nialliv a em llac elpoep dnA
,dniwlrihw a ekil dnuos a htiw ,ria eht otni esor eno yllaniF
”.ssa elbareffusni na ton m’I esuaceb“
.droccA dias ”,lleW“
snoitcejbo noitanitsederp yna evah ylbissop t’nac uoY
”,ti si ,etal oot ton s’tI“
ezag s’worc eht dewollof xof ehT
,mra ,edis sih degadnab nitraM
delrihw taht ecnelubrut fo seidde llams eht erew noitatiga fo sngis ylno ehT ”?dnA“
ot taerht suoregnad a hcus mih edam ria otni ydob sih nrut ot rewop s’dniwedarT woh fo
,eikooc rettub tunaep eht hguorht yawflah ,desuap nitraM
.ela regnig sih revo ylkrad dedoorb hteS
.did nitraM oS ”.em llet uoY
!taerg gniog yllaer s’ti dna haey hO“
.skcart sih ni deppots droccA
”.wonk I“ ,dehsinif hteS
tub deciton evah ton yam uoY“
,rehtohcae tuoba
,eciov sih ni feilebsid delffab elttil a
,dias ylimE ”!kcaB“ ”!GNIHTYNA
”?yas gocerp eht d’tahW“ ”.hO“
noitnetta reh morf troper swen eht dessimsid ylimE
?slatipsoH“ ”?tahw ekiL“
”!wonk uoy enoemos htiw otohp a ni eb ot teg ll’uoy ecnahc tsal eht s’nehw wonk reven uoy“
.detnioppasid yllaer eb ot ,ytrap gniddew eht fo trap sa ,ysub oot raf saw ehs tub
!htob uoy ees ot doog os saw ti tub ,krow ot kcab teg attog I
tub tnih eht teg yllaer t’ndid eH“
.sgniddew evol os did ehS !rehtegot
,citehtap s’tI“ .gniraelc saw daeh sih esuaceb ebyam
.meht hctaw ot ton gnidneterp
.rood gninepo ylwols eht hguorht mih dniheb pmalteerts eht morf emac ytilibisiv ylno ehT
,dias dniwedarT ”,yllatnedicnI“