,uoy rof evarg on eb lliw erehT .oot
,gninrom eht nI   .ainnellim ni
.ecneloveneb enigami uoy ,tirips ruoy fo epoh gniteelf eht ni ...dna
.snirg dna ,siht sesnes ehS
!hah ,deb latrom a ni detavitluc ylerar ylno si modsiw hcuS
.uoy revo speews worros gnirettahs A
,uoy dnuora teknalb ruoy fo gar ymirg eht llup uoY
,mmmM" .eye ruoy rednu pu eugnot gnol reh sgard dna
.dnuorg eht no sselefil ti sevael dna
,rerednaw ,thguard yht si rettiB" .snoino tuc ot
.modsiw elbirret dna tsav rieht lla ni
,niksretaw a dna kcap a yrrac uoY
.gnideelb dna gnignits ot sdap ruoy hctarcs ecalp siht fo seltten dna skcor eht taht os ,nrot si elos eht dna
detevoc evah uoY
.lla fo doolb tseteews eht esnes I meht gnoma dna
,tserof eht fo egde eht ot klaw uoy
?uoht tsdluow ,geB" .ssenilgu
.nerdlihc rieht dna
,gnillik eht htiw suoixna nworg evah uoY .nials dna
,tfihs srae reH .gnilkcac
"...tbuod t'nod I ,eeht htiw seid dna
.swolb nekcirts evah uoY .oot
,kcen ruoy fo kcab eht reh gniwohs fo aedi eht ta slwarc tlep ruoY
.ecaf ruoy gnola sehcuot
sllems eht dna sdnuos eht htiw
.dlog dna doolb fo remmihs a ni syar tsal s'yad eht stcelfer hcihw
,rednic a tub si nus eht litnu evil tliw uohT
.reverof ereh yats dluoc uoy taht hsiw ruoy si tI
,tleb ruoy ta efink a si ereht dna
?ton uoht tra ,retnuh-hctiw a tra uohT
.daed si neht dna sehsiruolf ti rednu dlrow dnoces eht dna ,seird aes ehT .yawa selbmurc niatnuom hcae
,taorht ruoy no htaerb toh reh leef uoy dna ,ecaf ruoy ot eson reh fo dap dloc eht stfil ehS
.leehw nogaw a rednu dehsurc tnepres a ekil ti rednu desserp yal uoy dnA
.gniht etarapes a ,dlrow eht fo gninrut eht dehctaw evah uoy retfa reve dna
.flesruoy ta ni reep uoY
--yruxul siht fo devirped era uoy yaw eht dna
,lanretam osla tub ,dirroh dna tneicna ,uoy erofeb gnidnats ,uoy morf flesreh swardhtiw ehS
,rereffuS ,evil tliw uohT
.swols gnihtaerb ruoy ,tsal ta neht dnA
"!ecneloiv yht fo emirc eht rof ,no dna no
tsdluoW" .uoy ta nolat detsiwt eno gnitniop
.tnemhsinup ruoy fo ynoga eht ni erusaelp lauxes a gnikat ,gnikorts dna gnizeeuqs
.od uoy tub ,lla ta namow eht ffo seye ruoy gnikat ro
,htiw uoy sehctulc ehs dloh leurc a si tI
seert dlo dnarg eseht fo stoor eht tuoba gnikluks
uoy rof ylno evas
,nwaf eht fo kcen eht skaerb ehs ,noitom htooms a htiW   ".egatod
?llif yht dah ton uoht tsaH !htaeD"
,htob cigam kcalb dna cigam etihw
.meht ni llewd ot edam erew uoy litnu ,efil ruoy fo srenroc krad eht enimaxe uoy did reveN .hpmuirt
.elbigelli won yrdlareh sti
.uoy sevom taht lliw ruoy fo flah ylno si ti
.tsew eht fo tuo sllor ezeerb nmutua looc a dna
,tser ni nopu nael uoy eert kao eht fo evarg ylenol a ekam thgim uoy spahreP
.lliw reh ot deredro ,reh evoba dna rednu deyarra snevaeh eht
,eson ruoy fo htgnel eht nwod gnikaerts sraet eht leef dna
,ereht dna neht elcarim gnillik reh gnimrofrep
.tae ydob yht tsum os ,latrom tra uoht sa tuB"
.wena srewolf eht llems dna
-reh si ti wonk uoy ,yltnatsnI
.namow dlo eht rof tuoba kool dna
,'nerdlihc' drow eht setsat ehs sa elzzum reh revo flesti slruc eugnot gnol A
.lla ta stsixe yldrah ti ,tsaf os seid 'esaelp' fo tirips ehT
,meht fo kniht uoy ,ylrettiB .slatrommi
,stserof eseht ni si ecalp s'flow A
,dnoyeb syal taht kraD gnihtoN eht ot yaw sevig tserof eht litnu
,hguone noos roF
.elpoep tneitnes eht fo eugnot eht skaeps taht gniht gnivil yreve si ehS
,emoh edor uoy sa uoy thguac ohw enorc tneicna eht fo maerdyad uoY
hsiloof si ti tub
,ni uoy nokceb ot sregnif ekil lruc sehsub dna srairB
litnu ,nus eht rednu snrut htrae eht dna wolb sduolc
.drow suoiciled a tahW .esaelP .esaelP"
uoht dna ,gnilflow ,evarg yht gnikees tra uohT ?he ,eid ot
.dlrow siht lla srevoc drawot gnihcram tra uoht ssensselemit fo liev eht dna
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.repsihw uoY ".esaelP"
.deksa ecirp on htiw
.rorre yht re'o gnipeew ytinrete dneps thgim uoht taht
.sehceeb dna sredla ,snrohtkcalb
,tuo snur dlrow eht erofeb dlohserht lanif eht ,dooW tsaL eht
.stseirp dna sdraziw dna srerujnoc dna stsimehcla ,sdrawretfa nem esiw htiw sklat gnol ehT
.efil ruoy fo thgiliwt gnidne-reven eht ni
.ylralugerri tuc sreksihw ruoy dna deppihc sgnaf ruoy
,won uoy denodnaba sah yromem eht fo trofmoc lartsecna eht tuB
.NGISLLAC htiw ,REDAER yb uoy rof daer ,ijustihoK yb ”dooW tsaL eht ni relevarT“ saw sihT
erehw tuons dna kcen ruoy no skram etihw era ereht dna
,htaed morf uoy tpek sah ecarg lufetah emos tub
hguoht ,od uoY   ".dnatS .emoC
,ecalp siht fo edam neeb evah spam on -won noitagivan on si ereht taht gniwonk
.nwaf elttil eht sekorts ehS ".ecalp
.htrae dna nevaeh eht ni sthgil gnicnad ekil reh dnuora deyarra srats eht
.kcab worg ot taoc ruoy rof gnitiaw fo sraey gnol ehT
.xeh reh ot mitciv nellaf sah ohw eno sa hctiw a deraef os ohw nam on si ereht dna
.ereh eeht ekat ot slevart yht rof
.esiwrehto ro eninac enilef
,reverof sevil hcihw taht raef ot
"!gnilflow ,eramthgin flah TRA ylurt uoht
,stibbar htiw raw ta ,ecaf reh ni sevlow ees uoY
.ycrem ronim a eeht droffa lliw I ,suht eeht llems ot em sesaelp ti esuaceb dna
ereht llewd taht sgniht dekciw eht ot kaeps thgim uoy erehw
.sgnaf regit tsniaga yldekoorc deltsen hteet kle talf ees uoy
.dlrow eht fo egde eht ta gnidnats era uoY
,dnop llits ,raelc a revo smrof gnipeew rieht tneb evah taht
,rettiB"   .redduhs uoY
sgel ruoy fo ehca ehT
depraw ekil doow daed reh tuohguorht sgnir enorc eht fo rethgual ehT   ".lufituaeb si
,enon ro nolat lla ro
.seert eht ni dniw fo gnihtaerb teiuq eht tub lla ta dnuos erom on si ereht litnu
.ecalp siht ot niaga emoc reveN
tneluccus si taem ehT
,nem eht htiw gnikoj rebmemer uoy
erofeb dnats uoy won dna sraey gnol ynam deklaw evah uoY
,rellik-hctiw a tra uohT
".uoy fo geb I ,epoh ylno dna tsal ym era uoY
hA" .efink ruoy gnippirg wap ruoy leef uoy dna ,tirips ruoy fo deb-raef eht ni toor sekat regna fo dees A
ni daert uoY   .emit fo dne eht
,wolliw eht rednu stis ehS
.rovas wen htiw nrub sdnuow dlo fo sehca eht dna
.eeht dedroffa emit eht htiw live on od dna
,yas uoY ".rehtom dlo ,esaelP"
".thguob ecnetinep yht sah modsiw regaem tahw em llet dna
deduolc era smaerd ruoy dna
taorht ruoy nwod selkcirt doolb taht drah os maercs uoY
yht raeh em teL .evah tlahs uoht htaed nehT
,flow rotsecna na sa yarg sa
.no og ot denimreted era uoy siht gniwonk dna
.ydaerla ti leef nac uoY
:yoj yloh rieht ni yrc skralwodaem dna sehcnif eht sa
.srehto eht fo ynam erofeb gnol dehsiugnitxe si nus nwo ruoy fo emalf eht dna
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.thgil on kcab worht seye neerg thgirb ruoY
.gnilflow ,niaga latrom a tra uohT"
.sruoh rof stsal sihT
,gninraw tuohtiw dnA   ".yrc s'tnetinep
ro shpmuirt tseuq ruoy litnU
,yraew era uoy rof ,aedi citnamor a si tI
.esroh a rof uoy deggeb
.eseht deirc reve erehwyna nam latrom oN
,ereht gnidnats reh ees ot ekaw uoY .thgindiM
srups meht fo ekam dna eeht nihtiw epoh fo stib elttil tsal eht hctans dluoc I
.noitulosba rof yarp dna ,yawa ti hsup uoy dna
!leenK ?gnilflow ,teef yht nopu geb ot motsuc yht ti sI
,eeht ot siht evig I
.evolgxof dna worray ,caliL
tsehsiw uohT ...rettib
.reh ni retlehs uoy dna ,tserof eht hguorht gniwolb ylneddus erew elag mirg a fi sa si tI
,egasiv reh dna ydob reh fo egakcerw tneb eht sraef ti rof
.hguoc uoy "...sdrib ehT
dna erusaelp fo ylno gnikniht dna gnilwoh dna gniknird
rehto eht lla dna
.retaw fo rorrim krad eht nopu kcab spets dna
,dlotnu gnireffus fo si hcnets yht sa tuB
,gnikahs ,dnats uoY
.uoy erob taht dlrow eht fo ssentsav eurt eht fo espmilg a hctac
.emas eht dna eno lla si ti dna
thguoht eht sa dna ,nelots neeb evah yeht taht ,sreh neve ton era yeht taht ysatnaf dliw neddus eht evah uoY
.taeper uoY ".esaelP"
!deedni ylevol si seid hcihw tahT
,uoy erofeb tuo sllor tI   ijustihoK yb
.erusopmoc ruoy niager dna bos a nwod ekohc uoY
?eeht rof ti gid ot namow dlo na ot tsemoc
.taorht ruoy gnipsarg ,yas uoY
".eeht sdroffa htrae
,edaf dna rekcilf thgil gniremmilg hcae ees uoY
.erom on si ereht dna
.efiw ruoy fo larenuf ehT
.eson ym dna swap ym ot flesyht dnemmoc dna ecnegludni siht namow dlo na oD .dnilb
,ereh lufecaep si dlrow eht tuB
.ruc ,nossel tsrif s'rehtom yht eb ot thguo ecneidebO"   .ecnereffidni otni devlossid ytleurc ,derob eciov reh
,gnidne-reven YLLAER s'taht yenruoj a no eeht dnes ot
,dluow traeh ruoy ,uoy llet ton did esruc ruoy dna yromem ruoy fi
,gnildrol enipul elttil A
,walc delrang a tuo sehcaer enorc ehT
.elttirb dna gnitlah
.stnepres dna reed dna sexnyl htiw raw ta
emit tsrif eht rof
.tsaerb ruoy ot drah ti sesserp dna
.laicepse ni ,eeht erofeB
,nolat flah era swap reH
.nwaf eht tae dna kooc uoY
.sworra debrab fo thgilf a ekil taorht ruoy morf nwardhtiw era sdrow dna
tsum uoy ,niav devorp si
,ydob reh revo gnimaor swalc reh ,ysatsce latot ni flesreh sdloh ehS .slleb
,elzzum daorb s'raeb a dna
".evila ma I ,evila ma I"
,gnidne s'htrae eht litnu hcram ot sruoy si tI .og
,thgilrats fo rorrim a pota
,oot ereht ni si raef yht rof ,deedni sey ,hhhO"
,yletarebiled ,ylwolS
.liat ruoy no gnihctac erif-hcrot eht fo gnileef ehT
.nwot eht morf uoy evord dna
,seldnac dnasuoht a fo gniffuns eht ni dne ti ees uoy dna
?he ,desruc eciwt eb uoht
reh ni duorp dna ythguah ,ria eht otni eson reh stfil ehS
,ijustihoK yb
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.ti no srewolfdliw llems nac uoY
dna walc a pu gnidloh ,skaeps ehS "--ha-
dooW tsaL eht otni og thgim uoy taht uoy devreserp dna
.uoy wollof ot skcirt s'gah on dna ,tra uoht ,eyA"
,oG .uoht tratspu ykcuL
.dloheb ot emoseurg si hcihw
,selims ehs dnim ruoy revo sessap
!sey ,deedni doog yrev ,hhhO" .seirc ehs "!hhO"
".rof era nerdlihc tahw si siht ,tsewonk uoht yleruS .krow ytrid yht mrofrep senob fo gab dlo na evah ot ,nam sselemahS
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”dooW tsaL eht ni relevarT“
,yponac eht evobA
.tnemenota gnikees emac I"
,nwod reh yal yam nrocinu a fo tsaerb eht ni worra na ro
.luos ruoy ni delgnat gnitnirpmi evisnapxe desrucca taht
"!ahA !haH ?he ,efil reh htiw ti thguob ehs rof ,eb thgim ti ylgnik dnA
,edahs rieht fo ssenkrad hcir eht ni
,ytsud og htrae ruoy fo niatnuof ylevol hcae ees uoY
,niaga skaeps ehs tsal ta dna uoy neewteb tuo flesti sehcterts ecnelis fo doirep gnol A
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.uoy fo geb I ,htaed em tnarg ,ylnO
,uoy rof nepo gniyal
..." .dnuorg eht tsniaga psar uoY "...seid hcihw tahT"
".dlrow siht morf yawa ssap tliw uoht
.yldesumeb ,swac ehS "?he ,htaeD"   ".uoy
.emit tsal eht si epoh uoy tahw rof peels dna
,ezag reh fo egnellahc eht ta sgnaf sraeb sruoy fo tcnitsni tneicna emos dna ,suoedih si ehS
.kcits gniklaw a rof raeps dekoorc elgnis a htiw klaw uoy dna
.latrommi si doolb yht dna ,tra uoht ,rerednaW
.deen tsetaerg fo ruoh ruoy ni
.gninnips llits si dlrow ehT
.gniyd era syaw dlo eht tuB
ecaf ruoy pu sehcnerw
swalc reh spans ehs
.latsyrc ni deppart diulf ekil ,xulf lauteprep ni osla era yeht llits era yeht hguoht rof
.tsrif swaj s'rehtom sih raef ton did ohw flow a nrob neeb evah ereht dluohs reveN
,spets suoituac htiW
,llet ot elbissopmi noisserpxe eht
.dnuorg eht nopu leenk uoy
,tirips ruoy otni thgiN eht fo eceip a dettink swalc tneicna reh ,dnuorg eht no gnipsar yal ehs sa dnA
,enaforp si thguoht eht tub
.hteet dehctamsim fo lluf htuom a htiw elims a uoy sevig ehs dna
,gnilflow ,eeht nopu seil sesproc ynam fo knits ehT
daehrevo gnosdrib eht si tnellecxe dna
.lios teews eht no gnidaert
ma I rof ,pup ,ecaf yht ton revoC
htuoy ruoy fo remmus dna gnirps nedlog eht ,sraey fo erusaem taerg eht revo kcab kniht uoY
dellup gnieb efink ytsur a fo enihw nori eht ekil eciov a ni sworc ehs ",rettiB"
,nerrab syal dlrow eht dna yawa nrub srats eht lla nehw ton
"!em htiw rellik-hctiw eht ton yalp os ,*pup* ris
.syaw ynam ni uoy snethgirf tserof eht fo trofmoc krad ehT
,tsal ta eid ot snigeb ydob ruoy fo hself ehT
,uoy ot revo sedirts ehs sa elppir neve t'nseod retaw ehT
.uoy nihtiw slwarc noisluveR
era erehT .gnidnefed efil ruoy tneps evah uoy secalptekram gniltsub dna
.ytisoreneg s'retsis ym fo noos oot ekops I
,won meht htiw gniyd era uoY
.tsal ta eciov ruoy dnif uoy dna
,deppihc si rae enO
,shtap tserof eht gniwollof yad eht fo tser eht dneps dna
,gnitnap dna gnivaeh ,flesreh sdloh ehS
,noitavlas ruoy ,revewoh ,si krad yloh taht nihtiW
,ohohoH .ohoh ,sevil tey yrlavihC ?htaed roF"
.pu gnillup spil gnol reh
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
,retsis ym fo swen llems I knits yht no rof ,erus
,wolliw a htiw ni ydob yht evaew dluoc I .daot sselhceeps a otni eeht ekam dluoc I
.doohtluda larutan dna
,dniw eht fo eltsur eht raeh dna
.rats elgnis a gnibrutsid reven
.em evah yam sdrib ehT"
,dnop eht fo ecafrus rorrim eht ssorca
,tuo ti gnitib reh enigami ylfeirb dna
,sezeerf traeh ruoY
.uoy brutsid ereh thgim serutaerc dliw tub
.sraet yht fo tlas eht dna
.mmM"   .uoy gniziniturcs ,snworf ehS
.enola ylurt era uoY
,reh erofeb flesruoy etartsorp uoY
yojne esaelP   .ytiniffaruF no
,tsdluow uoht fi ,kaepS
”dooW tsaL eht ni relevarT“
ecarg s'wodahs a htiw sklaw ehs dna
.flesruoy rof tserof eht fo esnapxe taerg eht lla evah uoy dna
.noitarepsed eht ,sserp eht fo taeh eht dna
kaeb s'worc a fo noitseggus eht ees uoY
reh ni reh ot tfel sthgiled wef htiw namow dlo na gnisaelp rof
.ti fo ewa ni eb esle ro
--ytilatrommi dirroh ruoy yb erew uoy sa deksam ,niaga uoy ta kool dluow gniht gnivil on yaw ehT .levart ni
!em sgnirb retsis ym tfig didnelps a tahW
.elims ot pu gnikool ,syas ehs
.emosdnah erew uoy ,raw ot edor uoy tsrif nehw hguoht
.htrae yssarg eht ot spil ruoy sserp
,deppir dna delios si gnik daed-gnol ruoy fo melbme eht dna ,yawa detsur ylraen si raew uoy liam fo taoc ehT
dnop eht dna yks eht morf srats eht fo thgil eht spir dna
,smle dna skao lla
,rehtael deniur eht hguorht tuo sserp teef ruoy fo swalc eht ,derettat dna nrow era stoob ruoY
.ydaerla yot nekorb a tra uohT
,sniap ynam dereffus evah uoY
"?edutitarG"   ".uoy knahT"
.eeht erofeb dlrow siht morf yawa ssap llahs yeht neve dna
,doolb reh fo tew toh eht rebmemer uoY
.flesti etipsed lufhtarw dna lufetah
.thgin eb lliw ti ,nooS
.lairub ton ,htaed gnikees ylno emoc I ,esaelP"
,ti desu evah uoy ecnis gnol oot neeb sah tI
,hcum oot saw ti ,yrlavihc s'thgink a htiw nevE .esroh erem A
.dewollof taht thgin eht fo daerd dloc eht
"?evael ot eerf m'I ...ma I"
,reh dna flesruoy neewteb erusaem rednels eht daert uoy
,erif taerg a htiw nigeb ti ees uoY
,nerdlihc rieht dna
swolliw fo evorg a ot emoc uoy
.rettib ylneddus ,stips namow ehT ".lla
.dlihc ruoy fo larenuf ehT
.si ti erehw efink eht evael uoy ,desitsahC
.pal reh ni daeh sti gnitser nwaf gnuoy a
,detaluceps evah sdraziw eht sa dna ,sey ,ecaps fo dne ehT
,htrae eht nihtiw derretni yal ohw lla ,dlihc ruoy dna efiw ruoy dna rehtom ruoY
.reh deweh dna drows ruoy koot uoy dna
.stibah dlo otni kcab gnillaf si ohw
,tnelis ylidaets seog gnosdrib fo dnuos ehT
ti ot netsil dna tsud eht ni yal uoY
?hsiw yht si htaed -neht doog yreV
,eye s'dnim ruoy ni sdnats ehs llits tub ,dlihc a ekil seye ruoy edih uoY
.ytinrete fo edutingam eht ,slairt ruoy fo dne eht erofeb ,dloheb uoY
eht gnissik ycrem tahw ees dna retsiS tsedlE eht erofeb timbuS
,thgiN fo derhs eht yawa snrub erifrats fo ynoga eht sa
era uoy woN .thgil lufetah eht morf trapa reveroF
.uoy revo dessap evah sgnaf dna sreggad
tirips desrucca ruoy tsal ta desnes yeht nehw tsehc ruoy hguorht demmar stcejbus ruoy krofhctip ehT
".reh tlaed uoht gnidnuow eht dna
enon taht sdnal dezilivic eht morf raf os
.eb llahs reve enon dna
tnemom a rof dna
,uoy rof rorroh erom on sdloh egami ruoY
,kcab daeh reh syal ehS
,dlrow siht ni cigam tsav a si ereht taht ees uoy ,dnop eht ni thgilrats gnilkniwt eht nI .gnivol dna
.ssarg eht otni gnippird
,mih yals thgim nogard a fo kcen eht ni drows a yaw eht dna
.diov etinifni eht otni pu erats uoy enod si ti nehW .seirutneC
,ereht kcab seidob fo sdleif
.tserof eht fo moolg eht otni sedaf wodahs reh sa reh fo ees uoy gniht tsal eht si enihseye ehT
.uoy sdloh gah eht sa elbmert ylno nac uoY
seltsac detluav-hgih eht era uoy dniheb raF
,won syaw dlo eht era syaw nwo enihT
latrom si hcihw taht rof larutan si ti rof
,senots ho ,srats ho ,hooO