.eerhT .owT .pets enO
,nehctik eht ot ni dna sriats eht nwod dettort ehS
.gninrom eht ni detelpmoc eb t’ndluoc taht gnihton
tuo flesti gnikat ton fo emirc eht rof ,nossel a gab siht hcaet ot deen dluow ehS
,reh desaelp trofmoc fo emotipe taht ni gnirebmuls fo thguoht ehT
.laog lanif reh detiawa gnieb yrev reh fo ecnesse eritne eht sa
.ereht og ot dedeen ehS .seye
,gnol oot neeb dah tI
.sriats eht fo pot eht ta dewolg ylevitisop htmraw lufrednow tahT
reh edisni werg ssenitpme fo gnileef a
dna lufrednow fo peels a ot
.noococ a ekil reh dnuora gnipparw
.nettogrof d’ehs gnihtyna rof ylsuoixna dnuora dekool ehS
stellep eht fo edis rehto eht nO
.reh fo tnorf ni ssem reehs eht yb tnedive
”deB ot seoG elkrapS
.ydob reh ni erbif yreve revo dehsaw ssilb erup sa
,flesreh ot deugra ehs ,teY
reh dniheb dednuos tooh railimaf A
roolf dnoces eht fo latsedep eht nopu ,ereht tas tI
,od ot tfel gnihton saw erehT
xob deneponu eht thguos dna yrtnap eht denepo ehS
yrtnap eht desitebahpla dna degnarraer yllacitametsys ehs sa delbmurg thgiliwT
.ytimertxe sti ot denethgit tonk eht sa tsetorp ni denaorg tI
elkrapS thgiliwT“:yojne esaelP
yltcaxe ti ecalp ot eton luferac gnikat ,noitisop lanigiro sti ot kcab ti decalp dna doof eht htiw mirb eht ot ti dellif ,cigam reh htiw lliswodniw eht morf lwob eht dellup ehS
,eson reh dellif nenil denaelc ylhserf fo tnecs eht sa ylluftsiw dehgis ehS
reh revo peerc htmraw desimorp sti leef dluoc ehS
.traeh sih ni ecalp a sdloh llits tub
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.ot dengissa neeb dah eh ssenisub revetahw rof gnivael erofeb thguob dah ekipS taht stelleP lwO s’malF & milF fo
.resolc pets eno saw
.reh ecarbme ot saw erised ylno stI .reh detnaw tI
.ksed derettulc reh revo dekool dna sgel reh dehcterts dna pu doots thgiliwT
denaelc-yrd ylhserf fo
,egabrag eht ta denworf thgiliwT
.rood eht denepo ehs emit yreve degnahc yrotnevni s'yrtnap denrad eht raews dluoc ehS ?ti saw erehW
trofkooB tnegA/yeliaB nhoJ yb ”deB ot seoG
.ksed krow denaelc reh fo tnemhsilpmocca eht ta delims ehS
.reh gnicneinevnocni yletamitlu dna
god yppup gnidaelp htiw detiaw dna
.ezirp reh demialc yllanif
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
ticilli eht ni ylhguoroht flesreh gnipparw
,esnetni ylralucitrap neeb dah noisses yduts s’gnineve sihT
,rebmemer nac eh sa gnol sa rof noitcif-erutaerc nettirw s’eH
.rehto hcae rof gnillac yltnelis hcae
.tiaw ot deen dluow
.deb reh otni delgguns dna ,nwod yal
thgiliwT“ saw sihT.eep ot evah I
.psarg reh fo tuo deppils ezirp reh sa
reh ecitne dluow ssenhserf fo noitasnes dna llems ehT .nenil deb
.psarg reh nihtiw saw ti ,woN .yawa raf oot
.trofmoc elbanigaminu
.erom ecno dehsaw neeb dah yeht ecno ,niaga emoc ylno dluow wenk ehs hcihw
sniffirg fo slautir lainomerec eht no yduts tnecer reh sa hcus
,reh ot resolc meht gnillup
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.htrof thguorb thguoht s’deb eht
,teehs eht nepo dellup ylwols ehS
.deined rehtruf saw peels rof erised reh sa depoord
.dedeen saw eh litnu ,esruoc fo ,saw tahT
spil reh morf dettime naom wol a
.ruoF .eerhT .owT .pets enO
.nepo tohs seye reH .deppots ehS
.maj deruovalf niradnam saw ereht ,daetsnI
,steehs dna sserttam tfos a fo trofmoc mraw eht htiw reh decitne
evah ot ,dehsilpmocca dna gnitrofmoc
,flehs eht no decalp ehs koob hcae htiW
gninokceb tnassecni
.desinagro dna naelc deniamer yrarbil eht erus ekam ot reh ot pu saw ti ,syad wef txen eht rof nwot fo tuo ekipS htiW .dehgis ehS
,rebmemer ot emit eht nekat dah ehs ykcul saw tI !hteeT
eht erongi ot deirt thgiliwT
.denrae yllufthgir os dah ehs taht
noitcefrep rof edalocca reH
.wollip deffulf-rehtaef dna
.pu dexim eb t’ndluoc yeht os ,flehs driht eht no eb ot desoppus saw reppep ehT
,srae reh desserac ylteews gnas slegna fo surohc a sa wolg ylnevaeh a ni ylthgirb gninihs
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.tep a deef ot tegrof ot gniht elbirret a saw tI
,srettam tnatropmi erom rof moor ekam ot flesti dir ot gnisufer
.ereht yawflah saw ehS .neT
.niaga sriats eht drawot kert reh nageb dna delims ehS
.ti dnuof ehs erehw
,trofmoc elbabircsedni dna elbaecalperri
.ezirp denrae-llew reh mialc dluoc ehs ,woN
.ecnasiun tnavelerri na dna
– denoisivne dah ehs sa tsuj saw tI
.ereht tsomla saw ehS !eviF
.ecalp lausu sti ni t’nerew stelleP lwO ehT
.erised etamitlu dna ,laog reh dleh taht gnimarf nedoow eht ees dluoc ehS .saw ti erehT
.rehto on otnu noisnecsa na saw tfig yldog
.reh gnippots on saw ereht ,emit sihT
.gnol os rof ,rof gnitiaw neeb dah ehs ezirp eht mialc ot ydaer saw ehs woN .enohs hteet reh
.rood tnorf eht ot derednaw ehs sa reh fo tnorf ni ti gnitativel
,ti mialc dluow ehS
,noitcifnaf ynoP elttiL yM a si sihT
,trofkooB tnegA/yeliaB nhoJ yb
.steehs denaelc ylhserf reh fo srevoc eht rednu evid yletamitlu dluoc ehs os ,rof gnikool saw ehs tahw dnif dluow ehs taht sepoh eht ni
,koob ysatnaf erutaerc cirtnec-nohpyrg tsrif sih dehsilbup yltnecer sah dna
.ecrof htiw gab egabrag citsalp eht pu deit dna
,seye reh desolc ehS
,daeh s’elkrapS thgiliwT ni gnuh thguoht ehT .deB
taht sdrawot pets hcaE
.lwocs a htiw xobliam eht ot txen nwod ti tes ehS
.llac s’neris a ekil reh ot gnas tI
.stellep lwo fo xob eht ediseb
.syaw fo gniyfsitas tsom eht ni reh dellihc
,ylpeed dehgis thgiliwT
.moor gnivil reh ot dehsur dna tooh suoicarg
.rehtruf gnihtyna nettogrof ton dah ehs rof ,dezzub ylippah dnim reH
steehs suortsul esoht ot nruter ot erised tnerehni reh
fo gnileef eht ot airohpue fo esnes lufrednow a gnidda
.nrettap desinagro-oduesp emos ni roolf eht ssorca nwerts erew repap parcs dna sllorcs ,skooB
.laiceps saw thginoT
.s’O-itseleC ,laerec etiruovaf reh eb ot desoppus saw
,steknalb eht otni delgguns ehS
.gnol os rof desimorp dah yeht htmraw
.htaerb reh rednu desruc thgiliwT
,skrow redlo s’nhoJ fo eno si dna
trofmoc dna htmraw eht ot democlew eb dluow ehs thginot ,oN
.yad eht fo tsom rof tpels eh nehw detsixe drib eht taht tegrof ot ysae saw ti
s’drib eht derongi ehS
,stamrof lacisyhp dna koob-e ni nozamA no ti dnif nac uoY .eriD
.efil sih fo tsom rof ytinummoc yrruf eht fo rebmem a dna ,retirw diva na neeb sah ohw ,yeliaB nhoJ yb
”deB ot seoG elkrapS thgiliwT“
.feiler ni dehgis dna reh dniheb rood eht desolc ehS !ti wohs ll’tahT
.reppep eht raen ton tub ,tlas eht ot txen ,flehs dnoces eht no eb ot desoppus saw tI
.ytuaeb suoidommoc fo ezirp gniwolg reh sdrawot yawflah ksat dehsinifnu na rebmemer ot desufer ehS
,hcneb eht no gnidnats lwo reh ees ot ,ylkciuq dnuora delrihw ehs dna
,gnillac tnassecni sti etipsed ,deB
,reh denokceb deb reh fo thguoht eht ,emit siht ,oN
,emocrevo ot elcatsbo rehtona tub thguan neeb evah dluow ksat lainem siht esiwrehto
.tsuguA fo htnom eht gnirud
,mraw erom neve siht edam erised reH
,dethgir ehs llorcs hcae dna
.setisbew liater suoirav no stamrof lacisyhp ni dna
.retteb saw ti – on
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.snoitcartsid rehtruf yna tuohtiw
,gnihsinif ylksirB
seye reH .nehctik eht ot kcab derednaw dna daeh reh koohs ehS
.deb reh dna reh neewteb gnidnats gnihton saw ereht ,woN
!won reh pots dluoc gnihtoN
,ria eht dellif deb dna ynop neewteb erised lautum ehT
.suoicsiwolwO def t’ndah ehS...
,tas ti erehT .ytnewT .neeteniN
steehs deb lausu reh ni gnipeels eb tsuj t’ndluow thgiliwT ,thginoT
ezirp eht mialc yllanif ot reh rof gninokceb
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.eralg dennapdaed a drib eht evag thgiliwT
.meht reuqnoc dluow ehs dna ,desrevart eb ot deniamer sriats eht ylnO
.tuo hsart eht nekat t’ndah ehS —iF .ruoF
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.elims lufssilb a otni werg nirg reH