.rekcor ym ot txen hcrop eht no niaga dna mih rof riahc ym ot txen kcossah a peek ot denrael I
.flesti ekaw yad eht hctaw
niaga ti no elims taht dah ecaf siH
.suovren saw I ,esruoc fO .etad tsrif ruo saw tI .suovren tib a naht erom tub
.sivlep detacolsid a
.ylthgils os reve daeh sih desiar dna
goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.sgge dekil eh fi mih deksa yllautca I
.sgod gnidulcni ,srieht tog s'enoyrevE .drow a s'ti tub ,wonk I ,drow dab a s'tI
meht wohs nac uoy evol revetahW .yllausu
.sworc eht rof dleif kcab eht ni mih tfel dna yadretsey mih tog I .t'nia eH
.llew etiuq gnola teg yeht os ,elamef era meht fo htoB
puorg eucser yksuh a yb deucser saw ehS
dluoc I ecalp a saw tI
.deriuqer toof xis
.htiw od ot tahw wonk I naht evol erom kcab evig yeht swonk doG
?I t'ndluow ,ecalp htaed eht ta kcab thgir eb d'I ,uoy esaelp t'ndid I fI
.thgif yna tuohtiw ylevissap dael ym dewollof eH
.evresed os yeht evol eht
.egdirB wobniaR eht tuoba seirots eht draeh evah I
,ecnef toof evif a sah ylno nur god ruo dnA
.dnuop god taht ta kcab flesym dnuof I tub ,ecalp eht ot revo gnivird rebmemer neve t'nod I
.taht tuoba doog tlef ew os ,yrevocer lacigrus reh ot gnidnet lrig eht yb detpoda neht saw ehS
.truoc eht ni etoyoc ruoy
.eoR ,dehsinif s'eh kniht I
.ylthgils os reve gniggaw saw liat sih dna
.god a evah uoy fi dlrow ylenol a hcus ton s'tI
.rehtegot gnihtyreve od hcum ytterp ew ,tcaf nI
,ydaer er'uoy nehw dnA
.eeffoc ym gniknird elihw
.ecalp eht gninnur nam gnuoy eht htiw gniklat niagA
.reh no gnikcehc ,robhgien a yb deripxe dnuof saw ehs nehw esuoh s'ydal ylredle
.truoc eht no
.dlo oot erew ew tlef yeht esuaceb nwod denrut erew ew
,meht ta kool uoy nehW
.gnidaer ylno er'uoy esuaceb t'ndid uoy esruoc fO ?taht eeS
?he ,ereht llits elip doow eht rednu nar I taht ees nac uoy dna
s'ereht ,wonk uoy os tsuJ .daeh
...tsuj ,ruoh doog a rof roolf eht no mih ot txen tas I
gnivael ,rac a yb kcurts neht denodnaba saw ,yksuh a ,amlA .eton s'retirW
,deriuqni ew ,dethgiled erew sklof retlehs eht dnA
,kcab reh thguorb dna pu welf yllautca ohw
.em ta pu dekool I nehW
.won ylenol ssel hcum leef I
.retlehs a tisiv dna og
.dray eht ni mih rof ecalp ytsur ,ecin a dnuof I
,semitemos skcirt yalp
.won shtnom xis neeb s'tI
.daeh sih koohs dna enim no dnah a decalp eh tub
esoht rof emit fo tol a fo tnuoma llams sih pu desu dah
.spuc eeffoc nwo rieht evah neve yehT
.xofeixiv os
.yob doog a s'eh mih llet I
llet I lliw rehtieN .sraey eht revo no dewehc neeb d'yeht erehw ,raeb-ruf dna draw tib a eb ot dekool taht swap nopu daeh sih detser yob dlo ehT .haow-liat ym htiw uoy rehtob t'nac I ,neht woN .xoF eixiV yb
.tsom naht reggib si s'elpoep emos taht smees tsuJ
.oot ereht gniyl mih ees llits dluoc I
.elohssa tnaem dnarre wen reve nA
.thgin ta deb ym erahs htob eoR dna ydnaM
.tuo seye ym deirc tsuJ
,su fo htob eht rof roC ot thgin doog yas dna og I .aedi dooG ?mih
,gnipyt ereh gnittiS
,tcaf nI .gnileef siht gnitteg retfa snoitca ym ot thguoht hcum ton
rof ecnad edistuo eht od ew dluohS
evoL lanoitidnocnU yojne esaelP
seod dnim ehT .yal ot desu yeroC erehw thgir rehtegot deldduc era yeht dnif
.rehtegot detpoda eb ot dedeen os dna
mih ot nwod dekool won tsuj I
.xoF eixiV yb evoL lanoitidnocnU si yrots s'yadoT
.dnim ym dessorc sthguoht ynam ,mih ta gnikooL
,s'Y owt htiw eixiV s'tahT
mih gniees saw I wonk I dna
.dnuop god lacol eht morf yroC detpoda I
.eoR reh llac tsuj I hguohT
.anewoR auhauhihC eht
.god txen reh dnuof I
.dlofderdnuh eno denruter eb lliw
.noiton eht ekil I oS
.renwo dnarre na yb demialcer eb ot gnitiaw
.seiksuH retsiS dna rehtorB ,yteicos enamuh lacol reh ta iuaM dna anoK dnuof ,nrut ni ,eW
.reve sgod nmad tseB
,yad txen eht nwod tup eb ot saw eH
.ereht nwod saw I yhw rebmemer neve t'naC
auhauhihc a dna ,epahs hguor ytterp ni saw taht
,yppah saw eh desseug I os ,edis ot edis morf ylthgils devom liat siH .sey a sa taht koot I dna deknilb eH
.kcen sih dnuora enilsehtolc fo epor elpmis a htiw em ot revo nevig saw eH
,krowrepap dna spooh eht lla hguorht gniog retfA
ti tub ,taht ni noitanigami doog yrev a dah enoemos kniht I
.neht dna won yreve ti egaruocne I
.sgod fo revol a eB
I tub ,yenom fo egdelwonk laer on evah I
.esicrexe etauqeda dah god eht erusne oT
dna emoh a meht evig ot su ot pu osla s'tI
.shtnom xis doog a neeb ev'yeht dnA
.tsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro god.ecioveht
.draug yob eht ot revo ti ssap dna redlof rehtael taht ni saw taht gnihtyreve ekat uoy dehctaw
,erohc a si tsafkaerb rof dah I tahw gnirebmemer ylurt dnA
?thgir ,doof elpoep tae t'nac eh syas gnihton ,tiaW
.erofeb ot desoppo sA
.detnioppasid eb t'now uoY
.on dias uoy dnA .txen
.owt erew ereht dias eH
ydnaM dnuohdoolb eht deman I
sdoow eht ni dnuof dnuohdoolb A
dna dlo saw eh sa
,noinapmoc wen ym ta nwod gnikooL
.em sa dlo sa tsomlA .won redlo ma oot I
.ees nac uoy lla s'taht
nehw emac yad eht neht dnA
.mih rof tsuj etalp a no tpek ,eikooc llams a mih dessot I
dna roolf eht ta elbat eht fo egde eht revo kool I
.noitidnoc reh fo esuaceb nwod tup eb ot deludehcs dna retlehs a otni denrut saw ehS
,niaga tellaw ym ytpme ti edam I
.gnivom ton saw ti erus ekam ot dekcehc neve I tuB
.oot ,deb eht no peels mih tel I
.rac ym otni meht teg
sih ta decalp d'I ssorc llams eht fo ffo gnitnilg nus eht rebmemer I
.taht ta hgual syawla I
.hguoht ,pal ym no gnittis eb ot gib oot elttil a s'eH
.dah syawla ti sa roolf eht no gnipmuht liat sih draeh
.boj sih od reven dluoc I
.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
yna erew ereht fi deksa nehT
saw I .ees uoy ,srab eht dniheb saw eH
trapa neeb reven dah riap eht sa
.taht tuoba knihT
na nihtiw derevocsid
evoL lanoitidnocnU saw sihT
em depleh neht eh dnA .hguone saw tahT
ot deen ll'I .keew eht fo tser eht rof snoitar muminim ekiL ?taht od tsuj I did yhW .yzarc eb tsum I
etoyoc ruoy ,ozirraC yb uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s'yadoT
,srab eht fo tnorf ni ereht gnidnats
.nehw kcab yaw tenretni eht derevocsid ehs nehw retcarahc reh otni nrob saw eixiV
gnileef a tog I yad eno nehT
.ereht dekrow ohw wollef gnuoy eht htiw gnittahc
.doof god emos yub
saw eh denoitnem dna yroC ot deddon eh nehw saw tahT
.thgit tib a era snoitadommocca ehT
.gniteem ruo rebmemer od I tub
.tellaw ruoy tuo ekat dna tekcop ruoy otni hcaer uoy dehctaw I .oN .taht tsuJ
.moc.xofeixiv si etisbew reh
.retteb leef em sekam
.worbeye na desiar dna retirwepyt ym morf god eht ta nwod dekool I
.ydnaM ,oot os kniht I
.hcrop eht no tops eeffoc gninrom ym rof hctaw
,retirw thguat-fles a s'ehS
.erus etiuq m'I .eerga nac uoy ,ylleb gib s'amam a otni deffuts era su fo ynam woh redisnoc ot pots uoy fI
,seirots reh ekil uoy fI
,nekorbesuoh syawla er'yehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er'uoY
.srieht ni flah dna flah artxe esu I
.relletyrots nrob larutan a tub
.ytilicaf sih ni sesac drah
.yeroC fo mih dlot I
.llac ym rewsna t'ndid eh
rood egac eht denepo nrut ni eH
.dneirf wen ruoy htiw syalp dna secnad ti woh hctaw dna traeh ruoy fo snier eht esool tel tsuj ,kceH
,airolG ot dias dna elcitra repapswen a ni reh dnuof I
,kniht I ,dna gel nekorb a htiw reh
I thguoht I semit wef A
.erac ruoy otni tel saw I dna
.esoppus I ,dlo gnieb morf semoc tahT .elcitra eht fo trap lanif eht togrof tsomla I
.tsael eht yas ot tluciffid saw hcihw ,gnihtrib ym tuoba uoy
,ozirraC yb uoy rof daeR .xoF eixiV yb
dna seye ym gnitniuqs
.ynapmoc doog yrev a era sgod dlo taht dda ot detnaw I
.eerf si gnidaer eht erehw moc.xofeixiv
dna gninrom eht ni eeffoc evah ew nehW
.sraet eht hguorht gnikool
.noitanimret reh fo daeha ruoh erem a gnivirra