,tesolc a ,flehskoob a
.em ta kcab gnirats reeb fo selttob deroloc rebma eht was dna egdirf inim ym fo rood eht nepo deppir I
,drawrof flesmih dehsup rethciR tnatsni taht ni tub dnopser ot denepo htuom yM    .rrup a htiw em ot dias tac wollef eht
.tfel gnihton saw ereht litnu reeb eht nwod delzzug dna ,elgna thgir eht ta ksed ym fo edis eht ot mals a htiw ffo pot sti deppop I ,eno gnibbarG
”?drah os taht saW  ?eeS“
.enoemos ot gniklat deyojne I tub ,trap ym no ekatsim a ylbaborp
.yawa thgir ton—
evorp ll’I dnA  .ib ton m’I ,yag ton m’I
em edisni peed noitasnes gniggan eht ffo ekahs em tel t’ndid llits taht lla flesym gnillet tuB
?enoyna gnirb annog uoY“  .dennirg I
.dednal eh nehw em egassem dluow eh dias eh dna
.rood eht desolc eh sa elkcuhc a htiw dias rethciR ”,esolC“
,neht kcab tluciffid deredisnoc saw tnemdnammoc sihT
.lauxesib sa detsil llits saw I erus ekam ot noitamrofni eliforp nwo ym dekcehc I
.ecaf ym fo tsom was llits uoy tub
”.owt ro etib a teg t’nod ew fi slrig emos egassem syawla naC  .lworp ll’ew ,hO“   .ekil saw I thguoht enoyreve tahw s’ti
.did ylniatrec I
.drawkwa tib a…tnereffid
,tluda na sa era uoy ohw semoceb taht fo emos dna ,etals knalb a si taht nosrep a
.niorg sih ta dekool I suoivbo ti ekam ot ton dah I gnihtyreve em koot tI
”,elbatrofmocnu era elpoeP“
.denigami I naht repeed saw eciov siH  .deksa eh ”?laD“
.hctam a dnif ot desu syug yag setis eht fo eno saw ti taht ,sessalc emos ni srepsihw dna enilepip eht hguorht ,draeh dah I  .tnaw dluoc uoy taht serised dna spihsnoitaler lacipyt eht naht erom raf nrael uoy tel LP ,meht fo emos ekil gib t’nsaw ti elihW
.ogol eht neht dna
.syad rof tuoba gnikniht ylterces neeb dah I gnihtemos did ew sa cirtcele tlef ydob ym ecno ta llA
tub…sraey rof taht edir uoy dna ,tra ,strops ,cisum ni detnelat ,detfig er’uoy ekil
”.taht ekil skcihc knurd od t’noD
,ti ni tas dna ksed llams eht morf riahc a tuo dellup rethciR
.moorhtab nwo ym dna
,gnihtyna ,gnihtemos yas ot htuom ym denepo I
.niks nwo rieht ni elbatrofmoc t’nera ohw elpoep htiw peels t’nod I tuB
.won litnu ,saw tahT
.si sallaD ohw aedi on sah eH
,uoy era ohW
,sallerbmu rednu dna sriahc no tuoba gniyl elpoep htiw dnalsi emos no hcaeb ynnus a fo demaerd I
.laD ,uoy ta dam ton m’I“
.niaga woble na htiw em degdun dna dias drarreG ”!haeY“
.erusaelp ni delbmert I
.ylduol gniffuh ,deb eht otno enohp ym dessot I dna regna ot em evord tsuj ti ,llitS
ztiurF dna sgniRsuirebiT yb
.deggurhs dna odeeps kcalb nwo sih otni deppets dah drarreG
.dewollof esuap A
”?UOY ERA EREHW ?lacol uoY“
,eb t’ndluow eh wonk I
pac llab lausu ym no dah I
,neercs hsalps eht tub gnihtyna ees t’nod I tsrif tA
,drarreG morf yawa ecaf ot denrut I dna knip fo edahs a denrut srae yM   ”?eman reh s’tahW
:fo draeh reve dah maet eht no syug on erus saw I egapbew a ot tnew dna bat resworb wen a denepo I ylsuovreN
,knurd ,tuo dessap I
.klat ot tib a rof edisa nniMcM koot yllautca hcaoC dna
.ti tuohtiw secalp gniog ekil t’ndid I
”?gniW tfeL  ?nniMcM“
?wonk uoy ,knurd oot tog ehs ,haN“
.daeh ym ni eciov denmad siH
.etis gnitad a no eb ot tcepxe d’uoy gniht eht tub gnihtyreve tuoba dettahc dah ew dna
.lufknaht saw I yaw a nI
.etis pukooh dna gnitad a saw  tI  .xniL-edirP
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
won ti si tluciffid erom hcum woh tub
.dekcutnu tfel trihs pu nottub a htiw snaej fo riap tsecin ym erow I os ,sehtolc ymmurcs ni tnaruatser ecin a ot pu wohs ot tnaw t’ndid I
.t’nseod eh ,elohssa tahT
,uoy enifed pleh taht slebal eseht lla teg uoy gnuoy er’uoy nehW
,wonk I ,efil eht gniviL
”.htiw xes evah ll’I nosrep eht t’nsi ti dna ot deklat I nosrep eht t’nsi ti ,won thgir gniraew er’uoy ksam revetahW
,neercs denekcalb eht ta dekool I sa dna
.dengis stcartnoc dah taht gniteem a morf emac tsuj I“
!ma I ohw wonk I  .flesym dekil I  .flesym ni edirp dah I
.ti nees dah rethciR dna ,eelf ot ydaer ,tnatiseh ,suovren os neeb dah I  .mih gniteem neht dna ,mih gnitxet nehw niatrec neeb dah I
daer taht ecnartne eht revo noitpircsni na erob
noil niatnuom eht htiw ppa gnigassem eht ni tsuj tub
.hsilgnE ni ”flesyht wonK“ ro ’notuaes ihtong‘
uoy…erew maet ruo no syug eht fo yna taht toN  .t’ndid I oS
.dedaog noil niatnuom eht ”,laD ,noooom’C“  .gab ym
taht rab lacol a saw snrohT
.ti gnisolc dna rekcol eht otni gab ym gnissot ,oot did I  .selggog sih debbarg dna gab sih otni dehcaer eH
.nwotnwod ta m’I letoh eht s’ereH“
,maet llabtoof s’loohcs ym no saw I regnuoy saw I nehW
.ecitcarp ro ,yduts ot ro ,ssalc a otni gniog saw I nehw mih dlot I netfO
.rehtona eno gnola gnidils seugnot
”.ssenisub rof keew siht sdoow eht fo kcen ruoy ni eb ll’I“  .dias egassem eht
.niaga em ot eil t’nod os ,srail etarelot t’nod I tuB
.edisni diputs gnihtyna od t’ndid ew
.enohp ruoy ni deirub eson ruoy dna
,taorht sih deraelc eh dna deworruf worb siH
.od t’ndluohs ylbaborp I wenk I gnihtemos od ot em dlot taht eno ehT
?thgir ,looc ytterP
”?thgir I ma ,ereh no gniog si tahw tsuj gnirednow ylbaborp er’uoY“
.ksam a erow I oS  .ot diarfa saw I traeh ym ni wenk I  ?drarreG
.eenk a revo saw elkna sih os sgel sih gnissorc
.elbaresim tlef tsuj I
.skcoj eht fo tser eht rof ti nwolb dah eno on raf oS
,gniniart ro ,ecitcarp ni syawla erew eW
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
,maet egelloc a rof deyalp dna egelloc ni saw I taht em fo tuo ti tog eH
?!syendik ym ekat ot gniog saw eh fi tahW
.yawyna ,erehwyna og ti tel evah t’ndluow I taht knurd os saw ehS
.gnihtaerb raluger ym niatniam ot dluoc I gnihtyreve gniod saw I  ”?oS“   ”?ti eveileb uoy naC
.drah teg neve t’ndid I ,tnemele ym fo tuo…os dna suovren os neeb
”,LRI pu teem dluohs eW“
,drarreG htiw moor rekcol eht otni deklaw I sA
?ti tuoba nepo eb ot hguone ti yojne I did…tuB
woh gnileef dna gniliec eht ta gnirats saw I
.peelsa llaf dna gnihtemos tae ot detnaw tsuj I flesym ot emit yna dah I emit eht yb taht yawyna ysub os yllausu saw efiL
.gurd tnemecnahne elam fo dnik emos rof da na tsuj saw egassem tsrif ehT
.pu dnuow er’uoY  .xaler ,xaleR“
.yug olop retaw a tsuj saw I
.niaga pot eht gnippop dna rehtona gnibbarg ,hsart ym otni elttob eht weht dna delrans I ”,elohssa gnikcuF“
.larutan saw taht ,lleW
.cte ,sekilsid ,sekil ,gnimmiws ,olop retaw tuoba deklat eW
.kcab denael dna daeh ym koohs I
.yasse taht hsinif dna moor ym ot kcab teg ylbaborp dluohs I“
.ralucitrap ni eno on ot duol tuo dias I ”,bmud si sihT“
.saw ti ekil ti dellac eh tub ssensuovren taht detalupinam ev’dluoc eH
.noil niatnuom elam A
.drawrof gnignah daeh ym
eye na tab t’ndid dna em htiw didnac erew uoy tey dna
”.etal er’ew fi su llik lliw hcaoc nom’C“
.deppots gnieb tuohtiw ni tog dna rotavele eht ot tnew I    .yakO
.rehtona dna ,rehtona nehT
.nniMcM htiw tuo gnah yllaer neve t’ndid eW
.edisni em detiawa tahw was dna noci eht dekcilc I ,evloser yleets ym htiw gninnur llitS
.ylwols delahxe dna etisbew eht ot tnew I
!taht ekil gnihtyna od annog t’nia eh ,eduD“   ”—mih htiw rewohs ,mih htiw dekan teg ew ,wonk uoy ,lleW“
.soib ’syug esoht detcessid tenretni eht no elpoeP
yojne esaelP  ,somsoc eht ni tfirda acro na ,iaK yb daeR
”?thgir I mA  .uoy htiw xes evah ot tnaw I tahT  .ydob ruoy rof ylno ereh m’I kniht uoY
.C112 mooR  .niaga noitamrofni eht dekcehc dna enohp ym tuo dellup I
,pu denethgit dah emag ruo elihw dna ,moor rekcol eht ni mih dnuora reteiuq elttil a tog sgnihT
.yad rehto eht yag sa tuo emac eduD“
”?hcum taht erac yllaer elpoep od…nom’C“
.ppa eht revo era uoy ohw dekil yllaer I dna ,emosdnah er’uoy kniht I  .nepo noitpo taht tpek dah I ,eurt s’ti ,lleW“
.cisum lacissalc ,tfos dna gnithgil mraw yb depolevne saw dna ni deklaw I ,devrennu tib A
,etelhta loohcs a m’I esuaceb s’ti yas thgim elpoep emoS
,stnemhsilpmocca sih fo duorp ,flesmih fo erus
.em fo edis eht ot llor ti gnittel dna reeb ym gnippord ,drawrof denael I
.yletelpmoc nekorb thguoht fo niart ym
t’ndid uoY“    .em ot txen nwod deppolf eh sa selims lla saw eH
,niaga ,dias I ”,eno dessim ,spoO“
.nirg a dna plug a htiw dias I ”,wonk I ,haey-
”?kcoc ruoy em wohs ot tnaw
.edis eht ot deppets dna delkcuhc eH
,edistuo gniniar saw ti tub
tsomla…tub yrgna dnuos t’ndid rethciR
.nam rehtona ot gniklat deyojne I  .em saw tI
.nees reve dah eh naht yenom erom htiw ecalp a dnuora gnirednaw dik egelloc emos tuoba derac yllaer eno on ro ereh eb ot hguone ecin dekool rehtie I sseug I
.gniod eb d’ew tahw erus t’nsaw I ecnis tib a pu desserd dah I
”!neht worromot uoy eeS  .looc ,looC“
?nwonknu niamer ot thguo sevles emos taht seveileb hcihw dlrow a ni
.eit eulb gnikirts a htiw riaffa yarg hsa na ,eit dna tius sih gniraew saw eH
?…huH“   ”.si eh erehw gnirednow m’I“
,senalp no gnitteg ro sgniteem otni gniog saw eh em llet dluow eH
.ecitcarp retfa yadot dnopser yllaer t’ndid uoY“
peerc a ,wonk uoy
---    .deneppah dah taht gnihtyreve tegrof ot deirt dna dluoc I sa peed sa yrrow dna yteixna eht dehsup I oS  .t’ndluoc I
.dedivorp ti ytsedom fo tib tseinit eht flesym gnivig ylkciuq dna ti otni gnippets
!sraey ni maerd tew a dah
.tew gnippos gnitteg dna srab eht ot gniog ekil leef t’ndid I dna
.lla me‘ niw t’naC  .llew hA“  .deggurhs drarreG
yb uoy rof daer ,ztiurF dna sgniRsuirebiT yb
.teem reven dluow I ohw yug gnulf raf emos saw rethciR taht aedi eht ni trofmoc dnuof syawla dah I
.derettam ssel hgiew dluoc ew taht ecnuo yreve deveileb dna reyalp loohcs dlo na saw eh tub ,yrassecen yltcaxe t’nsaw tI
.mrod ruo fo roolf htfif eht no egnuol eht ni
”.taht yas t’ndid I ,lleW“   ”?ydnah a neve toN
,eceerG tneicna ni ,elcarO cihpleD eht fo elpmet eht ,dnegel ot gnidroccA
.hsart eht ni pu dedne elttob rehtonA
,snrettap epirts ym tuo ekam yllaer t’ndluoc uoy tohsdaeh a ot ti depporc uoy fI  .sessalgnus dna no pac a dah I  .hcaeb eht ta em fo erutcip tneced a saw ti
,flesmih ot tpek yltsom ohw yug egareva na saw nniMcM   ?erutuf ym siht saW  ?yag I saW
,fles rehto emos evah ot
”?eman reh s’tahw ,em llet nac uoY“
.C112 moor letoh ot sngis eht dewollof dna rodirroc gnimoclew eht otni tuo deppets I htaerb ykahs a htiW  .efil ym ebyaM
”.ylrae yad a laed eht laes ot elba saw I
”.yoB-yllaD rof tuo kool attog s’enoemoS
.eugnot dna elzzum ym derolpxe eh sa em dloh smra sih leef dluoc I ,gnorts os ,mraw os saw eH
,seirrow on ,haeY“   ”?orb ,doog uoY
”edirP gniksamnU“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.drah os deirc I
?wonk ay ,uoy gnihctaw saw ehS“
.ot dnopser ot woh wonk t’ndid I LP no em rof gnitiaw egassem a saw erehT
.pmad erew sfeirb ym taht was dna steehs ym kcab dehsup I dnah eno htiW
.rethciR  .mih saw tI  .rood eht gninepo nam a dna nworht gnieb kcol eht fo dnuos eht deretsiger ylerab I ,eid dluoc I syaw suoirav eht hguorht gninnuR
emac sdnah sih dna denediw seye sdrarreG
.em yfitnedi yllaer dluoc taht tuo gnihtyna evig ton
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
,enola kcul no now I epoh I
,rekcol eht ni meht tup dna meht fo tuo deppets I  .og eno ni ffo sfeirb dna snaej ym gnillup
.odeeps a ylno gniraew saw noil niatnuom ehT
?eb ot tnaw I diD
.edisni segassem wef a htiw xob rettel pu-til A
.edis dnah tfel eht no pu dewohs renwo eht rof erutcip eliforp ehT
,sgniht gnigarapsid dias ro dessarah eno on
yawyna ,sallaD laer eht—
.nigol tih dna slaitnederc ym ni gulp dna gniht diputs siht tsap evom tsuj ot denimreted saw dna delworg I
”,gnihtemos ro tcartnoc a ngis ot tuoba er’uoy ekil kool uoY“
”.taht ekil gnihton s’tI“
.nepo C112 ot rood eht raeh t’ndid I
.srab eht ot kcab ti ekam dluoc I  .yawa nuR  .pots llits dluoc I  .ffo tog I dna ”12“ no degnid thgil eht sa tib elttil a pu kcip gnihtaerb ym leef dluoc I
,tsuj dluoc I  .gnihtyna ot
”?nniMcM tuoba raeh uoy ,yeH“
.ton esruoc fO  .rethciR morf egassem a ees t’ndid dna enohp ym tuo dellup I
ecaf ruoy no nirg a htiw keew lla dnuora gniklaw neeb ev’uoY“
.lla ta LP tuoba kniht t’ndid I dna yb tnew keew A
.daeherof sih fo tnorf eht debbur dna dehgis rethciR
.mrod ruo ni egnuol eht ssorca eciov eht ta deknilb dna potpal ym morf pu dekool I sa pu dekrep srae dnuor kcalb yM  ”?mH“    ”!sallaD“
.lanoitaercer si yalp I gnihtyna syad eseht tub
”—hguoht ,ti tuoba tihs mih gnivig s’eno oN  .detcepxenu
.eb dluoc tahw tuoba suovren teg t’ndid dna
.ti tuoba gnipissog won saw drarreG dna
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”…os ,teem ot detnaw uoy…naem I ,llew…W“
,eb flesym ekam dluoc I sa gnitivni dna yrtlus sa dnuos ot gniyrt ,slrig
.ni deppils dna rotavele eht ot nar I
.ffo llew ,yldesoppus ,saw nam siht tub ,rennid derugif I
.nem rof gnikool nem sa detsil seliforp morf lla erew yeht taht saw em desirprus taht gniht ehT
”?yako gnihtyrevE
.xniL-edirP ot kcab ,yawynA
gnieerga saw I ekil t’nsaw tI
!KCUF  .ksam a gniraew er’uoY
.og nac uoy sa hgih sa mia syawla dluohs uoY
,naem saw eno on ,dias I sA
.em dniheb rood eht gnimmals
.derutcip dah I naht evitatirohtua erom saw eciov siH  ”.sallaD ,tiS“
.gniyrc dna ,yrgna
.htaerb a retfa deunitnoc rethciR
t’ndah I  .nihtiw noitcere gnidaf ym fo eniltuo eht ees llits dluoc I
elttil a tlef sgniht tub
.dehgis dna enohp sih dekcehc drarreG
”.looc sdnuos taht ,haeY“
!tnatropmi si tnesnoC
:eno dnuof dna dah I seifles eht hguorht dehcraes I  .em eb
.neppah dluow tahw ees ot tsuj ylniam saw sihT  ?I saW
.nelehW sallaD htiw elbatrofmoc erom hcum os enoyreve edam taht ksam eht
.raey eht fo tser eht ssem a eb ylbaborp dluow I ro tuo ti erugif ot dedeen I  .erus eb ot dedeen I
.redlof a edisni ti dih dna ppa eht dedaolnwod osla I erus edam I
.era uoy ohw wonk t’nod uoY
;retteb on saw I
,rehtegot spil ruo gnikcol
.mih ot klat ot woh erus t’nsaw tsuj enoyreve loop eht fo edistuo
.sppa emos ot pu ti denepo dna ,kcab denael
,on ro sey yas t’ndluoc ohw elpoep ot taht ekil ffuts gniod ,wonk
.edistuo eht gnola sthgil gnignahc dna edacaf gnirettilg a htiw syerots nezod owt tsael ta dah gnidliub ehT
.yad eht ni sruoh hguone toN
,kcuF  !tuoba deklat ew gnihtyna tuoba erac yllaer t’ndiD
.nerrab saw ti os ,yadnoM a no thgin ta etal saw tI
.sselhceeps saw I   ”?sallaD
.nwo rieht evah ,ereh setius ro ,smoor eht llA
.elbat eht ot taht ssot syawla dluoc I tub )sdrawkcab denrut(
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,toh er’uoY“  .esle gnihton dna ”ih“ dias taht erutcip a tuohtiw enoemos morf tsuj saw dnoces ehT
,elbat a htiw afos llams a ,riahc a
yawa og t’ndid yag gnieb nniMcM htiw gniht ehT
.ylirgna delrans dna ,moor mrod ym ot ,loohcs ot kcab dehsur I
!olop retaw ta seca ohw kcoj a er’uoY  !trams er’uoY“
”!nelehW sallaD ,rehtegot dnim ruoy teG“
.em derehtob ti tub ,od yllacitsilaer dluoc I gnihtyna t’nsaw ereht wenk I dna ,yas ot tahw wonk t’ndid I
.deggurhs nam ehT
”.ffuts yag tuoba gniklat tpek ohw eno eht saw eh
?elohssa na hcus eb ot evah rethciR did yhW  ?ylneddus os truh gnihtyreve did yhW
t’nod I  .laD ,thgir s’tahT
,ereht saw rethciR
.tnew I pu dna nottub ”12“ eht tih I sa dednuop traeh yM
.era uoy tahw gniwonk ton drah s’tI  2
.erofeb eman lluf ym mih dlot reven dah I derebmemer I
.krow dluohs sihT
.nworf a dna seye gnirevawnu htiw em detrats ohw rethciR ta nwod gniralg ,ylwols pu doots I
”?uoy era doog woH
.loop eht ot tuo drarreG htiw deklaw I
.emit emas eht ta das elttil a dna deveiler saw I ecno ta llA
?hcum taht erac dluow ohw tub ,dekool enoemos fi enilno erew sgniht eseht ,eruS  …thgiew
54 dna 53 neewteb saw eh dias eliforp sih—
.selkna ym barg ot em detnaw tsuj ohw elohssa hcir emoS
,gnihtemos fo diarfa er’uoY  .yllacirohpatem—
.raluger flesym eralced tsuj dna lrig rehto yna ro einahpetS ro ytsirC dnif dluoc I
rebmemer t’ndluoc I regnorts ni kcik esnopser thgilf-ro-thgif a dah reve I fI
.doog ytterp m’I sseug I ,lleW“
.detiaw dnA   .dekconk I
.rekcol ym gninepo retfa sserdnu ot gnitrats neht dna ppa ym gnisolc ,dias I ”?huH“
.raey tsal morf selbat dlo eht dna VT llams eht dah ti ecnis egnuol roolf htfif eht no gniyduts dekil eno oN
.eman sih saw rethciR—
em naht redlo saw eH
.tsehc ym ni gniremmah saw traeh yM
!?gnikniht I saw lleh eht tahW
.em ta kcab derats regit lagneb a fo noitcelfer eht
.dnah sih ni knird lufroloc a htiw hcaeb emos no gnidnatS  .sseltrihS
?flesruoy ni edirp ekat uoy nac woH“
.yawa thgir pu deppop egassem eht nehw wodniw eht esolc ot tuoba saw I   ”?uoY
dna…erew ew ohw raelc saw ti sa gnol os
”?rof nirg eht s’tahw ,nam yeH“  .em dewoble eh
?yadirF no tuo og ot gnikool uoY
.mrod ym ot tnew dna potpal ym desolc I ,gnilahxE
,tekcop sih fo tuo enohp sih dehsif eh sa dias noil niatnuom eht ”?uoy ’nillac em raeh
.yendik a gnissim
.dewollof etis eht ot gnihsilbup neht dna ,gnivas ,gnitide fo tib A
.tenretni eht no enoyna tsuj htiw sedun erahs t’nod I  .hsireklats dednuos ro ypeerc erew taht esoht ro ,sda tsuj erew taht segassem eht deteled I  .thguoht I ?nem drawot erom nael etis siht seoD  .saw I
.nepo ti dekcilc I  .eno on ot
.elboN dna senraB no desahcrup eb nac hcihw seirots gniK nomiS oirt rieht dehsilbup yltnecer ohw
.dnim ym ni egami s’rethciR fo kniht ylno dluoc I sa worb ym nwod gnippird taews
.somsoc eht ni tfirda acro na ,iaK yb daeR
.wonk ay ,suoiruc tsuj saw I ,thgir lla ,thgir llA“
.dekrow gnihton tub ,regna htiw ti yrub ot deirt I ,delrans I
?no gniog saw lleh eht tahW  ?das
,niaga ,enola em tfel dna pu depmuj noil niatnuom eht dnA
.noil niatnuom eht ta dekniw dna dekrims I
---  ?em htiw no gniog saw lleh eht tahW
.knird detnit eulb a em gnidnah
.siht od ot woh tuoba niarb ym dekcar I   ?!ERUTCIP a…tiaW
?noitnetta syoB-yllaD thguac ohw enoemos tem yllaniF
truh elttil a saw ecaf s’flow eht ees dluoc I
.snaej dna tekcaj namrettel a gniraew noil niatnuom gnikool daorb dna llat rehtar a morf emac tI
.tew kcid ruoy tog evah d’ehs niatrec saw I“
,seenk sih no swoble sih gnittup dna drawrof gnittis ,ylnrets dias nam eht ”,ti ton s’tahT“   ”.yendik
?emit doog a dah tsuj dna rennid ot enog evah ew t’ndluoc yhW  !sgniht esoht yas ot evah eh did yhW
.yldetartsurf flesym ot derettum I
.enola saw I erus edam ,niaga ,I sa tsehc ym ni dednuop traeh yM
.drarreG rof dehsinif I
,raewrednu ym fo tuo deppirts ylteiuq tsuj dna niaga denaorg I
,llaw eht ot kcab ym htiw roolf eht no nwod depmuls I ,retal sreeb ynam ,hcum os gnitruh deppots dlrow eht nehW
.tsehc ym morf gnimoc moob suorednuht eht yb tuo denword gnieb seyek eht gnikirts sregnif ym fo dnuos eht ,mrof eht tuo llif ot nageb I
.denworf ,dneirf doog yrev ym
.pu dekrow os eb t’ndluohs I  .yllis saw sihT
---------—  .peels s'thgin doog a esu dluoc dna ecitcarp morf detsuahxe saw I
.em egassem ot gniog saw eno oN
.dedlocs teg ot tuoba saw ohw buc a ekil ti fo dne eht no gnihcrep dna deb eht ot revo gniknils flesym dnuof I
.sevaw ekil em revo dehsarc erusaelP
.ti no nem evah tsuj t’ndid ti taht desaelp
.elpoep eseht fo yna teem yllautca ot gniog t’nsaw I
.rethciR htiw noitatnorfnoc sih htiw slaed sallaD woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
?ton ma ro ma I ohw em gnillet ,eh saw lleh eht ohW
.ti tuoba wonk t’ndid I em no detaehc yeht fI
,ffuts thgil saw ti tub ,htrof-dna-kcab eht lla uoy eraps ll’I
”.deifirret er’uoY
.kcohs ni nepo llef htuom yM  .erofeb nwod tsiaw eht morf rethciR nees reven dah I
Y“   ”.decitcarp ew elihw yad rehto ehT
.elims rediw neve na htiw dias rethciR ”,sallaD“    ”.sallaD
.tnemom a rof thguoht I   ”.emag ruoy tuoba leef yllaer uoy woh em lleT
.sllab sih tsujdaer dna did nam yreve tahw od ot nwod gnihcaer
”!em rof gniog gnihtyreve evah uoY
,eman suouconni na esu ot erus edam I
”?ees uoy tahw ekiL“
”!epytoerets dab a s’tahT
.won efil ym morf hsinav tsuj ot gniog saw elohssa ehT
.nam rehtona ot klat ot ecin tsuj saw ti tub—
---  .dettimmoc saw I ekil skool tI
?si eh kniht eh seod lleh eht ohW“
,llew ,won dna ,taht did osla nniMcM tuB
.em ta derats dna kcab denael eH
.trohs flesruoy gnilles eb ot mees uoy ,oslA“
,raew ot em detnaw elpoep ksam eht otni kcab dils tsuj dna sthguoht ym fo og tel I
.mih ot gnineppah saw tahw riaf t’nsaw ti wenk I emit emas eht ta tuB
.afos eht fo kcab eht gnola mra sih werht dna delkcac drarreG  ”!thgiR“   ”?olop retaw ni ydnac eye eht tuoba ekil ot ton s’tahW“
,tuoba elbatrofmocnu leef dluow emos seussi tuoba deklat ew tub ,noitasrevnoc txet a tsuj s’ti ,eruS
.woble na htiw em gnigdun ,dekrims eH
,niaga dna niaga deslup ti sa gnixelf tsehc dna selcsum hcamots ym ,kcab deppolf dna denaorg I
,tnedifnoc saw enilno ot gniklat saw I nam ehT“   ”?ksam tahW  ?ksaM“
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ffuts level ecafrus
,dneirf ym ”,nam wA“
.mottob eht ta egassem eht deciton I nehw wodniw eht esolc ot tuoba saw I
.rehtie wonk t’nod uoy dna era uoy ohw wonk
s’yadoT dna ,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,netsil uoy sa taht
.noitsuahxe ni revo dellor I sa roolf eht ot meht gnissot
,flesyht wonk dna ezingocer ti ni yam uoy
”.tnew ti woh ees ot detnaw I
”!yug taht m’I…t’nod I“
”,htiw noitasrevnoc ecin a gnivah saw I enoemos teem ot detnaw I ,eurt s’tahT“
.tlef ti doog woh eveileb t’ndluoc I
,drarreG htiw noitasrevnoc ym gnirud edom peels ot tnew potpal yM
,srab eht ta lrig emos dnif ot gniyrt ot kcab og dna xniL-edirP eteled ot tnaw em edam tI
.nwo ym fo rac a evah t’ndid I sa nwotnwod rebU na koot I
.niaga tuo dessap dna flesruoy gnihsup erew uoy derugif I
,ekam ot eciohc a dah I won tub ,aedi taht ni trofmoc dna ytefas fo dnik a saw erehT
.em naht redlo ylraelc saw eh tub ,smoor rekcol eht ni ees ylraluger I syug eht fo emos sa denifed sa toN  .tliub llew ylriaf saw eH
?uoy dnuora enoyreve loof ot ksam a tsuj er’uoy fi era uoy ohw wonk neve t’nod uoy nehw od uoy gnihtyna nI  ?em nI
”.llab eht gnihctac dna retaw eht ni gnieb evol I  .tseb ym yrt I dna ti ta drah krow I
”.laD ,era uoy ohw wonk t’nod uoY
.riahc sih ni kcab denael dna denworf rethciR
.kcab ym evah wonk I syug
.dias enoyna tahw rettam on ,yltnereffid detaert gnieb llits saw nniMcM
tub driew tlef tI  .spil dna eugnot ym ssorca llor lworg enotirab a dna pord eciov ym tel neve I  ”?ereht er’ew elihw lworp ,wonk uoy ,ew llahs rO
dna eci fo lluf but a ni pu ekaw yeht erehw seirots esoht tuoba kniht uoy emit tsrif eht rof enoemos teem uoy nehw ,lleW“
.thginot ysub saw enoyreve nosaer revetahw rof tub
ylraelc t’ndluow
”?strops yna yalp uoy oD  .erutcip eliforp ruoy ni nuf gnivah er’uoy ekil kool uoY  !ereht yeH“
,moor letoh eht fo tuo demrots dna tnurg suoixna ,duol a tuo gnittel tsuj pu dedne I tub
?naem taht did lleh eht tahW  ?ksam tahW
.maerd a dah I thgin tahT
.no em gnihsup gnihtemos saw ereht tuB
.flesym ot moor eritne na evah I ylikcuL
noitaresimmoc eht dna
.hguoht olop retaw deirt reveN
.hcum sa truh t’ndid I tuB
.mih ees og ot dediced I ,pu ti dekcus I elihw…oS
.sehcni wef a yb em naht rellat saw noil niatnuom ehT
yllaer I ohw wonk t’ndid llits I taht noitasnes eht—
”.kniht I ,gnihtemos ro swen eht ekam reve lliw taht gnihton ,wonk uoY“  .dednopser I
.lla retfa ,pac ykcul ym saw tI
.neppah ylbaborp neve dluow gnihton ,em enifed ot dah gnihton ,neppah ot dah gnihtoN
.ecin saw letoh ehT
.raey loohcs eht fo trats eht ta deretne dah gnidliub eht fo retrauq siht ni enoyreve taht yrettol roolf eht aiv ti teg ot deganam I—
.deppolf ti wenk tub ekoj ot deirt I
.deb eht fo egde eht ot gninoitom
?era uoy ohw niatniam llits dna ytitnedi fo esnes nwo ruoy tsujda uoy od woH  ?sees esle enoyreve tub tif t’nod kniht uoy taht slebal eht tuoba tahw
.mih dnuora driew elttil a gnitca erew elpoeP
”?sseug I ,yako m’I…hO“
.ti dekcilc dna deplug I ,nottub ”retsigeR“ eht revo rosruc esuom ym gnirevoH
.tnemom siht ta tlef I woh ssecorp ot deirt dna wodniw eht tuo derats I sa gnidnuop llits saw traeh yM
.eye eht ni thgir em gnikool dna drawrof gninael
,daetsni ,su stcurtsni tahT
.pu tes ydaerla snalp dah elpoep esruoc fo os ,yadrutaS a no etal saw tI
.dnim ym otni dehsarc thguoht dlo tahT  .saw
ereh esac eht s’taht kniht t’nod I tub
.rewohs eht ni revo em ’nikool enoemos fo aedi eht ot desu ton tsuj m’I  .gnihtyna yrt d’eh naem t’ndid I  .yako ,haoW“  .pu
.uoy laer eht saw enilno ot ekops I nam eht fi wonk neve t’nod I
!taht rof hguone detacilpmoc ton m’I  ?ksam a gniraeW
.egnahc neercs eht deciton drarreG kniht t’nod I tub ,ylsuoixna dehctiwt liat depirts etihw-dna-wolley yM
”…mU…naem I…oN“  .detrulb I ”!seY“
.teiuq saw ti esuaceb ti dekil I
.ylddo detaert eb ot tnaw t’ndid I
dah I tuB  .pu em tlef dah ehs ,saw hturt ehT
.yalpsid no ydob citelhta dna enitsirp sih
.ylkciuq dednopser I wenk eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna ,edirP yppaH
.olop retaw gniyalp morf keew eht fo ytirojam doog a tew ydaerla saw I
.sruoh elpuoc a rof dettahc eW
.moor mrod ym ni saw I dna thgin yadrutaS saw tI
”?snrohT oT  ?yadrutaS
,thgieh ,ega etamixorppa yM
”!sedun emos erahs dluohs uoY“
.won tsuj did I ekil regna tlef reven I dna ,yletelpmoc os ,ylneddus os dezylana neeb reven dah I
!sneppah tahw ees ,wonk uoy
.drow sih tpek syawla eh dnA
.ydwor tog ew nehw did lla ew ekil mih ecarbme ot diarfa tsuj erew srehto dna llab eht dah eh nehw mih rof og t’ndid syug emoS
.ti no tuo em llac tsuj dna ecnatculer ym ees dluow eh niatrec saw I dna ,trams saw nam ehT
,wonk uoy ,saw ti sseug I“
?edistuo eht no eh saw
.lauxesib sa pu ti tes dah I
.sdneirf ym htiw ro supmac no ereh od I ekil tahc ot ksam emos no tup ot dah I ekil leef ot gnivah ton elihw nam rehtona ot yllaicepsE
.saw htuom ym yrd
,rethciR ot gniklat detrats I ecnis skeew elpuoc a neeb dah tI
,toh ton tub mraw nus eht
,em s’tI  .haey ,yeH…H“    .enotirab htooms A
.gnihton saw erehT
.sruoh wef a rof derewsnanu tis egassem eht tel I
.neercs no pu deppop ijome yelims A
deppiznu dna tib elttil a deplug I
.elttob ytpme flah a gnidloh saw dnah ym won dna ,sedis eht ot tah ym nworht dna trihs ym ffo dellup dah I yznerf gniknird ym gniruD
.yawyna ti nees ev’dluow rethciR
.ylisae dna ylnepo mih ot klat dluoc I os dna—
”.delttes gnitteg tsuj saw I  .yawllah eht ni dnats ot deen oN  !ni emoC .etuC“
.won tnereffid saw gniht elohw eht leef dluoc uoy tub
.moor eht evah I tespu m’I yas t’nac I tub
,gnorw saw ti em dlot taht eno ehT
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.won ksam a gniraew er’uoy os
.evil tnew eliforp ym nehw enilanerda fo hsur a tlef dna nottub ezilanif eht tih I nehw htaerb ym dleh I
.erutaretil rof od ot dah I gnidaer emos fo FDP a saw won neercs no pu emac tahw ,daetsnI
.sthguoht nwo ym ni dna yawa gnipyt ,niaga golb etavirp ym no neeb dah I
.yag yllaer saw I fi rednow em edam tI
,ti tuoba driew ro naem yllautca saw eno oN
em wonk t’ndid yug sihT
.neercs tnereffid a ot gnibbaT + tlA dna daeh ym gnikahs ,dias I ”,haN“
.elzzum sih ssorca dekcarc elims a neht dna em ta deknilb ,neerg fo edahs lufrednow a ,seye siH
.knurd enoyna htiw dnuora loof ton ot su denraw syawla hcaoC
.erutcip a daolpu ot dedeen tsuj I  .enod tsomlA
,emit eht lla nepo ti dah dna neercs niam ym ot ppa xniL-edirP eht devom dah I
.pu sdnah sih ,dias rethciR ”,haoW“   .depmuj I
,ksed a sah moor ehT
.flesmih fo erac koot eh taht yawa thgir llet dluoc I tub ,psirc erom tib a segde sih ,redlo dekool eH  .oot redaorB
.erom dettahc ew no tnew syad eht sA
taht em fo erutcip a dedeen I
?rellik laires a saw eh fi tahW
.redluohs ym no dnah a tup dna em dniheb pu deppets eH
.haey ,nuf gnivah saw I“ :dednopser I
”?moor mrod ruoY  ?reh ekat uoy d’erehW  .niw eht retfa uoy revo lla saw ydniC“
fo 1 traP ,ztiurF dna sgniRsuirebiT yb ”edirP gniksamnU“
,elpoep wef a detxet I  .ti
.ti leef ot emit ni tsuj pu tas dna psag a htiw pu ekow I  ”!!HAG“  …ot gniog saw I  …saw I
.maerd tew a dah I
.ti htiw yawa teg dluoc I taht wenk osla I tuB  .dab ,oobat
,egap tnorf eht tsuj ,semit ynam revo ti dekool dah I
”.dneirf a htiw gnittahc tsuJ“
,setammaet ym er’yehT
.tnemom taht ta gnileef yllautca saw I naht ecnedifnoc erom raf htiw ppa gnigassem eht no dias I ”,eruS“   ”?thginot yb emoC
.eil t’ndluoc I  ”.seY“
.kcab deilper eh ”,esnesnoN“
?enoyna llet I dluoC
epoh eht htob htiw detneserP
!eurt neve t’nsaw eH
.steehs ym gnippirg llits sdnah ,gnitnap ,kcab deppolf I dedne ti nehW
”.enilno ot gniklat saw I laD eht ton er’uoy tub pu dewohs yletinifed enoemos ,oN“  ”.ereh thgir m’I
.demmirt ruf ruo teg dna og lla su edam dah hcaoc eht dna dnekeew siht emag a dah eW
”.sallaD ,ruf ruoy fo tuo pop ot tuoba er’uoy deracs os kool uoY“
.elims gnimrahc A
”edirP gniksamnU“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots
.deirc I dna…seye ym gnirevoc dna pu erew sdnah yM
.od dluoc I erus t’nsaw I eno
.thginot neppah ylbissop dluoc tahw tuoba deracs er’uoY
.flesmih ecudortni ot rehtob neve t’ndid ohw odnar emos ot meht dnes ot gniog t’nsaw lleh sa erus I
.ylkciuq kcab dednopser rethciR  ”!taerG“  ”.eruS“
,dekan ereht gnidnats saw drarreG
,htiw gniknird tuo og dna htiw semag yalp I syug
.yug llabtoof a saw I ekil t’nsaw ti sulP
,god.ecioveht ta
.erutcip eht teg uoY  .cte ,gniniart ro
.euqisyhp dna selcsum s’drarreG fo hcni yreve ees dluoc I yhw saw taht oS
,odeeps eulb ym tuo dellup dna delworg I ”!eno on s’tI“
?laer neve saw rethciR fi wenk ohW  .nehw
?sruo ton si hcihw
.htab a ekil mraw naeco eht ni retaw eht
.edis dnah thgir reppu eht no noci noitacifiton eht was I neht tub
.knurd tog I nehw did yllausu I zzub eht gniyojne t’nsaw I dna ,sucof fo tuo
,niaga lanruoj ym ot debbat dna kcab denael dna dehgis I
.rood eht ta deppots eb dluow I taht os hcum os ton tub ,ycnaF
.reganeet gnuoy a neeb dah I ecnis erusaelp railimaf A
.tnemom eht nethgil ot deirt dna tsehc sih tsniaga dnah ym fo kcab eht deppals I  ”.yawyna ,nis sa ylgu er’uoy ,tuoba yrrow ot gnihton tog uoy sulP  .gniraew er’uoy tahw ta kool ,eduD“   ”—tub
,loohcs eht rof setelhta drac yllaer t’ndid
,wols tlef dlrow ehT
?syug eseht llet I dluoW
.eromyna ton ,hO“  .mih morf saw tI
.rehciR ot gniklat pots ot tnaw t’ndid I tub
.eldruh tsrif eht dessap dah yug siht raf oS
.su fo tnorf ni tes nus eht sa gninnuts rehtar nwotnwod fo weiv eht ,naelc dna hserf saw ria ehT  .etius lufrednow a saw edisnI
.ffo saw gnihtemos esnes dluow rethciR noos dnopser t’ndid I fi taht wenk I
”.yah eht tih neht dna gnitirw emos hsinif annog tsuj
,namow a dna nam a ,nemow owt ,nem owt neewteb stfihs taht ogol thgirb eht ta derats dna strohs myg dna pot knat a ni deb ym no deggel-ssorc tas I
.smelborp esoht diova dna erawa eb ot tseb saw ti tub
.maet olop retaw a no m’I ,strops emos yalp I
.ti rof kaerb a ekam ot evah ot gniog er’uoy ekil rood eht ta gnikool er’uoY“
eno siht piks esaelp