yldeticxe gab reh ot revo delbmarcs dna ailyW ot pu dekool esniK
?ailyW ssiM esolc yadhctah ruoy sI“
?neht ytrap hcaeb a tuoba woH“
.esniK ot railimaf ylralucitrap erew dna snogard tuoba egdelwonk nommoc erew stiart eseht fo llA
.ti tuoba gnikniht neve tuohtiw ni thgir deklaw ehs taht
.reh ot dnah ymils a dereffo dna
.erofeb sserdda rieht tuoba nezarb os eb tneilc a nees reven dah ehS
.egarots doof dna
.sredluohs reh otno kcab ti detfeh dna
.saw ehs erehw dezilaer ehs nehw yletaidemmi ecalp ni ezorf esniK
.ailyW ssiM ,uoy deliaf ev’I“ ”?gnorw s’tahW
.ffo tnrub saw taht elacs nepo fo hctap eht diova ot erus gnikam
.meht no derettacs senob hsif htiw setalp egral emos dna slisnetu prahs erew aera eht dnuorA
.revewoh snoissessop dezirp s’ailyW erew
.sgnaf ybab gnisol llits saw ehs nehw kcab saw flesreh rof gnihtemos gnitarbelec derebmemer ehs emit tsal eht dnA
lla retfa erohS elavremmuS ni evil uoY
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.era uoy sa citsejam sa tneve ruoy ekam ot
.noitcerid etisoppo eht ni ybsressap gnireets ngis noitcurtsnoc a sa eltbus sa gnihtemos neve ro
.”erohS elavremmuS ,poT niatnuoM 21“ fo sserdda denetrohs a dna
.no yal ot meht rof sdeb fo epahs etamixorppa eht otni sgel ynam reh gnisu meht dedlof dna renroc eht ni slewot eht koot neht ehS
”.uoy rof pu ti tes ll’ew dna
.irikenen.www no
.flesreh gnicnuonna ylreporp tuohtiw ni gniztlaw
.ereht revo llaw eht gnola slewot fo tes a s’erehT
htiw noisacco laiceps a etarbelec ot tnaw uoy ebyaM
,ma I sa derettalf sA“
.dluoc ehs sa peed sa gud dna
pu til seye s’ailyW ”.neht
.xodohtronu elttil a eb ot gniog s’ti tuB
.stneilc reh ot klat ot reh wolla dluow taht sllet elttil eht gnidnif ot desu nettog dah esniK tub
mrywkooB irikeneN yb
.cigam emos reh thguat dah sreh fo tneilc tsap a litnu
roivaheb railucep siht tuoba thguoht ni dessorgne os saw ehS
gab reh fo tuo reh htiw deirrac ehs
,snroh fo daetsnI
”!em wohs ,oS .em wohs ot evah uoy tahw ni detseretni ma I tuB
.taht fo thguoht neve t’ndah I !hO“
draoh reh ot revo nar ehs dna
emit gnol a ni dah ehs tsediw eht delims esniK ”?eraD ro hturT“
seye reh morf nus eht dleihs ot ecaf reh ot pu dnah reh desiar ehS
etuhc aval eht ot txen nwod tas dna ezis reh semit eerht saw taht teknalb a htiw pu flesreh derevoc esniK ”ma-
dnuorg eht otno nwod ti tes dna kcap reh devomer ylluferac ehS
.yzoc dna ecin teg ot etuhc aval eht ot txen pu sevlesmeht depporp yehT
”...ailyw-ww-wwW ssim-m-M gnineve-e-
.dlrow eht fo tsom ot nwonknu sesserdda rieht peek ot dekil yeht dna
!taht pots uoy ,won hO“
’swal-ni fo esac ni kaerb‘
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.retaw eht ni htrof dna kcab yldi ti devom ehs sa edam ti sevaw eht ees dluoc esniK dna ,hguoht degrembus liat reh tpek ehS
,skoob daeR-oT fo draoh sih morf gnidaer ton s’eh nehW
?sevitaler ruoy tuoba tahW“
.ailyW ssiM ,esruoc fO“ ”?KO taht sI
.moor niam eht dnuora klaw ot nageb esniK
tnemevom fo tnuoma llams a doof eht evag tI
kniht I dna uoy rof noitseuq erom eno evah tsuj I ,esniK lleW“
.ytrap rebmuls a evah ot evol yllautca d’I“
.dednuofbmud nogard eht ta dekool esniK
si yrots s’yadot dna
.slewej dna dlog htiw dellif ton saw ti tub
,liat reh fo pot eht no riah eht hguorht dnah reh dehsurb yldednimtnesba ehS
.deraperp eb dna yrt ot seilppus fo tnuoma evissecxe na dekcap dah ehs taht tnaem erohS elavremmuS eht fo snogard eht htiw ecneirepxeni reh hguohT
moor eht otni gnigrab emoc t’ndluow ailyW taht deifsitas saw ehs nehW
.doog tlef taht rewsna na no delttes ehs erofeb
ssenisub reh htiw ssorc ot eldruh ykcirt ylralucitrap a saw sihT
delebal eniw fo ksac lainomerec eht dessot esniK
.ydob gnol rieht nwod dna pu snrettap gnilarips ni rehto hcae otni gnilriws selacs neerg dna eulb
”ytilibatciderpnU“
,hguone mraw saw ehs hguoht sa tlef ehs nehW
.yaw elohw eht noisserpxe delzzup a htiw ecnartne eht ot deklaw ehS
,mrywkooB irikeneN yb ”ytilibatciderpnU“ saw sihT
.sraey dna sraey ni ytrap laedi reh tuoba thguoht t’ndah ehS
sthgil deroloc ylthgirb fo gnirts a saw xobliam eht ot dehcattA
,emit tsal eno kcap reh otni gud esniK
toof hcae no snolat htiw sgel xis dna liat gnol A
taht os erusiel ruoy ta esurep ot uoy egaruocne I taht kcap ym ni ereh selpmas emos evah I
ee dooog-gg-G“  .tsrif flesreh ecudortni ot denimreted dna dnuob saw esniK
tnepres aes a fo taht ot resolc saw epahs riehT
.lla retfa laiceps oot gnihton m’I
.snolat ynam reh fo eno htiw hteet reh gnikcip elihw
.noisacco no eleleku eht yalp dna tniap ot nwonk neeb osla s’eH
”?nrob erew uoy yad eht gnitarbelec ni detseretni eb d’uoy spahreP
?detnaw ehs ytrap fo dnik tahw wonk neve t’ndid ehs fi
”.thgin eht fo eno tnatropmi tsom eht s’ti
.nisab retaw a otni llif ot demees taht
taeh tneibma eht tel dna
.hctip ssenisub lausu reh otni dehcnual dna pu doots esniK
wob peed a otni flesreh derewol esniK ,taht htiw dnA
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ecnetnes-dim detpurretni saw tub
.niaga deksa ehs sa redluohs reh revo snroh ytrap evitsef dna snoollab eht werht esniK
evac s’tneilc wen reh ot ecnartne eht taht ees ot
snif eulb krad egral dah yeht
.erohS elavremmuS fo ailyW ssiM ,uoy ot yad dooG“
.em htiw lamrof os eb ot deen oN
,erusaert fo elip a saw erehT
.llew ylgnisirprus deriap taht hsif hserf emos detsaor yeht dna
.retaw gnivom ylwols ni
.retaw fo hsalps ythgim a htiw loop eht fo aera gnidnuorrus eht derewohs dna
.evac eht fo rebmahc niam eht ot rood renni na t’nsaw ereht taht
.liatne ot gniog saw ytrap eht tahw fo aedi llams a tsael ta dah stneilc reh yllausU
,llih a fo mottob eht ta kcor fo sekips suoregnad fo ecnelaverp eht
.lla retfa ytrap a rof aedi na evah I kniht I ,tahw uoy lleT
,noitcelfer eht otni derats ehs sA
enil a no tpek gnieb hsif fo elipkcots llams a saw ereht renroc rehto eht nI
.sraey ni remotsuc tsrif reh gnisol ot esolc saw ehs dezilaer ehs sa seye reh ni llew ot nageb sraeT
,nepo ediw ylno ton saw
,bmuht fo elur a sa
”.rehtie krow lliw taht kniht t’nod I os ,meht ot detaler saw I taht tegrof rehtar dluow ylimaf ym taht uoy erussa I“ ”?meht
!gnivres-fles os sdnuos tahT“ ,dias dna tnemmoc taht ta detrons ailyW
.selacs reh pu mraw
sehtolc dna ,setik
.tneilc wen a teem ot deticxe syawla saw ehs
ecafrus eht fo tuo ekorb epahs ehT
.tol a taht teg I ,haeY“
kcohs a saw ti oS
”.esu ot snoitativni dna snoitaroced eht kcip ot em pleh dluow tahT
.edisniatnuom peets eht pu debmilc ehs sa kcap reh fo thgiew eht rednu deniarts dlobok eht esniK
,mrywkooB irikeneN yb
”!eraD”,gnirewsna yltnedifnoc erofeb
ezilaer neve t’ndid esniK taht gnisirprus os saw tI
.dnuorg eht otno *duht* a htiw kcab reh ffo llaf kcap eht tel dna
.retaw gnilkraps eht ni yad lla dneps I tub ,esniK esneffo oN“
dessertsid saw esniK taht deciton ailyW
,nogard retaw a saw tI
,knarf gnieb m’I fi dnA
.aval gniwolf htiw dellif tip llams a otni tuo gud dekool taht
yb seitrap sklof rehto gninnalp ysub oot saW
.evac eht fo htuom eht rof dnuora dekool ehs sa
,saw boj reh fo trap siht sa gnitsuahxE
.ecaf rieht ni nogard a fo egasiv cinoci eht dah llits yeht tub
morf ward ot gninnalp ytrap fo sraey evah I taht uoy erussa I
”.gge na morf dehctah I yad eht ot detacided ytrap eritne na evah ot sa tnatropmi os ma I kniht oT
”ytilibatciderpnU“
kcap reh ot revo kcab tnew esniK
.tuo sgniht llup ot nageb dna
.mrof rieht fo tser eht pu edam
,neddih llew yllausu erew srial s’nogarD
,tsrow eht rof decarb esniK dna kcab daeh reh werht ailyW
htamretfa eht ni liat ot tuons morf dehcnerd saw esniK
”.ffo deird teg uoy pleh dluohs tub ,uoy no gib elttil a eb thgiM
.reisae esniK ot klat dluoc ehs os evac eht fo roolf eht no tuo ydob gnol reh dial dna elbatrofmoc flesreh edam dah ailyW ,elihwnaeM
.loop eht morf degreme tahw ees dluoc ehs tub
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.daeh rieht fo pot eht morf dedurtorp taht
”!ytrap ruoy nalp ot nigeb ot erehw wonk neve ot elbatciderpnu oot hcum era uoy
,eviterces erew snogarD
aaa’am-mm ,sey-y-yY“ ”.ti ta er’uoy elihw oot pu flesruoy mraw dna etuhc aval eht yb tiS .ffo flesruoy yrd og os ,tew dna dloc ylsuoivbo er’uoY
.seirots setirw dna semag sekam taht nogard a si ohw
.ten llabyellov a rehtegot tup ot
.erohs eht dna niatnuom eht ot ytimixorp eht fo esu doog edam taht ecaps evac tniauq a saw tI
.draeh tsuj dah ehs tahw ssecorp ot gab reh hguorht gnihcraes pots ot dah esniK
.hgual ytraeh a saw ailyW fo tuo emac taht lla tub
tik llams a dna llab hcaeb eguh a tuo thguorb ehS
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,evah snogard tsom sa
.loop eht fo ecafrus eht ni detcelfer seye wolley dna selacs nworb reh ees dluoc esniK dna
.revo erew seitivitsef eht retfa srotisiv detnawnu tuoba
”?gnilaeppa dnuos tsum retaw gnilkraps dna ria hserf eht yojne ot ecnahc eht gnitteg dna
yrrow ot evah t’ndluow stseug reh taht erus edam lleps yromem a htiw snoitativni gniubmI
.eno elttil ,won yeH“
,retaw dloc eht morf gnirettahc hteeT
!taht tuoba yrroS“
rennid retfa pu ekops ailyW
,sdrocer pu delip eseht taht llet ot yad reh ni sdraoh hguone nees dah esniK
.nogard a rof tcepser reporp eht gniwohs ton ot emac ti nehw regna ot kciuq erew eletneilc reh taht dnahtsrif denrael d’ehS
”.ti raeh em tel ,thgirlA“
eniw fo ksac eht ekorb esniK
tnaw dluow uoy ytrap fo dnik tahw em llet ot uoy tnaw I nehT !didnelpS“
,saw ehs edur woh eciton t’ndluow ailyW taht ecnahc a saw ereht ,esion hcum oot ekam t’ndid ehs fI
renroc tfel kcab eht ni noitces llams a saw erehT
.ti fo edis eht no gnitirw tuo ekam dluoc ehs ,xobliam eht ot resolc deklaw esniK sA
secivres reh rof dellac evah ailyW dluow yhW
,evac eht fo htuom eht tuo reh gniwollof emalf fo tuog a htiw
.hcaerb ot pu emac I nehw ’enoZ hsalpS‘ eht ni llits erew uoy kniht t’ndid I
”.ecneirepxe tseb eht uoy evig lliw tahw rof leef a teg nac I
,hsub gnimussanu na ot txen cigam fo remmihs llams A
.sdeen gninnalp ytrap cinocard ruoy lla rof .C.L.L seitraP dloboK ttubkciK gniredisnoc rof uoy knahT
senur cinocard ni tuo delleps ”ailyW“ eman eht dah tI
niatnuom eht ni eloh eguh a saw  moor eht ni erutaef tseggib ehT
.dluoc ehs sa yltneg sa
eulb lufituaeb a saw retaw ehT
.esniK ot revo ti thguorb dna
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
mottob eht ta deirub erew taht samajap fo tes a tuo dellup dna
”!ytrap a rof doom eht ni tsuj saw I
.evac eht fo htuom gninepo eht ot revo xobliam eht fo pot eht morf del taht
.uoy rof elbatius eb dluow taht gnihtyna evah t’nod I
”.yadyreve od I tahw dnuora deretnec ytrap elohw a gnivah ekil leef yllaer t’nod I
.regnuoy saw I nehw sdlobok rehto eht htiw taht ekil sgniht gniod no tuo dessim I
:yojne esaelP   .moc.irikenen.www
?ailyW ssiM etarbelec dna yrt ot tnaw uoy noisacco tahw deredisnoc uoy evaH“
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.nwo sih fo seirots emos etirw ot emit sekam eh
”.lla retfa ytrap tcefrep eht uoy evig ot ereh m’I
.ailyW morf esnopser a rof detiaw dna
ti tuoba gnikniht fo elihw gnol a reh koot tI
.hsif a fo epahs eht ni ti fo tnorf ni xobliam yduag egral a dah tub
.em rof wob t’nod esaelp
dnoces a rof desuap ehS
.mottob eht dehcaer yllanif dah ehs taht dnuof tub
.deeps gnisirprus ta ecafrus eht sdrawot miws ot nageb epahs egral a
noitaroced fo esoprup laud a devres dna
kaeps ot tuoba saw esniK