krad eht wonk I esruoc fO“
.neht ,sdnob lla fo eerf era owt uoY
.egattoc ruo fo rood tnorf eht hguorht yaw sih deillub flowerew yggahs ,llat A
”!nacnuD“   .nalp a dedeen I
.ton ro lliw I fi onnuD“ ,reh dlot I
.lluf tog reven seilleb rieht tuB .hcum os tae ot sgniht llams hcus rof elbissopmi saw ti thguoht I
.nam gnuoy ,suoicileD“
eileesnU eht
.flowerew a rof kooc ot woh mom ot nialpxe ot evah thgim I hguohT
.sehsid ym devol lla snilbog dna sdayrd dna sdlobok dna sniffup degnaf dna seiriaf ehT
.truoC eileesnU eht erofeb denommus saw I nooS
.dluoc I sa noos sa tisiv d’I reh dlot dna eybdoog mom dessik I ,ekac ruo dah lla ew retfA
!tih gib a saw tI
.erom detnaw yehT
.’ygidorp‘ a em dellac ehS
yenoh detnahcnE
uoy oD .dneirf dlo na morf epicer looc a teg tsuj did I …lleW“
!?siht em ’nillet uoy er’yhW“
,yrgna ,egnarts a neeb evah dluow eh
.raelc dna eerf ,su fo htoB
”.tsaef a htiw mih sserpmi ot deen eW
”.tfig s’yob eht gnirB .nacnuD“
.ti devol sudilyfnelG
,meht rof doog laer dekrow ti taht mom dlot dna kcab emac yeht nehW
.gnikooc lautir ym yrt ot detnaw sklof fo stoL
”eiP eileesnU“ saw sihT
.sbreh dna stiurf lacigam tseb eht dah yehT
.ysae laer dam tog yeht dna
”.deen ew tahw tcelloc t’nac em ekil yob kaew ,llams A
.traeh yb liated yreve denrael I
…seiriaf yna tsuj ton dnA
,dekrab eH   ”.era uoy ,haeY“
!dlrow eht ni nehctik gnizama tsom eht ot txen
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.ytrap yadhtrib ym ot xiranefeleM etivni tsael ta ,no emoC“ ,dias I
.slatnemele erif gnicnad htiw nevo eht detaeh I
.yrrulb emaceb gnihtyrevE
…os erew yehT .hcum oot dnuora meht detnaw reven I tub ,sdneirf loohcs dah I
.erehwyreve erew stib eaF
.sretnuh erusaert eht pleh ot snobnob redneval dna nomanniC
.daerb talf ,eseehc dellirg ,sgge deliob draH :ffuts elpmiS
.etatiseh dluow su fo rehtien ,yzarc tog ffuts nehw taht os ,oot nrael nacnuD edam I dnA
.mih devol llits ehs llet dluoc I
”.ecalp siht ni dneirf ylno ym rey dnA
,delwocs tsaeb ehT
.sknip dna selprup lla ,slootsdaot fo gnir gniwolg a otni deppets noos dna
!yadhtrib yppah a em hsiw ro em ot olleh yas neve t’ndid ehS
.elzzum sih ta walc ynit a detniop xiranefeleM   ”?ssecnirp yM“
er’ew ,mih gnirB .nacnuD“
.hsael klis etihw elttil a dleh flowerew ehT
.em rof drow wen a dah ehs ,net saw I emit eht yB
.detnaw I revenehw ,noitcelloc sih morf epicer eno evah dluoc I em dlot dna daeherof eht no em dessik eH
.elttil saw I nehw dnuora t’nsaw eH
.os dias ehs ,naem I .doog saw I
.’gniklat eniw eht saw ti‘
dias ehs gninrom txen eht tub
.redluohs ym no wap gib a tlef I
.sseug I ,erom ecno tsuj 'evres' dluow dna
.evlewt txen eht dnA
.dad rof ffuts dab tnaem
.snosaer reh dah ehs erus m’I
…klof eaf eht tuoba denrael I nehw s’tahT
”.emoh og annaw tsuj I dna nacnuD taht
.dnuora emit dnoces eht ,doof eht lla xif ot sruoh net em koot tI
:gnihtyreve dah tI
.desirprus dekool yriaf ehT
.emoh emoc t’nac eh dna
.did flowerew gnilbmurg eht dnA
,dias I nehT .desuap I
.esruoc fo doolb ni ,tcartnoc ecivres ym dengis I
.krad tog gnihtyreve ,moor eht otni welf ehs sa noos sA
---   .emoh saw I nehT
,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
…nehctik dnarg eht ssim d’I
.rotcelloc tsud eixip A
.gnorw saw tahw reh deksa I
,delrans eh nehT   .evom t’ndid eh ,llitS
.redrah saw teuqnab txen eht tuB
.sregnif reh deppans ehs nehT
ahctahW“ .sriatspu depol flowerew gib ehT
.yriaf dlo naem a gnivres fo sthgin gnol eht ssim t’ndluow I tub
.kooc ot woh em hcaet ot detrats ehs nehw dlo sraey neves tsuj saw I ,lla retfA
.seiriaf rof kooc ot woh denrael osla I tub
”!meht toN .esaelp ,oN“
.enihcam ediv suos eguh A
”?tnaw
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
stseuG   .deerga ehs tub ,deracs elttil a dna demahsa dekool ehS
,snoitrop rellams tuoba denrael I
si yrots s’yadot dna
.moor eht otni gnireggats tneserp laer ym thguorb gut yldneirfnu nA
.emit no thgir dednal ohw ,naivoleJ ecnirP evres ot emit ni tsuj ekow I
s’rehtaf ruoy erahs ot si ,yob raed ,tneserp ruoY“ ,dias dna em ot pu thgir derettulf ehS
.ruoh na ,ekil ,rof reh deggub I retfa em dlot ehS
.taht tuoba gnorw saw I ,ylloG
.denethgirf eb ot em detcepxe ehs sseug I
”.semoc eh nehw ay ekaw ’na mraw ti peek ll’I
.scisab eht ,wonk uoY .iahT dap ,niv ua qoc ,ojor elom ,élffuos
.sepicer laer em wohs ot detrats mom ,yaw eht fo tuo ffuts elpmis taht htiW
:laed a mom dereffo dna
.swalc kcalb ,gnol reh htiw gnihtyreve ta dekop ehS
.sevink elacsnogarD
.moor eht ni nosrep tseggib eht saw ehs ekil detca tub ,llat toof a ylno saw ehS
.esruoc fo ,stneidergni retteb teg dluoc ew os tsuJ
:rotisiv laiceps repus a rof dekooc I ,yad enO
tub …gnihtemos yas ot detrats ehS
.loord dna hteet llA
,tfig ym saw eh fI
ygolirT diputS rehtonA fo rohtua
.mih evas annog saw I oS
.thgin eht otni ffo del saw I nehT
.suovren saw mom tub ,yhw onnud I
.noob gniregnil s’fle krad eht rof tnemyap saw tI
.sretsnom reildneirf eht dna ,setirps ,sretfihsepahs
.em ot deneppah yllaer reven taht tuB
.noom lluf a gnirud noitcetorp rof seikooc lisab dna ,psiw-o-lliw ,gemtuN
.em ekil dekool eH
.efil elohw ym rof neeb dah dad erehw em dlot ehs ,gnitsat eniw morf kcab emac mom retfa ,thgin enO
.www//:sptth no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY .agaS yhI ehT dna
”!gnimoc si ecnirp nogard ehT“
.doog tsuj naht retteB
.raef ni reh morf yawa knarhs sniffup live dna snilbog reH
”.ecalp sih ekat ot esoohc uoy sselnu ,esruoc fo ,si tahT .laem lanif
.etollipap ne tibbar derettab dna ,ekaceseehc gnirettahc a
.trohs eybdoog ruo tuc ssecnirp naem ehT
.truoC eileesnU eht ni pu worg dna
,dias nam railimaf ylegnarts ehT
!dad wonk ot gnitteg nuf hcum os eb d’tI
.ecaf yzzuf sih revo dessorc snoisserpxe nezod A .detiaw I
.tseR“ ,delbmur nacnuD
!toidi elttil uoy on ,oN“ ,dessih ehS
.epirt kcor eht dna smoorhsum nottub eht neewteb erehwemos ,evac yrtnap eht ni devil eH .sseug I ,ned rO
,delrans flowerew ehT   ”!nacnuD“
.nuf fo etisoppo eht saw xiranefeleM
”.reh teg ot tuo m’I taht xiranefeleM llet dna rood taht tuo hcram d’uoy ,t’nerew uoy fI“
.sseug I ,yas smom lla tahw s’taht tuB
.niks tessur dna seye nworb ym dah eh tuB .detnuaH
.nworb ot detrats tsurc eht emit eht yb gnipoord erew seye yM
tahw …nacnuD deman saw eh sseug I
.teppom uoy ,ecnirp fle
.ymmut sih ni eglub eht morf ylthgils gnilbbow
!gniliec ruo rof llat oot tsomla saw eh dna ,yarg dna dliw saw ruf siH
.snioc koot yeht semitemoS
.sruoh nevele em koot teuqnab txen ehT .llitS
.rennuf sgniht ekam dluow xiranefeleM gnitivni thguoht I oS
.seiriaf eht htiw laed a edam eh ,eeS
.erofeb thgin eht reh detisiv ,xiranefeleM ,ssecnirp yriaf lacol ehT .reh edam I tub
.suoregnad repus era stneidergni eht fo emoS“ ,derumrum I
.yrrac dluoc I tahw pu dekcap I
”?niaga dad ees annaw uoY“
.driew gnihtemos deciton I nehT   .eno looc ytterp tub
.gniraelc tserof dehcnerd doolb eht ta dnuora dekool nogard ehT
.nehctik eht ni em pleh ot nacnuD deksa I
.dnah ym ezeeuqs sregnif suovren ,mraw tlef I
---   .maercs yeht dluoc yllog ,snilbog eht tuB
…mih tuoba sgniht elbirret dias eniw eht hguoht neve dna ,’gnihton-rof-doog ysuol‘ a mih dellac ehs hguoht nevE
”.ssertsim ,erusaelp ym eb hcum yrev dluow ti …hO“
”?sepicer cihtym sih fo eno evah uoY
,thgin tilnoom eht otni ffo ylf mih gnihctaw
.ylippah gniggaw liat
.em rof hguorht emac sudilyfnelG
.erehwyreve tsud fo sliart elttil tfel sgniw remassog reH
.tuo emoc t’ndluow sdrow
,suovren laer saw ehS
.thgilf sih morf gnivrats saw nogard kcalb gib ehT
.snoollab dellifrevo ekil deppop tsuj sniffup degnaf dnA
.meht derongi xiranefeleM tuB
.dedne tcartnoc ym erofeb yaw htaed ot em krow annog erew yehT
.revo eb dluow gniht elohw eht dna ,tsaef gib txen eht ta dad tae tsuj d’yeht rO
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.dnal ffo raf a morf sevle krad eht fo ecnirp a ,sudilyfnelG
eiP eileesnU:yojne esaelP
.pets ym ni gnirps a htiw elcric moorhsum eht ot deklaw I
”.noob ym denrae ylurt evah uoY
.’nihton ro reverof t’nsaw tI
.eniw gniklat fo dnik taht ekam ot esu ot lleps tahw wonk t’nod llits I .drieW
.yrgnuh os tog seiriaf taht em dlot reven moM
,elbamohtafnU strA eht fo sugaM
".yako s'tI" ,derepsihw I
,htaB fo ssecnirP eileesnU ,xiranefeleM fo ecneserp eht ni won era uoy ,slatroM“
,dias mom ,emit emas eht ta tsomlA
.gnilwab detrats mom nehw ekac etalocohc-egnaro ym gnikam erew eW .yadhtrib htflewt ym saw tI
.wols laer ,deddon moM
.yob eht rof stneidergni eseht tcelloc ot uoy redro I“
,seirrebesoog detnahcne htiw tnew I
.gnineve worromot ereh eb lliw naivoleJ ecnirP“
,idraciR lliB yb
”.swen ylevol tahW“
.doof yadiloh rieht ekam ot deen uoy stneidergni laiceps eht dna ,secips eaf lacigam dna
.esiw eb thgim taht ,seY .hA“
.tsehc yzzuf ,daorb taht ssorca smra sih dedlof eH
”?ssecnirp yriaf eht htiw teem I naC .yakO“ ,deksa I
.yenom gnigrahc detrats ew
.slautir evol eht ni esu yeht ekil ,aet elimomahc dna
”?sudilyfnelG wonk
”?egassem eht s’tahW“
.dab syawla toN .lleW
.ereh attuo su teg nac I kniht I“ ,denialpxe I
.ylimaf yppah gib eno ,puY
.esruoc fo emoh ym toN
,sdoow eht deretne eW
.nalp ym detrats I ,etelpmoc saw ksat sih nehW
,deppans xiranefeleM
,eaf layor eht rof kooc dluoc I
.lla ta dad wonk t’ndid I ,woN
,’nihton yas annaw t’ndid ehS
enigami t’ndluoc I .dad ym saw sihT :wenk I dna mom ta kool enO   .ymmut gnikooc ym dna em ot derapmoc tsael ta ,ynwarcs repus saw eH
.gnireffo reporp a ekam tonnac ew ,wol era sreffoc ruO
.flow a rof eman yllis a
.dad ym htiw secalp edart d’I wenk I
er’ew skniht ehs fi evila htob su niks ll’ehS
.saw eh esruoc fO
,esruoc dnoces eht yB
…nehctik eht ni nrael sdlo raey net taht ffuts lamron eht denrael I .’kooc emosewa repus‘ snaem taht kniht I
!ekac niahmaS eht pu dessem reven I esuaceb ,yllis saw tI
egdelwonk terces em evag eH“
:hsid tneicna na fo
idraciR lliB yB
.truoc layor reh dna xiranefeleM rof teuqnab tsrif ym gninnalp saw I ,retfa nooS
.ssecnirp ym ot dewob I
.’stneidergni eht detcelloc‘
.sruovaf ,semitemoS
.’on‘ yas ot dewolla t’nsaw ehs sseug I
,emit eht lla eaf eileesnU eht rof skooc eh won oS .hguoht tsol eH
.mom dna em eb annog tsuj saw ytrap yM .looc erew
.sgniw reh fo rihw dehctip hgih eht yb llet dluoc I
taht dnA .dne annog saw eaf eht htiw edam dad taht laed ehT
,elbmag ot dekil yehT .dliw tuB
.deracs erom tol A .rellat ,reggiB
,llew ecnirp eht dehsiw eW   ”.levart efaS
.srettirc dab eht erew yehT .seno
,eiP eileesnU eht fo parcs tsal yreve eta eH
.eta teg annog saw eh taht em dlot ehs nehw das os dekool mom tuB
,siht od lliw uoY
”.yletaidemmi trats tsum uoY
.delims I   ”.dneirf rey toN“
.flesmih sudilyfnelG morf detseuqer ,epicer wen dnarb a tog I
.emoh s’nacnuD
,gnikooc ym tuoba draeh ehS
.yas I tahw od ot mih dlot xiranefeleM tub ,ssecnirp eht ot denialpmoc eH
?thgir ,em yrrow annaw t’ndid ylbaborp ehs ,naem I
…devres ecno I dna nacnuD taht eaf live eht htiw mirb eht ot deffuts ,eiP eileesnU eht ekab ot thgin lla em koot tI
.rezeerf ni-klaw a nevE .rossecorp doof 005 retsaMeaF A
.serutnevda no tuo erew yeht tub ,srevid evac dna sretnuh erusaert eht detivni ev’dluow I .lamron
”!?su ot siht gniod uoy era yhW“
moc.idracirllib.www//:sptth
dlroW eileeS ruO morf yrots A
eh sa nacnuD erongi ot tseb ym did I
”.dik ,namliam rey t’niA“   ”.em rof egassem a reviled ot uoy deen I“
,mih tuoba sgniht dab yllaer emos dias moM
.nrael ot dedeen I tahw tuoba kniht dluow I dias dna mih deknaht I
.seroc elppa dna senob fo enorht reh dnuora dettilf xiranefeleM .dehcatta hsael klis ,em detrocse nacnuD
,ris ,kniht I“ ,dias I
.kcen ym dnuora ralloc klis eht deit flow yggahs ehT   ”.ereh enod
”.revo ti kniht I elihw tae s’teL
,sriatspu devil I
.yaw taht esle enoyna ta gnikool reh
.deneppah ti ,nehT
”.rednow dna cigam krad htiw dellif s’tI .eiP eileesnU
.fehc nogard taerg emos kooctuo dluoc eh taht teb dad ,yawynA
.sruoveD ohW ehS fo rethguaD
.mom dna em tuoba deirrow os dna ,dnik demees eH
:no gniog saw tahw tog I nehw s’tahT
.siht rof deraperp t’nerew eW
.niaga ylimaf elohw a eb ot nrael dna ,sepicer erahs dluoc eW
.wam sih revo tperc nirg gnikool naem A
,idraciR lliB yb ”eiP eileesnU“
.pord hsael klis ym tel nacnuD
.ylkciuq dedne yrc lanif s’xiranefeleM
”?plehw-nam ,taht kniht uoy sekam tahW“
.did eW   ”.wob yam uoY
”!htaed fo niap no
.syad ruof dna ,shtnom ruof ,sraey ruof rof em deen t’ndid yehT
,lles ot mom rof ffuts edam ylno ton I ,sraey elpuoc txen eht oS .esac ni tsuj ,ydaer eb ot dedeen I dias moM
.syad ruof dna ,shtnom ruof ,sraey ruof rof em detnaw ylno yeht ,sediseB
.modeerf tnaw uoy esuaceB“   ”.’nittolp
”.uoy tuohtiw ti od t’nac I tuB