.gniraelc eht ot ecnartne eht ta gnittis atiZ
gnÝ ot txen tis yam tuyL nehw emit eht si noitatidem fo emit ehT
.dehcneuq si tsriht sih
.ecnalab ot gnivigrof tsom eht era taht tnecs eht fo seton esab eht si ti esuaceb dna
,yrovas sselehtenon tub detlasnu
.eltit reh ylno spahrep ro
.tseird eb syawla lliw ti erehw evac eht fo kcab eht ot lwob eht seirrac dna
,dlrow eht ekam ohw yehT
.sdrow sih era enots tsniaga enots fo dnuos eht
,erohs eht gnola maertspu slwarc tuyL
ruf sih morf retaw eht llup htmraw taht tel ot
,erac derusaem htiw hsif eht stug citecsa eht sa neve sreyarp esoht htiw flesym niatsus I os dna
elap eb llahs leef yam eh noitale revetahw
rethgual htiw sdnuop eh eseht dna
mih htaeneb dnuorg eht leef ot tuyL rof tnatropmi si tI
,eno lausiv a fo ueil ni level larecsiv a no sdnatsrednu eh taht
mih egnahc ot dediced evah I taht flesym dna gnÝ devres sah tuyL taht raey hteitriht eht si ti dna gnitsaf fo keew eht fo thgin tsal eht si tI
,tsehc sih ot earohpma eerht sih gnildarc ,evac sih fo tuo spets eh nehw dna
,sedit ni snaeco riehT fo sretaw eht ta gut ot yks eht ni noom eht gnittes yb drol eht dednuofnoc ohw dog retskcirt eht ma I
.sdapwap sih fo tuo trid eht segassam eh nehw emit eht si sihT
,evac sih fo edahs looc eht morf ti pis ot dna
,stser evac sih hcihw no llih eht ot ralucidneprep sdoow eht otni ylluferac sklaw tuyL ,emitnaem eht nI
.mih nihtiw thgirb snrub drol sih fo ecneserp ehT
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,em fo dog eht era yehT dna ,sgniht lla fo dog eht si gnÝ“
.gnis sdrib eht sraeh eh esuaceb gninrom si ti nehw swonk eH
”.gnÝ ton era uoY“
.mih revoc yam hcihw trid yna ot thguoht sevig eh nehw emit eht si sihT
gnÝ .seye denekrad morf senihs
gnÝ ,ron ,ruf sih fo yna ffo evahs ron swalc deffucs-ydaerla sih kcin
egalliv eht dna tuyL woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.mih htiw gnola gnignis era sdap sih litnu
,uoy htiw si gnÝ nehW .uoy htiw ma I
,evac sih otni kcab lwarc ot mih rof tnatropmi si ti neht dna
,sruoy ma I ,ereh ma I
evac sih erofeb gniraelc eht fo egde eht morf esnecni eht pu kcip dna
,niar on si ereht dna mraw era syad nehw ,yad yreve fo gninrom eht nO
.hteet prahs htiw senob tfos morf yawa deparcs hsif eht fo hself eht era
.erac derusaem htiw skrow dna stis eh erehw
,seenk dna sdnah no
,htuos gniog segalliv morf nrut ni esahcrup yam ohw
,noitatidem ni yad eht fo tser eht sdneps eh dna
,thgil fo taht si ecneserp s’gnÝ taht yas dluow eh
,gnihctaw fo dog eht ma I dna ,enim rednu era emos
,edam si revir eht ot pirt rehtona ,gnihsinif retfA
,ssenwols decitcarp a dna erac derusaem htiw skrow eH
,skeehc sih nwod yleerf esruoc sraeT
,rail a si gnÝ ,siht nI
,swonk tuyL ,reyarp lla toN
.yad eht fo tser eht rof ecnanetsus sih eb lliw hcihw htorb niht a fo sgnikam eht
,kcen sih fo kcab eht hcuot I dna mih ot emoc I
,hcuot yb swollof dnah thgir eht elihw walcerof tfel sih ediug sbmil sih nwod levart dna
stneidergni eht htiw gnola mih edivorp ot serac egalliv eht smla revetahw dna
.htrae dekcap eht ni em ot sesiarp gniward
gnÝ .spot-eert eht tsap pu sesir dna gniraelc eht dna evac sih sllif srobal sih fo tnecs eht sa
,teef sih neewteb llird wob eht fo gnignis eht si reyarp siht fo sdrow eht neht
,uoy no nwod senihs ti nehw dna
,gnimmuh era sdnah sih litnu
.sdrow sih era llaw enots gnola gniggard spitregnif dna trid ni gniddap swap sih fo dnuos eht
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb ”gnieesnU“
.noitaerc fo sreyarp eht wollof noitcurtsed fo sreyarp ehT
.dlrow gnivil-reve s’gnÝ ot
esnecni eht evoba neve llems nac eh
dog retskcirt a ma I esuaceb stuohs eH
.gnippat eltneg htiw mih sediug kcits siH
.nekaw ot mih rof tiaw dna gniraelc eht ni tis I neht dna
,gnÝ ot txen nus eht ni syal eh ,gninrom siht oS
.edam evah yehT taht dlrow eht dna
,allinav dna aissac fo seton esab eht htiw
.sreksihw sih sehsurb eh nehw emit eht si sihT
.kni.oykam ta revo
”.dloheb ot uoy rof raed oot si ti os dna ,efil ruoy sedivorp nus eht taht deerced sah gnÝ“ .hgual I
ni derutaef seirots eht fo eno si gnieesnU
”,lufhtiaf ,nus eht ta yltcerid kool ton oD“
.nees ton si noom eht nehw neve
.liob a ot gnirb ot ecalp sti ni tup retaw fo guj eht dna srebme eht morf yalc dekab eht gard ot desu si
setib driht dna dnoces siH
,ytilanoitcerid dnatsrednu ot thgis ton deen eno rof
.semoc thgin looc eht dna stes nus eht retfa kcalb eht morf daerht etihw eht
,srehtaferof ruo fo sdrow eht pu reffo eW
.efink sih htiw stuc dna
gnÝ .revir eht fo sdnuos eht htiw mih ediug srae siH
.thgil htiw dellif si tuyL
.doof sih dnuora morf snref eht slrufnu dna edisa yalc tneps eht stes eH
.tsae dna htuos gniog
,sdileye desolc dniheb nus eht fo htmraw eht ees nac eh taht wonk I
.rednit eht ni gnitrats emalf wen eht fo htmraw eht leef ot sniarts eh sa tuat dehcterts noitpecomreht
deb ot seog eh dna
,dnuos fo egaugnal eht ni mih ot nekops evah I taht wonk I
evoba sevael eht yb worra s’nus eht ni tsac swodahs eht esnes nac eh taht wonk I
.ti dloh lliw taht earohpma owt eht dna egalliv eht deef lliw taht
ygolohtna yrruf cirotsiherp eht
txen emoc seton elddim ehT
.seirreb deird-nus ro daerbtalf fo sevael elats on
,won mih ot emoc taht thgil fo slriws dna sehsalf eht ta gnilevram si eh
.em ot noitoved gniwonknu sih rof ten sih ni hsif owt mih rof evael dna ,luftif
,maerts eht ni erom ecno sehsaw
.ekaw sti ni esnecni gniwos
.gniees fo ,gnikool fo
:daets s’gnÝ ni rewsna I
,llew sa denaelc eb ot deen dluow dna
,redwop enif eht ni worruf luferac a sward neht
,nekorb ro tuc eb ti taht gniriuqer tuohtiw swalc sih fo eno fo ezis eht seludon dnif ot stpmetta eh ,won roF
.thgil htiw gniwolfrevo si eh ,won yb dna
.nwo sih sllac eh revir fo noitces eht ot evac sih morf htap eht nwod ylwols sdap dna kcits gniklaw efink sih pu sekat eh
.deird dna gnuh dna dehsaw ylluferac neeb sah hcihw toor galf teews sdda eh siht oT
,retaw deliob ylno sknird tuyL
,htorb yrovas fo daetsni dna
.knabrevir eht morf yalc eldnub eht dnuora skcap dna ,snaecatsurc hsigguls dna hsif fo hctac yliad sih meht ni sparw neht ,eseht sehsaW
,noziroh eht no htarw riehT esnes I hguohtla esuaceb ,stiaw gnÝ ,ooT .tiaw I oS
.doow sa ylisae sa sluos mialc dluow ti tsrow ta taht thguat neeb dah eh dna noos oot tuo nrub tseb ta dluow taht eno saw
.slarips nihtiw slarips
;sessessop eh esnes a ton si thgis rof ediser ot gnÝ swonk eh erehw snevaeh eht ot pu kool ton seod eH
.em otnu mih ekat lliw I
,ecnetsixe yrev ym yb dna
.mih erofeb dnuorg eht ta skool dna seye sih snepo eH
.drol sih ot sesiarp eht ecnelis sti ni raeh dna
.mih dnuora seert eht ta dna gniraelc eht ta skool eH
.uoy ot straeh ruo pu reffo eW
,dna eson sih htiw segduJ
,nihtiw taem eht stae ,hsifwarc eht morf sliat eht sllup eh sa
,erom ecno ten sih sgnirts
emoc lliw taht nmutua eht ot ladopitna si tI
oga raey eno sa tsuj
.revo sbacs dnuow eht dna spots wolf eht litnu sehcuot eh lla nopu doolb fo reyal niht a evael lliw
.srevir ym htiw dnal eht gnivrac yb
ron swap sih fo sdap eht erujni ot tnaw ton seod eh rof ,erac derusaem htiw skrow tuyL
,taorht sih ni thguac gnitteg morf senob renif dna
traeh sih ecreip ot ecneserp s’drol sih ,daetsni ,swolla
.yks thgin eht otni dna esruoc ffo derednaw sah worra s’nus eht litnu no dnA
,retaw fo dog eht ma I
,meht eht neewteb nwod sesav eht stes dna reh erofeb deggel-ssorc stis neht dna
?gnÝ htiw nus eht ton saw rof
,llet tonnac yeht litnu ekoms no tsisbus yeht keew eht si siht sa
,noitcurtsed fo reyarp tsrif eht snigeb eh ,esnecni sih gniraperp retfa sgninrom eht nI
.drol sih ot dna robal sih ot noitoved tsehgih eht sdloh ohw eno ot nwonk ecneitap a htiw
.hsifwarc fo tnecs ydaeh eht dna hsif eht fo taf eht htiw denosaes
,flesreh rohtua eht yb daer ,2 fo 1 traP ,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
,cirumrut dna regnig fo seton elddim eht
,mehT rof wen osla si siht esuaceb
,ten sih ni hsif on era ereht rof
.thgis gnimlehwrevo
,gnÝ ot noitaerc fo sreyarp eerht fo dnoces eht llet ot si looc eht dna yrd eht dna teiuq eht ni esnecni erutam oT
.evitisnes tsom eht si hcihw
.reh fo retteb eht steg yllanoisacco ainamohparg esohw
,seirc eh sa nevE
,ykcits dna dettam ruf sih evael lliw
,elihw gnol a rof siht srednop tuyL
,tuyL ,seye ruoy nepO“
,erif eht morf knup a sthgil eh sa erac derusaem emas eht htiw skrow eH
htiw snruter dna evac eht otni kcab draob sih sekat eh neht dnA
,efil fo sraey ytrof retfa dna
.fleseno yb gnihgual yb no thguorb ssenilenol fo gnileef neddus eht semoc noitoved htiw dna
,snref daehelddif eht tcelloc ton tsum eh taht swonk eh
,tuyL htiw si
tnavres riehT fo ecivres nI
;sessessop eh esnes a ton si thgis rof slwob esnecni owt rehto eht gniniatnoc flehs eht rof kool ton seod eH
.gnicaf si ruf sih noitcerid eht ot thguoht sevig eh nehw emit eht si sihT
dlrow eht fo snialp htooms eht fo noitaerc sih ni gnÝ dednuofnoc ohw dog retskcirt eht ma I
.yarp ew erif eht fo taeh eht yB
traeh sih ecreip ot ecneserp s’drol sih ,daetsni ,swolla
,ecnatsni rof ,desimrus sah eH
.ton seod eH ”.seye ruoy nepO“
evac sih ot ecnartne eht ta tis dna draob llams a otno stneidergni sih rehtag lliw eh
.trofmoc seil lautir nI .lautir ni si
.tniuqs a ,kcarc a
,krad fo taht ecnesba riehT
,sdnorf eht fo sdaeh delruc eht fo si etib tsrif siH
mih htiw eciojer lliw I dna
,selcyc nihtiw selcyC
,dekan dna gnippirD .doof hctac ot
.htaerb sih nihtiw dna senob sih nihtiw dna traeh sih nihtiw gnÝ sraeh eh taht wonk I
.ecneh syad eerht rof esnecni sih ekam dna
.erofeb nees reven evah uoY“
.nus eht morf htmraw eht sleef eh nehw sekaw eh nehw yad si ti taht swonk eH
,ti tpurretni taht sevael hserf looc eht morf ,retaw morf
.erif eht fo teef eht ta meht dial dna sdoow-raen eht morf krab dna skcits ni thguorb eh ,erofeb thgin ehT
.evac sih fo htuom eht ot ti seirrac dna ecalp sti otni pu owt rehto eht stoocs dna enil eht ni lwob tsomthgir eht pu skcip eh ,tsal tA
,tnavres riehT fo ecivres nI .flesmih ot
,mehT ot sesiarp gnignis naht rehtar detaerc sah gnÝ taht lla ni slever dna ,gnÝ ediseb
:sthguoht sih wonk I
,skcor owt neewteb morf tuo swolf retaw eht erehw loop a si ereht ,evac sih yb revir eht tA
.ti htaeneb gnirps tfos tsal fo ohce na si gnirps tfos siht
”gnieesnU“   yojne esaelP
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.yrolg ruoy evres I ,noitca yreve ym
.pmac sih rof retaw htiw dellif eb ot redluohs sih revo gnuls guj a gniyrrac emit siht
,gnitirw reh fo erom dnif nac uoY
.ehtab dna hsif uoy nehw
.woleb nwot eht rof esnecni sekam eh taht yad eht si yadot rof
.noitarbelec fo keew dna thgin dna yad a rof flesti ydaer ot pu gnikaw si woleb egalliv eht taht wonk I dna ,slautir sih
,gnihtaerb ylerab
,stneidergni sih tuo dial sah eh woh si taht esuaceb pot ot mottob morf tnecs eht sdliub eh dna
,redwop mrofinu a otni meht ezirevlup ot eltsep enots a htiw dnuorg dna ratrom enots a ni rehtegot nekat lla era esehT
.niap tuohtiw erom ecno seye sih nepo nac eh dna
.edaf htmraw eht sleef eh nehw thgin si ti nehw swonk eH
,yad taht sehsaw tuyL
,gniciojer fo keew eht si keew txen dna
revir eht morf nward laem elgnis a ffo ylno stsisbus eh
,tey emoc ton lliw ti taht kniht I
.worra s’nus fo ecneuqesnoc a sa edahs dnatsrednu ot
,nidran fo stoor dehsurc eht htiw ,neht ,snigeB
,thgin si ti nehw dna yad si ti nehw swonk tuyL nehw syad no
.evol seil noitatidem nI
efink sih fo esu eht gniyolpme nehw erac ralucitrap htiw skrow tuyL
,erehw ,evac sih ot kcab yaw sih spat dna dnah ni kcits sih neht sekaT
,riomem a dna slevon ot smeop dna seirots trohs morf
,eman reh eb ton yam ro yam atiZ
ssenwols decitcarp htiw neht dna
.1 rebmeceD elbaliava
gnÝ ,seye ruoy htiw ees ot uoy rof raed oot osla era eW“
.tsal ta seirc eh ”!gnÝ“
.kni.sfhf ta
,tuhs dehcnelc seye
,ten sih ni hsif on era ereht fi dna
,raey eht fo elcyc eht
;reyarp sih kaeps ton seod eH
.retal taht esu yam eh deedni dna ,ecalp sti ni lapoc gnisu flesmih dnif yam eh syad reiloh nO .walc a fo htdiw eht citsam nommoc fo spordraet net dexim si siht oT
evac sih ot ecnartne eht ot meht seirrac dna draob sih otno sloot dna stneidergni sih srehtag eh os dnA
sessap tnemom eht litnu ssenkrad-non fo tnemom siht mih wolla I os
.tnemevom yreve sih gnidiug drol sih fo tirips eht
,eil dnik a si ti tub
em devres sah ohw citecsa hteitriht eht si tuyL tub
,ylleb sih llif ot redro ni sevil eerht fo gnikat eht rof dna ,doof sih rof
,noitarbelec ni ekab yeht taht sekac eht nosaes taht secips eht
:gnÝ ot yas dna pu kaeps yam tuyL nehw emit eht si lautir fo emit ehT
,retaw eht hguorht sregnif sih fo hsiws decitcarp-gnol a htiw dna skcor eht fo eno ot seenk dna sdnah no slwarc dna edisa kcits sih stes tuyL .ten a gnurts sah eh taht pag taht ssorca si ti dna
htaed thguorb ohw dog retskcirt eht ma I
ytilanoitcerid fo swal eht yb nus eht morf nekcirts
,dloh tsum naecatsurc a fo efil ytlis eht
,erus ma I ,dlofytriht em no kcab emoc lliw elbuort ym dna dog retskcirt eht ma I
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT     ”.uoy htiw ma I
;reyarp sih kaeps ton seod eH
.sessessop won eh esnes a ,thgiS
traeh sih ni noitoved htiw skrow niaga tuyL dna
,seye sselthgis gnignits dna ruf sih ot gnignilc dna eson sih ni gniregnil noitoved sih fo tnecs eht htiw
sevael fo edisrednu eht snuhs nus s’gnÝ yaw eht ni levram ot tuyL rof tnatropmi si tI
,dehsinif si drow tsal eht emit eht yb dna
”.evac ruoy fo tuo emoC
,syaw eseht ni gnÝ evres uoy nehW .llew sa ma I
.swollof taht ecnelis eht otni stnap eH ”.ees uoY“
,yarp ew nus eht fo thgil eht yB  ,yarp ew eciov nwo s'gnÝ nI
,meht dnuora sracs eht dna seye sih fo sdil eht neht
,mih sesimorp atiZ
,rewsna ot desserp eh erew tub ,ssenkrad morf thgil wonk ton seod tuyL
.sdnirg eh sa traeh sih ni noitoved htiw skrow tuyL dna
.raef nwo sti ti htiw sgnirb siht taht dna
,sehsa eht morf esor hcihw irausT nI
uoy htiw ma I dna
,ecivres fo stca sih mrofrep ot noislupmoc eht sleef dna gnÝ ot gniyarp si eh taht wonk I dna
,esnecni sih fo taht htiw gnilgnim erif eht fo ekoms eht htiW
,yad eht fo tser eht rof skrow dna syarp tuyL  .retfa
.pihsnoinapmoc elbatrofmoc eht seil noitatidem ni tuB
,segalliv rehto morf esahcrup spahrep ro worg yeht hcihw esnecni eht rof stneidergni eht fo
.seton esab eht htiw lwob eht otni ti stup dna ssargteews fo htgnel s’pitregnif a sekat tuyL dna
,gnuoY saW dlroW ehT nehW
,sehsinif eh emit eht yb latnoziroh gnikirts worra s’nus eht leef nac eh dna gnineve si tI
rehtegot efil ni stca sih dna mih ekat lliw I
,ria fo shtaerb ni gniplug dna
.neht mih ot emoc I
,sedivorp egalliv eht taht smla eht ecalp sti ni evael dna
tnecs yb dna hcuot yb steksab ro ,sraj ,slwob rieht ni stneidergni desunu gnicalper dna evac sih otni kcab ti gnignirb
.redwop suorbif a ffo evahs ot toor eht gnola ralucidneprep tsomla edalb eht gniparcs
.mih morf retaw eht sllup nus eht yaw eht dna ,htmraw eht stcelloc ,nus eht ta sgut ruf sih yaw eht leef ot tuyL rof tnatropmi sa si tI .ti ni thgiled dna rednow eht
,mih dniheb yldetatiga gnittilf liat sih
,yad eht fo elcyc eht si ,sehsiler tuyL
,stnahc eh sa won mih htiw si
,noitarbelec no evil yeht keew eht si txen dna reyarp no evil yeht keew eht si sihT
.noitcidsiruj ym si
,seid tuyL nehw rof
,gniliob won retaw fo guj eht ni decalp era sllehs hsifwarc dna noteleks dna daeh hsiF
.ewa ni skooL .rednow ni skooL
,debircsed evah I taht syaw eht ni mehT ot era uoy sa em ot lufhtiaf sa era uoy tub
,mih yrd worra s’nus tel ot kcab sih no syal tuyL
,flesym dna gnÝ gnivres scitecsa dnilb fo sraey ytriht semit ytriht retfa
.sgniht lla fo dog eht si gnÝ tuB“
,won sah eh tser revetahw neht dna
gninruom semoc noitarbelec htiw rof ,sraet htiw dna
.stnemhcatta yldlrow dna snoitome morf gnitsaf a osla si reyarp fo gnitsaf eht esuaceb ,egalliv eht ot epols eht nwod htap eht sklaw dna earohpma eht stcelloc ehs sa atiZ ot yldnik elims ton seod tuyL ,keew sihT
,sdrow dnik wef a dnoyeb esuaceb ,wonk ton seod eH
,speels eh sa hctaw I .yrgnuh
.daerb fo sevael on erew ereht
.seert eht fo krab eht dna trid eht dna skcor eht ot nward si ti sa mih ot nward si nus ehT
,uoy dnammoc tonnac I“ .yas I ”,oN“
”?wýT ,uoy era erehW“
.saelf dna skcit fo eerf dna naelc si tlep sih taht serusne eh nehw emit eht si sihT
.edistuo eht no dehcrap dna yrd si ti litnu slaoc toh eht gnoma eldnub sih seltsen eh ,erif eht fo noitrop a gniknab retfa
,ssargteews eht tuc erac derusaem htiw skrow eh sa flesmih ot snmyh sseldrow sgnis eH
.nwod edispu denrut gnieb ytilaer rieht htiw epoc
,rehtie ,gnÝ ot ecivres ni si reyarp lla toN
reduol on dna eb dluohs ti sa tsuj si gninrub doow eht fo dnuos eht taht erusne ot ti erofeb elihw a rof stis dna erif sih sdeef tuyL ,reyarp retfA
,yad siht ,raey sihT .snosaes fo egnahc eht ,skeew fo egnahc eht
,seirreb dna sdaerbtalf fo
:rehtegot yarp yeht dna
,gnÝ ot noitaerc fo reyarp lanif dna driht eht llet ot si liart esnecni eht yal oT
,lwob llams a otni detfis si detaerc suht ,esnecni eht fo redwop ehT
gnitnap s’eh litnu
.tip erif sih si evac sih fo ecnartne eht ta kcor eht ni esaerc a tsniagA
gnÝ ot sreffo tuyL taht noitcurtsed fo reyarp lanif dna driht ehT
,thgin morf yawa seihs nus ehT
,syad fo egnahc eht yb woleb deohce si tey dna drawpu sevom emit rof ,sraey fo larips ydaets a ni gnidnecsa devil si taht efil a si tI
noitamrofni erom etavacxE
esnecni eht rof stneidergni fo kcats eht
.sdop momadrac eht tnuoc ot
.owt rehto eht ediseb lwob eht ecalp ot sbmil sih nwod levart dna
.yks eht dna seert eht dna dnuorg eht ta skooL
.mih rof evael lliw atiZ hcihw fo evif dna ,snevo rieht fo taeh eht ni
,ti ot noitaler sih no setatidem eH
,gnitsaf fo keew siht ,keew sihT
regna s’gnÝ fo eciov eht htiw dehsur dna deraor taht erif gninrub-toh a taht swonk eh rof ,looc oot ron toh oot rehtien si erif eht fo taeh eht taht dna
,emit lanif dna driht eht roF
.gnimoorg laidnarptsop sih ot noitnetta luferac sih fo tca eht ni lever I dna
.yad eht tuohguorht nrub lliw taht lairetam eht fo klub eht osla sedivorp ti tub ,teews ,sey ,si ssargteews fo tnecs ehT
uoy ot ecivres ni si od I taht lla dna thgil fo lessev ruoy ma I
,seye sih snepo eh ,yllaniF
.redluohs sih no dnah riehT htiw mih sediug
nref daeh-elddif a fo sdnorf eht ssorca semoc eh litnu ssarg eht gnoma gnilwarc sregnif
.secaf ti edis eht no seert eht fo krab eht swollof dna
,pihsrow fo noitapicitrap evitca eht seil lautir nI
.erom ecno llits ,erom ecno tnelis si tuyL
.liat sih fo pit yrev eht htiw ratrom eht morf dehsurb tlis tsenif eht
,dna hsif a fo gnicnad eht sleef eh ten eht ni dna ,yadot mih no delims evah I
,ytnuob sih rof gnÝ ot reyarp trohs a syas eH
,eros dna gnihca sdap sih evael osla lliw ti
.swap sih fo snoitom eht ediug dna sbmil sih nwod levart dna
.nrut ni sekam eh taht esnecni eht rof
.stcesni fo surohc eht otni elttes yad eht fo gnosdrib eht nehw thgin si ti taht swonk eH
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb ”gnieesnU“
em htiw eciojer lliw eh dna
.stuohs eh neht dna
”.ecnayebo llams siht rof ksa I os dna
esnecni fo hctab retfa hctab sdnirg dna sdnuop eh sa gnÝ ot sgnis eH
,htaed fo dog eht dna gnihctaw fo dog eht dna retaw eht fo dog eht ma I elihw rof
.hsaw ot revir eht ot nwod yaw sih ekam ot evah dluow eh taht swonK
.tnempiuqe denoh ylluferac sih egamad ,mih evreserp
,meht nihtiw sllewd ti dna meht ot nward si tI
.ecivres seil lautir nI
,gnÝ ot ssenilnaelc fo reyarp a kaeps ot si retaw dloc ni hsaw oT
,toor sumalac eht evahs ot
.erif yb desaeler si taht htmraw evitpac a htiw seert eht sllif nus eht dna
gnileenk neeb dah eh erehw morf flesmih srebmilnu eh sa
”?sgniht esoht fo dog eht uoy era woH
,gnÝ ton era uoY“ ”.lufhtiaf
.hctaw osla yehT dna
,swonk tuyL ,sihT
.tuhs dehcnelc seye
,neddus eht htiw selggurts eh sa skeehc sih nwod skcart niats sraeT
,yad eht rof esnecni sih liops siht lliw ylno ton taht swonk dna flesmih tuc sah eH
,serif rieht fo taeh eht ni sekac llams ekab yeht nehw
,yarp ew eman s'gnÝ nI
,dlrow eht egnahc ,mih gnignahc yb dna
,draob sih snaelc neht tuyL
,yad eht ni tniop siht yb dna
.sdrow sih era hsa dna esnecni fo hsuh teiuq eht dna gnipmat eht fo mhtyhr eht
.tliub sah eh liart eht fo retnec eht ta esnecni fo dnuom llams eht ot ti sehcuot dna
.erofeb flesmih tuc sah eh rof
,mih shtaerw ekoms eht sa
,dne no setunim rof llaw kcab eht ot ecaf sih sserp dna evac sih otni kcab elbmarcs mih hctaw I os dna
,senob sih morf llihc eht dna
,efil sih fo elcyc eht
”.ees ot struh tI“ :syas eh dna
,daeh sih fo nworc eht neht
,llef hcihw irausT nI ,rednuht eht gnirb ohw yehT ,ti dne ohw yehT
;reyarp sih kaeps ton seod eH
,noinimod tcerid riehT rednu ton sgniht esoht fo tub
.gnilffuhs tfos htiw mih ediug teef siH
,spord deyenoh ni htuom sih morf sllaf
gnihtaerb reh raeh nac eh litnu ylluferac sklaw eH
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,lwob eht ot ti gnidda erofeb efink sih htiw tsrif siht setarg eH
.sraey ytrof sih ni nwohs tey ton sah eh rovref a htiw gnÝ ot syarp eH .syarp eH
.sessessop eh esnes a ton si thgis rof
gnitsaf fo keew eht si keew sihT
.seye eht ot lla evoba tseneek era sworra s’nus eht taht snrael dna ,nus eht ta kool ot ,neve ,seirT
traeh sih ecreip ot ecneserp s’drol sih ,daetsni ,swolla
.niaga yas I ”,ees uoY“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,htorb eht fo taeh eht etipsed ,litnu
tsol ecnalab eht dna
,taht erofeb raey eno dna
egnahc rof ydaer ma I
,duola sreyarp sih kaeps eh seod won ylnO .ecnelis era
ekab ot tuyL rof tnatropmi si tI
,tonnac nus eht fo dog eht yaw a ni retaw raelc no gnicnad thgil fo gninaem eht swonk ohw em ot ,em ot osla tub
”.em evres osla uoy
,erif yb desnaelc dna toh
.ydob dekan sih ta skool eH
,epacse ot deen lautcnitsni sih dna ,noisufnoc sih
.cinap ni dna rorret ni skooL
,slwarc ,tuyL ,yllautnevE
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.woleb egalliv eht dna flesmih shtaerw taht esnecni eht seraperp eh ,stnavres riehT ot dna
.lufhtiaf ,yad ruoy rof eraperp dna oG“
,eh nehw emit eht si sihT
yreppils steg htap eht nwod yaw sih ediug ot sesu eh kcits eht taht
,sekam eh esnecni eht sa reyarp fo yhtrow sa si siht taht desimrus sah eh dna
,htmraw sa mih srewop nus eht rof
momadrac fo dop deird suoicerp a fo eton pot enol eht htiw ,won ,sehsinif ,tcerroc ti gnimeed
,deruc-gnol dna drah ,kcits gniklaw siH
,esnecni fo tnuoma lamron eht semit eerht meht rof eraperp tsum eh keew siht os dna
,gnÝ ot noitaerc fo sreyarp eerht fo tsrif eht llet ot si pu mottob eht morf tnecs a dliub oT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,daerb fo sevael on erew ereht
.mih drawot kcab dna dnuora ten eht ward ot dnuora mra sih speews dna knab eht no yal yeht erehw morf ten eht fo dne raf eht fo sdroc eht pu sehctac eh
.llew sa ma I dna
foereht shtdiw-walc net serusaem dna draob eht tsniaga syal eh won hcihw dna dednuop dah eh ylsuoiverp hcihw
gnitsaf fo keew eht fo esnecni eht rof stneidergni eht fo lla skcats ti no dna evac sih morf erom ecno draob sih seveirter eh yadot oS
.redro ni ruf sih syal eh nehw emit eht si sihT
,sbmil sih gnola gnignis drol sih fo tirips eht
.llew sa mih htiw ti seirrac dna ,hsa htiw dellif hsid a stfil dna nwod sdneb eh ,yaw eht gnolA
,efink sih htiw tnedicca dab ylralucitrap a retfa ,oot ,swonK
,dnah tfel sih no pitregnif tsal eht fo sehcuot eltneg htiw skcehc eh hcihw
,tnavres riehT ot si ti fo emos rof
”!struh tI !struh tI“
,hsif hctac ot sdeer dettonk dna dednuop eht hguorht ylthgirb wolf retaw fo maerts tnatsnoc eht gnittel
,noos yad sih ot dnetta ot deen lliw eh taht wonk I .tiaw I os dna
,rorret sih wonk I .esuac dluoc efink a htiw tnedicca yna naht retaerg raf raef a dna niap ythgim a htiw kcurts si eh taht ,thgirb dna yrrulb ,sraey ytrof sih ni emit tsrif eht rof nus eht fo thgil eht seviecrep eh nehw taht wonk I :sthguoht sih wonk I
,yarp ew dlrow s'gnÝ nI
”?gnireffo ruo rof esnecni eht eraperp uoy sa smra ruoy gnola nrub dna traeh ruoy ecreip ew yaw eht leef ton uoy od tub ,I dna
,noom eht fo dog eht ma I
”.em dnammoc tonnac uoy
?dog retskcirt a osla ton I ma
?morf yawa seihs nus eht taht sgniht ton ereht era dnA
,stnavres dna tnavres riehT fo ecivres nI
,yrgnuh peels ot enog erom ecno sah tuyL .ydaer ma I dna
,tfel srebme era ereht fI
,em ot reyarp a si neerg dna etihw dna knip ni smoolb taht enehpsohp hcae dna
seitixelpmoc lufrednow tahw fo noitalpmetnoc tnelis a si laem sih fo tser ehT
.doof demaets sih desopxe ot trapa kcarc dna pat ot hguone looc si yalc eht
,ti htaeneb yad eht fo ohce na si ,oot ,gninrom sihT
mih htiw yarp ylno lliw ehs
,esnecni rof stneidergni ro daerbtalf fo sevael tfos on era erehT
.noitoved dna reyarp ni efil sih sevil tuyL
.laem sih htiw mih dedivorp I rof ,llew sa reyarp taht morf pus I
.thgila gnihctac gnildnik fo elkcarc wols eht dna meht tsniaga htaerb s’tuyL fo dnuos eht si reyarp siht fo sdrow eht neht
semoc tahw ot nosirapmoc ni
.ees yam rehctaw a tahw otni ,tcartsba revewoh ,thguoht stup ,rehsif dnilb ,ainakep dnilb
.tirips ni erup flesmih edam ydaerla gnivah ,gnÝ erofeb ydob ni erup flesmih sekam eh nehw emit eht si sihT
,ruf sih hguorht tuo spees tI
,gnitsaef fo keew eht fo
.ytluciffid ralucitrap emos seirrac wap eno fo esu eht ylno htiw dnuow a dnib ot taht
daenk dna hsurc dna lwob ym otni
,esnecni fo elcyc eht yb denifed era syad siH
.gnildnik dna rednit otni krab eht gnidderhs dna skcits eht nwod gnikaerb fo
reyarp siht fo sdrow ehT
,tonnac tuyL dnilb taht yaw a ni
,esina rats fo eton pot eht dna
secaparac enif tneverp ot hteet prahs hguorht ti gniniarts
,srehtaferof ruo fo ekoms eht pu reffo eW
;sessessop eh esnes a ton si thgis rof sward eh larips yxob eht ta kool ton seod eH
,regnif sih fo pit eht htiw enalp htooms a otni hsid ni hsa eht nwod spmat eh sa traeh sih ni noitoved eht htiw llits skrow tuyL dna
.trid htiw dna sraet htiw ruf sih sraems dna seye sih tsniaga smlap sih sdnirg eH
.drol sih htiw noitasrevnoc a si taht noitoved fo noitrop taht
.ssenlooc dna htmraw no setatidem eH .selcyc no setatidem eH .siht no setatidem eh ,won naelC
”?uoy ees I naC“ ”.uoy htiw ma I“
.smla mih thguorb ton sah atiZ
,tsaf a ylurt si ti ,yad txen eht dnA
.tsurt dna ecnarussaer seil noitatidem nI
delzzad eb sesnes sih tsel
,taeper I ”,wýT“ ”?wýT“
,dah eb ot snref on
”.htaed fo dna gnihctaw fo dna retaw eht dna noom eht fo dog eht ma I .wýT ma I“
,sdrow sih krab suorbif fo raet eht dna doow yrd fo kcarc eht fo dnuos ehT
.ekaw sti ni esnecni deredwop eht gnippord
,demrof sah eh taht rekab yalc eht morf epacse ot gninnigeb si hsif demaets fo llems eht ,neht yB
,ot nward si nus eht taht ytilauq ralucitrap a fo si ruf sih taht
”?gnineppah si tahw ,drol ym ,drol yM“
.retaw deliob dna noitirtnoc dna reyarp htiw dellif ylleb
erif eht morf htorb gniremmis sih evomer ot mih rof emit si ti neht dnA
.sdaeh eht morf rettub eht skcus dna
.maerts eht fo retaw eht ni efink dna swap sih snaelc tuyL elihw ria ni nword snaecatsurc dna hsif eht tel ot erohs eht nopu talf dial si eritne ten ehT
.thgis mih nevig evah I dna
,yad fo gnimraw wols eht ta srits ainakep eht nehW
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,ten eht ni hsif oN
,tibah sih si taht selcsum dexaler fo tils eht ot lausu sa nepo tfird seye sih
.ton ti swonk eh hguoht ,em erofeb erup flesmih sekam eh nehw emit eht si siht ,ooT
.gnitatidem ,gnigarof ,gnihsif ,reyarp
,wap thgir sih ni remmah dna efink eht sdloh eh esuaceb thgir ot tfel morf skrow eH
taht rof ,hctaw dna tis I
.esnecni eht dnib ot redwop okkam fo thgiew ni niaga driht eno eb ot segduj eh tahw dna
,tuo era slaoc eht fI
.esnecni eht fo gnithgil eht fo taht si
sevil tnelis rieht evil taht hsifwarc eht fo seidob dellehs-drah eht osla stonk sti ni sleef ,erohsa ten eht gniggard nopu
.gniraelc sih fo retnec eht ni deggel-ssorc stis dna ,nus eht otni tuo slwarc
.mih nopu si tsaf sih kaerb ot emit eht dna
.pots a ot wols efil sih fo sruoh eht nehw nrober eb ylerus lliw eh rof
.meht hguorht egnaro yksud gniwohs
,dlrow eht fo ytuaeb eht dnatsrednu ot citecsa eht rof neve tnatropmi si ti esuaceb
.mih rof hcum oot si gniees siht neve taht wonk I .mih dnuora dna
,evom ton seod eH
.erif fo gnildniker ro gnigrof eht si noitcurtsed fo reyarp dnoces ehT
.noitcartsid dna nis fo eerf dna naelc flesmih speek eh
,mih sesimorp drol sih ,dna
.gnÝ ot pihsnoitaler sih no dna
.tsap eht ni ,ti dniheb
,won swonk eh yrolg revetahw
.owt skculp eh hcihw fo
,noissimo fo eil a
.teliot sih evah yam eh mih sllet eson sih erehw ecalp eht ot sdnorf rehtruf edisa gnihsurb
mehT fo rednow eht etaicerppa dna ecnelis ni
.noisufnoc sih ta elims dna
.llew sa kcab sih ehtab thgil s’gnÝ stel dna tnorf sih no syal eh neht dna
.revir deddeb-tlis eht fo mottob eht no