”.tuyL ,yadretsey uoy htiw tsenoh yletelpmoc ton saw I ,revewoH
”.meht ekat slamina thgin eht tsel sekac eht dna daerb eht yawa tuP“ .yas I
,uoy osla dna sroloc dna nus eht dna thgil eht edam gnÝ fi ,sey
,em ot esiarp evig uoy
.pu semoc gnihctaw fo dna thgis fo dog eht fo
”?thgis tuyL nevig uoy evah yhW“
:wonk tub ,lufhtiaf ,hsiw uoy sA“
,seye sih sbur dna pu stis rehsif eht sa tnemesuma kcab dloh tsum I dna ,ecaf sih revo semoc noisufnoc fo kool A ”.wýT si tI
.sees eh hcihw taht gnissecorp pu nekat si
.drol ruo fo redro eht no edam eb ot tnemegduj on si ereht sa tsuj
,noitaerc fo reyarp driht taht
?sgniht lla fo dog eht ton gnÝ sI“
”.wýT ,hcum oot si tI“
,wenk eh siht ,yad ton si thgiN
flesmih denaelc dna reyarp sih dias sah eh retfA
,sraef dna sthguoht sih daer ot elba eb lliw atiZ ,level emos no
,eurt ,gnÝ fo taht si nepo era srae dna seye htob nehw sees ti sa ylerup sa raeh nac hcihw dnim ylno ehT“ ”…tub
.evac eht morf yawa kcab ecap-flah a sekat ehs dna
”.wýT ,uoy ot sreyarp yna ot sdrow eht wonk ton od I“
”!tirips A !tirips A“
drawrof evom emit taht tsniaga evirts ot gnihtemos evah tsum gnÝ rof ,sgniht fo yaw eht si sihT
.esnecni eht otni enog dah hcihw momadrac dna aissac eht htiw dekcepseb dna nus eht fo roloc eht si ekac ehT
”?siht enod sah gnÝ“
,eb ton dluoc egalliv eht taht syaw eht ni erup saw eh dna ,semit lla ta gnÝ erofeb erup saw eH
gnÝ .sdrow dna snoitca ruoy ni naelc dna erup eb ot
,sgninrom sih fo redro lausu eht ton si sihT
.tnavres a gnisaelp revo yteixna ym ta tnemesumeb s’gnÝ esnes I dna ,noitcafsitas sih ees ot desaelp ma I
noinimod ym era sgniht esehT“
,lufhctaw eht wýT ot
.llew sa em ot ,tnemom a retfa ,dna gnÝ ot sknaht sevig eH
,siht no elihw gnol a rof skniht eH
,terces a esnes dnuofwen sih peek ot eh ereW
— sraey ynam ni tsrif sih
”?ti sexif gnÝ dna soahc wos uoY“
,ria ni gninword dna gnipsag
,won dnatsrednu yehT tuB
ytuaeb nwo sti ezingocer ot esrevinu eht rof yaw a sa efil evag yehT stnavres riehT ot dna
,ecaf sih fo lla ni ekat ot hguoht sa taht dna yaw siht trad seye s’atiZ
”?ees uoy od tahw tub ,seY“
,kcits eht thguorb sah eh taht tseb eht rof si ti spahrep dna
”.lufhtiaf ,gnorts era uoY“
.gnivrennu si erif yb degnahc hsif eht fo thgis eht rof
,rehto hcae rof soahc wos uoy nehw tub
.elcarim siht fo meht llet dna egalliv eht ot nwod og tsum I“
.ssap ot esnecni ruoy fo ekoms eht rof mrif oot si retaw fo niamod eht dna ria fo niamod eht neewteb yradnuob ehT .lufhtiaf ,oN“
”?retaw eht dneirf yM
.flesti ria eht ni dnuof eb ot erew srewsna eht hguoht sa dnuora gnikool
,gnihctaw fo dna retaw eht fo dog eht era yeht taht ,wýT eveileb I“
.tsal ta syas eh ”,neht oS“
,gniknird dna gnihtab dna gnihsif yb emas eht lla yarp yam uoY
.atiZ ,uoy knahT .ees I“
.siht no skniht dna ekac ecips sih stae tuyL
”,seY“ ”!rednow a hcuS
citecsa sa elor sih yarteb ot saw egalliv eht erofeb eil oT
.roloc a nud os yb deileb si
,gnÝ ot tnavres ma I dna
?thgis em nevig evah uoy taht gniht dekciw a ti sI“
,retaw eht htaeneb si eh emit yreve dna ,gnÝ ot esiarp fo enil a sgnis eh ,ria rof pu semoc eh emit hcaE
.gnihtab snigeb eh sa neve elpoep sih fo tik a thgim sa syalp dna stset eH
,tnemhsinup a ton taht sI“
elcyc sseldne eht ni tniop tahw ta dediced dna mih koot gnÝ litnu eil a evil oT
,efil lluf a llits si esnes a tuohtiw devil efil A
.erofeb mih ot nwonknu neeb dah ohw dog a
dna reh ot esolc siht ,llew sA
deillus gnieb fo gnileef ehT
:ksa neht dna ,elihw a tiaw I
,sregnif sih htiw slooplrihw fo slennuf eht serolpxe ,sgel sih dnuora
.erif sih fo srebme eht fo wolg gnislup dna der eht ta slevram eH
”.suordnow ylurt gnihtemos ot del sah yloh gnipeek dna gnitsaf fo emit ruo taht dna
.nwo sih fo nworb krad eht ot desoppo sa etihw tserup eht fo ruf htiw dna
.sraet ot mih gnirb dna
,nwo sih si taht maerts eht fo noitces eht fo elddim eht ni sdnats eH
.nwonk reven dah eh taht esae hcus htiw esnecni fo earohpma eht pu dekcip ohw
”sdog fo redro dna soahc eht era yeht esuaceb
ylurt ot si esle enoemos fo seye eht otni yltcerid kool ot taht sleef eh tey ,seye reh ees nac eH
.uoy rof nekops sah tfig ruoy rof ,uoy tbuod ton od I
.tuo gnidnif enoyna fo thguoht eht ta dah eb ot rorret saw ereht tey dnA
.taerter yllohw ton seod ti hguoht ,netfos em ta regna s’drol eht leef I ,siht tA
”?retaw htaeneb esnecni ruoy llems uoy od ,lla retfA
”.nrut ni mehT ot sesiarp gnis ot si em ot sesiarp gnis oT
”?thgis ruoy deniager ton dah uoy taht won hsiw uoy oD“
.tnelis syats tuyL
.llew draeh ton dah ehs spahrep fi srednow tuyL dna ,edis eno ot daeh reh stlit atiZ
”.elihw a rof ,tsael tA
,dennuts dna ten ni depparw ,erohs eht no hsif eht htiW
”?wýT ,retaw eht htaeneb ees hsif eht oD“
— gnihtyreve rof ,nees eb ot em hcaet lliw uoy dna
.tnasaelpnu esnes on ni
ecneserp rieht ni dna ,enod evah wýT tnavres sih dna gnÝ taht gniht wen a si siht ,seY .seY“
.sreyarp ruo erahs ew dna
— dlrow eht ni ecalp sih ton si taht hguoht
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”?thgis ruoy htiw degnahc taht saH .wýT fo lufhtiaf
.dlrow eht morf sniard roloc eht hcihw ni yaw eht ni sknird eH
”.wonk tsum I tub ,niaga gniksa rof yrros ma I
.mih ot elims I ”?uoy era ohW“
.sgniht lla tuoba suoiruc sniamer eH
.tnemom taht ni mih sliaf egaruoc lla dna ,sknurt eht neewteb reh fo tnih a sees eh
,citecsa eht sa elor sih saw taht rof
”.emit tsrif eht rof was I
.gniees yb detcartsid nehw erup ssel leef I
.gnihton no ylgnimees gnisucof seye reh
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.morf emac yeht erehw ton wenk eh hguoht
.enituor gnieesnu sih otni kcab elttes ot stpmetta eh sa poord sreksihw sih dna seye sih sesolc eh ,semit eerhT
,yas dna ecnelis gnol ym kaerb I ”?wýT si ohW“
.revir eht ot nwod mih ediug ot kcits sih gnibbarg ,sraey ynam os fo tibah eht fo tuo
.kni.oykam ta revo
smeop dna seirots trohs morf ,gnitirw reh fo erom dnif nac uoY
.shgual rehsif eht ,noisufnoc s’tnemom a retfA
.erom ecno dlrow eht ni evom ot woh nrael ot sah eh
.reh tuoba wonk reve ylbissop dluoc eh naht mih tuoba sterces repeed wonk lliw ehs taht
.reh fo retteb eht steg yllanoisacco ainamohparg esohw
,noitidart egnahc dna egalliv eht tset ot saw hturt eht llet oT
.ylwols pu stis atiZ
.etatidem dna yrd ot dnuorg eht no syal eh nehw
.dog retskcirt a osla ma I tub
,dnuorg eht no gniyal yb gnitatidem desaec dah dna wýT htiw noitasrevnoc sih desaec ecnis dah eh
.tnelis sniamer eh os
,skniht eh ,si ehS
”.gniht wen a su rof dedivorp sah gnÝ won dna
”?nees eb ot raed oot erew sdog eht taht thguoht I“ ”.lufhtiaf ,seY“ ”?wýT“
”?tuyL ,seY“ ”.rednow I ,ylnO“
,stneidergni eht bard woh tsuj ta slevram eh dna yltnatsnoc retaw seye sih rof
,ees yam uoy taht yloh dna doog si tI“
— tonnac eh dna dne no syad rof dab si rehtaew eht nehw semit era ereht rof ,eurt eb tsum ti ,level emos no ,taht swonk eH
,retaw erup knird ro ehtab uoy emit yrevE“
.duolc a ekil mih dnuora sgnah ylohnu dna
.dloheb ot era ,hcuot eht ot railimaf os dna slirtson eht ni lufroloc dna thgirb os
,rekab yalc eht nepo gnikcarc retfa doof sih tae ot seye sih sesolc eH
!rednow a dekrow sah gnÝ“
.thgis fo scinahcem eht ylpmis erew esoht tuB
,emit tnavres ym evig I
,ees ton did I nehw ,yadot erofeb ,gninrom siht erofeB“
.thgis em detnarg sah gnÝ“
,mih naht retrohs
.evac sih erofeb gniraelc eht drawot htap eht fo evruc eht gnidnuor atiZ sraeh eh nehw seye sih sesolc dna dnim sih pu sekam tuyL
.duola sgnileef dna sthguoht sih sessecorp eh dna ,wols era sdrow siH
.laem yliad sih eraperp ot evac sih ot kcab sdaeh dna hsif sih snaelc eh sa mih htiw ma I
,sesoprup dna samora ni ecnereffid tsav eht etipsed ralimis os kool galf teews fo toor devahs eht dna
,ecnalab eht taht dediced evah yeht os dna ,ecnalab eht lortnoc yehT ,revewoH .seerga gnÝ dna
atiZ ot nosirapmoc ni tpecxe dnilb sa flesmih fo kniht ton did eh
.gnihctaw fo dna retaw fo dog ,yrros ma I“
,tub ,sdog eht fo yhcrareih eht dnatsrednu ton od ,tnavres a sa ,I“
”.yhw nosaer eht wonk yllohw tey ton od I dna
.em ot redro thguorb nrut ni evah yehT dna soahc dewos I dna
.tey ton ,lufhtiaf ,wonk ot uoy rof ton si tahT“
.ylluferac rewsna I dna
.erom ecno ten sih stes eh sa mih htiw ma I
”.sey ,noihsaf a retfA“
.mih morf ecneconni sih nekat evah I rof ,syad sih fo dne eht litnu ereht ti dloh lliw eh taht
.retaw looc eht depeets era shgiht sih erehw maerts a ni loop a fo elddim eht ni gnidnats
.llew sa siht fo tnazingoc si eh won dna
.sdrow yb deduolcnu esiarp htiw dellif ma I dna ,noitaerc ym rof speew eH
,em ees nac uoy taht os ti edam sah gnÝ .lufhtiaf ,oN“
.ainnellim regnol dna sraey gnol eht hguorht eurt neeb syawla sah sihT
”,hguoht ,uoy ees tonnac I“
,retrohs tub ,sey ,rednels dna gnorts
,llew sa em ot sesiarp sih gnignis si eh ,sevid eh emit hcaE
.mih pots ton od I dna ,wonk I ,flesmih gnitset si eH
,eciov reh ot noitartsurf fo egde na si erehT
wýT erofeb si eh llams woh tuoba skniht eh dna
.nialpmoc ton od I
.seye sih snepo eh os dnA
,tnecs a fo esab tsafdaets taht ,citsam eht taht
,em fo cipot eht tsrif nehw dexif ylisae eno tub ,eil llams a si tI .syas tuyL
,rellams ro regral sworg semitemos kcalb fo elcric eht taht sees eh
yllufhtiaf sa gnÝ evres I nac woH
,hsif ot ereh emoc uoy nehW
,wos I taht soahc eht egduj ot hcihw no dnuorg larom on si erehT
”.ylohnu tlef dna elcarim siht detbuod I
”.swonk llew tuyL sa ,sdrow ni era sreyarp lla ton rof
elcarim a thguorw sah gnÝ taht ees I“
,kaeps ton seod eh tub ,dnim sih ni snoitseuq esnes dna ecaf sih no noisufnoc ees I
,gnÝ ,drol ruo ot resolc si eh ,desolc era seye sih nehw dna
.sgniht lla fo gninnigeb eht ta em detaerc gnÝ ecnis neeb reven evah I sa gniwolfrevo ot delliF
,em ot kaepS“ .sraet htiw tew skeehc sih ees I dna ,desolc meht speek eh ,kcab sih otno sllor eh nehw neht dna
,ecaf sih no elims yramotsuc eht htiw ecalp yramotsuc eht ni gnittis ton si eh esuaceb taht sesoppus tuyL
.rehto hcae tsniaga evirts ro rehtegot krow ew reveroF
.hsif llams eerht sdnif eh hcihw ni ten sih ot sedaw eh
,dootsrednu ton dah tub nwonk dah tuyL hcihw ,noom lluf eht fo thgin eht si gnitsaef fo keew eht fo thgin tsrif ehT
,mrof deidobme siht ni dlrow eht gnoma sraey ytriht rof evil lliw I
.eurt si siht ,seY“
,eno yloh ,noom eht ees lliw uoy thginoT
”?uoy gnivres tneps emit si gnihctaw tneps emit ym taht won
.yloh ssel leef I“
.speew eh dna ,ytuaeb sti sdnatsrednu eH
,thguoht a elbirret oot saw htaed sih decalp eb dluohs
si eh llams woh tuoba skniht eH
,mih ediug gnÝ stel dna mih nopu emoc sah maerd taerg a hguoht sa sevom tuyL
.elcyc a ni evom ew reveroF
.redro sgnirb gnÝ elihw soahc swos ohw dog eht ma I
.sdon dna erom ecno atiZ ot selims eh neht dna siht tuoba skniht eH
,kcohs yb derrulb thgis hguorht detelpmoc era noitcurtsed fo sreyarp sih fo lla dna
noitamrofni erom etavacxE
,egnahc siht htiw detnorfnoC
,dlrow eht ekam ohw yehT
”.nrut ni drol ym si gnÝ dna
.yhw wonk ylthgir ton seod eh dna
.fleseno yllus ot si eil ot tey dnA
”?won I ma tahw neht
.netfos serutaef sih sih tA
,ekil-tnalp dna rettib etsat ot ti desuac taht maerts eht fo noitces sih fo retaw eht ot deneppah gnihtemos nehw emit a neve saw ereht ecno dna ,revir eht morf doof tuohtiw keew a og lliw eh nehw semit era ereht dna
.mih naht rednuor dna retfos
,htaed fo dna noom eht fo
”.flesym ot dna gnÝ ot reyarp reffo uoy ,os gniod ni rof
”?esnecni ym llems yeht oD“
.erom ecno sdnats dna tuyL ot selims atiZ
”.su fo lla gnihctaw si gnÝ dna thgis tuyL nevig evah I .ma I“
,daed eht nruom uoy emit yreve dna ,noom eht fo ytuaeb eht dloheb uoy emit yreve
.shtaed wols rieht eid meht sehctaw eH
.tnavres ym htiw niamer I dna ,emas eht lla desaelp ma I
,seye reh ees nac eH
.wap ym ni gnitrofmoc si tI“
.lavirra reh rof nepo seye sih peek ot gnilliw si eh ton ro rehtehw staebtraeh ytriht rof setabed eH
.noom eht fo esimorp eht ta thgin eht otni etal pu syats tuyL
.tuyL htiw ma I dna thgirb era seert eht fo sroloc ehT
,erom ecno em tsniaga gnisir regna s’gnÝ leef I
”.wýT ot esiarp ruoy eb lliw taht dna ytuaeb sti wonk dna
.lufhtiaf ,I si tI“
”.tuyL ,stnavres ruo fo ksa reve ew lla si tahT“ ”.wýT ,yrt lliw I“
”.em edam ohw yehT saw tI
”?ylohnu htob su edam uoy evaH
”.tuyL ot thgis nevig evah I dna
.uoy morf etarapes dlrow eht fo trap a era sgniht eseht fo lla tub ,dog retskcirt a ma I dna
,sgniht lla fo drol eht si
.daeh sih sekahs eH ”.hcum oot si tI“
,sey ,ehtil dna gnoL
,walc sih htiw hsa ni sgid eh worruf eht ees nac eh taht sezilaer eh dna
.seert eht fo yponac eht secreip worra s’nus eht erehw retaw looc eht ni
”.ti htiw egnahc dna worg snoitaerc sih dna
.llew sa si yloh eht fo esnes sih spahrep dna
,laem sih gniraperp fo thgis eht tuo tuhs ot seye sih sesolc eH
.siht ta deltrats skool tuyL
,tcaf erem siht yb si eh demlehwrevo woh fo skniht eH
,gnihsaw elihw ruf sih htaeneb tlef semitemos dah tuyL taht sracs eht rof kcehc ot dna seye sih ta kool ot
.su fo htob htiw si gnÝ rof
.evitatnet ,skaeps atiZ ”?tuyL“ .dnim
,taht seirrow eh dna ,meht ees
.hsif war fo rovalf eht ot regnarts on saw tuyL rof
,s’drol ym fo dna enim fo tnavres siht ,ylsuoiruc mih hctaw I
”gnieesnU“   yojne esaelP
nidran fo toor dehsurc eht taht dnif ot desirprus si eh ,esnes wen a si thgis mohw rof eno ot neve tub
.lufhtiaf ,soahc gnixif on si erehT“
.seod tuyL sa llew sa tsomla niereht yretsym eht dna sdog eht fo sgnikrow eht swonk ehs rof ,sdrow ym ta sexaler ehS
,gnidloh saw eh nwonk ton dah eh ssenesnet a morf xaler sredluohs sih stel tuyL
”.tuyL raed ,lufhtiaf ,oN“
,ydob nwo sih fo thgis eht ta rednow ni elihw a sregnil dna teliot sih ot dnet ot sdoow eht otni selbmuts tuyL dna sessap lautir rof emit eht ,tsal tA
.regna a ni stsiwt ecaf s’tuyL ”.rednow dna
.mih drawot sklaw dna snworf ehS
.nees eb ot em rof si gniees uoy rof ,egnahcxe eht
”.em htiw ti ekat lliw I
,wonk I ,tset a si tI
.hsif sih dnuora snref eht fo gnitsiwt eht yb desufnoc oot
.noonretfa eht hguorht htap gnol sti nwod gnippit dna daehrevo si nus ehT
.yaw eht gnola yam I sreyarp tahw ni knird dna
,gnitatidem dna gniyarp neeb evah I
.kni.sfhf ta
.tnelis niamer I ”.etelpmoc saw I
”.noitoved fo kcal a skaepseb ti tub ,spahrep ,elbativenI
,gniwolfrevo ot em sllif sgel sih dnuora gnivom retaw eht fo thgis eht ta ecaf sih no rednow eht sa tub
,em desselb evah tnavres sih dna gnÝ
?flesmih nrael yademos tsum eh taht dethgis eht fo egdelwonk emos siht saW
,kaeps ot hguoht sa nepo htuom
.raeh ot dedeen eh tahw dias evah I taht ezilaer I dna rewsna siht ta deifsitas skool eH
erup niamer lliw I taht uoy ni htiaf evah I dna gnÝ ni htiaf evah I“
.eil a gnivil eb yaw emos ni dluow eh ,sey neht
,mih fo hcum oot hguoht sa ,denepo era seye sih nehw decuder hsif eht fo etsat eht sdnif eh
.sdapwap sih htiw ria dna retaw neewteb yradnuob eht gnileef ,retaw eht evoba dnah sih snur eH
,ecalp sti ni skcap eh taht redwop nat eht ees nac
.elggiw dna rettilg meht sehctaw eH .sehctaw tuyL
,uoy erofeb emac ohw esoht evah sa yloh tpek evah uoY
,ereh ma I elihw decuder yltsav si gnirb I taht soahc eht taht dnif lliw uoy dna
,yaw on ni si ehs dna ,erofeb dah reve eh naht retteb reh llems nac eh
,evom seye reh sa dna
.reh dniheb tuoba secnad liat reh dna
”.hguone evarb ton ma I“
— mih naht def retteb si ehs ,ooT
.drol sih erofeb llits rellams dna
gnÝ .ma I tahw dna ohw si taht esuaceb soahc wos I
”?retaw eht htaeneb llems yeht oD“
momadrac fo tnecs thgirb-lewej eht elihw nus eht ni srettilg ylraen
.htaed dna noom eht fo dog eht dna gnihctaw fo dog eht dna retaw eht fo dog eht ma I“
.seye ym esolc I
.yteixna htiw mih sllif os od ot dna ,emit tsrif eht rof meht gniees si dna
,si ydob siht ,ma I
.flesreh rof rehto eht gnipeek dna tuyL rof flah eno tuo gnidloh
”.seid ti erofeb gnÝ ot sreyarp eht raeh dna esnecni eht llems ot ecnahc eht sah ereh erohs eht nopu hsif eht fi rednow I“
.siht sredisnoc ehs ,gninworf llitS
,atiZ eltrats ot smees reh nopu dekool dna seye sih denepo dah eh tahT ”.atiZ“ .selims eH
.htiw nrob neeb dah eh esoht naht rehto sesnes htiw enoemos eviecrep ot ,ees ot gnilliw si eh ton ro rehtehw setabed eH
.gniraelc sih fo weiv otni speerc ti tsrif nehw ecnatropmi sti dna noom eht sdnatsrednu eH .seod eh won tub
.erofeb wob ot esle eno on gniees
.revef htiw kcis saw eh dna rovalf eht evomer dluoc gniliob fo tnuoma on dna
.daeh sih nihtiw dias dah I tahw revo snrut eH
,retaw eht ot htap eht nwod yaw sih spat tuyL
.em hsinup ot tniop eno ta dehsiw yehT spahrep dna em htiw yrgna tsrif ta saw
.reh was eh erofeb reh sraeh tuyL os dna ,ytud reh neeb dah siht taht skeew lavitsef net tsal eht rof dah ehs sa
.yks sselduolc dna seert eht ot pu skool dna seye sih snepo eh ,tsal tA
,repsihw a evoba ylerab si eciov siH
,niamod ym ta serats dna maerts eht fo egde eht ta ,tsal ta ,spotS
,hsa fo lwob eht ni esnecni deredwop eht yal ot emit si ti litnu
.shgual neht ,yrgna skool tuyL
,dnatsrednu ton od I
”.nrob erew uoy ecnis seye ruoy denil evah syas rehtom ym taht sracs eht tuohtiw
.ecafrus eht woleb eagla dna skcor dna tlis eht ot retaw raelc hguorht sreep
.gnÝ ot duola yarp ot nigeb dna rehtegot leenk srehsif htob ,yawa tup si doof eht retfA
”?lufhtiaf ,naem uoy od tahW“
”.siht ekil dekool ti taht denigami reven dah I“
— ecarbme na ni tuyL dnuora smra reh tup atiZ hctaw I dna
,tuohguorht gnÝ ot gniyarp si eh taht wonk I dna
:ylteiuq ,neht ,sksa eH
”.egalliv eht erofeb dna em erofeb eil a evil ot eb dluow eno siht edih ot dna
,traeh eht ot esolc dleh eb tsum dna etavirp era selcarim emos elihw
.stcepxe eh hcihw ni syaw eht seye sih ot evaheb ton od sregnif decitcarp-gnol sih ot esnes hcum os ekam hcihw sevael ehT
”.wýT ,ton od I esoppus I“
seye sih gnits dlrow eht ni sroloc dna ssenthgirb eht taht mih ot wen os llits ,thgis fo kcohs eht tuoba skniht eH
,lufhtiaf ,ees ot uoy hcaet lliw I ,woN .dooG“
,ereht atiZ sees dna gniraelc eht ssorca skool dna seye gniees sih snepo eH
?ereht dloheb ot gnihtemos ereht saW
,sevitom ym dnatsrednu ro wonk ton seod eh hguoht ,dnA
.yadretsey did I sa yadot llew sa gnÝ raeh tonnac I tey dnA“
.sworg ylno raef sih ,siht ta dna
,neddir-thgis ,woN
.stnavres fo stnavres eht ylurt era yloh tsom eht rof
”?uoy ees nac I taht os ti edam uoY“
.em fo dog eht era yehT dna ,sgniht ynam fo dog eht era yehT“
”?denessel rewop rieht evah ot dog a rof
,gnÝ ot tnavres a dna erofeb etelpmoc saw I fi tuB
.mih ot ti detnarg dah taht sdog eht fo rewop elbidercni eht fo ton wonk dluow egalliv eht tey dna lasopsid sih ta thgis evah dluow eH
.meht ssorca sevom dniw eht nehw dnuorg eht ssorca ecnad swodahs rieht yaw eht ot sevael eht sekirts worra snus eht yaw eht morf
,htaed fo dna gnihctaw fo dna noom eht fo dna retaw eht fo dog eht ma I dna ,wýT ma I“
,yaw eht gnola liated yreve ot yltnatsnoc nward era seye sih rof
,nek reh dnoyeb egnahc emos mih ni esnes tsum ehs taht
,yaw nwo rieht ni yloh era htoB
”.revewoh ,yam uoy nehw emit a eb lliw erehT
.siht no skniht eh sa daeh sih swob dna deggel-ssorc stis tuyL
”?neht ,yloh ton stnavres ruoy fo soahc eht sI“
,yloh tpek sah egalliv eht dna
,seert eht ni evom wodahs reh sees eH
”.htiaf evah I tub
.elihw gnol a rof seye sih otni skool ehs ,tsal tA
.mih htiw yarp I
.si noom eht tahw ton wonk I hguoht
,yltcerid rewsna ton od I
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy
,reyarp sih tpurretni ton od I
.reh morf ekac decips eht stpecca eh dna
.mrof wen ym ni em ta yltnetni gnirats ,snworf eH
,esnes taht tuohtiw desiar
.won si eh tahw tuoba gnikniht si eh taht wonk I
,llits neve tsaerb sih ni rorret sdloh tuyL taht wonk I
,syaw ynam ni mih ekil hcum yrev erutaerc a si evac sih ot ecnartne eht ta gnittiS
.mih esirprus ton seod ssenkrad gnirb dluow nus eht fo ecnesba eht taht naem dluow thgil thguorb nus eht taht gnidnatsrednu suoicsnocbus eht dna
.noisiced sih sekam dna em ot semoc gnÝ nehw thgin eht si thgin taht dnA
,yloh eb ot si evil oT“
...llef hcihw irausT nI ,rednuht eht gnirb ohw yehT ,ti dne ohw yehT
,etsat eht htiw oot sa ,degnahc dah nwonk syawla dah eh erutxet ni egnahc ehT
”.won tnereffid eb lliw — gnihtyreve
,yloh tpek sah dlrow elohw eht spahrep dna
- wýT dog retskcirt eht yb thgis htiw detfig saw
.thgil eht fo kcirt emos si ti spahrep hguoht
,nac dog a ylno taht yaw eht ni ecneirepxe uoy tahw gnicneirepxe em fo rettam a daetsni si siht dna
,retaw fo dna gnihctaw fo dog eht ma I“ ”?uoy era tahW
.flesmih gninrub tuohtiw dne eht ot hguorht ti ekam ot ecnadiug s’gnÝ dna stibah sih no seiler eh dna
”.lufituaeb sa eb dluoc gnihtemos taht wonk ton did I“
,riomem a dna slevon ot
,lausu naht rewols raf si esnecni gnikam fo ksat gninrom sih os neve dna
.gniraeh sa llew sa gniees edam ohw yehT saw tI
,ehtab ot ereh emoc uoy nehw
.was I ,seye ym denepo dna ekowa I nehw dna
.rednow sih leef I mih hguorht dna ,loop eht fo noisnet ecafrus eht sleef eH
.sdnah ym pu dloh dna elims I
— thguoht yreve s’drol eht wonk ton od I rof ,gnÝ yb spahrep dna — tibah yb llits dediuG
,hsinif yeht nehW
.flesreh rohtua eht yb
,raelc dna nepo seye ruoy htiw uoy ees I tub ,uoy ees syawla I sa uoy ees I“
:sksa dna walc a htiw selacs kcurts-nus secart eH
.htrof emoc sdrow on hguoht
.1 rebmeceD elbaliava
,esnes taht tuohtiw nrob eno ot dna
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb ”gnieesnU“
.mih ediseb sekac dna daerb eht nwod stes dna mih ot sehsur ehs ,stnemevom reh kcart seye sih nehw dna
,mid dna yduolc eb ot desu yeht erehw
,deklaw ehs sa gnas atiZ .tuo gnikool evac sih ot ecnartne eht ni deggel-ssorc gnittis rof delttes daetsni dah dna
.kcalb krad si ruf eht ,liat sih fo pit eht no dna ,regral srae dna rednels erom ecaf A
,syawla sA  .flesreh rohtua eht yb uoy rof daer
,ten sih sgnirts eh hcihw ssorca pag worran eht yb pu dleh loop eht ni
.erom ecno egalliv eht ot nwod gnitraped erofeb
,yad lla siht no gnitatidem dna gniyarp neeb evah I
”.em ot gnis uoy taht sesiarp era esoht ,knird ot ereh emoc uoy nehw
”.seye ruo ni sevlesruoy rewol uoy
,elbatrofmocnu tuyL sekam sihT
”?atiZ ,ees uoy od tahW“
:syas dna ekac reh swollaws ehS
”?lufhtiaf ruoy eb I nac woH“
”.stnavres rieht htiw gnola egnahc dna nrael tsum sdog rof
,erom ecno mih nopu emoc sraet neht dna ,sdliub eh larips eht ees nac dna
.tnavres riehT dna drol eht morf trapa dnats I dna stnemevom sih ediug gnÝ stel eH
”?thgis htiw eb syawla gnihctaw tsuM“ ”.ma I“
.drol reh ot tuo sgnir eciov s’atiZ taht yaw tnalibuj eht ni ksab dna reyarp rieht hsinif meht tel I
”.seituaeb sti lla dna niamod ym ees yehT .lufhtiaf ,seY“
.sgnirb siht ssenkcalb eht ni lever I
.seye sih snepo eh nehw tuyL steerg ecnerrucco egnarts dnoces a ,gninrom txen ehT
.noitasnes htiw gniwolfrevo si eh rof ,llits retaw seye siH
,sdrib eht dna maerts eht dna dniw eht raeh dna evac eht ni ecnelis ni tis eW
neek erom si llems sih dna reprahs si gniraeh sih taht os seye sih gnisolc si eh taht
”.noitcidsiruj ym rednu era taht sgniht esoht ni gniciojer yb
,dlrow eht no hctaw peek uoy emit yreve
.ti fo snoitacifimar eht sredisnoc dna semit net revo ti snrut eH
,lufhtiaf reve ,tuyL ,emit tsaL
”?dniheb ti evael uoy lliW“
,ton tsum I wonk I hguoht dna
.tuyL dnilb sa ,rekam-esnecni eht sa
.uoy ot esiarp ym reffo I dna ,tfig ruoy yawa nrut ton od I
.rehtegot hgual yeht dna
.daeh sih stlit tuyL
fo trap lanif dna
”.etercnoc osla era em ot snoitacifimar eht dna
,lufituaeb deedni si noom eht rof ,yoj htiw em sllif thguoht ehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.erofeb reve dah ti naht mih nihtiw ylgnorts erom snrub noitoved sih taht sezilaer dna
?won uoy ees I nac woH“
,goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.mih dlot dah I tahw tuoba skniht eH
,tsal ,seye sih sesolc eh dnA
,tnorf sih no syal eh sa seye sih sesolc eH
”?lufhtiaf ,taht deen uoy oD“
,htaed fo dna noom eht fo dna gnihctaw fo dna retaw fo dog eht ma I rof ,noissimo yb eil a saw tI“ ”?eil uoy nac woh
.siht dnatsrednu ot mih rof doog si ti dna
,gnÝ fo lufhtiaf ,tuyL era uoY“
sih ni revo now ,eb dluoc eh sa erup sa niamer ot
”.hcuot dna dnuos ni od I sa thgis ni gniciojer yb ylisae sa mih ot yarp I esoppus I neht
uoy rof daer ,2 fo 2 traP
?noitaerc ym fo rednow eht ees uoy od ,lufhtiaF“
.spots yltpurba neht ,gniraelc eht sretne ehs sa sodnecserc gnignis s’atiZ
,em ot resolc si eh ,nepo era seye sih nehw taht wonk I esuaceb mih pots ton od I
.teef reh ot seltrats atiZ dna sneffits tuyL ”.ma I“
,sgniht lla fo dog eht
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
.erutan yrev ruo si sihT
.su htiw erup niamer lliw dlrow eht taht dna
.denigami evah dluoc eh yna naht latnemadnuf erom level a no tnereffid si ehs tub
,tuyL rof sekac ecips fo lluf teksab llams a dna daerbtalf fo daolmra na gniraeb ,egalliv eht morf pu semoc atiZ nehW
,thgis sih si wen os ,noisserpxe reh daer yldrah nac tuyL
.drol ruo fo rewop eht ni lever I
,tnavres yna taht swonk eh
.tnemeerga ni sdon eH
,lapoc dna momadrac dna aissac eht llems ew dna
.seye sih snepo eH
?ton eh saw ,gnieesnu sih fo esuaceb trap ni yloh saw eH
”.yloh eb ot eunitnoc lliw I
.tuyL fo taht detpecca I sa tsuj noitatiga reh tpecca I
.lufhtiaf ,thgirla si tahT“
.snaps rieht ni evah srossecederp sih fo yna naht yad tsap eht ni erom denrael sah eh rof
,dna evac sih ot gninruter erofeb ,roolf tserof eht no sumuh dna sevael eht dna sdoow eht fo thgis eht
.siht sredisnoc eh sa snworf tuyL
”.tnavres riehT si wýT taht eveileb I dna siht tuoba gnÝ ot deyarp evah I
,gnuoY saW dlroW ehT nehW
”.lufhtiaf ,eid ot gniog ton era uoY“ :daetsni gniyas
”?seye ruoy esolc uoy od yhw ,lufhtiaF“
,wonk I ,em htiw si eH
,owt ni ti tilps dna teksab eht morf ekac a pu kcip ot ylno hguoht ,seye reh streva yllanif atiZ
kciht dna nworb ruf ruoy ees I dna
gnÝ .os kniht ton od I ,oN“ .hgual I
,ti rof retteb emoceb dna nrael yam uoy taht os soahc wos ot dlrow eht ni elor ym si tI .ton si tI“
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb
.eb ot reh detcepxe dah eh gnihtyna ekilnu
.yad taht tey reyarp yna naht erom em sllif sihT
,tnavres riehT ma I dna drol ym era yehT rof
.gnÝ fo seye eht ni yloh ssel flesmih ekam ot dna
,efil ni eciojer dna evil ot
.lanogaid a morf mih hcaorppa ot gniraelc eht ssorca yawflah si ehs nehw edis eht ot secap wef a spets neht dna ,ylwols sevom ehS
”,gnineve tsomla si ti ,woN“
”?wýT ,won I ma tahW“
ygolohtna yrruf cirotsiherp eht ni derutaef seirots eht fo eno si gnieesnU
?mehT esiarp osla ton uoy od ,gniees ni tey dna
.rewop fo egnahcxe na si sgnieb gnivil yb nwos soahc ehT“ .eunitnoc I os
.egalliv eht fo ekas eht rof ti yortsed ot saw eil ot tub
,erofeb roloc fo nosirapmoc eht nwonk ton sah eH
”?sey ,gnihctaw fo dog eht era uoy taht yas uoY“
.gnitsaf fo emit eht fo gninnigeb eht ta erew uoy sa won yloh sa era uoy taht kniht I“
.yalc fo slufwap dna snref daehelddif sih srehtag eh sa tuyL htiw ma I
”.sdohtem lausu ym krow tonnac I ,mrof siht ni rof
,meht fo lla ton
,hturt llet ot deen eht dna
.setatidem rehsif eht sa sessap etunim wols A
.gnivael reh tpmeerp ot sa ylkciuq os seod eh tub ,elba si eh sa ylmlac sa skaeps eH
dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,lufhtiaf ,thgis ruoy ni ,neht ,eciojeR“
.kcalb ,yvan ,elprup ,knip yks eht sroloc gniraeppasid worra s’nus eht yaw eht ta srednow eH
.deidobme gnieb htiw emoc taht noitatlaxe eht dna rorret fo gnileef eht ni lever I
.mih nopu emoc sah maerd taerg a hguoht sa sklaw eh ,seod eh nehw dna ,gnivom nigeb ot wols si tuyL
.retaw eht fo ecafrus eht ffo stcelfer thgil eht taht yaw eht sehctaw eh dna ereht sdnats eH
”.retaw eht rednu ehtaerb ton od I ,oN“
.emit a rof mrof siht ekat lliw I dna flesym fo noitatsefinam etercnoc eht
,swehc dna ekac reh otni setib ehS
mih nopu emoc sah maerd taerg a hguoht sa sevom eH
,thgin dna yad neewteb ecnereffid eht llet — ton dluoc ro
.yad siht em desselb sah gnÝ ,atiZ“
.era yehT tahw si taht esuaceb redro sgnirb
.yltcerid rewsna ton od I ,niagA
,hctaw dna tnavres riehT dna drol eht morf trapa dnats I
.tnereffid syaw ynam ni tub
.maerts eht fo thgis eht fo peed knird seye sih dna
,skcor dnuora seidde retaw eht yaw eht ,oot ,sehctaW
,gnieb sih ,dnim sih fo
,mih fo retsam si s’gnÝ fo tnavres yreve taht
.ereht neeb syawla evah taht sgniht ni ssenwen eht fo skniht eH
,thgis uoy gnivig yb tca etercnoc a dettimmoc I esuaceb noitatsefinam etercnoc siht ma I
”?delbuort uoy era yhW .lufhtiaf
.yldniknu ton hguoht ,siht ta shgual tuyL
”.lufhtiaf ,sdog eht era os ,ta kool ot raed oot si nus eht sA“ .syas atiZ
.tsal ta syas eh ”,wýT“
.retaw eht otni spets dna sdon tuyL
,ehs sa llew sa daerb fo sevaol talf eht dna teksab eht ees nac eh taht gnirebmemer erofeb doof sih rehtag tuyL pleh ot sevom dna sdon atiZ
.ylteiuq dna ylkciuq syas ehs
,tuyL erofeb flesreh setartsorp dna seenk reh ot sllaf ehs ,sdnatsrednu atiZ nehW
,kcalb fo elcric a gnidnuorrus nworb fo gnir a fo edam eb ot mees dna ,krad dna dnuor era yehT
.gnimoc ni emit gnol a si rewsna siH
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM yb ”gnieesnU“
,yloh era uoy dna dog a era uoy fI“