.ecnalg a reh tohs arbeD
eht ekil ,esle erehwemos tsac si ecnartne eht spahrep rO
.mlaer ruo ot gninruter si cigam taht ngis a eb dluoc siht ,ytivitca larutanrepus ni esaercni eht htiW
.meht fo tnorf ni revoh koob eht tel dna
,retnec eht morf denepo dna denettalf erehps eht
”!lla su mood uoy erofeb latrop eht esolC“
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,derevoh erehps thgirb a ,retnec eht nI
.hguorht knuks eht gniwollof ,deggurhs ecnaL
,ecnatpecca ni dehgis nhoJ
sredluohs rieht debbarg ecnaL
,kcen reh dnuora ecalkcen a depsalc ehS
”citsyM nabrU“    :yojne esaelP
.tsom naht retteb tol a erutan yecaps ym htiw pu tup ylniatrec syug uoY
”…neht sneppah tahw rettam on oS“
.koob sih dettap dna dennirg nhoJ
.ria thgin looc eht otni
hsilop tsal eno selcatceps sih evag eH
,seinomitset ruo dna esoht neewteB
.tlucco eht dna ytivitca lamronarap fo srettam gnildnah htiw degrahc
,ecneserp regnorts ,regral a fo taht dnuora tohsgnils ot sarua ruo stfihS .ssapyb arua nA“
”?yawyna ,og ot desoppus lennut siht si raf woh tsuJ“
meht dniheb deohce sraoR
”?emot lleps eritne na thguorb uoY“
,htraE fo dnuorg dloc eht tih yeht sa noos sA
,meht dnuora lla deraeppa skcarc dna
”!em dniheb teg ,sixelA ,ecnaL  …krow thgim sihT“
.noitcudni yranimilerp ruoy erutseg siht redisnoC“
,slleps htiw meht til dna snug enihcambus tuo deppihw
”.eramthgin taht hguorht og ot evah reve lliw esle ydobon erusne ot gnikrow er’ew ,kniht tsuJ
.yrellag sih ni krowtra dna seirots htob gniwohs
.daeha thgil tniaf a was yeht ,yllaniF
.sdrawkcab gnineerac tnew eh sa dnuorg eht ni hcnert a devrac ydob sih tsaf os kcab mih gniworht
.regnad ni erom tup ylno dluow lained dna
rebmahc evisnapxe na otni pu denepo lennut ehT
.delims dna koob eht deppartser nhoJ
.sraey neve ylbissop
.stops thgir eht ni gnidnats elpoep hguone evah uoy nehw reisae slautir gninommus sekaM“
.yruf ni gnilrans ,teef rieht ot dellor dna
,kcab deppilf ecnaL
.drows sih htiw sbolg dica gnitcelfed
.gnol rof surebreC tsniaga tsal t’now sihT“
.selcatceps sih ot snel eulb a dexif dah nhoJ ,meht dniheB
.revoc kcab renni eht ot denepo dna
.gninrom siht reilrae nwo ym fo hcraeser fo tib a did I“
,sixelA dias ”,epoN“
.aera nehctik eht ni reh dniheb tnemevom ta deleviws srae tibbar reh
”?rehtie ,peels t’naC“ .dennirg ecnaL
.llaw fo noitrop til a revo swap reh devaw arbeD .retaw gnituops
.gninepo s’latrop eht denekrad erugif kcalb a dna
”…dlrowrednU eht ot emocleW“
.hguone llew gnola teg od eW“
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.tnahc teiuq a gnirettum
.elffucs suoiverp eht fo sdnuos eht yb detcartta
,noitaicnunorp tcerroc eht kcehcer ot desuap
.gnilims ,xis eht dnuora derehtag srehto eht dna leumaS .yawa dedaf dna
”.emot ym ni evah I slleps eht wonk yeht tbuod I“
,seitiliba rieht ni tnedifnoC
,shtnom rof niaga teg ton lliw ew ytinutroppo na—
.eninac dedaeh-eerht citnagig eht ssap ot elbanu
.siht od ew yhw fo rednimer tcefrep a …taht ta kooL“
sevlesmeht gniraperp era dna
”.nwod su tel t’noD .redaer dniM“
drah dednal nhoJ
,snosiop revetahw htiw dellif erew stekcop sih derusne ecnaL ,tinu rehtona nI
,segnellahc hguot fo ytnelp neeb evah erehT“ .deddon nhoJ
.latrop eht gnikcolb mrof eguh sti
,yaw rieht ni doots taht gnihtyna ta dehsals ecnaL ,tnorf nI
”.no rehtruf ecafrus eht ot yaw rehtona s’ereht yltnerappa os ,gnihtaerb llits er’ew ,lleW“
.sllaberif werht ecnaL dna ffats reh morf gninthgil decra sixelA elihw
,ogacihC fo enilyks til-ylthgirb eht gnieeS
.erehT“ ,detniop neht
niaga mlaer nwo sih fo ria eht ni dehtaerb nhoJ
,lehctas eht ot deddon eH ”.kcor
s’ereht tub ,seitreporp lacitsym rof aera eht gnitset saw enoemos gnitacidni slobmys cisab wef a ees I
,sserts s’enoyreve fo etips nI ”.uoy hcaet ll’I
.derif dna nups neht ,senur ni mra dna lotsip sih gnirevoc
.pu denael sixelA
.nhoJ ot devaw reed ehT
,eb thgim yeht dlrowrednU eht ni erehw
”?thgin worromot dnA“
,yrroS“ ,dias eh ”…hO“
”?aroruA gnimoceb er’ew naem siht seod …oS“
,slleps gnitarebrever dna erifnug fo sdnuos eht revO
.esroh a ,noinapmoc a ot delangis eh
.skcart rieht ni deppots
sixelA dna nhoJ ees ot emit ni tsuj tsalb rehtona morf yawa evod eH ”!t’nod
,delrihw dna pu tohs ehS
”.noisivid lamronarap a evah yeht esruoc fO
,skeirhs yna raeh t’nod I“ .delims sixelA
,deunitnoc eh sa latrop eht fo tnorf ni
”.setunim neves rof ecnart a ni ereh gnidnats erew eW .sisonpyH“
”!evael ton lliw uoY“ ,gniraor
.epat ecilop dna sreirrab drazah yb ffo dekcolb yletelpmoc erew skcart eht ,edistuO
,nihtiw era yeht fI .dlrowrednU eht sevael eno on dna
.latrop eht morf tuo dils snomed erom elihw redluob a dniheb meht gnicrof
,raen werd snomed erom sa
.snopaew rieht gniward elihw teiuq niamer ot gniyrt
detcartsid erutaerc eht gnipeek
”.deraperp eb os noos su tceted lliw surebreC
.enohp sih ta gnikool ,deknilb nhoJ
.afos eht ot txen roolf eht no nwod tas dna revo deklaw terref ehT ”.wonk uoy
.enohp reh no kcolc eht ta gnikool
,teef reh ot dereggats sixelA
.gnidliub eht edistuo tsuj niatnuof eht ta reh rof gnitiaw ydaerla ecnaL dna nhoJ dnif ot detixe ehS
.elyts tabmoc lacitsym ruoy gniredisnoc
.derettum ehs ”…ydaer ton er’eW“
lennut eht detixe oirt ehT .nhoJ dias
swap sih devaw raeb ehT ”!yrruh tsum eW“
”.ti rof dezingocer gnieb naht retteb si taht morf meht gnitcetorp sseug I .hguone eurT“
,suomrone na gnithgil
”?rof gnikool er’ew lennut neddih
”.ti ssapyb ot yaw a eb thgim erehT
.slennut eht otni
,peels fo kcal s’oirt eht fo etips nI
.tnempiuqe eht lla ta gnikool
”…deniur tsuj lla uoy tahw aedi on evah uoY“
.gnidaf si evac siht gniniatsus ygrene ehT“
.kcab snomed eht gnivird
,stekcop sti fo eno otni ffats detcarter reh dils dna
.htuom sih ni doolb detsat eH
”.etal oot ton er’ew yllufepoh os
,swalc s’surebreC ta hsals ot ni gnitnirps snrut koot bocaJ dna ecnaL ,koob eht demmiks ylhsirevef nhoJ sA
,yako haey …lleW !yeH“
”.taht od t’ndluoc stnega eht yhw rednow ,mmH“ ”.ytivarg
?neht ,noitatidem emos tuoba woh ,ereH“
.oot ,ma I“ ,dedda sixelA
.tuo kcab meht llup dna
,snmuloc eht dehsams dna latrop eht hguorht degrahc surebreC
”.nepo syats ti erus ekam
.hguoht ,seirevocsid ruo ni trap lauqe na dah yehT
depraw taht serehps dleihs gninommus
.tsalb taht retfa sdleihs erom tsac ot anam eht dekcal ehs wenk ehS
,tuo dehcaer tsif citnagig a dna dehsinav semalF
”.ydnah ni semoc gniht siht uoy dloT“
.laes ralucitrap taht ezingocer I kniht I“
.sllaw nrevac eht gnitaroced senur gniwolg fo snezod htiw
enog stnega eht gnidnif
,noitatnacni kciuq a ekops dna
”.ti esu annog ton er’yeht fi ti ekam ot
.nar yeht sa senur lleps gnivaew
.delkcuhc drahciR
”.eguH“ .dias ehs ”,seY“
”…nuf eb annog ton si sihT“
,ecnartne na ot ti gnitcennoc neve tuohtiw ereh ti tsac enoemoS
hguone egral latrop a wolla ot hguone serutcarf eht denekaew
.ppa na otni gnippat ,enohptrams sih tuo dellup dna seye sih dellor ohw
,degreme erutaerc eht fo tser ehT
.ton esruoc fo ,oN-
.dekniw dna daeh sih deppat tab ehT
.ti niatniam ot snoitatnacni gnitnahc
”?lennut neddih eht ot sdael eseht fo eno hcihW
.dnuora dekool dna teef sih ot tog nhoJ
,dehctamtuo hguohT
.redluohs s’nhoJ no wap a tup ecnaL
stleb sih fo eno otni sdiulf ecnessetniuq derolocitlum
,ytic eht otni kcab yaw rieht edam sdneirf eerht ehT
.dezad ,kcab dellor dna
.ecnatsid eht ni latrop eht ot kcab decnalg ylsuovren ecnaL
”!gnitiaw ereht era stnega esoht epoh tsuj s’teL
revo dehsur serugif eerht ,despalloc ti sA
meht dnuora dewolg senur nekorb eroM
.stnadnep eht no slobmys eht was eh sa
”.taht htiw evil nac I“ .delims sixelA
.ot deen ew naht regnol yna ereh eb ot tnaw t’nod I
”.lennut neddih eht ot teg ot aera siht desu s’enoemoS
.slleps wen dnif ll’uoY“
,daeh reh detlit sixelA
noitatnacni lanif eht daer nhoJ
”…hguoht ,dlrowrednU eht ni emot ym tsol I“ .dehgis nhoJ
”.pu ekaw nac uoy erofeb uoy ssik ot sah ytlayor retaerg ro lauqe fo enoemos ro ecnirp a taht noitalupits a eb thgim ereht ,sediseB
”?sknar ruoy gninioj fo demaerd ev’I gnol woh ezilaer uoy oD  …laernu si sihT“
.scitsym eht drawot latrop eht morf tuo degrahc tsaeb degniw ,gnikeirhs A
.decamirg nhoJ .enog
,ekops yllanif nhoJ
,gninthgil teloiv fo evaw a htiw detsalb eb ot ylno
.niaga ecno yraw emaceb oirt eht ,ecafrus eht morf yawa rehtruf gnitteg erew yeht tcaf eht dna aibohportsualc eht neewteB
,kcab detuohs leumaS
”,won rof pleh lliw sihT“
.emot lleps sih deppartsnu dna snel eulb eht dewots nhoJ
.tneve espilce ro temoc a htiw tlaed reven ev’eW“ .delims sixelA
.ssensselepoh dna htaed fo erutcip a detniap epacsdnal kaelb eht ,mih dnuora llA
”.tsael ta ,sesolc latrop taht retfa gnol litnu toN
ygrene rieht gnisu elbuort eht lla hguorht og dluow enoemos yhw onnud I
”.selcycrotom emos ni tsevni dluohs ew ebyam neht
,srehto eht laeh ot
nug sih dedaoler leumaS
,llaw dna roolf eht fo strap suoirav no
kcab gniylf oirt eht gnidnes
.noos ecalp gnikat eb dluow
.latrop eht gnissap erofeb deraeppaer tub
.nirg llams a dewohs neht
.ehtaerb ot meht gniwolla
”?pohs s’rehctub a otni nekorb dah taht spmi tnepres fo riap a nwod esahc ot deirt ew nehW
,hsalf thgirb a htiW
.ecaf reh debbur dna kcab yal sixelA
.scitsym eht ta kcab derats seye der-gniwolg htiw sdaeh eninac gnilwocs eerht dna
.ytic rieht gnitcetorp morf meht pots tbuod tel ot desufer yeht dna
”.mlaer ym ni ssenisub on ev’uoY
,suileA yb ”citsyM nabrU“
”!og s’teL .nocaeb a s’tI
”.niaga gnineppah morf siht tneverp yllufepoH
sgnieb erew ereht taht erawa llew saw ehS
”?yawyna ,ereh ew era yhw ,yeH
,gnidnatsrednu reh dnoyeb yllatot secalp dna
.meht detpurretni skeirhs yldlrowrehtO
”.yaw eht yb ,nhoJ s’emaN“
.tenalPruF yb 8 RAOR dna
.sselesu yletelpmoc s’ti won thgir os
.ni knas thguoht eht sa tnelis doots oirt ehT
.rood a gninepo ,detrap skcor eht dna
,desolc ti deruces dna
.ediw dennirg nhoJ
”.eb reve ll’I sA“ ”?ydaeR“
.sixelA dias ”,spuorg ni levart ot nwonk era stsitlucco ,lleW“
,drows sih gnihtaehs nopU
.daeh sih koohs raeb ehT
.msicitsym fo ega wen a dlareh ot gnipleh seno eht eb ll’ew ebyaM“ .sixelA dias
meht dniheb yawrood eht ees ot denrut selam owt ehT
delbmut stsaeb ehT ”…krow esaelP“
”!decarbme ,cigam dna ygolonhceT
.tab a dna ,reed a ,raeb a—
,tiaW …uoy did woH“
”!noitacided tog ev’uoy yas d’I
.redluohs s’nhoJ no wap a tup ecnaL
dna regnuoy saw I nehW“
.tixe eht s’taht tub ,seY“
.wap thgir reh dnuora niahc revlis ynit a depparw ylluferac neht
.arbeD ta dekool eH
.desolc latrop eht erofeb gnipacse morf meht deppots ohw
”!tuo yaw a evah eW
,pu kcab ekops nhoJ neht
”.sesod egral ni cixot si ereh ria ehT“ .detnap ehs
tixe lennut yawbus eht dehcaer yeht emit eht yb dessergorp llew dah gninevE * * * ”.siht od s’teL“
”.pleh thgim siht“ ,leumaS dias
”.seikoor llits er’ew tub
…haeY“ .deddon nhoJ
.renilcer nrow a no nwod deppolp dna revo deklaw knuks ehT
.redluohs sti fo trap dna ecaf sti ffo gniraet
,ropav gniwolg fo aes tsav a ot yaw evag sgarc ykcor ,ecnatsid eht nI
.mra s’ecnaL no wap a tup sixelA
.deddon htob ecnaL dna sixelA
.tuo yaw a rof gnihcraes elihw detcelloc ew sgniht
,neht ,tnemom a rof tnelis saw ecnaL
”.niaga spets esoht nommus ot ydaer teG“
,tey dlrow neddih a ni eveileb ot ydaer t’nera ereht tuo elpoep ynam os tcaf eht redisnoc attog uoy hguoht ,hguot s’tI .naem uoy tahw dnatsrednu I tuB
gnissap s’temoc sihT
.ytpme aera eht dnuof yeht ,devirra yeht nehW
”.etaf ruo eb lliw sneppah revetahw dna …sucoF“
noisrucni nomed a fo tnorferof eht ta sevlesmeht dnuof sixelA dna ,ecnaL ,nhoJ ,emit tsaL
.redluohs sih dezeeuqs ecnaL
.senil yel denekaew yb serutcarf yduts ot yojevoL temoC fo gnissap eht desu noisivid ruo morf maet a ,raey tsaL
…senur aroruA era esohT“
.der peed ot yks eht demmid tesnuS
,drawrof kcuns oirt eht dna
.srellewd htraE ,ecalp siht evaeL“
stsitlucco ehT .spmi tnepres—
”!suoires eb t’nac uoY“
,erab yletelpmoc saw dnuorg ehT
,decneirepxe er’eW
.gnitnemirepxe neeb sah enoemos …thgir     erew uoY“
mih tsap depael sixelA
,ylwols meht gnitatoR
”.eromyna dnuora gniht gib taht gul ot evah t’now uoy tsael tA
.erehps dleihs a pu dessot tibbar ehT ”!em revoc ,sixelA“
,erehps eht dednuorrus serugif dedooh eviF
”.I.B.F eht fo noisivid ygolohcysparap dna tlucco eht sa stsixe redro aroruA eht fo mra .S.U ehT“
.tsehc reh revo delgnad lobmys hkna na hcihw morf
.deppord waj s’leumaS ”!yrruH
nhoJ ot revo detnirps eram ehT ”!mih wohS !arbeD“
,ti drawot deppets serugif eht fo enO
.krad deniamer dlrowrednU eht ot etag eht delaes dah nhoJ erehw roolf eht fo noitrop eht hguoht
.deilper nhoJ ”!moolrieH“
.elcric detaroced
”.deretnuocne ev’ew taht ega rieht ydobyna naht erom hcuM
.denibmoc neht dna
”!depleh ew dnA .lla ta gnineppah saw lautir a tuo erugif did ew tuB
”!tey tsac t’nsaw ecnartne ehT
,etercnoc eht revo detingi senuR
llaw eht no detingi selcric detaroceD
”.htiw gnola teg dluoc ecnaL esle eno on s’ereht erus m’I dnA
.ecnartne s’toped egarots eht ta nhoJ teem ot detixe dna kcab sih ot ti depparts eh
.ediw delims nhoJ
.tip yreif eht morf esor sepahs egral owt ,daehA
.erofeb ereh tsac slaes lacitsym fo sngis era erehT
.kcab dekool dna deppots sixelA
,yawllah eht morf tuo gnireep nhoJ ees ot denrut neht owt ehT ”.oot ,ma I“
?ecnartne eht gnikam erofeb detpurretni saw ti tsac reveohw ebyaM“
.elims tub pleh t’ndluoc nhoJ
.lotsip rehtea s’nhoJ ta kool tsuj
.slobmys eht lla ta dnuora decnalg ecnaL
.kcor netlom dniheb tfel ti erofeb yaw eht fo tuo detrad scitsym ehT
.rehtona eno ta snug rieht demia redael eht dna nhoJ
.tuo detrups sresyeg gnimalf erom erehw
”?ew t’ndid ,ekatsim elbirroh a edam tsuj eW“
.deknilb terref ehT
drawkcab gniraos meht tnes taht evawkcohs lufrewop a dehsaelnu sixelA neht
,gniwolg fo slaiv dellif-ylwen dils nhoJ
stcA namuhnI ni ,eciwt dehsilbup neeb osla sah eH
.dehgis neht ,detatiseh eH
wonk ew gnihtyreve gnizilitu yb hguorht llup t’ndid ew erehw ni neeb ev’ew ecnatsmucric yna enigami t’nac I
.nwo ym s’ti yllautcA“
.taht rof t’nerew ti fi ereh eb dluow ew yaw on s’ereht …si hturT“
.ti dnuora gnirevoh slobmys dekips htiw ngised lacitpille na gniwohs ,demrof wolg a dna
”?meht tsurt nac uoy erus uoY“ .denworf ecnaL
emot lleps sih debbarg knuks ehT
taoc reh denetsaf sixelA
.kcor fo seceip dna srebme htiw gnola
latrop eht fo semalf eht morf tuo detrad swodahS
.ffats reh tuo dleh dna
.ecnaL dias ”,rehtie ,spart oN“
.secalkcen owt lakcaj eht dednah neht eH
.epacsdnal eht evoba hgih ti gnilgnad
.sevil rieht fo thgif eht rof
.lotsip rehtea sih deretsloh dna
”.sevil ruo fo thgif eht rof pu raeg neht ,smaxe ruo hsinif eW
.me’ tsurt t’nod I“
.gnoleb t’nseod taht teb ll’I“
.sruoh erem ni meht ecaf dluoc sdneirf reh dna ehs dna
,gnippird htiw tuo dehsal dna latrop eht morf tsrub erugif regral A
.ti did eW“ .delims dna
”!mlaer siht otni snoitanimoba erom yna gnirb uoy tel t’now eW
”…gnihtemos ro sdraug emos noitats dluow yeht kniht d’uoY“
,emanresu emas eht rednu ytiniffAruF ta dnuof eb nac ohw
”.ogacihC ot emocleW“
mih denioj serugif rehto owT
.daeh reh koohs sixelA
”.lleps gnorw eht gniworht ot eud erif no kcolb eritne na tes ylraen ew tub ,epacse spmi eht did ylno toN
.pu denael dna niaga seye sih dellor ecnaL
.flesreh mlac ot htaerb a tuo tel dna
,srewop lacitsym htiw stsitluc gnicaf fo elbapac seno ylno eht er’yeht wonk yeht
.noitatnacni kciuq a gnitnahc ,daeherof sih debbarg dna
”.ereh morf lennut nwonknu na ot detcennoc ylevitca enoemos taht noitacidni on
”?tiaw ot evah ew od gnol woH“
,tinu egarots sih ta gnivirra nopU
pu nhoJ depleh sixelA
.scitsym wollef rieht yb dednuorrus sevlesmeht dnuof stnega deucser eerht ehT
,deknilb sixelA dna ,ecnaL ,nhoJ
dedaf laes eht erofeb tsuj
kert rieht rof eraperp ot meht gnieerf
.eloh eht ni dellif etercnoc dna
”!dlrow ruo morf era yehT !ereht deppart era ohw seilla ruo eucser ot emoc ylno ev’eW“
,dnim sih otni gnidoolf eciov cihtapelet s’eram eht deinapmocca segami sa ezorf nhoJ
,dlrow siht ni tuo esle gnihtemos s’ereht gnikniht trats dna me’ ees thgim elpoep os tsuj og spmi wef a gnittel
,nwod depael sixelA dna ,ecnaL
deen eW“ .dnuora elcric ot deirt bocaJ
.tnatsni elgnis a ni lla ,gniod erew stsitlucco demuserp eht tahw
.gninnirg ,ecnaL dias ”,seY“
sixelA dna ,ecnaL ,nhoJ htiw nioj ot dehsur neht
retne nac ew erehw noitacol elbissop a no ni deorez yllanif evah ew won dna
lennut yawbus eht fo roolf deniur eht otno delbmut yehT
!yletaidemmi lautir siht potS“ ,detuohs nhoJ
”?feileb aroruA na taht sI“
,dedeen erew sredwop ro ,snoitop
”…tsrif peels ot teg nac ew dedivorP“
.edis hcae ta esoht ot gnitniop
.detuohs ehs ”!won ti od ,gninnalp er’uoy revetahW“
,nrow sih dennod dna
.egdod ot mih decrof tsalb rehtonA
bocaJ dna leumaS
.deraeppasid oirt eht dna
.mrof sti revo lla pu til senur deR
”??laes eht was uoY“
.sllaberif gniraes dna slleps degrahc htiw kcab nomed eht gnittih
”.yrevarb rieht rof derebmemer eb ot evresed yeht dnA“
,elcsum gniglub derevoc niks kcalB
.stsalb gninthgil s’tab eht yb dedia
tab eht dna arbeD
.dedaf elims s’leumaS
.reh denethgirf ti dna ,ecaf thgim yeht tahw rednow ylno dluoc ehs
.snroht daed gnilarips fo hctap lanoisacco na rof evas
”?krow tropelet taht ekam ot od uoy did tahW“
”.thgin rehto yna ekil tsuJ“
.latrop eht rof tnirps a no
.thgin tsal nomed cidica eht
.daeh reh koohs sixelA
,tiaW“ .gniod saw werc s’nhoJ tahw gniciton
.ereht dna ereh skcarc morf tuo dehsug erif fo semulP
.ecalp tsrif eht ni tsac ecnartne na reven saw ereht snaem hcihw
”?ydaerla tuo me’ koot ereht ni s’reveohw fi tahW
.evael ot eraperp ot srehto eht detcerid leumaS
.werc sih dna sivaD leumaS tnega htiw ereh er’ew ,oN“
.ffats reh no gninael
,txet eht denimaxe dna segap wef a deppilf eH
,eciov gnitarebrever ,peed a gnilworg
.stleb sih otni sgat lleps dellor dna ,sevink
.rof eraperp dluoc yeht tahw naht ereht tuo erom hcum os saw ereht wenk ehs
.emot sih tuo dellup nhoJ
.dehgual nhoJ ”…no emoc ,hO“
,leumaS ot deddon drahciR
.rewop si egdelwonk woh gnitartsnomeD“
.ot ton yrt I“ .denaorg ecnaL
,noisivid lamronarap s’IBF eht yb nrow sebor detaroced eht ecno ,gnihtolc riehT
.deddon yllaciots ecnaL
.thgil ynit s’egdirf eht yb pu til mrof s’ecnaL dnif ot ylno
.hguoht ,gnol taht evil ot evah ll’ew tsriF .ebyaM“
?thgin tsrif ruo rebmemeR“
.tnecer yletinifed si siht ,peY“ .deddon ehS
.delims dna htaerb rehtona koot nhoJ
lautir tlucco krad a taht ecnedive derevocsid yeht
.taocgnol rehtael dlo sih no dellup dna tleb rehtona ot ti gnuls neht
.thgil edivorp ot mlap sih ni llaberif a til ecnaL ”.stops
decarbme yllufraet
,elcric eht morf gnissim era dedeen sngised eht flaH“
.meht dniheb nwod gnihsarc
.wollof ot meht rof denoitom nhoJ
.worbeye na detfil ecnaL
”.ti ot pu nwo ot deirt I nehw em deveileb reve eno on tub ,emit eht ta noitacav no saw ehs ylikcuL
.denediw seye s’reed ehT .gnizilibatsed
.smaerd rieht ni regnil ot deunitnoc ecaf yam yeht tahw revo raef
.tsrif ta wonk t’ndid eW“
tsuj …sselesu saw ti dias reven I“
.dennirg sixelA ”.maet a er’eW
.laes tixe eht was ylno ew yhw s’taht oS“ .dennirg sixelA
,regnol elttil a rof tnelis saw moor ehT
.erom tib a dlrowrednU eht htiw sevlesruo ezirailimaf nac ew kniht I
”.og ot syaw a tog ev’ew os ,retaw eht revo tniop a ta ssorc senil yel ehT
.enohp nwo s’nhoJ no degnip egassem a dna
.desare stnecs rieht dna
,neppah taht tel I fi truh teg dluoc elpoep niaga neht tub
,rellams hguorht snocaeb gnidnes neeb evah eW
.daeh sih dehctarcs nhoJ
.ereh llits er’ew tub ,snoitautis lahtel dna ,separcs esolc
.ti evorp ot hguone ysae saw lleps gnitceted-eil a gnitsaC“
”,ssenihtrow rof degduj gnieb er’eW“ .ecnaL dias
”.tsom eht ta oga sruoh wef a tsac ylbaborP
meht fo daeha pu esor srallip enots neht
,surebreC fo taht ekil arua lufrewop a tsniaga semusnoc ssapyb taht anam eht ot eud hguohT
”?emoh ecalp siht llac reve dluow gnieb fo tros tahW“
.esolc gniwollof sdneirf sih htiw surebreC drawot dehsad nhoJ dna
”…won erofeb snomed ypmiw emos gnicaf neeb ev’tsum ew kniht I
,meht fo lla rof gnignahc-efil eb ot niatrec saw worromoT
sdnah s’bocaJ dnuora detingi swalc gniwolg eguH
…morf nekahs llits tsuJ .thgir lla s’tI  …oN“
,dewolg spit s’ffats eht sa drawrof dehsur snomed ehT
.tcatnoc nopu deziropav dna ti delian nomed ehT
,llaw fo snoitces suoirav ta gnikool ,detniuqs eH
”?nug taht teg uoy did erehW“
redisnoc tsomla d’I
”…flesti laeser ot ti tcepxe t’ndid I“
”?drahciR ,owt rehto eht era erehW“
,swap reh devaw dna kcab deppets ehS ”.ereH“
deppord dleihs ehT
gniniamer dah ehs anam tahw desu sixelA
”?su tsurt yllautca uoY !sknaht …woW“
”.stnelat lacitsym ruo derevocsid ew erofeb neve rehto hcae nwonk ev’eW
”…emityna em ffo teg ot eerf leef ,haeY“
.noos aroruA eht morf tisiv a tcepxe dluoc yeht gniwonk
arbeD dnif ot ssensuoicsnoc otni kcab deppans nhoJ
”.meht tsniaga krow thgim tahw wonk I kniht I
”…noissim eucser a egatobas ylraen dna tpurretni did uoY
.gnol taht tiaw ton s’teL“ .deredduhs suxelA
.dlrowrednU eht fo tuo dna pu dehsur scitsym xis eht dna denruter snmuloc enots ehT ”!oG !woN“
.ycarucca tcefrep htiw sreusrup gnilian
”!sespalloc ti erofeb og attog eW
.seye sih dellor ecnaL ”?ynitseD
.erus os ton m’I“ .dennirg bocaJ
”…su gnisahc deppots evah snomed ehT“ .deknilb nhoJ
.erom ro owt ylbaborp ,elim a tsael tA“
.meht fo enoN“ .denworf sixelA
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.edalb drows sih dnuora thgil fo sevaw tsac dna elbmut a otni flesmih dediug ecnaL
,enil nekorb a ekops eh
”.ngised yawetag a s’tI ?taht tuoba tahW“
,noitagitsevnI fo uaeruB laredeF eht fo srebmem era eW
.wodniw eht tuo spmalteerts eht morf gnitcelfer seye sih
”!devivrus dna dlrowrednu eht ot tnew yllautca eW
.esu cigam eugor rof ni su gnirb ro snopaew ruo etacsifnoc t’ndid yeht tub ,taht ylno toN
,secnalg dedart stnega eerht ehT
.nihc sih debbur ecnaL
.htap rieht gnikcolb snomed eht yawa dehsals eh dna
.derrucco tnedicni s’yadretsey erehw morf
.deppord waj s’nhoJ
aera eht revo swap reh dennap sixelA
.evila rehto hcae peek ot
,meht ta bolg a gnulf dna deraor nomed ylio ehT
.od ot tnaem er’ew tahw od eW“ ,derewsna nhoJ
,sdaeh s’surebreC ta gnirif deppots leumaS
”.serugif elpitlum …sliart tnecS“
,depraw daeha latrop ehT
”!su tsurt yeht snaem tahT
”,yaw siht ti ta kooL“
deraeppasid llaberif s’terref ehT ”…emalf taht esuoD“
,nekiruhs elpitlum detresni eH
”.tamrof emas eht ni era seriomirg ruO .koobe na sA“
?dlrow ruo otni kcab ti edam yeht nehw stnega esoht fo selims deveiler eht ees uoy did tub
detloj nrevac ehT
decaf yeht erehw tops eht ot gnimoc litnu sliar eht edisgnola gniyrruh
.lennut yawbus eht ni decaf dah yeht nomed cidica fo epyt emas ehT
fo selpmas wef a era erehT“
.sregnif sih deppans eH ”.noos uoy gnitcatnoc eb ll’ew dna ,launam taht no pu ydutS
.ylisaenu dehgis knuks ehT
”.niamer llahs yeht neht
,mrod ’sdneirf reh ni hcuoc eht no yal ehs sA
,lleps kciuq a detuohs knuks ehT
.degnul dna revoc revo dednuob nomed rellams A .ecniw a gnicrof
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,yad txen eht hguorht retsemes eht rof smaxe tsal rieht etelpmoc ot deganam yeht
.ssecorp eht ni animats rieht gnitsoob
drawrof dehsur bocaJ
,swap rieht tuo gnulf sixelA dna arbeD
,daerps dna dehcated ti dniheb skcolb etercnoc eht neht
fo strap 2 fo dn2 eht eht saw sihT
.roolf s’nrevac eht gnidnuop
sti htiw dnuora temoc a worht nac rats a woh ekil adnik
,neeb evah yam ereht yks revetahw derucsbo ekoms kcalb ,evoba hgiH
”.raf suht sretnuocne ruo fo tsom devivrus ylerab tsuj ev’eW
”!su kcolb lliw arua s’god tnaig taht esiwrehtO .hguorht tropelet ot thgis fo enil raelc a
koob sih tuo dellup nhoJ
.seiromem ruo esare t’ndid yehT“
.temoc a fo gnissap eht yb no thguorb
.gnihtyna rof ydaer tlef yeht
.gnola siht yrrac ot nosaer erom eht llA“
.neercs sti no senur fo seires a deyalpsid hcihw ,enohptrams nwo reh pu dleh dna dennirg arbeD
,nepo tsrub dnuorg ehT
,ruoh sselpeels rehtona retfA
,seye reh gnirevoc morf sgnab reh gnipeek
.gnipeels elbuort gnivah ew era won ylno ,raf os evah ew lla gnicaf retfa ,woh ddo ti dnif I .epoN“
”.yawetag delaes-yltnecer A
…noisivid lamronarap a sah .I.B.F ehT“
,rethgirb dewolg laes ehT .detnahc neht
.ti ekam t’ndid yehT“
.tsael ta ,ecalp thgir eht ni er’ew suoivbo s’ti ,lleW“
.deppots neht ehS .gnihctiwt eson
”,su gnihctaw er’yeht tuB“
.dnuorg eht otni ffats reh demmaj dna
.gninthgil gnicra
”?…gniod uoy era tahW“
.taht ta seno denommus-ylitsah dna
fo 2 traP ,suileA yb
,raeg lluf ni elihw tropsnart cilbup diova ot gniog er’ew fI“
.stnega deppart eht eucser ot noissim eht gninifed ,dnim sih ni tsac arbeD noisiv eht meht ot denialpxe nhoJ ,nar yeht sA
,cigam krad morf dlrow rieht tcetorp ot yenruoj rieht nageb yeht nehw tsniaga thguof dah yeht tahw fo etips nI
.llaw eht no elcric gniwolg tnaig eht ot denoitom nhoJ
”,nommoc oot si feilebsiD“
”!ega wen eht rof semot llepS“
”.egdelwonk cilbup ot nruter yllaudarg ot sah taht gniht fo tros eht si sihT
,ymils a delian skraps eulB
.hcraeser rehtag ot dlrowrednu eht deretne yeht dna
,sllaw dekcarc eht gnola wap a nar sixelA
”.thguoht ew naht retteb s’ti …yllautcA“
,dnabdaeh reh deruces tibbar ehT
.delevirhs dnuorg eht ot llef ti litnu
,owt uoY .setunim wef a ylno rof deniatsus siht peek nac ew ,yakO“
.kcohs ni meht ecaf ot delrihw stsitlucco ehT
,dehsiruonlam dna niht erew seidob riehT
…emit siht tub ,stseuq ruo ni swal yna kaerb ot ton dettimmoc er’ew wonk I“
,nomed gniyfirret a htiw retnuocne na gnivivrus ylerab retfA
,no dna no dehcterts lennut worran ehT
.mih rednu detfihs ecnaL
sevlesruo retne ot
.tnacav si aera eritne sihT“
.nees ev’ew tahw morf ,detfig ytterp er’yehT“
.emoh s’rehtomdnarg ym pu welb yllatnedicca I ,slleps dna sexeh gninrael
.leumaS degdun arbeD
.gnivael erofeb mirb eht gnola regnif a gninnur
.latrop eht drawot dehsur anaugi dna lakcaj ehT ”!og s’tel ,bocaJ
.latrop eht ta detniop nhoJ
,ni yaw rieht edam scitsym eerht ehT
fo strap owt fo dnoces eht si yrots s’yadot dna
.htap eht gninepo
.lehctas dezisrevo ,dedaol a nwod tes raeb eht elihw
”.owt uoy htiw gnithgif dna tuo gnignah yojne od I .thgir er’uoy
tsehc eht ni surebreC kcurts koob ehT
denediw seye s’nhoJ
.gnitargetnisid ,kcab gniylf ti tnes dna nomed gnilioc
.em htiw er’uoy ,bocaJ ,arbeD“
,surebreC deretnuocne yeht ,yletanutrofnU
,mrod reh nI   ”.ecnaL ,sknaht
.ni tup ew krow eht segdelwonkca eno on taht gnitartsurf s’ti ,llew …tsuj I
.kcor erab dna erif tsuj naht erom raf si dlrowrednU ehT
.emit hcum evah t’nod eW“ .doots dna
tuo erugif dna yrt ot ecnis tneve laitselec yreve gnirud slatrop elbaniatsus ssel
.emirg dna toos ni derevoc
mra sih tuo dleh lakcaj ehT
”?kcab ti teg annog …uoy erA“ .dekwag sixelA
”.llaw kcirb a fo tnorf ni rood a gnittup ekil s’tI
,egrahc epahs enacra na ekil detanoted dna
,suileA yb ”citsyM nabrU“
eveileb ot gniyrt nehw suoregnad eb nac yeht dna ,nrobbuts era elpoeP
”,dettimmoc er’uoy ecniS“
.tnaig eht drawot dehcnup dna decamirg nhoJ
.nihtiw yal dlrowrednU hsilleh ehT .erif gnituops
.sixelA dias ”,gnihton s’tahT“
.gnihtolc dna ruf rieht morf gniliart semalf htiw
,pleh did seuqinhcet s’ecnaL
.lakcaj eht deilper ”,sivaD leumaS tnegA“
”.ecalp siht edih ot ytiliba rieht ni tnedifnoc yltnerappa erew yehT“
stneve laitselec eseht gnirud nepo decrof eb ylisae dluoc dlrowrednU eht ot latrop a taht derevocsid yehT
”.sreirrab esoht ssap ot evah ew kniht I
,lotsip rehtea sih htiw kcab derif dna delrihw nhoJ
”.rehto hcae htiw kcuts er’eW“
,revoc rieht dnoyeb serutaerc neesnu ta derif anaugi na dna lakcaj eht ,reh dniheB
,sbreh lanicidem
,meht dniheb llaw eht kcurts bolg rehtonA
”?yawyna ,su knaht ro su eveileb ot gniog s’eno on nehw siht gniod peek ew od yhW“ .ecnaL dias
”?lleps gnipeels oN“
.htaerb rof depsag dna dnuorg ykcor gnimaets eht tih sixelA dna ,ecnaL ,nhoJ
,tah demmirb-ediw
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.swodahs eht ni gnithgif kcuts m’I …os
esirprus ni delrihw tsaeb dnoces ehT
.noissim eucser a si sihT
,krow tseb ruoy od uoy erehw era swodahs ehT“ .delims nhoJ
,stsaeb eht fo eno delapmi dna
.snihs sih gnibbur ,deleenk nhoJ
”?llew sa ,ereh deppart eerht uoY“
.peels ot elbanu ,gniliec eht ta pu derats sixelA   2
.riahc eht ni detfihs nhoJ
.delevart yeht sa drawnwod gnilgna
.egassap rellams eht hguorht deklaw yeht sa eson sih detfil nhoJ ”.ydleiwnu
.llef srae s’sixelA
,dlrowrednU eht sretne eno oN“ ,delrans surebreC
,lleps kciuq a tsac sixelA
enohp eht dewots neht lakcaj eht ,tnemom a retfA
?spahrep ,pihsdneirf ot detaF“
,su eveileb ton thgim elpoep ,eruS
,cnys ni ekops sdaeh eerht s’surebreC
,tropelet ot gniyrt ,weiv fo tuo deppils dna
.dah reve ev’I sdneirf tseb eht era owt uoY
.ffo flesmih dehsurb ecnaL
.seye sih deworran ecnaL
yltcaxe mih gniwohs
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
!are ruo fo sroirraw lacitsym tsetaerg eht fo emos emoceb ot elba eb thgim ew ,su dlot yeht tahw retfA !gnizama si sihT
,meht ta degrahc surebreC sA ”.yllaretiL
,su eucser ot dlrowrednU eht otni emac uoy tcaf eht gniredisnoC“
dnuorg eht morf tohs ekips latem A
skcor htiw yawetag eht hguorht detlob enoyrevE
.ecnis reve dlrowrednU eht nihtiw deppart neeb evah yehT
.secalkcen lacitnedi nwo rieht tuo dellup neht
.nopaew sih derewol dna delwocs ,lakcaj a ,redael ehT
dehsalf latrop eht
”.rehtegot ,siht fo lla ,siht gniod er’ew dalg m’I
.niaga ti esu ot elba eb t’now ew
.ksam sih dekcehc neht
.deilper leumaS ”,slaunam ycilop ruo fo enO“ ”?siht si tahw
,secnalg dedart stnega rehto eht dna leumaS ”?…uoy erA
,ezorf scitsym xis ehT
.no deunitnoc ecnaL
,senur tnemniatnoc era esehT
.pu rehto hcae depleh enoyrevE ”…yrroS !hO“
.erif toh-etihw fo evaw a detsalb dna wap a tuo dleh surebreC ”…eht tahW“
,delrans knuks ehT
N“ ”…noitingocer rof siht gniod er’uoy em llet t’noD“ .decniw nhoJ
.dehsalf ylirgna gninthgil fo scra elihw
,moor gnivil eht ni rehtegot peels ot ffo tfird ot hguone demlac yllanif yeht sa hguoht
.esirprus ni revo decnalg lakcaj ehT
.sgar derettat ot decuder neeb dah
”?noitatropeleT“ .nhoJ dias ”…aohW“
.latrop eht niatniam srenommus owt rehto eht depleh arbeD elihw
.lleps ralucitrap a no deppots nhoJ
.latrop ot pu spets edivorp ot
.ybraen thgil eulb gniwolg a ta detniop nhoJ
”.peelsa erew uoy thguoht I
— ereht ydaerla si ynomrah ni evil nac ew taht ecnedive ehT
.mih ta kcab gnirats
.swap sih tuo dleh dna nwod koob eht tes neht
,nhoJ .selcatnet ylio
semalf eht hguorht deohce raor gnitnuah A
yrd ygrene sti gnippas ,retsnom eht dna mih neewteb desruoc gninthgil dna
.sknaht ni rehto hcae ot ylisaenu deddon eram dna tibbar ehT
”.decrof eb t’nac tI .sdnim rieht ni tes ev’yeht revetahw