.aredlaC enotswolleY eht
fo surohc a dna derettacs ylneddus snomed ,woleb nwoD
.hguorht debmuht yllacitnarf dna koob sih dehctalnu nhoJ
.dehcaorppa nhoJ .kcohs etum ni
.scitsym eerht eht denefaed
kcalb ni dehtolc terref a—
”!spmi tnepres er’yehT“
.enola eb ll’ew esruoc fO“ .dennirg ecnaL
,ezeerb looc eht gniyojne ssarg eht no tas sixelA dna ,ecnaL ,nhoJ
”?tcennoc ti seod tahW“
.ppa etilletas a pu dellup dna
htiw gnitcaretni temoc eht tsuj naht erom gnihtemos yletinifed s’ereht ,elbisiv siht si enil eht fi tub ,seY“
.daeha srac eht morf sgnalc duol yb dewollof ,denaorg lateM
gnidliub ytpme na fo foor eht ot debmilc serugif owT
.ti tnev ot edils eht dellup neht
.ygolonhcet gnithgiferif ni secnavda ot eud syadawon serif morf taerht a fo hcum ton s’ereht ,woN
”!ereh hguorht thgiarts gninnur eb tsum enil yel ehT
,detapissid neht wobssorc ehT
.erew yeht ,yaw a ni ,lleW
,eno eb lliw ereht dna ,lautir ehT
,ecnaL dias ”…tahW“ .deredliweb
,lautir a eb annog s’ereht fI
morf yaw eht lla sehcterts eno sihT
”!regnol elttil a no dloh tsuJ“
tleb sih morf diulf deroloc-der fo laiv a debbarg dna
* * * .ti no tca ot epoh hguone tsuj dna dnim ni nalp a
”.ereht tuo s’tahw ecaf ot era ylurt ew deraperp woh rednow em ekam ot gninnigeb si gniht temoc elohw sihT .I od roN“
.koob eht hguorht gnikool tpek knuks ehT ”!nhoJ“
.dlrowrednU eht ekil smlaer rehto morf mlaer lacol ruo dna htraE slaes taht krowten lacihpargoeg a fo trap era senil yel ,woN
seirevocsid dnuofwen rieht htiw epoc sixelA dna ,ecnaL ,nhoJ woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.noisolpxe sag larutan cihportsatac a demeed neeb dah tnedicni ehT
,tnedicni eht gnirevoc gnihton saw erehT
.delkcuhc dna selcatceps sih ot snel eht dexif nhoJ
.lennut eht ni retnuocne eht tuoba yas ot tahw fo erusnu ,wodniw eht tuo ylsselmia ro sdraobroolf eht ta gnirats neewteb gnitanretla ,esolc tas yehT
.kcen s’nomed eht gnikirts
niart eht ecaf ot denrut yehT
”.syawbus s’kroY weN ni segassap neddih esoht ekil adniK
,tnorf pu tsrub yreif ,gninefaed a tA
emaceb lennut ehT
.resyeg gnimalf a degdod dna
”.seitiroirp egelloc ruoy epacse ot msicitsym dna cigam fo dlrow eht gnisu er’uoy kniht ot gninnigeb m’I“
niaga derif nhoJ
,neeb ev’dluow erehT“
”.ereht s’ti tuB .ton esruoc fo ,rE“
,dica fo maerts gniraes a tohs dna
.swap sih revo denommus swalc gniwolg suomrone htiw doots ecnaL ,ti dniheB
secnalg dedart srehto owt ehT ”…siht od ew nehw
,yalpsid eliga sih deunitnoc eh sa drows s’ecnaL deflugne semalF
.ruf sih tsniaga ezeerb eht gniyojne
.epacse ot sretsnom rehto dna snomed swolla hcihw ,dlrowrednU eht dna mlaer ruo neewteb noitarapes eht nekaew
”.scitanul etelpmoc era su eveileb ot mees od taht seno ylno eht taht ro
”.uoy emalb t’nod I“
,serif eht esuac yltcerid t’ndid temoC s’aleiB ehT
tuo dehcaer sixelA
”.tey decneirepxe t’nevah ew tol elohw a s’erehT
sregnessap eht deppots ylevitceffe dah sdraw latnem dna lleps reirrab ’sixelA gnivorp
.delialf dna dekeirhs erutaerc eht sa
puorg eht drawot detrad erom eerhT
.noziroh eht no desucof dna
.tuo ti depiws dna revo detropelet ecnaL
osla sah eH .yrellag sih ni krowtra dna seirots htob gniwohs
tuo ffats reh dleh ehS
.foor eht fo edis rehto eht ot meht tsap deklaw nhoJ
”.dewollof teg thgim ew fi rednow I ,sulP
.dnuorg dna yks eht htob gnola senil yel ees nac uoy ,sloot thgir eht htiW .senil yel fo
”.ereht tuo gnihtyna nees t’nevah I tub ,llips ograc a neeb s’ereht gniyas era elpoeP
”…snomed tceted ot ytiliba emas taht dah I hsiw yllaer I“
,tuo koob eht dloh ot sixelA detcerid dna
dedeen noitatnacni eht dnuof nhoJ
.ecnaL dias ”,suoires eb t’nac uoY“
egrahcsid anam eht morf htaerb a tuo tel ehS
”.tneve erutcarf eht morf retaw eht fo tuo pu esir yllautca lliw dnalsi na taht elbissop neve s’ti ro ,egrab a no rucco dluoc lautir ehT“
”.detsixe ti wenk neve eno on ,neht erofeB
8 RAOR dna stcA namuhnI ni
,ekal eht ta tuo detniop nhoJ ”…neht eb lliw ti
.tuo smra reh gnulf dna
ti thguac sixelA
.emot sih tuo dellup dna kcapkcab sih deppiznu nhoJ
,sgnidliub detadipalid tsdimA
.eno yad morf sevlesruo yb siht gniod neeb ev’eW
,ytic ralucitrap siht rof tub ,dlrow eht ni scitsym ylno eht ton er’ew wonk I
”?1781 fo eriF ogacihC taerG eht no pu daer uoy fo rehtie evaH“
,daerps smra reh tpek sixelA
.ti pots ot evah eW“
”.nwaps thgim taht snomed fo emulov eht tuoba denrecnoc erom eb dluohs ew tub ,seY“
.gnikniw ,sixelA dias ”…tsixe neve yeht fI“
nom’C“ .dniw eht ni derevaw taht taoc gnittif-mrof a dna dnabdaeh a ni tuo dekced eod tibbar a dna
”?siht od dna tuo og ew nehw uoy htiw koob egap-derdnuh-evif eritne na yrrac ot deen uoy kniht uoy od yhW .taht yllaicepsE“
,wap ni koob sih dah ydaerla nhoJ
erussif yldlrowrehto eht esolc ot gniyrt
”.nac ew yaw emas eht sliart tnecs rieht revoc ot elba eb ot meht nwonk reven ev’I tub
.niart eht fo raer eht morf gnitaname stuohs eht ot nward
,egelloc eht ta kcab devirra yllanif oirt eht
,stsitlucco krad htiw gnilaed yletinifed er’eW
.klaw rieht morf yraew dna derit
”…ekatsim gib a saw sdneirf ym gnikcattA“
,tuo decra gninthgil dna
,foor s’niart eht no dednal dna
noitailater s’rehto eht epacse ot detropelet neht
”.retaw eht revo tuoba gnivom staob lortap ecilop eb dluow ereht esac eht s’taht fi kniht osla dluow I tuB“ .nhoJ dias ”,ytilibissop a s’tahT“
.tnorf eht ta semalf eht epacse ot gniyrt
”.lautir eht tpurretni dna ni mooz nac ew os tsaf gnihtemoS .taob a tner ot deen ll’eW  …neht yakO“ .ekal eht ta tuo decnalg eh sa
.lennut liar eht morf ti skcol taht cigam eht ssapyb nac ohw
.denettalf srae ’sixelA
.yawa mih dettaws nomed eht tub
pag neddus a revo deppoh sixelA
yks fo hctap rehtona ot revo decnalg dna
.dne rehto eht ta gnilgnad knuks eht htiw ffats reh dehctulc dna
scitsym ot ylno elbissecca
,eerf dellup dna llaw kcirb a ni sevlesmeht deddebme seugnot ehT
”.tey maxe yrtsimehc ruoy rof deiduts neve t’nevah uoY“
.tsud otni yawa gnilbmurc yllanif litnu edalb eht rednu dehtirw dna
,ylddo mih ta gnikool meht deciton dna
”.retaw ekil t’nod dlrowrednU eht morf serutaerc tsoM“ .ecnaL dias
.taoc sih detsujda dna thgiarts doots nhoJ
detloj niart eritne ehT ”.peY“
,detlah niart eht dna tuo tnew sthgil ehT
,snooccar eht rof gnihsur
.llaberif a gnilf ot ti dniheb deraeppaer dna
.emoh edir derahs eht no tnelis deniamer oirt ehT
.tnelis ylddo deniamer snoitces redlo s’noiger eht fo emos ,eltsub ytic-renni thgin etal s’ogacihC dnoyeB   2 fo 1 traP ,suileA yb ”citsyM nabrU“
.delbmurc dlohdnah s’nhoJ tub
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.lerrab eht dnuora gnirevoh senur gniwolg htiw lotsip deroloc-eznorb a gnimia doots nhoJ ,meht dniheB
.emalf otni tsrub neht dna
,edis rehto eht morf tuo dehsal serutaerc fo riap rehtonA ”…ti gnirB“
,detsetorp yltneloiv ti sa nwod kcab ti deggard dna nomed cidica eht debbarg
.mih detpurretni emalf fo tsrub rehtona tub
...eb dluohs enil yel ehT“
.em thguat rehtafdnarg ym seirots morf meht tuoba wenk yllautca I ,lleW“ .delims nhoJ
.wolb lufrewop a dehcnual neht
…sixelA ,esrow s’tahw onnud I“
.nepo erutaerc eht erot dna hguorht decils skaerts eulB
.daeh sih detlit ecnaL
,niart eht demmals gnihtemoS
.detaerc ylesoprup saw tI
niks sti otni meht debrosba erutaerc eht tub
”!erif ot enummi s’tI !nhoJ ?…eht tahW“
lotsip sih morf laiv der eht detceje eH
pit eht ta deslup gninthgil dna
.dnuora lla deohce sraor yltsahg
,depoh I sa doog sa toN“
.daeh sih detlit terref ehT
”…gnisicrexe neeb ev’uoy dias uoy thguoht I“
rof murof troppus tenretni taht fo esuaceb si ereht tuo srehto era ereht wonk ew nosaer ylno ehT
.gniraet enil yel elpmis a rof gib oot yaw saw thgin tsal thguof ew tsaeb tahT
,gnipraw ydaerla s’ti ,temoc taht ot sknahT
.rood eht no dekconk dna
.dnik ruo ot nwonk snoitanimoba hctirdle citpylacopa suodnerroh tsom eht fo emos decaf
dna snoitan tnereffid morf srednefed lacitsym fo seugael rehto emos htiw denioj aroruA eht tub
.sdneirf reh nioj ot denrut dna
”.snailivic eht morf ti laes og ll’I“
.kcab gnirats seye gniwolg fo sriap eerht was ylnialp sixelA
.spam eht detavitca dna enohp trams sih tuo dellup eH
,mlaer rieht morf kcab ti laes dna
,rafa morf ti delian selitcejorp der-gniwolG
?snoitarujnoc rojam mrofrep ot no os dna ,sgnissap temoc
”.ti ni scitsym ylno eht era eerht ew dna noillim flah-
skrap ynam s’ogacihC fo eno revo yltnaillirb enohs nus ehT
”,ecalp sekat lautir tnatropmi yna emit emas ehT“
.niart eht fo kcab eht ot teg ot enoyreve rof detuohs dna
.selcatceps sih ot snel der eht dehcatta dna kcab denael nhoJ
koob eht desolc ylwols nhoJ ”?taht saw“
.denediw seye s’nhoJ .sixelA dias ”…ho hU“
”!gnimoc erom raeh I“
ro lleps a ot sdrow tcaxe eht gnicnerefer ylkciuq fo yaw emos deen thgim ew nehw wonk reven uoy ,sediseB
ffo snel eht dellup nhoJ
”?thgin tsal morf ekil gnihtemos yB“
”!pu em lluP !pu em lluP“
.meht rednu deraeppa skcarc erom tub
.nagihciM ,dnalloH ot ogacihC morf seog ti kniht I ,thgir pam siht gnidaer m’I fi lleW“
”.sthgink nabru eb ot esohc eW
.psarg s’wap eht fo tuo mih llup ot sixelA rof emit ni tsuj dehsinif dna
”?emit naem eht ni slatner taob emos otni kool owt uoy naC
,edis eht morf ti delian tsrub prahs a tub ,dica tips ot deraperp dna
.redluohs reh no wap mraw a tup nhoJ
.noonretfa siht maxe suluclac a evah I ,yakO“
s’ti ro ,gnitciderp s’enoyreve naht resolc s’temoc siht rehtiE
”.elihw a ni ecno yreve kaerb a deen stsiybboh nevE“
,dehsals dna degnul terref ehT
seugnot dehtoot sti htiw ti ta gnihsals
tsuj s’tI  …wonk I ,wonk I“
tnemom a rof yks eht otni pu dekool knuks ehT
.pih sih tsniaga delgnad koob revocdrah deruces a erehw
koob eht deppord ylraen sixelA
,tnorf eht dehcaer yllanif scitsym eht nehW
.meht ecaf ot nups dna sllaw eht fo eno ffo dekcik ti elihw
.swodniw eht edistuo dehsalf skraps tneloiv dna
fo strap 2 fo ts1 eht saw sihT
!koob ym deen eW“ .pu debmilc dna
.ti gnitlah ,bmob redwop a dessot dna kcab gnarps ylkciuq terref eht tub
,diulf eulb gniwolg fo laiv a ni devohs dna
tuo deppets ylsuoituac knuks ehT ”…doog ton s’tahT“
noziroh nretsae eht ta wodniw eht tuo dekool nhoJ
.tegrof meht pleh dluohs tahT“
,flah ni nomed eno tilps eH
.ti esahp neve ton did
”?rof gnimmarc uoy era maxe hcihw ,woW“
.srehto tcetorp pleh ot stnelat ruo esu ot esohc eW .su eb ot sah tI“
.tcatnoc no yawa maets sropav suonosiop gnittel
.decniw sixelA ”??suoires uoy erA“
.gniyduts drah fo ruoh na revo morf tser a nekat gnivah
.ereh fo tuo enoyreve teg attog eW“
.did gnipacse snomed tub
”.depacse evah thgim seno suoregnad erom eht fo emoS
.redluohs sih no wap a tup ehS
”.dnuorgrednu eb ll’tI
”…si gniht siht tahw tuo erugif ot emit hguone evah annog m’I kniht t’nod I“
yb desuac erew noiger eht revo lla daerps taht serif eht demussa elpoep emoS
ti fi evitarcul ytterp eb dluow ti kniht d’uoY
.reddal epacse erif gnikaerc
,detnahc dna denoitom ylkciuq knuks ehT
”.eno siht no enola eb ll’ew raef I
.ti dnuora depparw senur gniwolg fo elcric a htiw
.suoires teg ot deen uoy ,nhoJ“
.worbeye na desiar ecnaL
”.tey serutaerc esoht dnuorrus yllamron taht stnecs ciruflus yna thguac t’nevah I ylikcul tub ,haeY“
.anam erup fo desopmoc wobssorc gniwolg a gnirujnoc
.meht rof dehcaer dna niaga degreme wap kcalb ehT ”!yrruH“
,niarts morf despalloc dleihs ehT
revo dekool sixelA
,niart deniur eht fo snoitrop dna sllaw lennut dekcarc eht no erom deyarps ekirts yrevE
.temoc eht no yduts ym rof era eseht ,han ,hO ?huH“
.ti ta nekiruhs denosiop werht dna
,ecaf sih nwod gnimaerts doolb fo liart dna niap eht erongi ot gniyrT
terref eht no denrut taht daeh dnoces a gniworg
.meht dniheb sdnuos gnilffuhs gniraeh
gnikeirhs ,nihtiw morf devlossid nomed eht dna
,eciwt dehsilbup neeb
.enil yel denekaew eht morf tfel
.serutcarf eseht htiw lluf swap sih evah thgim
”?lortnoc rednu ti teg nac srenommus eht erofeb yawa nur t’nseod denommus s’revetahw erusne ot yaw retteb tahW“
regna ni deraor nomed ehT
:yojne esaelP     .tenalPruF yb
”.ngis dab a s’tahT
.ffats reh tuo dleh dna niart delgnam eht tsniaga yawa dekcab sixelA .erif gnituops
.maxe ym rof kcab daeh ot emiT“
.spmalteerts kaew eht gnidnuorrus swodahs eht ni detfihs tnemevoM
.dnoces tsal eht ta gnipacse
.segap eht etingi ot gninetaerht
,emot s’nhoJ was dna
.erutcarf lanoisnemid erem on saw latrop tahT“
”.ydaerla gnitrats s’tI“
ti htiw dedilloc serutaerc ehT
.swalc sti dekaos dicA
.seugnot nedal-htoot elpitlum tuo tohs dna
,ezorf snooccar owt ehT   ”.krow ot emiT“
,esolc emac taht gnihtyna gnidderhs
,htraE ot tsesolc eb lliw temoC renreB-izlawhcS eht ,won morf sthgin owT
.retaw eht revo ecalp ekat ot gniog t’nsi
.yks eht ni elbisiv ylisae temoC renreB-izlawhcS eht gnikam
”.snoitcennoc lacigoloeg tsuj erew senil yel thguoht I“
lotsip rehtea na gniyrrac …uoy ro …drows a gniyrrac …em wolla annog er’yeht ,thgiR“
.emoh niart eht dedraob dna snoitats L eht fo eno ta nhoJ tem ecnaL dna sixelA ,retal sruoH
.elzzum sih revo pu ksam a dellup ecnaL
,sessalg sih devomer
kcab derats snooccar owt ehT ”…boj eciN“
.wohemos dewollof erew ew fi desirprus eb t’ndluow I ,wonk’Y“
,meht woleb detfihs skcor dna dedaf eriF
.od yeht wonk lla eW“
teef sih ot dellor nhoJ
.gnihsals dna gnihceercs
.gnihtolc dna ruf rieht no gnikraps srebme
”…aroruA fo redrO eht otni detcudni eb ot evig t’ndluow I tahW  …haeY“
,nees ev’ew sgniht eht eveileb ot sesufer cilbup eht fo ytirojam eht taht
.segap hguorht gnimmiks
,kcab thgif ot ydaer ,dehcuorc eH
”.ruoh na rof sthgiew tfil I syad-ffo eht no dna ,yad rehto yreve selim net nur I“
”.thgindiM“ .sixelA dias
,tilps dna delbraw erutaerc ehT
.hcterts ot pu denael dna skoob eht desolc eH
noziroh eht ssorca decnalg nhoJ
dnob ydaetsnu-ydaerla eht detpursid ti dna aera eht revo lla saw anam laudiser ehT
,smra sih gnola decnad senur tiL
”.retteb wonk ew ,lleW“ .deilper ecnaL
.enips s’nhoJ nwod nar llihc A
.did ehs sa lleps gnilaeh kciuq a gnignis
.ereh skcatta nomed morf elpoep tneconni gnitcetorp er’ew gniredisnoc
”.emit siht yb og ot sromur dehsuh evah neve t’nod eW
.mih dewollof dna delggig tibbar ehT
”…regnol hcum pu dleihs siht peek t’nac I“
htuom sti denepo tI
.erutaerc eht drawot gnikaerts erofeb
”.od ew tahw rof deen suoires a s’erehT
,ruf ro riah fo dioved saw ydob stI
,erehps evitcetorp eht ta degnul tsaeb ehT ”…wen s’tahT“
.tnew yeht sa yawa snoitrop gnippir
.thguoht ni deworruf worb ,desuap nhoJ
.delley ehs ”!gnihtemos od t’nod ew fi ni evac annog si ecalp sihT“
.wap eerf sih ni bro yreif a denommus dna
tuo wobssorc derujnoc sih dleh nhoJ
tluser eht era seicnetsisnoc lacigoloeG“
,tnahc tfos a derettum sixelA ”?yako owt uoY“
.sixelA dias ”,dab os eb t’now tI“
no siseht tnecsed a tuo erugif nac I fi kniht uoY“
.pirg lotsip sih otni ti dils neht
.dehgis dna riah sih hguorht wap a nar ecnaL
tuo dellup ecnaL ”.gniregnil llits si tnecs stI“
,enoyreve gnissap retfA
”.ssalc yrotsih ni ylnO“ .deggurhs sixelA
.daeh reh detlit sixelA
taeh eht morf dewolg sliar ehT
”.gnitnemirepxe neeb ev’yeht dna
.meht fo eerht lla depolevne dna tuo tsrub erehps gniwolg A
.tah sih no tleb eht morf snel der a dellup dna
”…hctaw t’nod uoy fi tseb s’ti tub ,mU
.tsud suonosiop ni ti gniduorhs
.dennirg nhoJ
.rafa morf gnignul spmi eht nwod depins yltrepxe nhoJ elihw
.dehcuot yeht gnihtyna trapa gniraet
”.ti truh neve t’ndid eW .nomed taht taefed t’ndid eW“ .ecnaL dias
”.enil yel eno naht erom gnitceffa
,ecnaL ta dehsur dna morf denwaps ti erutaerc eht morf eerf dellup daeh dnoces ehT
.degrahc dna deraor nomed ehT
,kcab denael nhoJ
delriws yltneloiv eriF
.gnitnap ,derettum nhoJ
,kcapkcab reh fo tuo dor a dellup sixelA
.denediw seye s’sixelA
.deleviws srae ’sixelA ”.hcnic a eb ll’tI
erehps eht morf gnitceje gninthgil ehT
”?llorne ot tneps uoy yenom hcum woh rebmemer dnA
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
”.niart cilbup a draob no …lotsip yna ,llew—
,emanresu emas eht rednu ytiniffAruF ta dnuof eb nac ohw ,suileA yb ”citsyM nabrU“
.erif thguac ti fo renroc a dna
.retaw eht revo gnissorc erew senil yel eht wenk eh erehw
.regral hcum eno siht
.era ew erar woh sevorp ytivitca fo kcal sti dna
”?aroruA eht yb deciton teg thgim I ,hcum os senil yel htiw wercs stemoc yhw
.gniliec deniur s’lennut eht revo gnivom swodahs was dna
,lennut eht ni meht dnuora pu denepo skcarc erom ,elihw eht llA
ti evoba deraeppaer ecnaL
.snooccar eht dna sixelA drawot denael dna
.skcart s’yawbus eht fo deniamer tahw fo egde eht no gnitser
.drows sih htiw kcab ecils ot gninnips
.thgirf deye-ediw ni depsag nhoJ
,ffats degrahc-anam reh htiw ti dehsams dna
taog cinomed dna tnepres fo noitanibmoc delacs a
,llaw eht otni dehsarc ti erofeb yawa evod nhoJ
seilamona lacigoloeg neewteb snrettap edam yeht thguoht elpoep nosaer ehT
.derettulf srae s’sixelA
?’sregnirb-mood‘ stemoc llac ot desu ydobyreve woh wonk uoY
”.me’ fo owt s’erehT“
degnul knuks ehT
”?ti t’nsi ,oot ,sromur aroruA esoht tuoba denrael uoy erehw s’taht teb ll’I
.ydob sti morf dehs yllaunitnoc hsa dna diulf gniwolg htiw deppird sgnaf stI
snomed sseltnuoc fo smaercs yrgna ,duol eht dna
,noitatnacni deirruh a derettum dna doots eH
”.snoissim eseht no tuo gniog detrats ew ecnis reve gnippils neeb s’.A.P.G ruoY
”.oot ,anemonehp suonimul tsuj erew shtiarw thguoht ecno elpoeP“ .dennirg nhoJ
,tes ot nugeb ydaerla dah nus ehT
a-dna-owt fo noitalupop a sah ogacihC
.foor levarg eht otno delbmut dna
epahser dna praw nac flesti dnal eht esuaceb saw
.noitailater cidica s’nomed eht diova ot detropelet neht
”.sevlesruo ecap attog tsuj eW .siht ta doog ytterp ydaerla er’eW“
,ni dellips dna nepo srood eht dellup srac drawrof eht ni elpoeP .drawnwod
”.hguone elbapac ton er’eW“
.snooccar denethgirf eht dna flesreh dnuora erehps evitcetorp gniwolg eht gniniatniam
owt eht neewteb dednal sixelA tub
.tceffe emas eht htiw ti gnillik ,retsnom tsrif eht otni derif dna nups nhoJ .deid ti sa
.revo delias ti sa swalc sti gnissim
.nihc reh debbur sixelA
,L eht gnola slennut yawbus wef erar eht fo eno otni dednecsed niart ehT
,drows gnimalf sih htiw nwod debbaj dna
.gnibrutsid ylralucitrap si sromur fo kcal ehT“ .dehgis nhoJ
snailivic denethgirf eht tsap yaw rieht decrof oirt ehT
,dedolpxe dna daeh sti kcurts nekiruhs eerht tub
”.raeg yvaeh taht lla htiw nwod flesruoy gnipparts ro taoc gib taht gniraew ton si pleh thgim tahW“
noitailater sti morf yawa gnurps neht
.nhoJ dias ”,tniop dooG“
,toped egarots eht ta yrnopaew dezilaiceps rieht gniwots retfA
doots knuks ehT ”…etunim a tiaW“
.terref eht derettum ”,gnihton si siht ,nhoJ
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.meht deteerg thgis hsilleh a ,woleb raF
,suileA yb ”citsyM nabrU“
.erehps s’sixelA ta yawa tae ot deunitnoc tsrif eht elihw
.egrahc rehtona gnidiova ,yawa evod dna tilps yehT
.knuks eht dias ”!evah I“
.tuo dehcaer wap kcalb citnagig a dna
.ti hguorht etib ot gniyrt dna
.dne hcae ta dewolg taht ffats a mrof ot wap reh ni dednetxe hcihw
!larutan ton si erif sihT“
,desolc seye sih htiw ssarg eht ni kcab yal ecnaL
.snoitanilcni era evah ew lla won thgir tub
,pu decra semalf erom dna
siht lla naht gnitseretni erom hcum os
”.sthgin wef txen eht rof ti morf snwaps revetahw ffo gnithgif ysub eb annog er’ew snaem taht dna
”.enola eb ot tnaw t’nod I
,raey tsal nopu delbmuts uoy scitsym rehto
surebreC …rebmemer tub“ ,dias eh ”,haeY“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”!pu kcab siht esolc ot yaw ylno eht s’tI
.niart eht otni kcab dekcud dna sgat lleps
”?neht gnirrucco tneve yadsmood a saw erehT ?ylsuoireS“
”.dlrowrednU eht htiw erutcarf repeed a snaem senil gnitcesretni owT .doog t’nsi sihT“
dekeirhs erutaerc ehT
.ydob sti otni ti gnikcus ,edalb eht debbarg dna tuo detloj niks ylio s’erutaerc eht tub
.nagihciM ekaL ta tniopssorc eht ot yaw eht lla
.hguorht wollof uoy dnamed dluow yeht erus m’I
”,retaw revo si ’ereht‘ woh ecitoN“ ”.ereht dna…“
.sdap eton elpitlum dna
”.ecalp siht revo lla eudiser anam s’erehT“
,taocgnol rehtael dlo sih dewollib dniw eht dna
”?2102 no dne t’ndid dlrow eht nosaer eht er’yeht wonk uoy diD
.erif ehtaerb snomed emos taht tcaf eht sediseb s’taht dna
.reporp ytic eht otni edir derahs a llac ot elba erew yeht litnu
,stsixe llits snomed fo taerht eht ,revewoH
.srats eht gnoma elbisiv ylraelc saw temoC renreB-izlawhcS eht erehw
.liat dna teef sih ta dehsals woleb serutaerc eht sa kcab mih gniward
,enohp trams sih htiw delddif ecnaL
”?og maxe eht d’woH“
.erehps dleihs gniwolg ’sixelA gnilian
.syad wef txen eht revo htiw gnilaed eb thgim ew tahw revo kcerw suovren a gnieb em ot sknaht
”!kcab gnidaeh s’ti ,nhoJ“
.elbarenluv riap eht gnivael
.sdneirf reh ot denrut ehs
egde eht ta derehtag ecnaL dna nhoJ
.sthgil ytic eht ta kcab decnalg sixelA
.deneppah dah tahw gniees neve ro gnidrocer morf
,ti morf deslup evaw gniwolg A
skoob owt yb derevoc
.segap eht demmiks dna
.dlrowrednU eht fo secrof eht tsniaga kcab thgif dna
.drawnwod meht gnignulp
.resolc deppets ecnaL
.mih ot nopaew eht gnidnob
revo detnirps sixelA
.feilebsid ni derats sixelA
?ereht tuo slautir gnimrofrep morf stsitlucco egaruocsid ot tnaem s’taht fi tahw …yeH“ .deknilb sixelA
taoc sih kcab dellup eH
.gninepo eht dnuora gnihtyna trotsid serutcarf esohT
tnahc dnoces a detuohs knuks eht
.srae reh fo eno debbur ylsuovren sixelA
.pu gnisolc yllanif litnu eloh eht ni gnillif
.dleihs eht ta dehsals dna degrahc tsaeb ehT
reddal eht fo pot eht detserc yllanif knuks A
?mrod ruoy ni thgin eht dneps I naC
,rewsna ton did selam owt ehT
.ezeerb thgils eht ni deyaws liat sih sa
* * * ”?yduts em pleh annaw ecnaL dna uoY
,htraE ot esolc yllaer ro thgirb yllaer era taht esoht sa hcus ,stemoc elbatoN
”…thgir er’uoY“ .dehgis nhoJ
.pu gnicnalg ,dias eh ”…syuG“
.tamrof cinortcele ni skoob lleps desruc rof tekram eht tuoba rednow uoy sekam adniK“
,mih ta degrahc dna
.swodahs eht morf gnigreme erutaerc ekil-drazil niht-eriw
.rebmem aroruA na sa esu ot detcepxe uoy tahw drawot seiduts ruoy deraeg uoy dias uoy ,rebmemer tub ,seY“
”?neppah lliw lautir eht kniht uoy od nehW“
.tsereves rieht ta eb lliw serutcarf lacitsym enil yel eht dna
,htaenrednu morf detpure semalf dna
”?stnenoppo reggib gnicaf eb ll’ew naem taht seod oS“
”.lausu sa ,suoivilbo yletelpmoc saw cilbup lareneg eht elihw dlrow eht devas aroruA ehT
,stlob erom tuo detsalb nopaew eht dna
.epahs larutannu na ni tuo deyalps sliar nekorb dna lennut demrofed
,meht dnuora lla pu semalf werht taeh esnetni ehT
,gnitnap ,wap sih tuo dleh eH
.tibbar eht ot kcab denrut nhoJ
.tamrof koobe ni semot lacitsym tneicna on era ereht esuaceB“
kcor fo noitrop dilos a debbarg yllanif nhoJ
.seye denediw htiw meht ot denrut eH
”!tnemele retaw eht ot kaew er’yehT !rednow oN“
.seye sih gniworran ,desuap eH ”.ti
.rof gnikool saw eh yrtne eht dnuof yllanif eH
enohp trams sih debbarg nhoJ ”…haeY“
…tuo em dekaerf yllaer ereht kcab deretnuocne ew tahw …syuG“
,eiree na was dna denrut yehT
.klawedis eht gnola gnilbma snooccar sselemoh owt was dna
.slipup gnikcal seye gniwolg dna snroh ynips htiw
.daeh sih dehctarcs eh ,spam eht ot enil eht morf gnikool fo setunim lareves retfA
.roolf gnilbmurc eht ot knas dna drah llaw a tih nhoJ ”!!nhoJ“
,lennut eht morf gnignah tsaeb gnikluh a was dna pu debmilc sixelA
.ymehcla fo tnairav rehtona tsuj s’yrtsimehC“ .deggurhs nhoJ
.daeh reh detlit sixelA
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”.surebreC“ ,deilper dna
,gnitnap ereht tas
.temoc eht ot eud won elbisiv ylno s’tI“
.tah demmirb-ediw sih yawa wolb ot gninetaerht
,reh ta dehsur tsaeb ehT
”?noitautis gnitaob eht no ew era erehw ,lleW“
htuom gnippird suomrone sti denepo tI
”.selim owt goj ot deganam yllautca I keew tsaL“
”?ew era ,worromot rof ydaer ton er’eW“
,swodahs eht fo tuo dehcrul epahs rehtonA
.syawedis daeh sti gnikconk
seye sih detniuqs ecnaL
niaga deirt ylkciuq nhoJ
.tsud ot meht gninrut
.lotsip sih derewol dna deknilb nhoJ
,koob eht debbarg dna detropelet ylkciuq ecnaL
draw latnem a htiw gnola sregnessap eht tcetorp ot lleps reirrab a dehsalf sixelA
,tsael yrev eht tA“ .dehgis nhoJ
,nwod deppord sixelA
,desaeler osla saw erif ,sretsnom eht desaeler taht denepo sraet eht nehw os ,yreif
.egnul ot gniraperp erom owt ecaf ot doots dna dnuora drows eht delriwt ecnaL
.nonemonehp larutanrepus fo tros siht htiw gnilaed fo elbapac seno ylno eht er’eW
.gninrom siht gnihcraeser saw I tahw yltsom s’taht ,lleW“
”?regnorts eb lliw tuo emoc taht sretsnom eht oS“ .pu denael ecnaL
.swap sih gnieerf
.nhoJ dias ”,devivrus ew tuB“
,taht ylno toN
…erujnoc ot snoitom eht ro shtiarw tsorf gnitaefed no dohtem a
”.tuoba su gnillet peek uoy sroirraw lacitsym fo redro terces taht rof tpecxe ,lleW“
,yaw evag meht htaeneb roolf eht tub kcohs ni kcab depael oirt ehT
nhoJ dna reh gnirevoc dleihs a pu gnulf ehS
.slautir gninommus rieht nehtgnerts ot stemoc fo ecneserp eht esu yllacipyt stsitlucco krad tub
.nomed eht no tceffe on dah tub
”.won era ew erehw fo tsae selim ruof ro eerht ylhguor ,ekal eht revo yltcerid enil aredlaC enotswolleY eht htiw stcesretni tI
steerts ytpme eht hguorht yaw rieht edam eerht ehT ”.og s’teL
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,ybboh a siht llac yldrah d’I“
nomed cidica eht ,ybraeN
.drawrof enoyreve gnitfihs
,sgnipporctuo kcor debbarg yehT
.srehto eht ot kcab ti gnulf neht
.lluks sti hguorht drows a gnimmaj ,ti fo pot no dednal ecnaL dna
”.ecnaL ,uoy ekil tun ssentif a ton m’I ,lleW“
,tleb s’knuks eht ta detniop ecnaL
dlo na no dednuop spetstoof litnu ria thgin eht debrutsid dniw eht ylno
”.tey gniht eritne eht deziromem t’nevah I sulP  …ffuts
noitatnacni kciuq a devaw sixelA
.taes eht no kcapkcab sih tes nhoJ .deksa sixelA
dehctip niart eht dna sllaw eht gnola decar skcarc
,thgir eb lliw snoitidnoc ,eruS
detloj tsaeb ehT
”.emit siht ruflus fo tnecs tniaf a llems I
,sepiws suoiruf s’tnaliassa owt sih degdod ylsseltroffe ecnaL ,ybraeN .detuohs sixelA
.dluoc eh tseb sa derutseg dna denrut nhoJ
”…L eht gnisu ot kcab og dluohs ew kniht llits I“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.thgir saw ehs wenk tub
,reh ecaf dna tsiwt ot detrotnoc neht
.egde s’foor eht revo denael dna denrut ehS
.anam fo deniard
.ylereves erom senil yel eht tceffa nac
”…nalp a evah uoy epoh I“ .decniw sixelA
.ti gnimrah tuohtiw kcab tsaeb eht devohs ylno ti tub
,supmac eht dehcaer yllanif yeht nehW .dehgis eH
denrut eH ”?ti eeS“
”?uoy t’nod ,gnihtemos leef uoY“
.rucco lliw lautir a mrifnoc yllautca nac ew fi pleh thgim ti ,mU“
htuom sti denepo nomed ehT
rehgih degrus semalf ehT
mrod ’selam eht ta devirra sixelA
,ik htiw tsif sih degrahc dna kcab deppilf eH
.pot eht ot yaw sih edam eh sa driht a fo shtaerb gnipsag eht ot gninetsil ,detiaw dna
.yab ta ytisoiruc rieht peek ot
.yrrow t’nod ,siht tog ev’eW“
.roiretni eht gninekrad
.noos no gniog ytivitca lamronarap fo tol a tcepxe nac ew ,saw eriF ogacihC eht egral woh nevig dna
,llew ,dna elitsoh ylbidercni si dlrowrednU ehT
,meht derussaer ylmlac ehS
tilps dnuorg ehT
,yad txen ehT *** ”…eurT“
…nwod wols ot deen yllaer …owt uoY“
”!etunim a rof detcartsid ti peek tsuJ“
,semalf eht hguorhT
flah rehto eht depsarg nhoJ elihw tuo ti dleh dna
.snooccar eht fo tnorf ni swap reh gnivaw
,diuqil eht revo decra gninthgiL
.sixelA dias ”,taht gnitrats erofeb revo si retsemes eht retfa litnu tiaw ot tnaw thgim uoY“
.dica gnihsug s’nomed eht diova ot kcor egral a dniheb detrad dna
.tnew ti sa gnilrans
.dnif dluoc eh deefswen dna etis gnimaerts yreve gnikcehc
.despalloc lennut eht fo strap erom sa neve tuo kcab lwarc ot gniyrt ,dluoc ti gnihtyna ta depsarg
,depsag tibbar ehT
.ria eht deffins dna
.tcapmi eht morf erif fo mrots a gnihsaelnu
,enil yawbus taht dnoyeb erehwemos deirub lennut neddih a s’ereht si sseug yM .ma I“
,deniarts sixelA dna ecnaL
ylsuodnerroh a detanimulli serif llams ,latem delgnam eht dnoyeB
.raey a tuoba rof siht ta neeb ylno ev’eW“
,sespilce litnu tiaw yeht woh rebmemeR
.meht fo tnorf ni nwod tas nhoJ
”.dlrowrednu lacitsym eht ot suoivilbo yletelpmoc si tnemnrevog eht ekil ton s’tI
”.trats smaxe lanif nehw thgiR“ .dehgis ecnaL
”!!gnihtemos oD ?syuG“
.won thgilyad ni elbisiv yllautca era enil yel taht fo seitreporp lacitsym ehT“
.erehps eht gnispalloc ,swap reh derewol dna htaerb a tuo tel sixelA
.nagihciM ekaL gnikoolrevo
,trams ylgninethgirf era snomed emoS
dna senil yel htiw tcaretni anemonehp laitseleC
deretne sixelA ”.ni nom’C .xelA yeH“ .pu denepo nhoJ
”.eb ot erehw wonk ew
.doolb rof gnikeirhs ,ecafrus eht hcaer ot gniyrt rehto hcae revo derebmalc sedutitluM
yawa dekcab ecnaL
.dehcaorppa ecnaL
.mrof s’nhoJ dednuorrus wolg thgirb a dna
.derekcins sixelA
.swalc tnaig yb deppir fi sa yawa nrot niart eht fo snoitrop was yeht
”?senil yel tnereffid owT“
,lennut eht fo edis rehto eht no depuorger nhoJ dna sixelA
”.ffuts efil-laer ,lacitcarp …gnirob
.yruf ni gnihceercs ,tuo detrad spmi dna meht dnuora lla depraw swodahS
.tnew ti sa dnuorg eht ni skcarc erom gnippir
.liava on ot tub tuo drows sih llup ot deirt ecnaL
koohs lennut eritne ehT ”…sselrewop er’eW“
.tsae detniop eH ”!erehT
.meht detpurretni gnipeeb enohp trams s’nhoJ
elbat moor gnivil eht dnif ot
erew ew erehw morf seog erutcarf tahT“
,pu nhoJ depleh dna
,detapissid dna sdaeh rieht dednuorrus wolg a retfA
”.scitpeks eht lla rof t’nerew
.edis eno ot enoyreve gniworht
.timmoc nac dna scisab eht wonk uoy evorp ot ,wonk’Y
.derutpur era slaes eht nehw
.riah etihw sih hguorht wap derit a nar dna
,tropelet a otni deppilfkcab ecnaL
detpure hsalf thgirb A
sixelA dna ,ecnaL ,nhoJ
.taeh eht morf tfel swolg egnaro derettacs yb ylno til ,tnelis yliree
.dnal yrd no kcutS“
.sevlesmeht snel laiceps eht gnivah ton
”.sterces gnipeek ta era ew naht retteb tsuj er’yehT
”?ereht kcab og ew gnitseggus uoy erA“ .deralg ecnaL
!erussif lanoisnemid a fo elddim eht ni thgir er’eW
wap kcalb tnaig ehT
tnemevom sih htiw delttar dna deknilc raeg siH
”,od llits yeht ,yllautcA“
.emit emas eht dnuora yb gnissap
,syaw etarapes rieht tnew oirt ehT