uoy oD“  .noitom gnipmup a ni nwod dna pu dnah ym devom I
,hguorht gnissap tsuj erew uoy dias uoY
a htiw retnuocne tsrif ym saw sihT
kcab kool I nehW
erofeb ,gninrom eno kcurt pukcip eulb-ybab dlo ym otni denwo I sgniht wef eht pu dekcap I oS
a dna ,ydob tes yvaeh a fo tib a
oot teg ton ot luferac gnieb saw I
noitpecer gniddew eht fo thgin eht no ecnad ot em deksa kciN nehW
?ay t’nera ,flesruoy fo daeha elttil a ’nitteg er’uoY“
:elihw a rof .A.I.M tnew eh yhw no ni em dellif edualC
yrotsih a gnirebmemer tuoba
,ekil ,sthguoht driew eseht teg I tuB“
terger neve ebyam dna wonk reven ll’uoy ,yrt
.yllautca ,esrow tog tI“
”!!EREM’C  !EMOH M’I  !SYUG“
yrots eht tneserp ew os dnA
;VT no ees uoy gniht taht did ew eveileb ot dah uoy
.enif saw did I gnihtoN  .dekrow dias I gnihton
s’ti…s’ti dna em htiw serahs eh ecneirepxe na ro yrots a sah eh dna no gniog ffuts eht fo emos tuoba mih llet I
dna…nwod dna pu kool eht dna erats eht
.yag gnieb rof em ta maercs ot detnaw tsuj daD ym kniht I
”dnobagaV“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
tlef tI  .yag gnieb tuoba dah reve d’I noitasrevnoc labrev tsegnol eht osla saw sihT
rebmemer I ,notsoB ni raey taht no
.oot ,dessarrabme erew ew tub ,erus ,rehto hcae ees ot yppah erew eW
wols ni su fo htob eht rof degnahc sgniht ,thgin taht retfa tuB
,peelsa llef kciN tub erom
,lleH  .lamron erom dna erom gnimoceb saw swohs VT no elpoep yag gniees dna
”.won sraey eerht no gnioG
emaceb I woh si tahT  .snigeb
erew eW  .deticxe ,esnet
dekil I taht wenk I dna ,yag saw I wenk I  .notsoB ni ereh
,ega ym eb ot teg uoy nehw taht od uoY
ton did uoy ,morf emac I erehW  .dexaler ylwols
dna tnedifnoc saw eH
.sdnah sih ta nwod dekool dna dehsulb kciN
”—thgin eno ti tuoba deklat eW
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,dael eht ekat ot woh wenk yllaer su fo rehtieN
.nwonk reve d’I gniht ylno eht neeb dah nwotemoh ym
.kcen sih fo htgnel eht nwod gniog seye sih rednu ecaf sih no sthgilhgih deroloc-taehw rethgirb
,srevol yaw-eerht ehT
taht dna ,tuo em hsup ot gniyrt t’nera yeht taht wonk I
.sraey esoht gnirud taerg saw gnihtyreve taht yas ot t’nsi tahT
taht deirrow ,flesym revo gnihtolc yggab gniraew llits saw I
.daeh ym fo tlit tneconni na htiw owt eht ta dekool dna ,elbat eht no meht thguorb ,setalp etarapes ruof no sgge dehsinif eht deppord I
neeb dah ti ekil ydob reppu sih ot dleh taht trihs elcsum kcalb dettif a gniraew saw eH
;sklof fo dnik tnereffid a era ereht elpoeP
.rehto hcae yojne ot tnaw tsuj yeht
:dnim ni sgniht owt
.esruoc fo ,ereht morf devlove tI  .dehcuot spil ruo nehw srats was I dna yob a htiw ssik tsrif ym saw kciN
,dlot eb hturT   .syug dna semag ekil
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.gnorw etiuq saw I ,tuo snrut ti sA
”.oga shtnom owt bulc eht ot trihs wolley taht erow I nehw em degduj uoY“
.evivrus ot hguone dah I tub ,hsac htiw demlehwrevo reven saw I
htiw dnA  .snoitcerid ynam ni tilps eb nac tub
ro krow em tel ot sregnarts fo ssendnik eht no yler ot dah I nehw srednow em did edis yob-yrtnuoc htrae-ot-nwod yM  .ereht dna ereh sboj ddo gnikrow ,setatS detinU eht dnuora tnew I
,aP ot eton a tfel I  .tfel dna
,dias tsoh ym ”!emoh ot emocleW“
”.gnol siht detsal s’eh eveileb t’nac I“
dezilaer I emit eht yb etad ot detrats kciN dna yelsneB rosseforP
enola skool yb mih wenk I os dna
?yako yrtnuoc eht fo tuo teg uoY  !ti edam uoY“
emos dna ,tellaw ym ,rac ym
.emid eht no peels dluoc flesym ekil yob a erehw em wohs
,mom ym dna em no tuo nar eh ,dad yM
,retal syad elpuoc A
.rehto hcae fo erawa er’ew dna ,rehto hcae evol tsuj eW“
.nepo erew setagdoolf eht ,suht dnA
flesruoy tuoba tuo
”.tnereffid s’tI  !oN“
.loohcs hgih fo skeew wef tsal esoht yltnereffid em detaert yeht tuB
.gninaelc eht no draobrevo gniog t’nsaw tub ecalp eht fo erac koot kciN taht sngis
?pihsnoitaler a ni rehtegot teg ew fi neppah lliw tahW  ?em ekil dik a ni ees eh seod tahw
,xes dah ew nehw kciN rof nellaf
.elzzum sih ni tsaot fo eceip a htiw delkcuhc edualC taht ,elbat moor gninid eht ta tas eerht rehto eht dna nehctik eht ni sgge emos gnikam saw I nehw
.tuo gnimoc em ot llew ekat t’ndid skloF“
tub pu desnet I
degnahcxe dah eW  .ecarbme yppah eht neht
oitar eno-ot-eno a ton si evol taht pirt eht gnirud denrael I
.guh a otni em dellup dna delims eH
”—em erofeb eid ylekil ll’eh tub ,dlo neve ro tneicna t’nsi eH
nos s’yelsneB saw I fi su deksa erofeb tem reven ev’I mohw stseug fo elpuoc a hcihw gnirud(
”?truh teg reven sgnileef ruoy dnA“
”.sallef notsoB uoy htiw gniht a eb ot smeeS  .wonk uoy ,enilno segassem ym ssim syawla uoY“ .pu
,yllautneve setammoor emaceb ,esolc
.neht kcab thgirb os ton saw I
taht pag a llif lla ew dna ,rehto hcae deen yllaer eW  .ffo hcnarb
,detisiv ev’I secalp eht ,del ev’I efil eht tuoba kniht I sruoh roF
”…tahw saw tahw wonk t’ndid I dna syad eseht hcum sa klat t’nod ew sulP
.xaler ot trats ,yllanif ,yllanif
.ereh neeb syawla evah ew syas taht yrotsih eht dna
.erotskoob a ni nwotnwod boj a tog I dna ,ti dneps ot gnideen yllaer ton fo efil ym morf pu devas tnuoma tneced a
sevil ruo fo rehtie tuoba cificeps gnihton tub
.dad ym eb ot hguone dlo
.repooC ni yltnereffid evom ot demees emit
.ecneirepxe gninrael eguh a em dereffo ffatsgalF
.laoc fo senil wen rof yaw eht gnidael
.noitnetta erom gnideen enoemos ro sgnidnatsrednusim tsuj era seussi esoht yllausU
,nwotemoh ym naht nepo erom s’ti esuaceb notsoB ni ereh loohcs tra ot emac I  .onnuI ,tuB“  .nam a eb ot saw ,emit eht ta deveileb I ,tahw em thguat eh tub ,lla ta esolc
dna em dnuora reteiuq tib a erew elpoeP
eht dna ttub ym neewteb demmaj gnieb fo sruoh retfa yssem artxe dna—
m’I…si gniht eht ,lleW“  .ylwols delahxe
dna tes dah nus eht ,neht yB
t’nerew eW  .srac xif
ekil ti fo knihT  .pleh nac I ebyaM
,mih ecaf ot denrut I
.tem ev’I elpoep eht dna
,dekil ew sgniht eht tuoba dettahc ew—
.yltsenoh derewsna yeht dna ,did I  .snoitseuq ym tuoba nepo eb ot em dlot
,uaeB“  .trihs olop a dna snaej fo riap ecin a ni ylemosdnah desserd rehto eht
.mih htiw hgual ot tnaw uoy edam taht hgual ylloj
,decneirepxeni dna gnuoy hguohT    .detnaw I tahw
.hgual a htiw dias edualC
os saw I tub ,neht kcab erom hcuot ni peek t’ndid I yrros m’I  .nam ,lleh saw tI“
:gnikniht peek I  .deracs llits m’I tub
,ynnuf dna drawkwa
.yrtnuoc ruo fo sniev eht hguorht gninnur llits
.repooC ni pu gniworg em tuoba yrots a t’nsi siht tuB
tsael ta ,ot terces ym dlot I
os dna evila os gnileef
,leuqes eht gnihsilbup yltnerruc era dna
a ekil ,nael tub tif
.redneg nwo sih deicnaf eh taht flesmih ot ti tpek evah dluow yob trams A
,enilno edam I sdneirf ym ot deklat I  .yag
esuaceb ti evol I dna ,gnilbmuh s’tI
,s’kciN dah I ekil noitautis efil sih wonk t’ndid I ecnis rehtie mih no esopmi ot gniog t’nsaw I
saw tI  .thgin ymrots a no
,sdnob esoht niatniam nac uoy ,noitacided dna krow fo tol a
a detivni neht dna gnitad syug uoy ereW“
”…wonk uoy…uoy nehW“
.nwod kcapkcab ym tup I sa dias I ”,sknahT“
,revo dehcaer edualC
,yteirav taht gnirevocsid nam a fo
”.uaeB ,etilop oot gnieb er’uoY“
dna elihw a rof gniog saw I erehw aedi on dah I
pihc ot em tnaw uoy fi yenom emos evah I  .taht ekil d’I“
.xes ot dael dluow gniteem siht fi wenk su fo rehtieN
.reeb sih deppis dna deggurhs kciN    ”?ffuts yag
,dekan em nees ev’uoY  .uaeB“
.gninworf flesym dnuof I
.raef taht wenk I dna ,gnol os rof ni taht gnidloh neeb dah eH
.dekcilc tsuj lla ew taht dnuof dna
.emit eht lla thgil der ni dehtab gnieb
,enif saw gnihtyrevE
dna mih devol I taht mih gnillet
.mih dnif yllautca ot tcepxe t’ndid I tuB  .cificeps eb ot ,ffatsgalF—yaw siht tuo saw eh wenk I
.emit gnol ,gnol a rof
t’nod uoy fi tuB  .gnihtyna ot uoy stimmoc gnihtoN
a saw I ,shtnom ylrae esoht ni seciohc ym no kcab gnikooL  ————  .dnobagav a
”,su gniyduts er’uoy ekil su hctaw uoY“
dna tnuh ot woh em thguat
,elpoep reeuq era ereht sa reeuq eb ot syaw ynam sa era ereht rof
.daor eht no tuo tes dna kcurt ym ni
.xaler ot su teg yllaer t’ndluoc olaH fo emag a nevE  .ti
eht pu dna gnidliub dlo eht otni em del yob eht ,srats thgirb fo riap a ekil gnilkniwt seye siH
wonk ot detnaw I  .kcaJ eman eht yb gniog nodnoL gniugalp ecanem a neeb dah ereht yldesoppuS
.tuo ti krow ew dna ,gniht elohw eht tuoba su gnirehtob eb yam taht gnihtyna tuoba klat eW
.rof em emalb ot sgniht dnuof yeht ,raews I…gnimraw labolg rof tluaf ym saw ti ,sgnirehtag ylimaf ot og t’ndluoc ew tluaf ym saw ti ,sdikdnarg evah t’ndluow moM ym tluaf ym saw ti :tluaf ym saw esuoh eht ni melborp yrevE
”?htoB  ?nemoW  ?nem tuoba kniht
.dlrow eht dna ecneics
.ti esu ot dedeen ehs dah noitartsurf ni deid ev’dluow ammE tnuA ym thguoht I taht llams os saw nehctik ehT
.ttub yob yrtnuoc ym deretlehs yletinifed dah tI
saw eH  .uoy ekil ,nooccar a s’eH
.did ti sa hcum sa drawrof tnemevom sthgir yag eht hsup depleh tahw s’taht kniht I dna—
,deneppah llits semirc etaH
”.uoy gnidulcni ,elpoep fo tol a ot gniklat deppots adnik I
evah ohw ,ztiurF & sgniR suirebiT yb
.lufwa eb llits dluoc elpoep dna
gar ylio na dah eh dna ,pohs scinahcem a rof ogol eht saw larotcep tfel sih revO  .no dehsurbria
.hgis peed a koot eH
”?pu ti raelc taht t’nseoD“   ”.neM“
.ega fo sraey neethgie saw I nehw nageb—
ohw elpoep rof puorg tahc a ni tem eW
.tsrif ta rehto hcae derolpxe I dna kciN
.rethgual ruo ot hcum
elbatrofmoc oot tlef I dna
t’nod eW  .oot em rof erac yeht dna ,yllauqe meht rof erac I
saw eH  .flow etihw a saw ,nosaJ ,dneirfyob rehto ehT
”,regguh a s’nosaJ“
uoy nac…gniwons saw ti nehw nwal eht gniwom ton ekiL
)serutcip fo sdnik esoht neve ,sey( sraey eht revo serutcip ynam
.yrutnec ts12 eht ni tfihs ot nageb nem yag drawot sedutitta s’elpoep taht syas yrotsiH
.pihsnoitaler ylop
.yletamitni wonk uoy enoemos etah ot drah s’tI
yaw taht niamer ylekil dluow dna evol ni llits erew yeht wenk I ,gniddew rieht ta niaga meht was I nehw tub ,esruoc fo ,suovren saw kciN
.syaw elbakramer tub
syawla ,egatnavda sih ot taht desu aP dna
”.ttuB gniR ,emit nwo ruo yb krow yletinifed eW“
.nwo ym morf secneirepxe tnereffid dah ohw elpoep erom ot klat dna teem ot detnaw I  .sdab eht dna sdoog eht gnidulcni ,yag eb ot
.seye eht ni thgir em gnikool ,resolc ni em gnillup dna kcen eht yb em gnibbarg
deirt yehT  .hcum os hguorht gniog dna desserped
.tohs a ti evig ot dediced eW  .xes retfa…seY“
tub…gnipleh erew yeht thguoht ylbaborp yeht yaw lufwa ,detsiwt emos ni…em devol yeht
”.tisiv nac uoy fi ksa nac uoy kniht I
efil ym fo tser eht rof notsoB ni devil evah dluoc I elihW
,dellac yllautca erew yeht sa elpuorht ro
”.rehtegot gnieb ekil yllaer eW
.em ot leurc reven erew—
,yag eb ot tnaem ti tahw tuoba snoitseuq fo stros lla em gniksa
.pu srae sih dekrep dna hceeps yhtapmys ym detpurretni edualC ”!yeH“
.dexaler erom tsael ta ro ,knurd erom dna erom
ym ni lohocla hcum oot
.elbat eht ta nwod tas I sa noos sa deksa I
”!ni emoc dluohs uoY ?gnileef uoy er’woH  ?derit uoY
evah dluow I taht ,emit eht ta ,deirrow saw I  .nuf dah dna dehgual ew tub
?nem gnikil tuoba gnorw m’I fi tahW  ?em fo nuf ekam elpoep fi tahw
erofeb ti ta gnirats kciN tog hcihw ,dnah ym dereffo I  ”?kciN  .haeY“
.dneirf enilef ym ta retsum dluoc I elims tsemraw eht dehsalf I
.noitacinummoc :wonk ydaerla ylbaborp uoy gniht ynroc eht si yek ehT“  .dehgual nosaJ
emit etavirp dedeen yeht taht erawa eb ot demees yehT  .semitemos
.hcum sa enilno gnimoc deppots neht dna
,elbissop lla ta fi
ew did reeb dloc fo snac wef a denepo ew retfa litnu t’nsaw tI    .deirt ew tuB
hcihw trihs-t citelhta dettif
mih teem ot ekil d’I“
.ereht t’nsaw ti wenk I dna gnihtemos rof gnihcraes llits saw I ,yppah neeb dna
,ztiurF & sgniRsuirebiT yb ”dnobagaV“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.dessarrabme ,daeh ym fo kcab eht debbur I ”,hA“
.tnaw uoy sa gnol sa yats nac uoY“
.nem yag rehto gnidnif no hcum oot sucof yllaer ot
.rehto hcae tuoba hcum taht lla wonk
?wonk uoy ,gnidliub dna gnidliub tpek sgniht tub ,tsrif ta yako…erew yehT
taht dna ,em ot emoclew sa regnol on saw repooC taht leef ot esnes eht dah llits I
.ega ym dnuora
.deirram teg ot hguone suoires tog yeht taht tuo dnuof I ,retal sraey eerhT
”.gnirob ytterp s’tI“  ”.enilno gnitsop
:delley dna ,elzzum sih revo sdnah sih deppuc ,edisni em del yllufeelg etoyoc ehT  .deniatniam-llew
.deggurhs dna dehgual I
,ereht dna ereh spuc ytrid wef a ees
erew raef dna ,dertah ,yrtogib
dekool tub dlo saw esuoh ehT
na yllausu ,hguoht hcuot ni tpek llits eW
.ti devol I  .evila dna suoregnad
————  ”.gniws eht ekat em gnipleh rof sknahT“
ssendrawkwa taht saw ereht ,emit tsrif eht rof kciN tem I nehW
.tnatsid nworg dah ew tub
tsuj htiw tfel I  .ti saw taht dna ,gninrom eno retupmoc ym no gnipoons moM ym dnuof I“
.siht gnitirw m’I yhw era seirots ,seY
a dna strohs fo riap citelhta na erow eH  .wodniw eht otni gnikool tacbob gnuoy a ees ot denrut I
.uaeB dneirf tenretni dlo ym si siht ,iM ,yaJ
gnieb tuoba seirrow eht llA
eb ot tnaem ti tahw dnatsrednu ot dedeen I flesym dnatsrednu ot detnaw I fi taht wenk I
?taht eveileb
.efil ym ni enilucsam
”?sdneirfyob ym teem annaw uoY“
tuoba lla su dlot eh dna yrotsih fo naf a saw eH
”,yllis ,drah era spihsnoitaler llA“
.saw I naht gnola rehtruf demees eh tub ,tnaem yllaer yag gnieb tahw yltcaxe erus t’nerew
.tuo derugif dlrow elohw eht sah eh ekil s’ti
”?wonk uoy ,ytilatipsoh ym kaerb ot yrt t’nod uoy sa gnol sa enif er’uoY
,tsuD ot emoC ,rellirht egA nairotciV rieht nettirw-oc
”!gnihtemos dias adluohs uoY“
.skcor dna seert neerg llat yllaer
enoemos dah yllaer reven I os
…flehs eht no tsud ,degnarra ylecin os ton skoob emos
.etavirp sevil ruo peek tsuj ew os ,tuo meht driew nac ffuts ylop eht tub ,yag er’ew taht enif era ereh dnuora elpoep tsoM“
tsom eht fo riap a dah eh taht ees dluoc I ,em ta dekool dna gninway deppots eh ecnO
t’nsaw tahT  .thguoht eht ta deklab I
,)su fo eerht lla fo tuo elkcuhc drawkwa na tog hcihw—
taht deveileb I ,saw I taht yug fo dnik lluf-flah-ssalg dna tneconni nA
derit saw liat degnir yM
.neht kcab tuo dnuof dah aP fi enod ev’dluow I tahw wonk t’ndid I  .tfel I litnu
.ees dluow enoemos deirrow
”.dnuora uoy wohs dluoc I  .elihwa yats uoy epoh I tub
.raey a rof notsoB ni deyats I
naem I ,driew tlef dah sgniht taht yas I nehW  .no denrut sthgilteerts eht
,retupmoc a ta yawa gnipyt dna gnuoy sraey ytenin ,ma I ereh oS
a gniraew rehtnap kcalb a saw eno ypeels ehT
os…ti tuoba klat ot tnaw t’ndid I dna ygrene eht evah t’ndid I
,yeH“  .seye teloiv emosdnah
.seliM dna nosaJ ,sdneirfyob ym ot uoy ecudortni em tel
”?no frus ot hcuoc a tog uoY“
.gnisu syawla era sdraob egassem eht no syug eht taht eno eht ,ppa gnitad yag a no tem I yug siht s’erehT“
.ecafrus eht no si racs yreve ton taht snrael uaeB woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
saw eh ekil dekool ti os srae sih dna daeh sih no der spit ruf sih deyd
.em htiw od ot tahw wonk
.notsoB ni ecalp sih ta elihwa yats emoc ot em detivni ,kciN fo eman eht yb yug a ,meht fo eno dna
.edualC otni depmub I nehw
tlef I dna dehsinif saw reeb yM  .deddon I
.sfeirb eulb yks fo riap a dna potknat
owt sih dna eh( meht fo eerht ehT  .pihsnoitaler suoromaylop a ni saw edualC  ”?sdneirfyob…mU“  .nepo gnuh htuom yM
era ohw nem ekil yllaer I naem I ,taht yB
ffo kcuf ot uoy sllet yteicos fi neve
:derewsna ylteiuq neht ,drah dewollaws ,daeh sih tsniaga kcab dedlof srae siH
,tniop siht litnu pu esuaceb si ereh trats I nosaer ylno ehT
.moor tnorf ynit a dna moordeb eno tsuj dah tnemtrapa ehT
.ediw smra sih gnidaerps
,degnahc swal eht sa nevE  .ti morf raF
smelborp ylimaf gnivah saw eh taht dias etoyoc eht ,ylraluger mih htiw gnittahc raey tsal ym nI
.dias edualC ”,ot dah enoemoS“
,sgnir liat gniyarg htiw nooccar a
.ekat t’nod uoy gniws yreve ssim uoy taht wonk osla I tub
,erehwyreve sbmil dna sgel
.ezeehw ot dedneterp I ”!…lleT…naC…I“
.ainrofilaC ot yaw ym no pots tser a sa anozirA gnitaert tsuj yltsenoh saw I dna
dna pan a morf pu nekow tsuj dah eh ekil eye na gnibbur eno
yeht woh ees ot gnitseretni saw ti dna ,cimanyd laiceps a dah oirt ehT  .dehctaw
.depoleved reve pihsdneirf mraw a naht erom gnihton tub
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knaht dna ,edirP yppaH
tog ew sa cisum tfos ot denetsil eW  .02/02 ,uoy rof thgisdnih
”.syad gnimag dlo sih gnissim s’eh nehw uoy tuoba sklat edualC  .seliM m’I
,notsoB ni devirra I litnu naeco eht nees reven dah I
ot evah t’nod uoy ,edualC“
.kcurt ym fo tuo tog dna delims I
.sdrow nekops sa evael tsuj ot doog oot erew yeht taht em dlot eh dna
saw I  .ylnepo os syug rehto guh
tnaem ti tahw tuoba hcum wonk t’ndid I tub ,nem
,dik a saw I nehw enilno ot ekops I enoemos saw edualC
”.egduj t’nod osla eW
.yhw sseug nac I ,kcab gnikooL
,pu peek ot tseb ruoy gniod er’uoy dna erom dna erom pu gnideeps eb ot smees dlrow eht nehw
dna worg detnalp ew sdees eht hctaw ot si od nac ew lla ,em ekil nem roF
.emas eht detnaw yeht tuo denrut ti dna meht fo htob morf erom detnaw I
.yug doog a m’I dlot dna dleh gnieb ekil I
.em htiw gniknub er’uoY  .yaw oN  ?letoh eht ta yats uoy tel ot gniog saw I kniht uoY“
.krad tnew I os ,aidem laicos no em gniklats ,em gniwollof
,ti nihtiw ecalp sih dna
,erom ecno ,gnihtyreve pu dekcap I oS
.etalp sih rof gnihcaer ,dias flow etihw eht
,anozirA litnu ,saw tahT
dna pu gniog tpek ew sa gurhs a htiw dehgual I
dna kcapkcab a ni sehtolc
.rae ym otni gnihtemos derepsihw dna ni denael eh
”.gnol oot esopmi ot tnaw t’noD  .erus toN“
neht ,citnamor eb dna ffo og edualC dna seliM ees I fi rehtona eno fo suolaej teg ew rehtehw naem uoy fI
yojne esaelP  .flesmih rof
.ffo tfel ew erehw thgir
peek ew lativ si ti edirP gniruD
.eciuj egnaro emos flesmih deruop eh sa elttil a delggig nosaJ  ”?tahw tuobA“
.lufreehc dna ,yldneirf ,mraw syawla saw etoyoc ehT
”?krow ti seod woh os ,yakO“
.gniK nomiS fo ygolirt eht dne ot nettirw gnieb yltnerruc si koob driht A
tsuj yltsom I ,meht htiw gnivil fo keew tsrif eht rof ,oS
wenk I dna ,stnerap ym
”…enigami t’nac I  .hguor
”.erofeb llif yllaer dluoc su fo enon
.tif dna ,emosdnah saw eH
pu dekcip I dna edualC taht ekil dnA
,seirecorg ro rac eht htiw pleh ot revo emac eh revenehw nooccar dlo siht fo gnilbmar eht ot denetsil eH  .nwod meht etirw I taht detseggus enim fo dneirf gnuoy A
”?drah ti t’nsI  ?ti niatniam uoy od woh tuB“
.efil ym ni gnihtemos gnissim saw I ezilaer em edam tI
.lla ti dias ecaf s’kciN  ”.deracs
mih ot ytinigriv ym tsol I
.seirots ruo ot netsil ot gnilliw era ohw esoht erutrun
”.tuoba gniklat er’uoy tahw wonk t’nod I“
meht tsuj saw ti gnikniht ,ti gnitarelot ,tib a rof dnuora kcuts I tuB
.ezilaer ot emoc noos dluow I esle enoemos ot degnoleb traeh sih ,sediseB
dah I fi peelsa llaf ot dednet I ecnis ,deretsalp
t’ndid ew ,ytilautca ni tuB  .sdneirf dlo erew ew ekil gnitca dna sekoj gnikam yb ti dih dna pu ti deyalp eW
.kcurt eht edistuo morf dias eciov a ”?uaeB“  .MP 02:3 deyalpsid won kcurt ym ni kcolc ehT  .MP 00:3 yb sserdda siht ot emoc ot dlot saw I  .gnivom doolb eht teg ot ti dekcilf I os—taes rac
.detnaw ew tahw erus saw su fo rehtien dna
.dnah ym pu dleh I  ”!haoW“
.won ytpme tsomla reeb ym
siht tuo gnirugif kcul yna dah uoy…kciN…oS“
.guh thgit ,ecin a otni em gnillup
.snoitseuq yna ksa t’nod uoy teY“
.dnalgnE nairotciV
.gnihtyreve tuoba llet ot yrots a dah eh ,dias dneirf tacbob ym sA
.retaw fo elttob dloc a em tog tacbob eht ,egdirf eht gninepO
?wonk uoy ,’nihton ro esopmi
!emit eht ta aedi on dah I hsog dna
.kniht I ,meht ekil I yhw s’tahT
.ecnahc a tog I nehw mih llac dluow I taht
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.tuo ti erugif yllareneg yeht ,su ot esolc steg enoemos fI
”.ydaerla swonk nwot eht erus m’I ,lleH
.gnidliub enotsnworb dlo na ta noonretfa remmus etal taht kcurt ym dekrap I nehw erots ydnac a ni dik a ekil saw I dna
.sllih nainigriV tseW eht ni repooC dellac nwot llams yllauqe na ni loohcs hgih llams a morf detaudarg ylhserf tsuj dah ohw nekcihc gnirps a saw I
.meht ot eybdoog yas ot dahI ,yllautneve oS“
,hcuoc derettab ym no tis netfo I ,hctib laer a si sitirhtra ym nehW  2 fo 1 traP ,ztiurF dna sgniRsuirebiT yb ”dnobagaV“
,renid eht ta etoyoc eht otni depmub I nehw oS
,gninrom eno litnu t’nsaw tI
.tacbob eht morf elims a em denrae tahT   ”.tnemgduj oN  .redluohs a eb si od nac I tsaeL  .ereh hsarc em gnittel yb tuo em gnipleh er’uoy ,yeH“
.yag gnieb rof puorg troppus ylno ym saw taht ,neht kcab tub
nrut s’seliM saw tI  ”?…ro driht
.rehtona eno ot klat ot woh wonk t’ndid I dna kciN  .drawkwa
.did I sa hcum sa tenretnI eht gnitsurt rof ymmud
”.uaeB ,gnisufnoc yllaer s’tI
.daeh sih koohs yltnemehev kciN   ”—ni
sdneirf yag dah enoyreve
er’yeht…naem I  .yltsenoh ,truh tI
.elttil a ffo wohs ot ti erow eh taht raelc saw ti tub ,eltbus saw tI
rosseforp eht htiw ni evom ot detnaw kciN tub ,esruoc fo
tuoba reverof klat nac dna—gnireenigne fo rosseforp a s’eh—detcepxe I naht redlo
.terces ytrid ym tuo gnittel detrats I fi em tpecca dluow elpoep
.notsoB evael ot dedeen I
?no gniog s’tahw
etiuq t’ndid taht dlrow a ni
.rehtona eno ot era ew woh dna pihsnoitaler ruo htiw elbatrofmoc m’I  .epon—
erew swal ;eurt si taht ,trap tsom eht roF
.pihsralohcs ym tog I  !ti noitnem t’noD“
.yluJ ni MA 53:4  .nwot ym tfel I tnemom eht rebmemer I
.ereht boj a teg em gnivah tuoba deklat neve eH
.repooC tfel I ecnis dnim ym no gninrub neeb dah taht noitseuq eht ksa ot egaruoc hguone derenrag I  .metsys
,lleW“  .em desirprus tahT    ”.on ,yllaer toN“
,seititnedi fo yteirav ruo
.tnereffid er’uoy esuaceb
.rewoT eht nwod nruB
”.siht uoy ksa em teL“
tog eW  .nwotnwod rab yag lacoL  .sdneirf erew eW“
.dnatsrednu reven dluow aP
,nug enihcam a ekil sdrow tuo gnitoohs saw tacbob ehT
.noitnetta detnawnu
.ti leef dluoc I ,kciN rof gnihtemos otno
.dedda nosaJ ”,od yeht eruS“
sdnuos tahT  .ezigolopa
.snoitseuq driew gniksa dna sevil rieht hguorht gnikcip
emos neewteb dekcut esuoh a derahs
efil ym ni sterger wef evah I
”?rof ereh uoy era gnol woH
,yelsneB rosseforP ot em decudortni kciN
ot tnaw t’ndid I“
.derewsna edualC ”?su fo eerht eht naem uoY“
.nirg etoyoc kramedart sih htiw dias edualC ”,setammooR“
)cificeps eb ot ,sdneirfyob
.kcab eht no yllaivoj em dettap eH
.htaenrednu selcsum sih fo senil eht ffo dewohs dna ydob sih ot gnulc
.tfel I retfa hcuot ni deyats sdneirf yM
sevlesmeht ot ti tpek sdneirf fo puorg llams ym yllufknahT
”.htap taht klaw ot tsrif eht ton m’I wonk ot ecin
,ecnarelot dna noitcetorp lauqe erusne ot thgir dna tfel dessap gnieb
,esrow ro daed pu dedne ev’dluoc I
os erew sruoh wef tsrif esohT
.oot ,spihsnoitaler raluger ni sneppah taht tuB“
erew nem owt ehT  ”?XR sretsaM gniR ni eca na saw ohw nooccar eht ,wonk uoY
dah I  .tner ym diap dna etammoor s’kciN emoceb yllaiciffo dah I
,rood tnorf eht ot gnihsur emac nem owt sa gnillaf teef yvaeh fo dnuos eht saw erehT
flesym dnuof I woh tuoba yrots a si siht dna—
.sklof gnuoy eht rof s’ti ,eromyna uoy rof t’nsi dlrow eht taht ezilaer ot ylno
eno gnol ,doog a devil I—
.daeh sih koohs neht ,rotpurretni sih ta delworg seliM ”!nosaJ“  ”.xes retfA“
.ni deppets ew dna tnemtrapa llams sih ot rood eht denepo tacbob ehT
.netfo taht ton s’ti tuB  .emit enola emos teg nosrep driht eht stel
.yag yllaer erew yeht fi wonk neve t’ndid ohw syob owt neewteb pihsdneirf drawkwa na no detrats notsoB ni emit yM  ”.ti
,shtnom wef yreve liame
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
”,heH“  ”…enoemos htiw noitasrevnoc a ni thguac tog I neht dna ereh tog uoy erofeb ettal a teg ot detnaw I  .etal elttil a saw I yrroS“  .sriats
”?nwot ni elpoep llet uoy od tahW“
”!nwod mlaC  .larenuf sih retfa efil a gninigami er’uoy won dna gnitad neve t’nerew uoy dias uoY
:segap eseht no nwod nettirw tnaw I dna tegrof reven ll’I gnihtemoS
efil ni egats taht ta flesym ot refer ot ekil I sa—”dnobagav“ a sa yrots yM  .enueJ ”uaeB“ tnomuaeB si eman yM
.emit puorg sa hcum sa tsuj
.erutnevda eht fo trap saw taht
.daeh sih ekahs ot
elihw dna ,efil ym ni syawla saw aP  .deddon I  ”.efil
.degnahc gnihton yllaer hguoht—degnahc dah tahw htiw spirg ot gnimoc
s’taht tuB  .gnivom teg yllanif ot gnol os nekat evah t’ndluow sgniht ,stib drawkwa eht tuoba deklat tsuj dah ew fI
.deracs m’I ,uaeB ,wonk t’nod I“
,noisiv thgin lufrednow ruo ni edirp ekat snooccar eW  .sllih eht ni dnif reve dluoc uoy srenim tseb eht fo eno saw eh tub ,gnola tog etiuq reven eW
”.ti ni doog dekool llits uoy tuB“
.senal yromem enog-gnol ym nwod gniog
,ekawa saw esle enoyna
?seid eh fi tuoba tahW
.tekcop kcab sih fo tuo gnignah
.htaenrednu liat degnir yhsub ym gnikcut ylluferac
.em rof emankcin sih saw tahT
tuoba yraw osla tub suoiruc ylbidercni saw I
.snirg etoyoc suomaf sih fo eno gnihsalf ,htoob eht ni nwod tas ew ecno dias edualC ”!ereh er’uoy eveileb t’nac I ,eduD“  .renid eht fo kcab eht ni htoob ralucric eht ot em del dna em dnuora mra sih dah eH
yrots siht woh si tahT
rehto hcae no desucof dna tuoba derac yllauqe
.rekihhctih flowerew ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
seno eht—ereht elpoeP  .hguoht ,gnorw em teg t’noD
em teg dluow ffo gniwohs
elpoep eht dna sthgis eht dna spirt eht gniyojne saw I yltsenoh hguoht ,efil ym fo doirep taht ni nem yag ynam teem t’ndid I
dna sffur keehc sih fo eno hguorht dnah sih nar dna pu dehcaer eH
.ffatsgalF ni ereh pu dedne
dah eH  .remmiws ralucsum
”.ereh sdneirf er’ew tub tcepser eht teg I
,sthgilhgih etalocohc klim thgil htiw deppit srae ,ruf deroloc-ydnas—
ti dna ,emit ot emit morf ffo riap eW
.spets sih ni ecnuob a htiw ygrene fo llabruf a
.enif eb dluow gnihtyreve dna yaw siht eb yllaer dluoc I taht ;tluda
.nem redlo otni
.laer yrev dna eurt saw ti—
.tsaf oot devom dah yteicos taht tnemugra eht rednu lla
.saw eh sa nepo sa eb dluoc I dehsiw I dna ,duorp
.edualC htiw neppah t’ndid emas eht tub ,su neewteb
.ztiurF yb detartsulli retpahc hcaE
dluoc uoy—ni devil osla tub naelc saw ecalp elohw ehT
dah eh ;dlrow elttil ym ni ytinilucsam fo elcannip eht neeb syawla dah eh nam teiuq a saw eh
,erehwyreve stnemevomretnuoc erew erehT