.reffus t’ndid dna
”,taht ekil elpoep egduj t’nod I“
.efil fo sklaw lla morf elpoep fo sdnik lla htiw daorb dna esrevid saw tI
,ylsuovren liat sih hctiwt regit eht dehctaw I
lauxesomoh a eb ot tnaem ti tahw ni nossel yrotsih a teg ot tuoba saw I
tsipareht a ees ot tnew eh
flesruoy gnicarbme dna
.enim ekahs ot dnah tnaig sih tuo gnidloh ,em revo derewot eh ,elbat eht morf pu doots eh nehW
oc evah ohw ,ztiurF & sgniR suirebiT yb
,t’nod I dna dneirf ym llits er’uoy tuB“  .gninworf
.emit eht lla yppah os tsuj erew yeht taht saw em kcurts taht gniht ehT
I dna ,deirram tog ew erofeb
”.taht tuoba deirrow er’uoy fi ,uoy tuoba ssel gnihtyna kniht ,wonk uoy
.tuo dehcaer dna hsarc ot ecalp a rof gnitseuqer tsop ym was nam A
dehctaw I  .tnuoc ot tnaw I naht slarenuf erom ot neeb ev’I
a sa od ot dedeen I ffuts eht lla fo tsil eht ffo dekcehc I
enoemos ,efil ym ni dlonrA ekil enoemos detnaw I taht neht dezilaer I
.yllaitini mih fo tuo elbmum a naht erom teg ot tluciffid ylbidercni saw ti neht neve dna
,uoy naht redlo raey eno
doog os gnileef tfel I  .uaeB
,ylwols eid—nem lufrednow—nem doog
I dna ,gnivol erom ,citnamor erom eb ot em detnaw ehs llet dluoc I tub
dna em deppots eh ,nwotnwod hguorht gniklaw elihw thgin enO
,tcirtsiD noissiM eht ni doof lufrednow eht gnitae
noitseuq eht tuo erugif em depleh ohw efil ym ni elpoep lufrednow tem I
I thgin taht dna ,tengam a ekil mih ot nward
.no dehsup I ,llitS“
sa ylraed meht ssim I
.ereht sraey owt tneps I
.semag oediv gnikam weiV niatnuoM ni pu dekrow eH
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna
.su neewteb detaroireted ylkciuq sgnihT“
:reganeet a saw I ecnis dnim ym no syawla saw taht
”.em ot pu denepo dlrow ym
rood eht ta meht gniteerg nooccar a was daetsni dna regit a detcepxe yeht ecnis ,rof meht emalb t’nac I hcihw—desirprus dekool eH  .ereht gnidnats ega ym tuoba regit gnuoy a was I
,revo detoocs ylteiuq I
.emit ssorca gnihtemos ta gnikool eb ot demees dna desucofnu seye sih sa delims dlonrA
.mrah-fles fo sthguoht derudne gnivah retcarahc a fo edam si noitnem
.tcepxe ton did I mrahc a htiw em ta nwod delims eH
,yrotsih yag fo
.enola…lla evoba dna ,yllufniap
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
syawla eh ,emoh saw I dna rennid ot tuo og ot detnaw eh nehw tuB  .reffo
.yrotirret detrahcnu saw sihT  .ega ym dnuora gnirevoh nem sediseb em ni tseretni nwohs dah eno on won litnU
did I hcihw ,em htiw sbulc eht ro srab eht ot tuo og ot detnaw reven eH
.yag eb ot tnaem ti tahw tuo erugif ot nwot llams sih tfel eh woh tnuocer ot nageb uaeB rotarran ruo ,emit tsaL
ho…rab a ta yug a tem I“
.ailanrehparap emag oediv rehto dna semag fo sevlehs dna srotinom ,sretupmoc suoirav htiw hcnebkrow gnol a saw erehT
”.hguoht ,neeb evah dluohs I swonk droL
,gniroloc detum htiw moor eht enohs gniliec eht otni tes thgil egral A
.elbat eht ot denoitom dna dias regit eht
dna hcet siht rof erawdrah eht edam I“  .diulf dna psirc
emos ekat ot detnaw eh desirprus elttil a saw I
.em llet ot gniyrt saw dlonrA tahw s’taht kniht I
”.dnuora emac reven taht yllufknahT .oot
dna efiw a dah uoy esuaceb…naem uoY“
noitarbelec a sa dednetni si yrots s’yadot elihw
,s’08 eht fo cimedipe SDIA eht dna ,kliM yevraH sa hcus
dah eh( yadrutaS rehto yreve puorg snogarD dna snoegnuD
,dliw semitemos erew mih htiw tneps syaD
esucxe yna dnif ot gniyrt saw I
,taht tuoba deracs tsomla saw I
.tnetnoc tlef I taht efil ym ni emit tsrif eht
”.efiw ym tem dna saw I ohw em edam tahw tuoba gnihtyreve dewollaws
,naem I tahw wonk uoy fi ,ytiliba ym esol
semit ynam llam eht ot em thguorb eH  .syug
saw taht eeffoc fo puc gnimaets eht dnuora sregnif ym gnipparw ,nwod tas I  ”.sknahT“    ”.taert yM
tpek dna edisni lla ti tpek I  .lufwa os dna
,detcefni neeb dah I fi ,taht dezilaer dna reh no detaehc I elihw semit lareves efiw ym htiw peels ot deirt dah I
dluow I ffuts neve ,sehtolc fo sdnik lla no yrt em dah dna
.meht dnuora elpoep eht ot thguorb yeht yoj tahw dna
.ylthgit mih gnigguh ,dlonrA ot pu deklaw
.ni deppets eh sa dias eh ”,yeH“
,hguoht ,ffo gniwohs tuoba lufhsab saw eH
.sih eb ot desu taht ksed eht ta gnittis ,yawa gnipyt ,won thgir esuoh eht ni m’I  .yenom fo tnuoma gnisirprus rehtar
dna derudne eW  .srettam
.ti eveileb nac uoy fi ,nigriv eulb eurt
erom esuoh eht fo tuo em gniwollof detrats eH
,eerf eb ,flesruoy eb dluoc uoy ekil tlef uoy esuaceb detarebil tlef uoy dnah eno nO
a saw I  .thgin gniddew ym no suovren os saw I rebmemer I  .deirram tog
,htiw eb ot detnaw yeht ohw elpoep eht dnuof dah yeht taht llet dluoc uoY
erehw tnew I ,anozirA gnivael retfA
.rehtie ,ekaf t’nsaw tI
.selbuort ym hguorht em ediug pleh dluoc ohw erutam dna esiw
,won gniyrc ylnepo saw nam ehT
.roirp sedaced eht
I…tub dnik dna evitroppus saw I  .taht llifluf
dik yag a tsuj naht erom eb dluoc I dezilaer I taht ffatsgalF ni saw tI
”.flesym ekil gnileef yllanif saw I esuaceb ylimaf gnuoy ym morf yawa emit gnidneps ,yawa gnikaens
.ti rof dedlocs eb dluow eh ekil gnitca
.yrros m’I ,syad esoht ni laicifrepus os saw I  .neht kcab
,ecnedifnoc erom ,ecneirepxe erom dah I
,ni elttes ot gninnigeb erew ohw nem erew esehT
.truh eb ot deracs os saw I esuaceb sgniht gnileef morf ffo flesym tuc
.erutinruf paehc thguob reven dlonrA
,etaG nedloG eht gniees ,zartaclA ot gnioG
,gnivorpmi yletinifed erew sgniht ,dik a saw I nehw kcab ,eruS
,pihsnoitaler suoires a dah reven I  .enola osla saw I tub ,yppah saw I
.taert sih syawla saw ti dna ,em detivni
moor ym ni deyats dna emit rieht evah ylimaf eht tel I os ,ni egrab ot etilopmi eb dluow ti thguoht tub ni nioj ot detnaw I
.emit doog a gnivah dna
.ssendnik ot eye dnilb a nrut ot gniog ton saw I tub ,ni ffar ffir
.rewoT eht nwod nruB ,leuqes eht gnihsilbup yltnerruc era dna ,tsuD ot emoC ,rellirht egA nairotciV rieht nettirw-
tsniaga og dna sevlesmeht eb ot tesolc eht fo tuo semoc ohw nosrep yrevE
.enim ni did yeht ekil nem yag etah t’nseod taht yteicos a ni flesruoy eb ot
.erom gnihtemos fo llup eht tlef dah I ,niaga ecno dna
,VT no nees ylno d’I sgniht eht gniees dna doowylloH ot gniog
,einrA“  ”?klat ew naC“
,ot klat ot ohw ,ot nrut ot ohw wonk t’ndid I
,dlonrA dnuora smra ym tup
,efil ym ni emit tsrif eht roF
tcartta ot detnaw I fi sserd yllaer ot woh em dewohs nosaJ
.llet ot erom hcum os syawla si ereht os ,dettimo ro dewodahsrevo netfo si yrotsih ruO  .elpoep
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA   .rekihhctih
.gnivil t’nsaw I ,noitcnuf ot elba saw I elihw dna ,nwod traeh ym tuhs I
.sessalg demmir neerg htiw
,gnigru ym tA  .esolc yrev emaceb ew ,yad taht retfA
anozirA ffatsgalF ni emit sih gniyojne uaeB tfel eW  .mih htiw secneirepxe rieht derahs ohw tenretni eht morf sdneirf tem eh yenruoj sih nO
.eulg ekil kciN ot kcuts dah I taht bulc yag a ni nwo ym no eb ot deracs os saw I erehw
.no gnikrow m’I taht epytotorp a si ffuts siht tub won tekram eht no s’tI“  .denialpxe eh
.drah dewollaws dlonrA
.nruter ni gnihton rof deksa dna hcum os em evag ohw sdneirf eseht gnirebmemer ,deb ot og I
.nocab dna sgge delbmarcs rof gnikool ni nevird
.syaw ynam os ni em rof gnidrawer neeb sah ,uaeB
tub stekcop stnap desserp-yltaen sih ni sdnah sih htiw evael ot denrut dlonrA
yeht hguoht( ytrap dna emit eht lla tuo og ot deen ro tnaw t’ndid
erew stnemevom ehT  .drows tnaig a gnidleiw—regit deroloc eulb a—ratava na fo RV ni edam dah eh gnidrocer a em dewohs eH
,efil gnuoy ym fo tnemom gnitarebil tsom eht neeb dah ti tuB
erew dna ,)did llits yletulosba
,yadot dna ,gnilhctah a sa neht kcab etanutrof saw I
t’ndid I syaw ni em truh mih gnisoL
.sgniht ytsiruot eht did I ,esruoc fo ,tsrif sgniht tsriF  .sedaced
.boj a dnif em pleh ot dereffo
.kcab semoc syawla yoj dna
,sraey eseht lla retfa nevE  ?yag eb ot
,reh evol od llits I dna ,reh devol I
.pleh ym rof gnidaelp saw eH
”?naem uoy od tahW“
”.thgir leef t’ndid gnihtemos taht gnikniht rebmemer I tuB
sesrun eht ,slatipsoh eht ni gniyd dna kcis erew nem eseht nehW
rof ot gnikcolf neeb dah elpoep +AIQTBGL erehw ecalp a
meht raen og ot tnaw t’ndid
si ruhtrA“    .htaerb
.dellirht tahwemos osla tub
,god.ecioveht ta
.sdraob egassem wef a no tuo eman ym tup I os
.dah reve d’I tseb eht fo emos yldettimda
.ereh yllaicepsE
detah I  .dnuora emoc ot sraey em koot tI“
.llaw eht gnidloh dna gnitnap ,renroc eht nwod gninnur emac eh sa detuohs dlonrA ”!tiaW“
.ti dekil I tub ,redlo enoemos htiw flesym ees dluow I thguoht reven I neht litnU
gniddew rieht ot tnew I
.eeffoc emos uoy gniredro fo ytrebil eht koot I“
neve dna enif saw taht
.ycnaived ym yfsitas ylno ot detnaw dna sloohcs deklats
I taht ,nerdlihc gnisuba tuoba og dluoc I thguoht elpoeP
,kcis reh nettog evah dluoc I
,ereh secalp tsom ot derapmoc hcum tib a eb yam esuoh ehT“
,uaeB dna…thgin eno ortsaC eht
.ti rof toidi na saw I dna nodnaba sselkcer
.bos mih tlef I dna redluohs ym otni ecaf sih deirub eH
taht safos devruc gnitanimulli
naem ti seod tahW
taht wenk I tub ,tcepxe
.)naf a emaceb ylkciuq I dna emag eht otni em depor
erew yeht yppah woh
.lanimirc a gnieb sa emas eht tsomla saw yag gnieb ,nam regnuoy a saw I nehw…nehW“
”.sbons esoht fo eno ton ma I taht wonk tsuj tub
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,enola ton era uoy taht rebmemer ot uoy egru god fo eciov eht ta eW
.nus eht ekil pu til ecaf s’dlonrA sa dehctaw I
.sreh I dna secnetnes ym hsinif dluoc ehs ,sdneirf tseb
.daeh ym detlit I
”.saw I ohw gnieb
erofeb thgin yreve erutcip rieht ta kool I
.esuoh eht revo lla sllaw eht otni neddih neercshcuot
.snosaer lufrednow tub tnereffid rof rehto hcae dedeen htob ew taht
”.gnihtyna em llet ot evah t’nod uoy
peels sih ni tnew eH
ot elba saw I yhw s’taht kniht I
)duol oot erew sbulc eht dias eh hguoht(
.gnihtemos em wohs ot detnaw eh fi mih rof emit ekam ot noissim ym ti edam I
,nem ot detcartta saw I wenk ehS  .reh noows ro
,doohrobhgien yag eht ot og ot egaruoc eht pu dekrow yllanif dah I  .emit revo krow
nam yag a eb dluoc I—
dna em dessap delcsum regit regnuoy ehT
sih dna krow morf dneirf ddo eht sediseb
.dereffus evah tsum nam eht hcum woh fo thguoht eht ta sraet gniddehs flesym leef osla dluoc I noos ytterP
.elbmuh saw dlonrA
.yltfos dias I ”,einrA
,ocsicnarF naS fo ytic lacirotsih eht ni flesym dnuof noos I dna yawhgih eht pu em dellup gnihtemos tub
”?dlonrA er’uoY  .em s’tahT“
t’ndid eH  .noitareneg a ni ecno
,lleH  .taht ti dellac yllaer eno on tub ,cimedipe SDIA eht saw ereht ,neht kcaB“
.daeh ym koohs dna yletilop delims I
.efil fo dnik taht htiw evirht dna
tuo hcaer ot dna
.yag eb ot doirep lufwa na saw emit taht ,uaeB“
”dnobagaV“   yojne esaelP
tlef I  .teef ym ffo em tpewS  .kniht I ,noil a ,hsog
.meht rof tnaem t’nsaw ti ekil ,ffo osla tub enif tlef ti taht dias nemow htiw tpels dah ohw nem yag taht wenk I  .saw
”dnobagaV“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.yletilop em hsuhs ot dnah sih detfil regit rehT
.dnobagav a sa yenruoj ym eunitnoc ot daor eht no kcab saw I oS
.sevil rieht gnipoleved
,gniht dab a ton s’tahT“
htiw yddig eb ot demees dlonrA
.ainrofilaC—seog ylbativeni aciremA dnuora yenruoj gnirednaw a no enoyreve
.gniK nomiS fo ygolirt eht dne ot nettirw gnieb yltnerruc si koob driht A
,sevil rieht gnirahs elpoep ot gninetsil—secneirepxe eseht lla retfa
,rood eht derewsna I nehW
.edisni kcab emac dna ,daeh sih koohs ,deppots
.laeh mih pleh ot enoemos dedeen eh dna dednuow saw dlonrA
.ma I sa dlo sa eb ot ykcul denmad m’I
htiw dnuora tpels I
,ot tnaw t’ndid syob eht nehw semit ynam tuo enog dah I ,ereh tuB
ecnahc eht evah uoY
flowerew ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
tnew uoy erehwyreve ti draeh uoY
ym eb ot hguone dlo saw nam sihT  .ydob sih revo tfird ot gnitnaw seye ym gnileef tpek I
.meht htiw sthgin tneps
meht truh dluoc ti taht aedi on dah I  .ega elddim otni llew yag gnieb htiw elggurts dluoc dlonrA ekil elpoep dnik
.htooms dna mraw saw eciov siH  ”?uaeB“
.wenk ehs erus m’I“
.thgilf ekat dna daeha og ,oS
,edirP yppaH
.tuo na dah I taht sreerac ruo dna syob eerht fo erac gnikat htiw ysub os htob erew ew syob eht dah ew nehW
.ytiledifni ym tuoba luferac ton
dna sbulc yag eht ta nem dnuof I efil ym fo trap eht saw tahT
yawa seog niap taht s'ti ,modsiw fo lenrek eno trapmi nac I fi tuB
.gniworrob saw I moordeb eht ro—
.yldneirf ylbidercni osla tub devreser saw dlonrA
fo aedi eht no neek ssel tol a dna eerf erom tol a saw xes ,neht kcaB  .etar dipar a ta nem yag gnillik saw ti tub ,saw ti tahw wenk yllaer eno on
,syob ym tuoba uoy dlot evah dluohs I
.emoh kcab nrow evah reven
ecnerefer fo tniop eht tahw wonk t’ndid I os erofeb namow a htiw tpels reven dah I
.eb ot ton drah deirt I oS  …em ekil t’ndid yteicos taht dna ,gniyd erew sdneirf ym taht dna
.gnilims saw eh tub ,ecaf sih nwod gnimaerts sraet htiw em ta derats dlonrA   ”.ot desu I ekil nem yag rehto dnuora eb ot woh wonk
.retal sraey neves yawa dessap dlonrA
.ylnmelos deddon dlonrA  ”?sdik
yug hcet laer a saw eH
tuoba thguoht dah I
.rood ym no dekconk dlonrA taht tfel ruhtrA litnu t’nsaw tI
—   .dnobagav raed ym ,derevocsid eb ot hcum llits s’erehT
.mih htiw tnew I fi og ylno dluow eh dias tub
saw I  .tarD“  .detnurg eH
.no neht morf devlovni yllacitnamor emaceb eW
.gninrom txen eht litnu emoh emoc t’ndid I dna
,yldettimda ,saw gninrael dna htworg fo doirep tahT
,yag gnieb em no ti demalb reven ehS
.suoicerp si yenruoj hcaE
,seitinummoc dna sdraob egassem enilno on ,syad esoht ni tenretnI eht ekil gnihtyna t’nsaw ereht—
.gnol tsal t’ndid ti taht deticxe os saw I ,hsinif
.uaeB ,ecno naht erom edicius deredisnoc I
,yrotsih ruo tuoba gnihtemos denrael I
.esle gnihtemos saw ti—gninnigeb eht morf taht llet dluoc I ,em ecnamor ot gniyrt t’nsaw eH
.tol a hguorht neeb dah su erofeb nem eht taht ezilaer ot detrats dna
.revo mih krow ot gnitrats sraey eht ees dluoc uoy tub ,myg eht ta emit sih htiw pu tpek ohw nam a—
.tnereffid si yenruoj hcaE
dluow I emit eht fo tsom dna ,netfo snoitaler lauxes evah t’ndid eW
.pohs eeffoc lacol a ta pu teem ot dediced eW
rebmemer I ,gnissap rieht tuoba das leef I nehw tuB
,rosseforp sih dna kciN fo kniht em edam tI
.enilno wenk I elpoep eht tsuj dnoyeb derised dna yxes tlef I
uoy htiw erahs ot detnaw I gnihtemos si ,redaer raed ym ,tahT
.kaeps ot os ,gniw rieht rednu em koot osla yehT
,dehcuot spil ruo nehw ,dezilaer I  .yag gnieb tuoba
,ylimaf ym tsol I taht detah I  .yag gnieb
.xes eht gniyojne saw I dna
tub emaf ro yenom tuoba erac
.dneirf ym saw ohw namow a gnitruh saw I dna ,elpoep doog ynam os tsol I“
.ztiurF yb detartsulli retpahc hcaE
gnihton wenk dna efil ym ni devlovni os reven saw aP nwo yM
.noitalubirt emos
,htiw pihsnoitaler a poleved ot enoemos rof gnikool ,gnitrilf saw I tub
.spil eht no em dessik
,dessarrabme demees eH
”.yawyna gnihtemos fo elddim eht ni saw I  .einrA ,taews oN“
,ztiurF & sgniRsuirebiT yb ”dnobagaV“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
.ti dekil I tub ,ssik eht fo ekam ot tahw erus t’nsaw I tsrif tA
ro emoh og ton ot
.yenom dah nam siht taht neht dezilaer I
a htiw dellortnoc eb dluoc emoh eht ni gnihtyreve woh em gniwohs
.zurC atnaS ot devom dna ,syob ruo koot
dah I taht dezilaer I
.koTkiT esu ot woh tuo erugif did reven dlonrA
.regit gnuoy eht tuoba noitalever siht yb ylpeed dehsulb dlonrA
s’ti tub ,reirrab taht odnu ot drah dekrow ev’I
dias eH  .emit fo tnuoma etanimretedni
,setalocohc ro srewolf reh gnirb ot erised eht tog reven
,noituac fo drow A
a eb thgim siht thguoht I ,da ruoy was I nehW“
tuoba s’ti ,rehtar tub ,snoci etaroproc dna swobniar tuoba t’nsi yag gnieb taht—
,aera siht ni enoyna wonk yllaer t’ndid I  .ytic eht fo
”,degrahc sa ytliuG“
.enola nos dna rehtaf eht tfel I
.detnaw I tahw dna saw I ohw fo gnidnatsrednu retteb a dna
.sevil rieht fo tser eht rof rehtegot erew seliM dna ,nosaJ ,edualC
,efil sih tuoba em ot pu nepo ot mih rof shtnom koot tI
t’nac llits I—tem tsrif ew emit eht ta ega s’dlonrA tsomla saw I nehw dnabsuh etal ym gniyrram ,nem wen gniteem
.regnol detsal evah dluoc ti hsiw tsuj I
.em naht redlo hcum os enoemos gnitad fo ytilaer eht saw siht
.ocsicnarF naS ni erutluc yag eht gnivol flesym dnuof I dna no tnew skeeW
.em decaf dna riahc a no tas eH
,thgin yreve ton ,emit eht lla toN
.secneirepxe evitisop yltsom dah I taht ykcul yrev saw I taht won dezilaer I  .hcum os
.ytic eht dekoolrevo llih a otni tes saw taht esuoh sih otni em del dlonrA
saw eH  .ruf egnaro taht rednu gnilppir selcsum emos evresbo did I hguoht ,tcepxe dluow uoy ecarg enilef etlevs taht evah ton did ydob sih dna derit elttil a dekool seye siH
.pihsnoitaler ylop-yag sih dna edualC htiw
taem eht otni hteet ym knas I erofeb tsiruot
”?ereh dlonrA si ,yeH“
.daed ton fi gniyd ro kcis erew sdneirf ym ,siht lla fo pot nO  .thguoht I os ro
meht fo tcepxe yam yteicos tahw
”.meht denodnaba seilimaf rieht dna
.swov ym dna efiw ym no detaehc
.deid dna kcis tog sdneirf ym fo ynam os ,uaeB ,dog ho…tub
saw I dna ,evah dluohs enoyna naht erom rof ti derudne ehS
.ylenol saw nam ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ecaf sih fo ruf eht no niart tsiom a gnimrof sraet
?wonk uoy ,namow taerg a saw ehS“
,lairt emos ecaf lliw
,ereh gnieb uoy tuB  .eerged emos ot ,uoy hguorht ylsuoiraciv efil wen siht gnivil ot timda I dna suoivne m’I
dennuhs dah I tuo dnuof uoy fi em no nwod kool dluow uoy diarfa saw I tub
”,edoc eht gninifer neeb ev’I
dnuora emac ohw sluos esoht fo eno saw nam eht dnuof I ,enohp ym no pu mih kool ot elba saw I nehW
htiw etelpmoc ,srellortnoc dna selggog RV erew llaw eht nO
,em tfel ehs dna em dnuora nwod gnihsarc emac lla ti yllautnevE
,redrah gniyrt ton yb ylimaf ruo nekorb dah I tub
.secived gnikcart laicaf dna ydob-lluf
.ti fo tnemom yreve gnivol yleniuneg erew yeht dna
enueJ ”uaeB“ tnomuaeB
.ot klat ot eno on dah I  .yawyna seno gib ton
.eno degnir ym htiw deniwtretni dna dnuora dehcaer liat depirts sih ,thgin taht emoh deklaw ew sA
.ti rof dehsup I fi efil ni teg dluoc I tahw em dewohs yllaer ohw nem eht meht redisnoc I
erew eW  .krow ta llew os gnola tog eW
.erom ees ot denraey I
tsev a dna trihs pu nottub ecin a gniraew
”.ti tuoba klat ot yako…m’I kniht I“
.snaem ti tahw uoy llet
.llet nac uoy erus m’I ,pu llits
dah ohw etyhpoen eht ton saw I ,anozirA tfel I nehW
.pleh deen uoy fi
”.uaeB ,neht kcab emit tnereffid a saw ti ,llew…I
.wonk uoy os tsuj ,llew sa htnom siht emitemos yb pots ot gniog ylbaborp era owt rehto ehT  .stelpirT
.esolc dna ylthgit mih degguh dna
”.tiaw uoy tsuj ,yad eno rojam gnihtemos eb ot gniog s’ti tub taerg ton s’tI
ym tuoba mih ot denialpxe I
.kniht elpoep tsom naht redrah si
,eno yb enO  …rewoT ortuS ot gniog
deen fo esuaceb resolc dellup erew ew kniht I—su htiw tnereffid saw ti tub
?noitareneg ym erofeb nem eht tuoba tahw tub
.edisni eht no wen dna suoromalg saw tub edistuo eht no dlo dekool esuoh ehT  .krowtra dna safos gnikool-evisnepxe htiw swodniw egral dah tI
stseug dah reven eH  ?ega ym saw taht emoh enoemos gnitivni gniod dlonrA saw tahW ,gnikniht ylterces tub ,dias I ”,haeY“
na rof ytic eht ni yats ot gnikool saw I taht dna ”erutnevda“
.derevocer ylkciuq tub—
peed a koot dlonrA sa yletilop denetsil I
.gninrom yadnuS eno rood tnorf eht no kconk a saw ereht nehw daeh a ot emac lla ti tub
.sdrawtuo ton ,sdrawni decaf lla
ot woh wonk t’ndid
!evitcartta saw eh tub ,aP
evah I  .owt ro htnom a ekat ro evig
.notsoB ni t’ndluoc I taht yaw a ni erutluc yag eht decarbme yllaer I nehw emit eht sa ffatsgalF ni nruojos ym fo kniht I  2 fo 2 traP ,ztiurF dna sgniRsuirebiT yb
ecnis nwonk dah ehs
woh ezilaer ot gnitrats saw ehs kniht
gnikool-doog llits saw regit ehT
.nuf gnivah llits elihw dluoc eh sa raf sa egdelwonk sih hsup dna dlrow eht ot gnihtemos evig ot detnaw
.noitcetorp lauxes
.yletelpmoc nwod emoc sreirrab eht tel tsuj ot em rof ytinutroppo taerg
yllaer…t’nod I dna tol a flesym tuoba klat t’nod I
”.dlonrA ,erew uoy yrros os m’I dna“ ,dias I
.nediA dna werdnA ,snos rehto owt
.noissap taht ot tnematset a saw ned sih dna
a dna emoh sih em tfel regit ehT
.seye ekil-srecuas htiw sregit gnicarbme eht ta gnirats ereht doots I dna deffup liat degnir yM   ”!daD yeH“
tesolc eht fo tuo gnimoC  ————
,doog taht aedi on dah I
,nerdlihc dah dna seitud ylrehtaf ym enod dah I
.slarenuf rieht—yldas—dna
”.uaeB ,uoy erofeb rood eht ot teg ot gniyrt
.lla retfa ,eerf-tner ereh evil em gnittel saw eH
.seye sih depiw dna ecaf sih morf sessalg sih dekculp regit redlo ehT  ”.saw ti eurt
I dna yag ton saw I flesym decnivnoc I oS
.moor emag eht ni nuf gnivah meht draeh I hcihw gnirud ,sruoh rof dnuora kcuts ,ruhtrA ,nos ehT
taht yaw eht ni ton…tub
.regit redlo na saw eH
,notsoB ni evah t’ndid I modeerf fo dnik a saw tI
.emoselohw syawla tub ,ynnuf semitemos
.ti htiw yako saw ehs tsrif ta dna
.noitcartta lauxes erup naht rehtar
htiw sdneirf eb ot tuo thguos evah dluow I enoemos ton yletinifed saw eh tub…wonk uoy…sa ”dlo“ toN