,tcaf nI .erofeb deneppah reven dah flesmih nihtiw noitome eniuneg
.skooB goD daB yb ,5 raoR rof noissimbus a sa yrots siht etorw ohw
”.lla ta elbuort on s’tI“
no og ot erom elttil dah eh dna stluser deetnaraug derussa dah sweiver eht tub
sweiver remotsuc htiw ylhgih derocs dah koob ehT .rehcsE .C.E yb
.edis regnessap eht otni gnippets
.ti denepo eh tnemom eht unem sih deppord ylraen yeroC
eson sih ni srotpecer etaciled eht ta delkcit maetS
,naem I .pu teem ot detnaw uoy fI .ti tnaw uoy fi
,kiavoJ dnaloR yb ”selbairaV“
.deilper netsE ”,iH“
.teerts eht nwod regrub a gnitteg reippah eb d’I .em rof siht od ot uoy tnaw t’nod I“
,xes rof msimehpue a saw esarhp eht mih dlot hcraeseR
.tuo ti dleh eh sa roolf eht ta neht
,denrael dah eh ,sgniht esehT
.yletauqeda desserd er’uoY“
.swarts dna stekcap ragus htiw gniwolfrevo
.noisneherpmoc dnoyeb demees noiton ehT
.terref eht fo etisoppo riahc eht otni knuls dna sgel sih neewteb dekcut llits liat
.derusaem ro detaluclac eb t’ndluoc tsuj taht
nrut t’ndid eH .netsE deksA
yeroC ta revo ecnalg a htiw dehsinif eh ”,sessalg owT“
pihstruoc gnirud esora taht snoitautis laciteroeht eht nialpxe ot no tnew koob ehT
.desuap yeroC ”.yeh ,hO“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.iH“ .rekaeps eht hguorht deppils kaeuqs deticxe s’xof eht sa gniltsur citnarf a dna rettalc duol a saw erehT ”!netsE“
.sthguoht sih tcelloc ot
,tas osla yraid sih erehw wodniw eht ot revo edorts eH  .nwotnwod fo
.ilumits s’dlrow eht ot yletairporppa tcaer ot mih wolla dluow taht sesnes fo tes nwo sih
;yawa elim a gnimoc was eh tahw rof hguone tsaf tcaer ton dluoc netsE
,eugnot s’diordna eht ffo gnillor drawkwa tlef sdrow ehT
pu pets ot revres eht rof emit ni tsuj unem eniw eht htiw flesmih deipucco netsE
.ylrettib taps eh ”,klaw ll’I“
,yawa deklaw dna deffocs retto ehT
.derettum eh ”,selbairav ynam ooT“
.stekcop sih otni swap sih dekcut dah yeroC tub
,ecno naht erom yeroC htiw seye thguac eH
.siht sa hcus serutidnepxe dennalpnu rof yawa dehsats yenom fo ytnelp dah eh
,emit lausu sih ta efac eht otni deppets netsE nehw taht tpecxE
.gnitrilf fo tca evitceffe tub ,elpmis a demees tI
daeh sih tsniaga deretsalp erew srae deppit-kcalb siH
.skrow erutuf yna gnitsop eb lliw eh erehw egap yrruFoS sih gniviver no gnikrow yltnerruc si eh
”,eciohc tnellecxE“
”!ecalp tsrif eht ni meht ees ot tnaw t’ndid I“
.thgieh lluf ta elzzum s’xof eht fo trohs sehcni wef a tsuj gnimoc ,eganam dluoc eh sa llat sa doots dna
.desserd saw eh woh tuoba suoicsnoc-fles yrev dekool eh dna
erew ereht tub ,hcum mih thguat dah koob ehT
gnihtyna yas dluoc terref eht erofeB
sa terpretni ylno dluoc eh tahw fo esnes railimafnu na dna elzzum sih ot elims feirb a thguorb
”,eciton trohs hcus no raew ot recin gnihtyna dnif t’ndluoc I yrroS“
.lautir xelpmoc a hcus htiw laed ot tneiciffusni yltnerruc si gnimmargorp yM
.ecin ecalpemos meht ekaT
.netsE ot yretsym a fo tahwemos neeb syawla dah xob ehT
”—esaelp ,xuagraM uaetahC eht evah ll’ew ,seY“
”?thginot sknird emos barg ot tnaw uoy did ,oS“
sa noitome eht dezingocer eH
koobeton sih ot revoc eht desolc netsE
.laem eht rof gniyap t’nsaw eh fi secirp eht yb tespu eb dluoc yeroC woh dnatsrednu t’ndid eH
”?gniog uoy era erehW“ .rac eht dekrap dah netsE erehw morf yawa ,yawklaw eht nwod ffo demrots dna leeh sih no denrut yeroC ”!em gnidulcni ,uoy dnuora enoyna ot dnim on gniyap elihw dnuora yenom ruoy gniworht tnetnoc yltcefrep demees uoY
.s’xof eht tsniaga ti gnihsurb
.flehs eht no kcab ti tup dna egap laudividni hcae hguorht pilf ot deganam dah eh setunim net nI
,rac sih ot kcab deklaw eH
”.uoy llac ll’ew ,esaelp ereht revo tis dluoc uoy fI
.os did eh sa yeroC no regnil ezag sih gnittel ,ssalg hcae otni eniw eht deruop erdnA
”.ereh emoclew leef t’nod I
,dnim on meht diap netsE
pu dellor netsE
,eit der a htiw trihs pu-nottub elprup a ni desserd tuo emac yeroC
,desum netsE ,ekil eb ti dluow tahW
”?etad a eb ot siht rof dnetni ton uoy diD“
”.netsE s’tI“ ”?siht s’ohW“
seinomitset dna sessentiw evah dluow eh
.ereh morf selim si ecalp ruoY“
.xof eht ta pu gnicnalg yllanoisacco ylno elihw smeti doof eht revo gnicart
.laiceps leef rentrap ruoy ekaM
.snikpan revotfel emos htiw llips eht pu depiw eh
”?yako ,noitnetta erom yna tcartta ot tnaw t’nod I
.taht tuoba yrrow ot deen on s’erehT“
.ni tes ydaerla dah sniats eeffoc eht tub ,snikpan ybraen emos htiw flesmih debbad ylkciuq eH
.ecnetsixe sih egdelwonkca ot ydaer t’nsaw ylpmis dlrow eht dna
reehc lufhsab s’xof eht fo dioved saw pohs ehT
.dehsinruf ylesraps dna llams saw tnemtrapa ehT
.raf oot elttil a tsuj puc eht deppit d’eh
”?ecalp nwotpu yztir tahT“
.ecaf sih revo sdnah sih htiw tnaruatser eht morf nar dna
.ffats eht htiw troppar doog gnidliub fo laog sih otni llew deyalp sihT .’hsurc a gnivah‘
.detpurretni eh ”,rebmemer I“
,ecnanetniaM nuG dna gnitaD fo trA ehT
.rood eht ni deklaw taht elpuoc txen eht elttileb ot ffo
.ytisoiruc eniuneg fo nrob saw noitseuq ehT
.hgis detarepsaxe na tuo tel retiaw eht dna dekeirhs yeroC
mih sdrawot delbmut ssalgeniw s’yeroC sa dehctaw diord eht
”,eiT-dnA-tiuS ,yas ot uoy rof ysaE“
.locotorp ot gnidrocca og dluow rennid dna pu sserd ot troffe eht edam htob dah yehT
tahw htiw dehctiwt rae siH ”.ti fo erac ekat ll’I dias I“
puc sih esiar ot erus saw eH
,ni tif mih pleh dluow sdneirf gnivaH
.rehtaf etal sih fo taht dna
”—tub ,erofeb deklat ev’ew ,naem I
.dnah ni repap dna nep htiw reporp dna thgiarts doots ,yeroC naht rellat sehcni wef a ,xof A
.flesruoy eB .ruof-ytriht enil ,nevesytxis egaP
”.eussi na eb dluow ereht yhw ees t’nod I
.sehcuoc gnitiaw eht no trapa ecnatsid drawkwa na tas dna netsE morf yawa denrut yeroC
.emoclew t’nsaw ylsuoivbo I
,doof rof deen fo kcal sih ot sknahT
,desraeher dna yffuts saw eciov sih ,ekops retto ehT
.ti denepo eh retfa xob a eb ot eunitnoc dluow dna
,detseggus koob eht sa ,syad owt detiaw dah eH
fo tros yna fo ecneserp eht gnisneS
elbat eht no nwod ecaf unem eniw eht deppilf netsE
.gnitrilf fo tca elpmis rehtona tey ,rehtegot hsurb sregnif rieht gnittel
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.nwo sih fo yna ssorca emoc reven d’eh
.gnihctaw eb thgim thguoht eh enoyna ot gnitrad seye sih ,derettum yeroC
.ddo tlef enituor yliad sih ni kaerb ehT
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.srac gnissap eht ta tuo gnikool ,ffo deliart yeroC
taorht sih gniraelc erofeb stnemom wef a rof sredluohs depmuls htiw doots xof ehT
,onnud I“ ”?yas uoy od tahW .em no s’tI“
rehtegot hsinif regnol on dluow yeht eniw eht rof elbat eht no derdnuh a werht eH
,esu ot rorrim eht ni elims ekaf tcefrep eht gnicitcarp tneps d’eh sruoh eht tup netsE .detsetorp eh
,atsirab gninrom eht ,yeroC
.erom gnihtyna yas dluoc netsE erofeb retnuoc eht ot kcab detaerter xof ehT
esor llits nus ehT
,taes sih ni detfihs yeroC
’.laer‘ gnieb yllautca ni tseretni on dah eh ,ni dnelb ot saw evitcejbo niam s’netsE hguohT
lortnoc fo tuo gnitaeb traeh s’yeroC ees yllacitcarp dluoc eH
.nwod unem eht tup eh sa hgis a niatnoc ot elbanu ,dias netsE
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,derewsnanu snoitseuq ynam os
.xob nedoow nialp a ot txen
.mih fo tnorf ni tuo sdnah sih gnignirw
dehsinif eh sa thguoht eh ,serutaerc ylliS
.rennid rof detnaw eh tahw dediced ydaerla dah eh ,gnirekcib rieht fo tsdim eht nI
.meti evisnepxe ylralucitrap a ot detniop dna kcab unem eniw eht deppit netsE
.yaw fo tros tcaf-fo-rettam yrev a ni detats eh
,unem eht ni eson sih deirub dna htaerb sih rednu gnihtemos delbmum yeroC
,eerht-ytneves derdnuh-eno egaP
.spis neewteb sesnes larehpirep sih ni
”.emoh gniog m’I“ .dnuora
.moor gninid eht ot muidop eht morf devaw eH
.sgel sih neewteb dekcut liat sih dna
.sehsiw s’retsam sih noitseuq ot nosaer on saw erehT
suoirav pu dekcip dah netsE
.s’yeroC yletinifed saw eciov ehT ”?olleH“
.emoh yaw sih no trihs wen a yub ot evah dluow eH
weiv detcurtsbonu sih gniniltuo ,llis wodniw eht nopu tas
.sksat cisab gnimrofrep nehw ysmulc emaceb xof eht taht ro
”?riS ,pu pot a ekil uoy dluoW“
”.niaga elpoep esoht ees reven ll’uoY
.gnikaerb fo ytrebil eht koot yeroC taht meht neewteb ecnelis drawkwa na saw erehT .xis-ythgie enil
dnatsrednu ton dluoc eh taht stpecnoc evitcejbus erom neve dna
”?siht gniod no tsisni uoy od yhw“
.noitautafni fo sllet erew
.flesmih ecudortni dna
”,netsE s’eman yM“
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.sriatsnwod efac eht morf eeffoc kcalb ,lluf sretrauq-eerht ,muidem a
.nikpan eht ot drawot deddon netsE
.elbat eht otno tuo dellips dna puc s’netsE morf dewolfrevo eeffoC
,eb ti tel netsE os ,rehtruf eussi eht sserp ot sselesu demees tI
.dellac eb eh detsisni dah rotaerc sih sa
.yadot retal erots koob eht yb pots dluow eh spahreP
.yrwa os enog dah taht noitautis eht evas dna yrt ot
.rehtegot swap sih gnignirw yb nikpan eht ot noitnetta gniward dna
.sregnif owt htiw elzzum sih fo egdirb eht gnihcnip
.retirwepyt a fo taht naht tnereffid hcum ton gnitirw sih
,rac eht ot pu deklaw yeroC
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.noisiced sih htiw eussi koot ylsuoivbo ohw
.era ew ereh ,nauqaS“
.tsiaw sih dnuora mra na tup dna xof eht sdrawot deklaw netsE
,yeroC ,sriatsnwod
saw hcihw ,dnats tnemidnoc ybraen eht gnikcots htiw flesmih ysub ot yawa deirruh yeroC
.noitautis euqinu s’netsE rof etairporppa tsom eht demees dna
,raeg otni rac eht detfihs netsE
.emarf ehtil s’xof eht tnemilpmoc ot llew did dna tnaruatser til-eldnac llud eht ni enihs ot demees eH
.gnitad fo tcepsa yreve erolpxe ot detnaw eh ,sselehtreveN
.elims eniuneg ekaf s’netsE ekil hcum
,snoitome rieht dna elpoep gniyduts neeb d’eh sraey eht lla nI
”...tnaruatser eht rof ,haey ,lleW“
setubirtta ynam oot
.dnim sih otni depees tbuod fo revils A
xelpmoc oot erew snoitomE
.rettam laivirt a hcus saw srehto fo snoinipo eht tuoba gniyrroW
.pu wap a xof eht dereffo dna doots netsE
daeh s’netsE ni sraeg ehT
.siht droffa ylbissop t’nac I ,netsE“
.detatiseh eh rebmun eht laid ot tnew sregnif sih nehW
?laudividni rehtona htiw devlovni emoceb ot
esicerp os erew stnemevom siH .elahni dna
.ssergorp rehtruf yna gnikam erofeb detelpmoc eb ot deen lliw hcraeser lanoitiddA
.drocca nwo sih fo doots dna yawa ti dehsurb yeroC
.gnirats ydaerla era elpoeP“
.mih ot ecneuqesnoc elttil fo saw yenoM
.ereht elbatrofmoc t’nsaw I
,lavorppa ni deddon eh nehW
;yraid a peek ot mih dlot syawla dah rotaerc siH
,kool—ton s’ti ,oN“
skeehc dekaerts-raet s’enipluv eht fo espmilg a thguac eH
”.uoy evird em teL
,wap s’xof eht tsniaga hsurb ot niaga deirt eH ”?rettam ti seoD“
.yna sa trats a doog sa saw siht dna
taes sih morf depmuj yeroC
”.taht droffa nac I fi wonk t’nod I“
.netsil t’ndluow uoy tub
.erecnis sa ffo emoc ot yaw thgir eht tsuj ni waj sih gnitalucitra
xof roop eht gnisaeT
.efarac eht morf gniruop elihw derevihs yeroC sa ylluferac dehctaw eH
.yleritne ecalp tnereffid a ekil leef pohs sriatsnwod elttil eht edam taht wohemos dna
strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.retsam sih morf tfig gnitrap a
.tsif dehcnelc ylthgit s’yeroC nihtiw delknirw saw tI
,ot tnaw t’ndid I uoy dlot I“
.deciton t’nevah uoy fi ,tnemele ym fo tuo yllaer m’I“
”,nauqaS rednu noitavreseR“
ecnalg syawedis a yeroC gnivig
deworruf worb s’yeroC
,unem rennid eht pu dekcip dna
mih fo tnorf ni elttob eht dekrocnu eH
.tuo tup ll’yeht dna ,pu tuP
,niaga pu depip yeroC ”,netsE“
.gnileef tnasaelpnu na saw tI
!netsE ,llib gninaelc-yrd a tuoba erac t’nod I“
,dniheb spets lareves dewollof eH
eton koot eH  ’.tnemesuma‘
.eniw eht eveirter ot ffo ,elbat eht morf yawa edilg ot demees dna dapeton sih no delbbircs erdnA
”selbairaV“       :yojne esaelP
,flesmih ot delbmurg netsE
.tnatsni na ni pu emac selkceh sih dna dekaep eciov s’yeroC ”!netsE“
.ecnetsixe fo tuo dedaf ylkciuq taht gnignir thgil a gnivael
.eeffoc sih ’knard‘ eh yldiulf woh htiw skool drawkwa wef a derenrag eh taht
.yteicos otni noitargetni sih gnicrofnier
.tsehc sih ot esolc dleh nikpan eht gnipeek elihw dnah s’terref eht koohs yeroC ”...mu ,naem I ,rE .wonk I“
.noitceffa ruoy etartsnomeD
.sknab yromem sih nihtiw yltnenamrep derots won saw mih evig ot dah ti noitamrofni eht fo llA
,ecnatsni hcae ni dna
.stnap dna trihs s’xof eht otno dna elbat eht revo gnillips ,swap ykahs sih morf delbmuf ti sa
.tcaer ot detcepxe saw eno woh dna
”eeffoc-ruoy-yojne“ derettum dna ylhsipeehs depley yeroC
.llib eht gnitoof ni melborp on was netsE ”.taht
pu kcap ot tuoba saw dna yawa noitnetta sih denrut netsE
;repap retlif fo tnih a dna
.did syawla ti sa deunitnoc netsE rof efiL
”,tuo gnittes tsuj saw I“
.hcraeser rof hcum oS
.deddon yeroC ”?ti saw ,yeroC“
.dneherpmoc ylurt ton dluoc netsE gniht rehtona tey erew seitirucesnI
.gniknird fo noisulli eht detaerc taht euqinhcet detfarc ylluferac a hguorht
,)evif-ytnewt( ega s’yeroCsa hcus ,sliated
sih
.enohp sih pu gnikcip erofeb
.dnes tih eH .sthguoht nwo sih morf eerf daeh sih gnikahs
.daeh sih tsniaga kcab denettalf srae siH
”,htiw ffo epiw ot gnihtemos uoy teg ll’I“
.taes regnessap eht otni deppils eh sa derumrum yeroC
,kiavoJ dnaloR yb ”selbairaV“ fo
.derevaw eciov s’yeroC
”?yrrow eht lla tuohtiw rehtegot laem ecin a evah tsuj ton ew naC“
.meht rof srood nepO
.wodniw eht ot ralucidneprep tas taht hcuoc a htiw moor gnivil eht ni tas riahcmra nworb egral a dna ,llaw nehctik eht tsniaga pu dehsup saw elbat moor gninid llams a
elpoep htiw sretnuocne suoiverp no desab eno tcurtsnoc ot evah dluow eh
,seerged evif-ytrof pit ,etavelE
.eeffoc sih ’gniknird‘
.tnamada neeb dah retsam sih tub ,ecitcarp eht tsniaga deugra
.rehtruf rettam eht noitseuq ot nosaer on was netsE
.puc eeffoc sih gnola regnif sih fo pit eht nar netsE
.tceffe derised eht dah tnemilpmoc eht
.stseuqnoc suoirotciv ’srehto fo selat eht dna
.riahc sih fo mra eht tsniaga stsif sih hcnelc mih edam dna sthguoht sih deduolc tI ’.noitabrecaxe‘
.gnitruoc etaitini ot sehsiw eh taht gnidnatsrednu ym si tI
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta
.ti fo niatrec saw eh won dna
”.emit doog a evah ll’eW“ .tnetsisrep eB
.lla retfa rehtegot teg ot tnaw ton did yeroC dna llac ot gnol oot detiaw dah eh ebyaM
.eritta lamrof sih ni netsE deciton dna rac eht ot pu deklaw eh nehw dessarrabme ylbisiv
”.emosdnaH ,uoy sa ecin sa toN“
.srewolf meht gnirB
.thguoht eh ,doog yna mih od t’ndluow tI
.sesnes denethgieh sih tuohtiw neve ,tsehc sih edisni
,xob a saw xob ehT .sliated eht htiw flesmih nrecnoc t’ndid eH
.esaelp I woh yenom ym dneps ot esoohc nac I“
,renroc raf eht ni tas ksed siH
.retal rof tekcaj sih otni nikpan eht dekcut eH
”.siht ekil ton ,lleW !oN“
.ruof enil ,ytenin egaP
.gninrom txen eht devirra eh nehw ereht llits saw pohs eeffoc eht dna
.ecnayonna dellac evah dluow rehtaf
dezilaer eh erofeb trihs sih otno dna nihc sih nwod delbbird eeffoC
,erom gnidaer ni detsetni er’uoy fi dna skrow reilrae sih fo eno yojne uoy sepoh eH
.snoitaluclac sih ediug ot stcaf elbaifitnauq ro snoitauqe on htiw
.droffa ot elba neeb dah netsE tius eht morf yrc raf a saw eritta s’xof ehT
.eeffoc dewerb ylhserf fo efarac a htiw gnidnats yeroC ees ot pu dekool eh nehw tnemom a rof gninrut deppots
.netsE ta gniralg erofeb raet rehtona yawa depiw yeroC
.ylraelc detats netsE
.noisacco eht rof tius a pu dekcip dah netsE
,denoitseuq reve saw ecneitnes sih fi taht os
”.drow a tuohtiw dne ym no tuo em dessot ev’dluow yeht erus m’I uoy rof t’nsaw ti fI
.elttob eht fo ffihw tsrif evah ot netsE dewolla dna
?uoy ot tnatropmi taht snoinipo rieht erA .t’ndid yeht tuB“
efac eht evoba xelpmoc sih ot detaerter netsE
,pis rehtona ekat ot dedneterp eh erofeb retnuoc eht dniheb xof gnihsulb eht ot
.anosrep detcurtsnoc ylluferac sih fo trap elgnis a tsuj saw enituor sihT
.terref eht htiw tcatnoc lacisyhp ni elihw noitcnuf ot elbanu demees yeroC dna esnet saw wap siH
?won meht htiw deugalp gnieb eh taht ti saw woH
,efac eht fo raluger a gnieb htiw emac taht klat-llams eht hguorhT
.drow rehtona gniyas ton
.hctorc s’yeroC dednuorrus taht eniw fo hctap derolocsid eht ot deddon eH
secnereferp lauxes sih dna ,)otaihccam faced-flah( knird etirovaf sih
.gnineve siht rof revres ruoy eb ll’I ,erdnA si eman ym ,olleH“
.yhw tniopnip t’ndluoc eh hguoht ,noitautis eht yb desuma saw eH
.lamron sa deecorp dluow
,naem I .uoy rof ,seY“
,ecitcarp ni ro yroeht ni ,suorcidul demees ti fo lla dna noitamrofni yrotcidartnoc fo lluf saw tI
”,won thgir noitnetta erom yna tnaw t’nod I
.noitinifed laretil tsom sti yb noitutitsorp delbmeser thguoht eh hcihw
”.eno evol dluow I“
.erutarepmet ydob ni esir dna etar traeh detavele s’xof eht fo
,thguoht eh ,suolucidiR
”?notselrahC no pu s’aerdnA naS tuoba woH“
.ecivda gnitad fo egap retfa egap hguorht gnisrap
.noitom ekahs-dnah a ni wap sih detfil eh
.rehtruf pu ruf fo stfut sih gnissum ,yawa meht depiw yeroC erofeb
.niaga flesmih werdhtiw ylkciuq yeroC tub
.ydaer eb ot elbat rieht rof yltneitap gnitiaw
.bof sih no nottub eht tih eh sa efil ot gnimoc enigne eht
.tey tsuj elbat a evah t’nod ew os ,kcolc’o thgie rof si noitavreser ruoY
;enituor emas eht htiw detrats gninrom yrevE   2 fo 1 traP
,slaitnesse lamron rehto dna taeh
.liat sih dnuora ylthgit dehctulc swap sih dna
”?seniw esuoh ruo fo eno htiw ffo uoy trats I naC
xof eht wollof ot deunitnoc netsE
.won litnu elbissop saw ti eveileb ot nosaer on dah eh
,elims a fo tnih a htiW
dehcuols erutsop sih htiw roolf eht ot dekool eH
.muidop eht ot pu edorts yeht nehw os od ot deunitnoc dna smra dekcol htiw ni deklaw selam owt eht sa
.ylbaredisnoc desaercni etar traeh sih dna pu til skeehc s’yeroC tub
.trihs klis etalucammi sih htaeneb demoorg yltcefrep saw ruf siH
,sllaw eht tsniaga deohce eciov siH
no kcab tekcaj sih deggurhs eH
.wonk reven thgim eh thguoht netsE ,eb dluow emit taht nehW
.tuo deppets eh sa elims drawkwa na deganam yeroC
.worbeye desiar a htiw yeroC ot neht dna netsE ot dekool muidop eht yb gnidnats retto nA
”.eit dna tius a ni taerg os ton m’I
ecaf sih dekaerts sraet weN
.dnah ni nikpan a htiw mih dehcaorppa xof eht nehw
,yteicos ni ecalp sih wenk eH
dah eH .noitacinummoc dna golaid gnicitcarp fo yaw a sa dna
.koob eht morf etouq tcerid a neeb tsomla dah tI
.ti dias eh nehw gnicnivnoc dednuos taht kniht t’ndid eh nevE
pal sih otni delruc saw liat siH
”?rettam yeht od tahW“
.mra thgir sih revo depard nikpan denrettap a htiw retal elihw a meht dehcaorppa retto ehT
.ksed sih morf doots dna
,nades yruxul llams a ni
.ylgnidrocca egareveb sih fo selgna eht gnitsujda
”,ysub neeb ev’I“ ”.uoy morf kcab raeh ot gniog t’nsaw I kniht ot gninnigeb saw I
”.ereh elbatrofmoc ton m’I !esaelp ,netsE“
.rebmun enohp sih htiw em dehcaorppa
,enog gnol saw rotaerc sih hguoht nevE
.enoyreve ot ylppa ton did cigol s’koob eht yleruS
.edistuo mih dewollof dna
werb sih yojne ot dedneterp eh sa mih dnuora zzub snortap rehto eht dehctaw netsE
,kiavoJ dnaloR yb
.tekcop sih ni kcab enohp eht dekcut dna nottub llac eht tih eH ”.etad a s’tI“
,emit emos rof noitautafni s’yeroC fo suoicipsus neeb dah netsE
.rood regnessap eht nepo ot rac eht dnuora yaw sih edam dna rac eht fo tuo deppets eH ”.ereht yatS“
.mih rof deruop neeb dah taht ssalg eniw eht rof ylikahs gnihcaer
eeffoc nalametauG fo sdnuorg htiw delgnim ,edirdyhid negyxo—
sa dootsrednu yleugav eh gnihtemos saw sihT
”,suolucidir gnieb er’uoY“
dengised dah rotaerc sih ,mih dnuora elpoep eht ekil tca dna
.tnatropmi leef meht ekam ,stnemilpmoc meht eviG
,tuo sthguoht sih delbbircs eh sa moor eht dellif sehctarcS
,dnatsrednu dluoc eh sa raf sA
.ylreporp detalume eb ot seicnetsisnocni htiw delddir dna
,wap s’yeroC morf repap delknirw eht koot netsE
.efilthgin teiuq eht revo draeh ylisae erew sbos s’xof ehT
.tca eht fo snoitacilpmi eurt eht fo erawanu yltsom llits saw tub
.detseretni er’uoy taht no tel t’noD .deil eh
.nehctik eht ot ffo gniklaw erofeb derettum eh
wap eno ni sessalg owt htiw kcab emac xof ehT ”.hsiw uoy fI“
ereh raluger a flesmih ekam ot devirts eH
.elbissop erew taht fi ,rewol neve tnew srae sih sa
,ecneserp sih ni denekciuq eslup s’yeroC taht eciton ot gnol notamotua eht ekat ton did tI .)nem(
.rehto eht ni eniw fo elttob a dna
”.thgirla ,llew ,hO“
demees ti ,lufepoh os dekool xof ehT
.uoy htiw gnineve tnasaelp a no ti dneps ot esoohc I
tnaruatser eht otni meht dewollof serats drawkwA
”.uoy rof denaelc-yrd taht teg nac I“
.stsif sih dellab eh sa
.elggig detcepxenu na delfits diletsum ehT
”?neves ta pu em kciP“
.tuo tup ll’yeht dna ,pu tuP
”?revo si siht nehw esle erehwemos og nac ew ebyam ,kooL“ .taps eh
dellepmoc tlef netsE litnu ecnelis drawkwa ni owt eht gnivael
.yaw eht yb ,yeroC s’eman yM“
,gnihton dias tub ,revo decnalg yeroC
.kaeps ot netsE egdelwonkca ot gninrut yletarebiled erofeb yeroC ta decnalg eH
”!kcehcyap s’keew ym fo flah er’yeht ,sreziteppa eht ta kooL
,evael sih koot netsE
,liat sih fo kcilf etarebiled a evag netsE
”,ssensuoicsnoc-fles eht htiw niagA“
dah ylpmis elpoeP
.yeroC ot denrut dna krap ni saw rac eht sa noos sa elkcub sih desaeler netsE
.lla retfa deterpretnisim dah netsE ebyaM
.thgir saw emit eht tlef eh eht litnu denepo eb ot ton saw xob eht taht snoitcurtsni cificeps nevig dah rehtaf siH
.gnorw ylbirroh gniog saw etad siht mih llet ot koob a deen t’ndid netsE
.oot ,mih ot gnikil a etiuq nekat evah ot demees
,rehtaf sih ot tnematset a sa yraid sih ni etirw ot deunitnoc netsE
.desolc saw noissucsid eht ,denrecnoc saw eh sa raf sA
txet dedniw-gnol naht
.nees eb ot erehwon saw yeroC
,revewoh ,yad eht fo tser ehT
,mih ot neppah ot erew gnihtyna esac ni ,sthguoht sih fo riomem a
”,ot evah t’ndid uoY .uoy knaht ,hO“
”.yaw siht thgiR .nauqaS .rM ,ydaer si elbat ruoY“
.devac yeroC ”,thgirla ,lleW“
,wap sih ni thgit dleh nikpan eht ta nwod dekool yeroC ”?em rof taht sI“
,etuc gnieb sa roivaheb eht dezingocer netsE
”—ereh morf edisa
tcaretni oT .eeffoc
?em ta gnikool erew yeht woh ees ton uoy dluoC
”.hcum oot si sihT
.gnitad fo tra eht ni seiduts sih etelpmoc lliw netsE woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
,dias eh ”,ecin kool uoY“
.tol gnikrap eht otni dellup yehT
.gnol os rof efac eht morf yawa eb ot lausunu saw tI
atsirab ehT - MA 74:9 4102 ,52 yaM
retsam etal sih morf sekaspeeK
.semit eerht gnar enohp ehT
,nwo sih fo ytilanosrep laer on dah netsE ecniS
.retnuoc eht dniheb ytefas ot kcab gninnur erofeb
”?detnaw uoy tahw ton siht sI
.mih tnioppasid ot emahs a