.edistuo deppets eh sa nirg a ot denrut elims siH ”.si ti ,seY“
hcrep sti morf xob eht debbarg eH
,elzzum sih no elims eht ,liat sih ni kcilf citegrene eht—
,deknilb rosruc ehT
.xof eht esaeppa ot hguone eb thgim taht gnipoh ,dias eh
.efac eht fo tuo dna ni ylsselmaes deretlif ciffarT
,won meht ta gnikool selbat fo rebmun eht ot dnuora dekool netsE
”.ti nepo ot nehw wonk ll’uoY“
.psag a htiw kcab dellup xof eht erofeb spil mraw s’yeroC fo gnirekcilf
.retiaw ruoy eb ll’I ,navE si eman yM“
,gnihtyreve mih llet I yad eht eb lliw samtsirhC taht dediced ev’I
”.thgin taht deretnec-fles yletelpmoc erew uoy tub ,suovren er’uoy taht teg I
ffo dewohs taht trihs-t kcen-V knip a dna
.evif ta ffo m’I ,kooL“
.mih raeh dluoc ybraen stnemtrapa eht ni elpoep eht erus saw eh taht hguone duol detuohs eH ”!uoy llet ll’I“
,enodnu yal sksat
.feilebsid ni hgis a dehtaerb eh sa
.diordna eht ot yrassecen demees naht tsehc erom
.etad deliaf suoiverp sih taeper ot ton dediced dna snalp gninid sih revo yeroC htiw dah dah eh elbuort eht derebmemer netsE
detxet riamA“ ”—wonk t’nod I“
?ecaf sih no kool eht ees uoy diD“
.pu dessem ev’I dnA“ .derettum yeroC
.tluassa lauxes thginot did uoy tahw llac yeht eveileb I“
rezalb rehtael a ni xof etihw wons a ot denrut won saw noitnetta sih tub
”?yrassecen taht fo lla saW“
.enituor gninrom sih ot ecneirepxe elbarovaf
.yteirav detsehc-talf eht fo namow a rof nekatsim eb dluoc eisseJ ,ecnalg a ta ,taht desoppus netsE ,tnemmoc s’revres eht rof sA
.uoy gnivres eno eht eb lli kniht t’nod tub
.retsiger hsac eht no ydaer eht ta sregnif sih ,pu kool t’ndid yeroC
.enola dna tsol ,riahc retupmoc sih ni tas eH
.elzzum s’xof eht tsniaga spil sih desserp
”,tnetsisrep ylniatrec er’uoY“ ”.haeY“ ”.oS“
”?taht fo lla llac dluow uoy revetahW“
.nekorb tlef eh erehw
.enil rehto eht no ylivaeh gnihtaerb yeroC raeh dluoc netsE
muroced sa hcus sgniht tuoba erom ylbaredisnoc wenk eh
”?noisses ’pu mraw‘ elttil a ot yas uoy od tahW
.rorrim weiv-raer sih ni liatgnir eht gnivael ,evord netsE
”?emas eht leef ton uoy oD
.noitartsurf sih etipsed ,elims mih edam tluser ehT
!tobor gnikaerf a ru ekil gniklat potS“
sdrow otni tup ot deirt netsE
,desoppus eh ,esnes lacigol erom edam tI
”,netsE s’ti ,iH“ ”?ooolleH“
deredisnoc neeb evah tsum liatgnir eht hguohT
.ti dias eh sa emahs fo tnih a htiw dekcilf srae siH ”.ynapmoc ...dah I
.hgual suovren a htiw dias yeroC
.tluciffid ...si gnitpadA
.edistuo doots yeht sa meht fo owt eht tuoba denrecnocnu yletelpmoc demees eH .detaes erew
.smra sih ni deldarc sunem eht dah ydaerla eH
”—ytilibaborpmi lacitsitats a si nataS“
.enod saw eh retfa llew litnu noitasrevnoc ta tpmetta elgnis a gnikam ton
.hgis a htiw deggas
.esiwrehto tiaw ot nosaer on dah eH
dnah s’toleco eht otni sllib fo lufdnah a dekcut netsE ”.sknahT“
.yrgna dna deracs
.ffo nrow dah stceffe eht litnu tiaw ot evah dluow sksat renif dna delddum emaceb cigol dneherpmoc ot ytiliba siH
.morf gnimoc saw noitome fo esnes siht erehw erus t’nsaw eh hguoht ,’htrim‘ sa gnileef eht dezingocer eH
.detapicitna naht tluciffid erom saw hcraes ehT
mra eht yb netsE debbarg eH
,enola era uoy esuaceb uoy ot tneserp ym denepo ev’uoy tbuod on evah uoY
demialcxe eisseJ ”!tihs ,hO“
,denoitseuq raguoc gnissap ehT
,noitseuq eht fo tuo saw mih gnillet tub
.retsiger eht fo sedis eht deppirg yeroC
,yawa llup ot deirt netsE
,sdrow sih dewols dna liatgnir eht ot dekool eH
.taerg sdnuos renniD“
railimafnu ,tneiciffeni saw tI
.uoy llac ot saw detnaw I lla ,taht lla retfA“
,ni dnelb ot ,evitcejbo niam sih ni deliaf dah eH
.gnitrilf fo mrof rehtona eb thgim siht gnisseug
.netsE ot denrut dna
”,eman ruoy em llet ll’uoy fi ylno tub
liatgnir ylbbub a htiw efac a nopu emac eh keew taht retaL
srosnes sih no ezah tnasaelpnu na tfel tI
.tnetsisni saw pirg s’eisseJ tub
.wodniw eht tuo gnikool elihw derettum eh ”,haeY“
.ydaer t’nsaw ylpmis dlrow eht ,ton ro gnimmargorP .flesmih dlot eh ,ydaer t’nsi dlrow ehT
”?ris ,redro ruoy ekat I naC“
,sgel s’terref eht pu deliart sregnif s’eisseJ
.enoyna ot terces ym laever ot reven em demmargorp uoy yhw won dnatsrednu I
,deknilb netsE ”?tahW“
.desufnoc dna detaefed
,esuoh eht no s’tI“
”.uoy ot pu ti ekam em teL“
.sthguoht detcartsid morf derraj
.ria eht ni pu smra sih werht eH
,ssalg s’eisseJ deruop revres eht sA
.dnuora eb ot tnaw ton did eh taht enoemos gnimoceb ylkciuq saw eisseJ tub ,mih edisni dliub ot gninnigeb erew taht sgnileef eht ebircsed yletauqeda t’ndluoc eH
.eulav yratenom yna dloh dluoc eman sih woh erusnu ,deilper eh
.htiw railimaf saw netsE taht dnik eht ton tub
,llet dluoc eh tahw morF .ni dnelb ,elgnim
.ekoms fo duolc a otni thgir deklaw eh sa elzzum sih fo tnorf ni wap a devaw netsE
depmuls sredluohs s’yeroC
netsE ot denrut xof etihw ehT
.llew seog ti taht yarp I dna
pu dekcip dna retupmoc eht morf flesmih deggulpnu eH
.llac eht detanimret dah taht
tcaer dluoc yeroC erofeb dna drawrof deppets netsE
.gnieb eritne sih dedoolf ssensuovren dna noisnet elbabircsednI
yromem citedie sih fo pleh eht htiw nevE
.mih rof gnitiaw saw flow desserd-llew yllauqe na erehw tnorf eht ta muidop eht ot denruter eh
,dnim s’netsE ni detaeper sdrow ehT
.emoceb dluow uoy denigami I nosrep lufrednow a tahw dna
,elbainednu saw xof eht ot tnemhcatta elbacilpxeni siH
.knird ot gnidneterp elihw noitom decitcarp taht ni eeffoc sih gnippit
.tnatsid nworg sah dna rennid ot evitpecer ton saw yeroC tnapicitraP
:troffe tsal eno ekam ot netsE rof emit eht saw woN
”,eno regae eht ew t’nerA
.elzzum sih otni pollacs a deffuts eh sa elggig ot deunitnoc eH
.llaw a tsniaga ti gniworht dna
”.tnaruatser eht ta uoy no desopmi I dna ,uoy ot netsil t’ndid I“
”.etelpmoc leef I .tnereffid
,reffo ot sah efil tahw fo tseb eht ecneirepxe ot
”?uoy t’nera ,gniht elttil gnimrahc“ gnirettum
.ekil eb dluow eltsimocac eht htiw setad erutuf tahw no detcelfer eh elihw deddon
.tuoba liat sih gnihsal dna yddig saw eH
.noitautis eht rof etairporppa leef t’ndid ti wohemos tub
saw erehwesle ecivreS
.wap ni sehsid owt htiw ybraen yldrawkwa gnidnats saw navE
,kiavoJ dnaloR yb ”selbairaV“
”,nemeltneg ,gninevE“
.thguoht eh ,yaw eno ylno s’erehT
.yadot od I tahw gniwonk tuohtiw tca na hcus fo snoissucreper eht dootsrednu ylurt evah reven dluoc I
.denrut dna deppots yeroC
.gnihton otni ylkciuq gnidaf
eno emoceb ot ydaer era uoy snaem ,snoitome ecneirepxe ot ytiliba ruoy htiw gnola
,uoy dengised I nehw taht wenk I
.raed dloh uoy elpoep eht htiw
ot evah I taht em gnillet er’uoy won dna draobhsad ruoy otni em mals uoy tsriF
.mih fo tnorf ni unem eht denepo eh sa navE ot delims eH ”.esaelp ,retaW“
.rethgual-kcom fo dnuos eht edam eisseJ ”?sussiM eht rof dnA“
.suoixna ylgnisaercni mih gnikam eno hcae
.yawyna yojne yllaer t’ndluow eh doof hcum oot gniredro ni esnes on saw ereht tub
”.gnivrats m’I ,tae s’teL
,ylluferac dehctaw netsE
”.draeh I ,uoy ffo spil sih peek t’ndluoC
”.emit fo etsaw a saw ereh gnimoc wenk I“
,ssenisub sih ot kcab denrut enilef eht don a dna elims a htiW
.elggig a htiw dias eh
,eton eht devomer eH
,gnitca neeb ev’uoy yaw eht gnitca rof nosaer doog nmad a evah uoy sselnU“
nettirw ylnommoc d’eh esarhp hsilgnE nommoc a gnizilitu kcab etorw eh
.egnahc s’terref eht koot eh sa edis eht ot dna nwod dekool eH
.ot naem t’ndid eh hguoht ,derepsihw eh
.citehtapa dna tneiciffeni ,wols
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.boj etauqeda na gniod ton saw eh
.yeroC morf saw egassem txet ehT
.noitpircsed ruoy tem taht enoemos htiw xe sih was eh em dloT
.ti rof ereht t’nsaw xof eht fi
.daeh sih tsniaga kcab dekcilf srae s’netsE
.lufsseccusnu neeb sah gnitad fo tcejbus eht otni noitarolpxE –
,krad eht ni sbats llits erew esehT
”...lla retfa ecnahc dnoces a uoy evig tsuj ot em tcepxe uoY“
.nosaer dna cigol deifed did liatgnir eht gnihtyrevE
srae sih fo ssenikrep eht dna
”,tnemetatsrednu na s’tahT“
.enog dah thgin rieht woh ta rettib llits ylsuoivbo ,yeroC taps
efac eht morf uoy rab tnac i
,egnahc eht revo dednah yltneitap netsE
,won mih ot esnes ssel neve edam gnihtyrevE
.rood eht tuo yawflah ydaerla saw eisseJ tub ,dednopser diletsum dexelprep eht ”,ti tog I ,haeY“
.dnatsrednu yeroC ekam dna yrt ot
”?thgin tsal tuoba klat ew naC“
,meht evol uoy meht llet ot liaf ton od
.uoy dnuora dlrow eht htiw
,devirra yeroC litnu setunim eht detnuoc eH
efac eht edistuO
,dne no gnidnats saw riah s’liatgnir ehT
,spollacs dna retsbol sih otni gud liatgnir eht drow rehtona tuohtiW
.rehtaF ,uoy morf edisa enoyna htiw meht tneps ev’I raey tsrif eht eb lliw ti dna ,gnimoc era syadiloh samtsirhC ehT – MA
.ylsselwalf dessap stset lanretni sih fo lla ,dekcehc eh nehW
.og tel reven ot dna ti otno dloh ot
.daeh sih tsniaga kcab desserp srae sih dna yllis tlef eH
.sgel s’netsE neewteb tser a ot emoc wap sih gnittel
.uoy fo duorp os ma I dna nwo ruoy no stiart eseht fo lla htiw laed ot woh gninrael er’uoY
.seye s’xof eht otni derats eh
.gnitirwdnah s’rehtaf sih saw elbbircs eht taht gnivresbo
.retupmoc eht ta kcab derats dna nwod koob eht tes eH
”?gnineve siht rof owT“
deraeppa eisseJ ,etad suoiverp sih ekilnU
.dellortnoc regnol on eh taht
.elpoep rehto evresbo od I“
.xob eht denepo dna hctal eht deppop eH ”.ti htiw lleh oT“
,emit tsal eht naht rennam lausac erom a ni deraperp saw netsE ,dnuora dellor ytriht-neves emit eht yB
,kiavoJ dnaloR yb ”selbairaV“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT         .rehtaF ,uoy ssim I
.eunitnoc ot netsE rof yltnatcepxe gnitiaw ,tnelis saw yeroC
.pissog ytirbelec dna noihsaf erew snrecnoc ylno s’eltsimocac eht hguoht
.denoows eisseJ ”,rac eciN“
.ylkciuq emoc ton did gninrom txen ehT   .dehgis dna
,tnemtrapa sih ot kcab deklaw netsE
.ecnanetniaM nuG dna gnitaD fo trA ehT
.flesmih dedulcni taht dna ,dluohs ti sa gnitca eb ot demees gnihton tub ,tnatsnoc saw emit wenk eH
.rof ezigolopa ot gnihton evah uoY“
,nwod daeh sih tup eh daetsnI
,snortap eht fo tser eht gnomA
.rotinom sih rednu morf pu til enohp siH
”.uoy htiw od ot erom gnihtyna tnaw t’nod I
.elggig a htiw dias eisseJ
,did netfo elpoep sa elgnim ot
.liatgnir eht ta nwod decnalg netsE
.skeew wef tsal eht ni flesym tuoba tol a denrael ev’I ,kooL“
specib denot ylthgil sih fo trohs tsuj deppots seveels eht dna ruf nworb fo tfut thgil a
.fo devorppasid yltaerg netsE taht gnihtemos saw mih dnuora esle enoyna rof drager fo kcal siH
”.netsE ,ti nepo ot nehw wonk ll’uoY“
.ti rof hcaer dluoc revres eht erofeb kcab ti deppans ylkciuq eisseJ hguoht ,detaes erew yeht ecno yawa unem eniw eht devaw netsE
elbatrofmoc kool ton did taht snaej thgit-ruf gniraew
”.nosrep retteb a eb nac I ekil leef I ,uoy htiw m’I nehW
enohp sih otni elbac ecafretni llams eht deggulp eH
”?huh ,yadot yad ysuB“
.edis eht ot ffo detnac srae sih htiw llit eht ta nwod dekool yeroC
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ti od ot flesmih gnirb t’ndluoc eh tub ,yas ot yldab detnaw eh sgniht erew esehT .doolb dna hself ton m’I .diordna na m’I
,pit ruoy seog erehT“
.yawa decnuob dna
”?gniog ew era erehw oS“
.netsE dniheb mrof ot nugeb dah enil a litnu tnelis saw yeroC
,yawa gninrut erofeb deppil-thgit yrev gnipeek elihw
”.uoy ees ot tnaw t’nod I“
.thgir sgniht ekam ot ,dnatsrednu ot rewop sih ni gnihtyreve enod dah eH
,noitcnuflam ot dengised t’nsaw tI
.meht fo owt eht neewteb dekool eH
”!emoh em evird ot detagilbo era uoY“
.rethgirb tib elttil a steg yad eht ekil leef I
,oN“ ”?retal kcab llac I dluohS
taht dnatsrednu ot gninnigeb saw eH
.skrow erutuf yna gnitsop eb lliw eh erehw
.woble sih ta bur ot tsehc sih ssorca mra na gniyal ,ffo deliart eH
,siht fo gnah eht teg ot gnitrats saw eh erus os saw eH
,tnatropmi denmad os xob eht saw yhW
.dennalp sa og t’nseod gnineve rieht nehw retaw toh ni mih sdnal atsirab lacol sih htiw etad s’netsE ,emit tsaL
.elzzum sih tfel yeht sa noos sa sdrow esoht gniyas detterger eH
”?eituC ,uoy pleh I nac woH .eisseJ s’eman ym ,iH“
.detaeper eh ”,yrros m’I“ ”?tahW“
,kcab llup t’ndid yeroC nehW
,yeroC ot klat ot saw tnemom taht ta detnaw eh gniht ylno eht tub
.tndluow u sseug I“
.ylthgils ylno tub ,gniyl saw xof eht taht
.derettum yeroC ”,trats a s’tI“
.elbat rieht gnihcaorppa saw ohw stnap sserd kcalb htiw
.tleb sih no gnikrow detrats dna
.ffo evord dna rac eht otni tog yeht sa nirg sih edih t’ndluoc eisseJ
”.ereh ni gniklaw emac sruoy sa etuc sa gum a fi rebmemer yletinifed d’I
.yeroC ,dnatsrednu ot tnaw I“
egap yrruFoS sih gniviver no gnikrow yltnerruc si eh
.gnitad fo tra eht ni seiduts sih etelpmoc lliw netsE woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT .noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.hcaer s’netsE fo tuo ti llup ton did eh tub
”?thgir lla gnihtyreve sI“
”.revo si etad sihT .melborp ym regnol on s’taht ,emoh gnitteg rof sA
”.hsulb flesmih nataS ekam dluow taht sgniht od ot gniog era I dna uoY“
netsE”.elgnis gnieb naht sgniht esrow era ereht tub
,evol ecneirepxe ot nrael lliw uoY
.s’yeroC hcuot ot tuo dnah sih dehcaer netsE
”.emoh yaw nwo ruoy dnif uoy tseggus I ,thginot elbuort erom yna tnaw t’nod uoy fI
,dnuora dellor kcolc’o thgiE
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.yas ot esle tahw erus t’nsaw eH ”.erus ,haeY“
.taorht sih deraelc yeroC
.won ti tnaw tnod I dna
,detatiseh netsE
?ereh dnuora wen uoy erA .uoy teem ot eciN“
.nosrep nI“ ”?ti si tahW“
,enoemos laiceps taht dnif uoy dluohS
,sllaw eht ffo deohce eciov siH
”.od ot em tnaw uoy tahw wonk ton od I
.mih dniheb efarac eht ot revo decnuob dna
.sthguoht sih otni tperc tbuod fo dees ehT .t’nac uoy tuB
.rof gnizigolopa eb ot desoppus saw eh tahw tsuj rof ,thgin taht gnorw enog dah tahw tuoba kniht ot deniarts eH
thgit ti dehctulc dna
elims ylbbub s’eisseJ dehctam tI
.gnimoc terref eht was eh nehw moor kcab eht ot nur ot kciuq saw xof eht tub
.drawrof pets a koot netsE
.nikpan a fo kcab eht no nwod rebmun sih etirw ot gnol hguone ylno tub ,desuap eisseJ ”,hO“ ”.oN“
”!suolaej yllatot saw eH
roiretxe nialp ylgnitnuat sti dna
,gnihtyna yas ot ,kaeps ot detnaw eH
”.gnissim s’eh tahw wonk ot mih tnaw I dna rood eht hguorht deklaw tsuj xe yM“ .deralg eh
,ytisoiruc larutan dna sessecorp gninrael ruoY
”.tuoba klat ot gnihton s’erehT“
,og tel yllautneve eisseJ
”?eituc ,sruoy ro ecalp ym oS“
wap sih devaw liatgnir eht tub ,egnahc etairporppa rof tekcop sih otni gud netsE
.raeh ot demees netsE ylno taht yaw a ni
.thguoht eh ,yletairporppa tca ot woh wenk yeroC
”!ereh morf selim si esuoh yM
.evlos ton dluoc eh elddir rehtona tey htiw mih gnisaet
etavitca ot ylno dengised erew taht
.tfel yeht erofeb mih ot dias dah navE dna riamA htob tahw tuoba kniht tub pleh t’ndluoc netsE
,dednemmocer saw lausac-ssenisub erehw tnaruatser nailatI rellams a saw s’onailatI
.emoc dluow gnihton tub
.semit fo tseb eht ta tluciffid erew elpoep fo smotsuc eht tub ,dnatsrednu ot detnaw eH
.mih fo tnorf ni srepap fo elip eht revo wap sih gnivaw
sthguoht htiw deugalp gnieb saw netsE dna ,dezinagro t’nerew srepap
yeroC tuo snrut tI
skrow reilrae sih fo eno ot gninetsil yojne uoy sepoh eH
,krow ot nwod tas eh revenehw tub ,sksat ynam sih fo eno tsuj etelpmoc ot yad eht tuohguorht deirt netsE
”.enil eht pu gnidloh er’uoY
.draobhsad eht htiw etamitni emoceb dah taht
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.railimafnu dna hsrah snoitcelfni eht
.erofeb sa reppihc sa tsuj saw derewsna taht eciov ehT
.emit rehtona gnitad fo tpecnoc eht tisiver dluow eH
.retrohs gnitteg saw segassem neewteb yaled ehT
?emoh yaw nwo ym dnif
.erehwyreve ruf gnilf ot gninetaerht
.dnah ni efarac a htiw retnuoc eht dniheb morf tuo deppets yeroC
.elims netsE edam namow a sa eisseJ fo aedi ehT
.nigeb ot ydaer si yenruoj ruoy snaem siht gnidaer er’uoy taht tcaf yrev ehT ,netsE
”?uaeb wen ruoy tuoba tahW“
.nirg a htiw deltsihw eltsimocac ehT
,eisseJ ot kcab dekool eH
”.uoy llet ot deen I gnihtemos evah I“
.gninnalp sih ni ekatsim evarg rehtona tey edam evah thgim eh taht denrecnoc
,gnol rehtona saw erehT
.rood eht ot denrut netsE sa derettuts eh ”,yeh—H“
.edisni neeb evah thgim thguoht netsE gnihtyna morf yrc raf a ,edisni repap fo pils enol a saw erehT
.deneppah tahw ydemer ton dluow seigolopA“
”.efil ecin a evah
.deilper netsE ”.uoy knaht ,seY“
?ydaerla gnillac ,netsE yeH“
.ot desu teg dluoc eh gnileef a saw siht ,revewoH
”?knird ot gnihtemos uoy teg I naC
.siht ekil soiranecs tuoba mih thguat dah koob gnitad eht ro efil sih ni gnihtoN
.ffo erew yeht dna raeg otni rac eht werht eh os
”.netsE s’ti ,yeroC“
?ti nepo ot dewolla eh t’nsaw yhw dna
,elims a htiw dias eh
.yllanif ,deilper eh
”,netsE“ .delggig eh
.lla retfa etadidnac tcefrep eht saw
.erats suoludercni
”?huh ti staht oS“
?tpeni os eb ylbissop eh dluoc woh
.gnilaid erofeb stnemom wef a rof rebmun eht detcepsni netsE
.enohp taht pu gnuh yeroC tnemom eht dehsurc eb dluow
yeroC fo espmilg a thguac netsE yad txen ehT   2 fo 2 traP
ylisaenu liat sih detfihs yeroC
rennid ta ti tnaw tndid I
”.doog yna si egakcap eht erus ekam ot ’yub uoy erofeb yrt‘ a ekil fo troS“
.gnitad dna pihstruoc hguorht
etad deliaf eno sih fo sthguoht ot derednaw dnim sih
.lautcnup s’ohw yug a ekil I
ydob sih fo strap eht ta gnibbur erofeb
tleb taes sih delkcubnu dah eltsimocac etanimeffe eht evird eht otni setunim eviF
.senituor-bus krow sih etelpmoc ot
.erofeb dah eh sa kcab eht ot taerter ton did eh
.ecnelis ni ereht doots eH
.yenom ruoy tnaw tnod I
.reganam eht sa mih dezingocer terref ehT
,uoy tuoba leef I woh nialpxe ot woh wonk t’nod I ,yeroC“
”.emosdnaH ,thgie ta pu em kciP
.srotpecer eson etaciled sih pu gnizzuf
uoy morf gnimmargorp ruoy fo strap dih I
.yldaorb dennirg dna
”.taht rof etal elttil a sti tub ,ezigolopa ot u tnaw I
.pley deniap ,duol a htiw draobhsad eht otni liatgnir eht gnidnes ,sekarb eht no depmots netsE
troffe na ni retupmoc sih otni flesmih deggulp netsE
,txetnoc tuohtiw tub ,semit elpitlum egassem eht dessecorp netsE
feirb a desnes eH
.retsaf klaw ot detrats dna yawa mra sih dellup eH .dessih yeroC ”,og teL“
”!tiaW“ ”—revo si noitasrevnoc siht nehT“
.sselesu saw egassem eht
,nwod deid dah noitautis eht fo taeh eht ecnO
.reziteppa rellams a rof detpo eh sa derugif netsE ,ecnedicnioc ylpmiS
.tfel dna deretne elpoep sa gnihctaw yb emit eht dessap netsE
,trohs erew sesnopser s’netsE
.liatgnir eht fo hguone dah dah eH
.eeffoc gninrom sih netsE evres ot yppah naht erom demees ohw ,retnuoc eht dniheb enola gnidnats
.pirg sih htaeneb dekcarc doow eht litnu
dnatsrednu dluoc yeroC taht yaw on saw erehT
.noitcerid s’netsE ni worbeye desiar a gniworht
...leef I ,uoy dnuora m’I nehw taht wonk od I tub
.elbanialpxenu dna elbignatni demees noitanalpxe eht hguoht ,dnatsrednu ot gninnigeb won ylno saw eh tahw
”.yhw wonk t’nod I dna uoy tuoba gnikniht pots ot elbanu m’I
.mih tel ton dluow sthguoht sih dna dnim sih tub
.daeh sih ni deohce sdrow s’rehtaf sih sa
”.tnaruatser eht tuoba yrros m’I“
,tpada ot desoppus saw eH
.yrt ot dah eh ,liaf ot demood erew stroffe sih fi nevE
.tnemgdelwonkca ni deddon dna sselehtenon delims eH
”.netsE ,siht od t’nac I“ .kcab deppets yeroC
em teeM“ .esuap evitalpmetnoc
elggig rehtona evag eisseJ
.etteragic sih no yldeticxe deffup eh sa rof dellac noitautis eht naht deticxe erom raf demees eH ”?gniddik uoy erA“
gnid duol a htiw noitasrevnoc eht detpurretni reward hsac ehT ”.uoy htiw
.eisseJ no sucof ot ,niaga ecno ,decrof saw eH
.yklis dna suoiruxul ,enohs ruf siH
.rac s’netsE fo eton koot eh nehw denediw seye s’eisseJ
?won lavorppa ym rof etarepsed os uoy era yhW ?tahw em lleT“
.ti teg tnod yllaer U“
.esiwrehto ni drow a teg ot ecnahc a dah netsE erofeb pu gnignah eisseJ morf kcilc a saw erehT
”.kciuq ti ekam dna ,tolreM esuoh eht fo elttob a evah ll’I .retsiM
.ecnahc eht nevig ,dnim sih egnahc dluow eltsimocac eht depoh tub ,gninnalp saw eisseJ tahw fo aedi doog ytterp a dah eH
,lanif noisiced eht ekam ot thguoht dah netsE erofeB
.noitartnecnoc fo kcal sih rof nosaer rehto yna fo kniht t’ndluoc eH
”?huh ,nuf laer emos evah dna ecalp ym ot kcab og ew yas ayaddahW“
.dnatsrednu ot nigeb dluoc eh hguone drah thguoht eh fi tub
deunitnoc eisseJ ”!sruoh rof klaw t’now uoy ,raed ,tnemtrapa eht ot kcab teg ew nehw uoy ot od ot gniog m’I sgniht ehT“
tniop eht ot flesmih detaeper netsE
.ronaemed pot-eht-revo esiwrehto s’liatgnir eht fo tuo nellaf dah msaisuhtne eht fo emos tub ,deerga eisseJ
.elzzum sih no elims a fo tnih tsethgils eht htiw ezag s’netsE tem yeroC
,sesnes sih detlusni ti won tub ,erofeb tnacifingisni os neeb dah tI
,sdradnats lamron yb evitcartta ylbidercni
.yllis ,enif si siht
.ti saw siht erus saw eh ,etad tsrif a no od ot ton tahw no nossel a reve saw ereht fI
sdrow neewteb ni deddon ylpmis eH
.roivaheb ddo tnecer s’yeroC dna
”.esaelp lluf sretrauq-eerht ,eeffoc muideM“
54:9 4102 ,02 rebmeceD   ”.wols
”?netsE ,tnaw uoy od tahW“
.taht ekil thgin a retfa deneppah reve gnihton ekil gnitca ot kcab eb dluow u serugif
.ecnesba sih deciton srekrowoc sih nehw devil-trohs saw epacse siH
.tnemeticxe sih niatnoc ot elba ylerab ,rac eht sdrawot kcab mih deggard dna
.em ediug ot uoy fo htob eht tuohtiw ti enod evah t’ndluoc I dna
.eye sih fo renroc eht fo tuo eisseJ ot dekool navE
.dnah s’yeroC dezeeuqs netsE
.citamelborp emoceb ot gnitrats saw ti dna ,tnetsisni saw eltsimocac ehT .denaorg netsE
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,eisseJ dna netsE htob fo tnorf ni meht tes dna sessalg owt htiw tuo emac revres ehT
,ti rof dellac noitautis eht nehw segareveb dna slaem emusnoc ot dengised neeb dah eH
.lla ta efil on ekil demees xof eht tuohtiw efil a wohemos tuB
etad tnerappa sih dna riamA erehw elbat eht ot gnikool
.elbat rieht no eye na peek ot kcab gnicnalg ,flesmih desucxe ylteiuq
”,dnah rehto eht no ,yot yob ruoY
,roivaheb namuh fo epocs detimil s’netsE htiw nevE
.liatgnir suoixonbo eht rof ”tuo gnittup“ ni tseretni elttil ylgniraps dah netsE tub
.mih dnuora dlrow eht fo tser eht ekil tsuj
”.neves-ytrof rallod a eb ll’tahT“
”.erofeb ti tnaw t’ndid lleh sa erus uoY
.gninrael ,snoitidnoc thgir eht rednu ,dna gnitupmoc fo esoprup eht rof dengised neeb dah ti ,mih ekil hcuM
,erom gnidaer niA detsetni er’uoy fi dna
,gninrom txen eht pohs eeffoc eht ot snruter netsE nehw dna emoh flesmih klaw ot sreffo yeroC
.nwod dna pu mih dekool dna
.eeffoc eht gnikat erofeb detats eh ”,stnemegnarra wen ekam ot dah yltnecer I“
”,etad ruo tuobA .yrros m’I“
.thginot gniod eb thgim yeroC tahw ot daetsni gnitfird dnim sih
”!elpmas elttil a gnitteg tsuJ“
.lla retfa devlovni yllacitnamor emoceb ton meht fo owt eht taht
”?emosdnaH ,nalp eht s’tahw oS
”.rac eht ni em tselom ot deirt eh retfa emoh klaw mih edam I dnA“
”selbairaV“       :yojne esaelP
.srotpecer egami sih desolc dna
”?noH yako ,esle gnihtyna deen uoy fi llac a em evig lleW“
”,rof gnizigolopa er’uoy tahw wonk neve t’nod uoY“
.sserdda ym uoy txet ll’I !taerG“
,desoppus eh ,reisae eb thgim noitautis ehT
.yaw sti no ti tnes dna egassem eht demrifnoc eH
.gniklaw detrats dna netsE morf denrut yeroC
.noihsaf ralucitrap yna ni slewov fo gnirts detagnole
.yas ot gniht thgir eht ekil dednuos ti tub ,tnaem taht tahw wonk etiuq t’ndid eH
,ekoj a ta tnih eltbus a spahrep ,delggig eH ”?thgir ,uoy nO
.mra s’yeroC debbarg dna drawrof dehcaer netsE ”!evael t’noD“
,retnuoc eht dniheb gniretiol
.neeb dah yeroC htiw etad sih retsasid tnerappa na tahw gnirebmemer
”,ssenisub dehsinifnu fo tib a tsuJ“
.gniyap eno eht saw eh ecnis ,morf gnimoc eb dluow pit a fo kcal siht erehw desufnoc saw netsE
.gnilbmert saw ydob s’netsE
.mih fo tnorf ni retnuoc eht no eeffoc gnimaets s’netsE tes eH
tuhs rood rac eht demmals dna tuo deppets liatgnir ehT
.serutarepmet lanretni sih ni esir a tlef netsE dna
!uoy fo evren ehT“ ”.tuo teG“
,lliswodniw eht htaenrednu seceip lareves otni dedolpxe esuom eht sa derettacs seirettaB
.mih nevig dah rehtaf sih xob nedoow llams eht htaeneb yltcerid
,noitcerid lareneg s’terref eht ni ekoms welb dna dehgual liatgnir eht sa
enog saw ot demotsucca nworg dah netsE taht elims lausu s’xof ehT
.senot derepsihw ,hsrah ni tub ,ekops eH
ksed sih no enohp eht tfel eH
.netsE ,doog eb retteb dah sihT“ .devirra yeroC
”?olleH“   .reve naht regnorts won saw yeroC llac ot egru eht tub ,yhw nialpxe t’ndluoc llits eH
,nosrep nwo ruoy otni worg dna ytirutam hcaer dluow uoy taht dnim ym ni noitseuq on saw ereht ,revewoH
,netsE morf tupni elttil htiw kaeps ot yppah
”.uoy tceffa snoitca ym woh fo gnidnatsrednu retteb a ot em sgnirb ekatsim hcae tuB“ .dedda eh ”,tol A
.lla retfa yats ot yeroC ecnivnoc ot elba neeb t’ndah eH
.yad yreve mih llet ot erus ekam I dna
.etarebiled dna luferac meht gnikam
derettam ti fo enon ,rof demmargorp neeb dah eh tahw fo sseldrager dna
,revewoh ,did yrtiucric siH
.owt ni sriatsnwod saw netsE
.ti ekil leef t’ndid erus eh tsael ta
”,uoy htiw thgir lla eb dluow taht fi ,rennid gnikniht saw I“
.flesruoy rof efil ecneirepxe dna pu worg uoy ees ot teg reven dluow I
.pu ydit ot emiT .moor kcab eht otni
.secnalg gnoledis gnikam mih hctac ot deganam terref eht tub
”.ecivres tnellecxe eht rof uoy knahT“ .delims dna
;rof uoy demmargorp ev’I tahw si sihT
,taes s’revird eht otni revo gninael saw dna
,redro ot emit emac ti nehW
”!pit rallod ytfif a ,ekil si sihT“
.detaeper eh ”,uoy llet ll’I“
.gnitca neeb ev’uoy woh nialpxe yllaer t’nseod taht tub ,netsE yrros m’I“
.elbmurg a htiw smra sih dessorc yeroC ”.ecnahc dnoces A“
”.ezigolopa dluohs I ekil leef I“
.slautir gninrom sih ot satsirab wen niart ot emit hcum os koot ti dna
.ngised s’rehtaf sih ot detfarc neeb dah taht
”.retteb hcum os od nac uoy ,gnilrad em morf ti ekaT“
,diordna na saw eh wenk yeroC fi
.denifernu dna deggaj stnemevom s’liatgnir eht ,niaga dezeeuqs wap siH
:ssem a erew senituorbus siH
.enituor laicos gninrom sih otni etaroprocni ot elacol wen a gnidnif tneps erew syad wef txen ehT
.thgin eht otni ffo nar dna denrut eH
”?thgir ,llib eht tog ev’uoY .ekoms a deen I ,naM“
”.gniod er’uoy tahw pots esaelP“
.uoy htiw eb ot tnaw llits I ,deneppah sah taht lla fo etips nI
”,no tleb taes ruoy tup esaelP“ .gel
?gninoitcnuflam eh saW
,gnitad fo seicacirtni eht tuoba elttil wenk eh hguohT
.tnaruatser eht hguorht detanoser taht hgual llirhs a htiw
?gnorw saw tahw oS .rewsna emas eht mih evag tnempiuqe lanretxe ynA
.egassem eht fo ytilanif eht dootsrednu eh
.daeh sih koohs dna delims toleco ehT
,kaerbtraeh dna evol tuoba hcum os denrael ev’I
.hteet sih tirg ot mih desuac dna
,erofeb elims a gnirud drawkwa tlef reven dah netsE
gniraeppasid erofeb seitud etunim tsal emos htiw flesmih deisub yeroC
dehguoc toleco ehT
drawrof deppets netsE
.noisacco eht rof desserdrevo ylthgils dekool netsE
.gnimmargorp sih tsniaga dna
.esle enoyna ro netsE sdrawot ragluv neeb reven d’eh
.netsE morf ecnatsid sih gnipeek llits ,kcab deklaw yeroC
xob eht ta dezag eH
.niaga mih gniees ot drawrof kool t’ndid ylniatrec eH
.tuo tup ll’yeht dna ,pu tuP
;esnopser evitcejbo yletairporppa na etalumrof ot tseb sih deirt eH
stnap s’netsE deppiznu eisseJ
”.enif sdnuos taht ,haeY“
.yaw rehtona eb ot dah erehT
.eiteews no emoc ,wA“ ”.efas ton s’tI“
,deiduts dah eh tpecnoc a
”.uoy ot klat ot tnaw t’nod I“
.sucofer ot egami eht dewolla dna
.emoclewnu yrev dna hguor saw pirg siH
”.gnihtolc ruoy deniats taht eniw eht gnisahcrup rof ecnanep sa gninaelc yrd ruoy fo erac ekat nac I
”.erofeb etad a no neeb reven ev’I“
.skooB goD daB yb ,5 raoR rof noissimbus a sa yrots siht etorw ohw
.derugif eh ,ydaer teg llew sa thgiM .evif-ytrof xis
.dnuof eb ot erehwon si yeroC
.redlof rieht otni kcab srepap sih delffuhs netsE
.elbat eht no nikpan eht dessot dna spil sih depiw eH
.delevorg ev’I dna dezigolopa evah I
.enil rehto eht no esuap a saw erehT ”.yrros m’I“
”.s’onailatI ekil ecalpemos fo gnikniht saw I“
.dnatsrednu t’ndid llits eh sgniht rof mih ot ezigolopa ot
.pis rehtona koot netsE
”?taht saw lleh tahw ,netsE“
,noitasrevnoc s’eisseJ no desucof gnipeek seussi dah eh
.sih ni swap s’yeroC koot dna
.yrassecen ton tub
.detsetorp netsE
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
eet flog deralloc ,naelc a ylno gniraew
,rehtaf ,mih evol I
.wodniw eht hguorht xe s’eisseJ ot kcab gnikool ,deksa netsE
elbarovaf eb regnol on yam ti secnatsmucric tnecer ot euD
”.dluow I“ ”!t’ndluow uoY“
.pu elkcub ot dlot erew uoY“
.trihs sih morf selknirw eht dehsurb eh sa dias netsE ”,oN“
.esuap gnol rehtona saw erehT
”,tcefrep ton m’I wonk I“
.noitacinummoc fo sdohtem suoirav eht tuoba denrael tsrif eh nehw
?mih ot gnineppah saw tahw oS .siht fo yna rof demmargorp neeb t’ndah eH
,hctiwt dna yletaidemmi esnet selcsum s’xof eht tlef eH
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.kcab wap sih dellup yeroC ”.esaelP
,pu gnuh dah yeroC taht sngis rof denetsil netsE
ffo wohs ot hguone tsuj pu denepo kcen ehT .snaej eulb dna
dehsinav dah xof eht enifed ot demees taht sgniht eht fo llA
”.noitceffa dewohs eno woh saw taht thguoht I“
keew a ni yeroC nees t’ndah eh gniredisnoc ,tnavelerri saw tI
denruter toleco eht taht neht ylno saw tI
.noitautis eht ot dnopser ot sselpleh
s’yeroC rednu dessarrabme ,yawa dekool netsE
ma54:01 4102 ,82 yaM
.ereht yllaer ton saw terref eht taht flesmih ecnivnoc ot gniyrt fi sa
,rebmun eht denimaxe netsE
.evirra ot eniw sih rof gnol tiaw ot evah t’ndid eisseJ
.lla retfa ,eniw emos evah dluow eh dediced netsE
.netsE ta ecnalg gnoledis a gnikat
”,uoy llet t’nac I“
esimorp I tub ,noitcnuflam a gnicneirepxe era ro
.noitome war fo snoitacifimar eht eldnah ot hguone derutam dah uoy nehw
,netsE htiw tcatnoc eye gninruter ton
”.ti s’tahT“ ”?ti s’tahT“
.seralg yrgna sih hguorht detrotsid dna delknirw serutaef sih
,ssenisub ym ton s’ti ,kooL“ .ffo deliart eh
sredluohs s’enipluv ehT
.ytitnedi eurt sih laever ot ,gnimmargorp sih tsniaga gniog netsE tuohtiw ton—
;regna saw liatgnir eht sdrawot tlef eh tahw
.yawyna eceip emit sih ot gnikool flesmih dnuof eh ,emit eht fo erawa syawla saw netsE hguohT
.noitasucca na naht eno evitisiuqni na fo erom neeb dah noitseuq ehT
sredluohs sih fo gurhs a htiW
,retal sdnoces owt-ytriht dna setunim nevelE
edis ot edis morf spih sih devaw eltsimocac ehT
.deggeb eh ”,esaelP
.eeffoc gninrom sih rof seunev gnignahc ni tseretni on dah eh ,yraid sih ot yrartnoC
;tuo ti erugif dluoc I taht gnipoh saw I tub ,wonk t’nod llits I taht tol a s’erehT
.tuo dettuj ti sa gnalc hsrah a dna
.gnorw enod ev’I tahw dnatsrednu ot tseb ym enod ev’I“
,retfa yltrohs deraeppa liatgnir ehT
.pal sih otni ylbatrofmoc liat sih gnilruc ,taes regnessap eht otni depmuj liatgnir eninimef ehT
.msaisuhtne sih htiw gniliec eht hcuot dluoc taht srae—
”!suoiralih s’taht ,netsE hO“ .eciton tuohtiw meht neewteb ecnelis eht gnirettahs ,rethgual otni tuo tsrub eisseJ
.dediced eh ,ti od dluow eH
.thgin tsal etad sih gnirud em
daeh sih koohs netsE
retnuoc tnorf eht ot yaw sih gnikam ,pohs eht ot rood eht hguorht dehsup netsE
eht ot dnopser ot desoppus saw eh fi erusnu ,dednopser eh
,kiavoJ dnaloR yb
,yako t’nsaw gnihtyreve fi eil ot nosaer on dah liatgnir eht gnirugif ,flesmih ot deggurhs netsE
.suolaej yllatot s’eh ,mih tegroF“
.wols ti ekat s’tel tub ,thgirlA“
dna nwod setalp eht tes toleco ehT ”.uoy knahT“
.unem eht no gniht evisnepxe tsom eht dekcip dah eisseJ
tnemgduj sih deduolc sthguoht elitsoH
.yeroC htiw tcatnoc-eye gnikam dna
.tcatnoc eye ekam t’ndid yeroC ,netsE evres ot tuo emoc did eh nehW
.wol depoots srae sih htiw roolf eht gnola delwarc seye siH
,tlef eh ,esoprup ylno siH
”,dnatsrednu t’nod I“
ksed sih no esuom sseleriw eht gnibbarg erofeb tnemtrapa ytpme eht ot detuohs eH
.ecnatsissa yna dereffo meht fo enon tub ,segap eht hguorht deppilf eH
.nos ym ,efil fo tfig eht htiw uoy sselb I
”.ereh tog ev’ew tahw ees s’teL“
,revo dekool netsE
;hctaw sih ta dekool dna nwod enohp eht tes eH
.retnuoc eht dniheb morf deteerg trihs nottub etihw a ni toleco na
.netsE ot kcab gninrut ,wap a devaw dna deffocs eisseJ
”?dnim ni evah uoy did nuf fo dnik tahW“
,euqinu a hcus dedivorp xof eht nehw eunev wen a gnisoohc tluciffid saw tI
”?yrros m’I“ .noisufnoc emos
.doolb dna hself erew eh fi sa lohocla dna eniw ecneirepxe
.detcepxe naht renoos gnimuser eb ot dluow gnitad fo yduts sih taht demees tI
.dnoces-tilps a rof deremmihs mih erofeb deraeppa taht steehsdaerps ehT
.ralloc sih xif ot netsE gnivael
.sthguoht s’netsE otni depees noitartsurF
.sriatsnwod pohs eeffoc eht ta hsur gninrom eht fo dne eht gnikram
.selbairav ynam ooT
.etad tnerruc sih ot ralimis morf raf saw xof eht dna
.ronaemed citegrene dna
.snoitacificeps esoht fo enon gniteem saw eisseJ dna ,cilbup ni gnitca rof srennam detpecca ylnommoc dna
meht fo erutan railimafnu dna war eht ,tlef dah eh snoitome eht dellacer netsE
.ti nepo ot emit thgir eht eb reve dluow ti nehw wonk ot yaw on dah netsE
.yb evord taht srac wef eht dna spmalteerts yb ylno derewop ,etalosed dna teiuq saw thgin ehT
.dnuora dellor kcolc’o evif nehw ytpme ylraen saw pohs ehT
.selbat ybraen yna fo yaw eht fo tuo ylluflliks htrof dna kcab gnikcilf liat sih
”?retal kcab emoc I dluohS“
”.remrahc a hcus s’eH ?netsE dneirfyob wen ym tem uoy evah ,riamA“
.stnemevom eltbus dna elims eltneg s’yeroC ot nosirapmoc ni delap ti dnuof netsE
.ssik tsrif a retfa etairporppa eb dluow noitasrevnoc fo dnik tahw erus ton ,pmirhs deirf sih no dehcnum netsE
,tnaruatser eht ot kcab daeh sih denrut netsE ”.os yas uoy fI“
.gnimmargorp sih fo eroc yrev eht tsniaga tnew yeroC gnilleT
”.setunim neetfif ni pohs eht ta
.thgin eht rof egrahcer ot moordeb sih ot tnew dna
,ydegart ni dedne yletamitlu dah etad rieht hguoht nevE
.tekcop sih morf syek debbarg netsE ”.erus ,haey ,hO“
.yeroC fo ffo seye sih gnikat ton
.tcaer ot woh fo erusnu saw eH
.ylsseltroffe snalp sih etucexe dluow eh emit sihT
.detimil saw snortap rehto eht ot rettahc sih dna
.sterces tsepeed ruoy meht htiw erahs ot dna
.deddon ylpmis eh os ,taht ot yas ot tahw erus t’nsaw netsE
stfig esoht erahs ot woh dnatsrednu yad eno yam uoy taht sepoh eht ni
.etarebiled si noitisnart siht taht
.noitasrevnoc eht etaitini ot woh erusnu ,stekcop sih ni sdnah sih htiw doots netsE dna
.doirep gnitiaw tes a saw ereht erawa t’nsaw I“
,yhw nialpxe t’ndluoc eH
.dnim on netsE gniyap dna selbat nwod gnipiw
dnah sih ni repap eht delpmurc netsE   .selrahC ,evoL
”?eiteewS ,emoh ta selbuorT“
”!naem uoy tahw wonk t’nod I“
.rood s’eisseJ ta gnivirra retfa txet kciuq a tuo tnes netsE
,elbat s’netsE hcaorppa t’ndid eH
dapeton sih no nwod gnihtemos etorw toleco ehT
.ssik detcepxenu na otni drawrof mih gnillup ,ralloc eht yb netsE debbarg dna
,dnuora er’uoy nehW“
.sriatsnwod rodnev eeffoc eht tneuqerf ot
?gnitartnecnoc emit drah a hcus gnivah eh saw yhw os
s’netsE nwod dna pu wap a gninnur
”,ynnuf gnihtemos dias uoy ekil tca tsael tA“
,nekorb era uoy taht kniht yam uoY
.redluohs eht no hsup lufyalp a netsE evag eh ”,yoc eb t’noD“
.edis eht ot ffo gnikool elihw delbmurg eh ”,ot desu I“
,yawa dekool yeroC hguohT
.yad erom eno tiaw ot evah tsuj dluow stcartnoc gnitnuocca siH
noisserpmi eht netsE evag noitatiseh s’yeroC
”.uoy ees ot tnaw I tub ,etad ruo gnirud deneppah tahw dnatsrednu ylluf t’nod llits I“
”!retsiM ,em htiw lacinhcet teg t’noD“
.gnimmargorp sih rof tnaem ti tahw dna
htiw lufhtuom tsrif sih dehsinif netsE
”?flesruoy naht rehto enoyna tuoba erac u oD
”.og dluohs uoy kniht I“
.gnicneirepxe morf deretlehs neeb ylsuoiverp dah tub
,yb dessap raguoc ykcots ,trohs A
,pu deppilf liat s’eltsimocac ehT