”.sevil lanosrep ruoy tuoba noissucsid knarf
”?yletal emit doog a gnivah saw eh ekil mees eh diD“ .deksa I
enalp eht draoba morf noisolpxe na fo esuaceb nwod tnew enalp eht taht wonk nitsuJ did woH“
,yad yreve ssupelggunS ardnaS yb dekcus kcid sih gnitteg saw dna tius inamrA na flesmih thguob
–  ”.niaga nosrednA rM ot kaeps dna og dluohs ew kniht I“ .deddon I
…uoy semitemoS“ .denialpxe I
,deedni ,erew ”ruolf“ dna ”ados gnikab“ dellebal seno ehT
.enirevlow eht morf mra ym fo barg mrif a yb detcartsid saw I  .gniregaw ym yb
.taochcnert egieb a ni tar a ,tcatnoc ym ot revo deklawI   .thgim elpoep eseht
.noisiv s’reklaW rM ssorca ylwols gnicap ,denialpxe I
,syawyella elpuoc a nwod ,skcolb wef a pu klaw llams a koot I
.redrocer xob kcalb eht raeh ot ni dellac si yalbmerT evitceteD ,yllanif dnA
,detnioppasiD“ ”?sthguoht reH
”.ecivressid eht etiuq ,flesruoy ,deedni dna ,mih ,reh gniod er’uoy kniht I ,relaed gurd a er’uoy taht neviG“ .redneterp taerg on saw nam sihT
.der gniog ,dias syhR ”?reH“
,uoy otno era elpoep wonk uoy taht won sgurd fo lluf enalp eht pu wolB
ylevitisiuqni em ot dekool enirevlow ehT
”.gnitirwdnah taht esingocer I timda ot dengiser ma I“
”.tnelis niamer ot thgir eht evah uoY
”.uoy ees ot ereh era senoJ evitceteD dna yalbmerT evitceteD ,reklaW rM“  .edistuo gniniamer tser eht ,gnidliub eht deretne stnega laredef owt dna syhR ,flesyM
.rehpargotohp yawliar dna
.edis eht ot ffo htoob a ni tas enim fo tcatnoc a deips I ,moor eht dnuora dekool I sA
.taoc ym ni ti gnicalp dna rettel eht pu gnidlof ,deddon I ”?stcatnoc
.ti ni gnigludni saw I dezilaer I tnemom eht ti pots ot thguos I dna ytleurc sseltnioP
.wonk I lla s’taht ,sallaD rof
lever ot tnemom a koot I
”.devoleb reh fo etaf eht no erusolc reh gnivig rof I dna flesruoy gniknahT
”?swen eht gnikat ehs
nosrednA kcaJ ,tcepsus dael eht
,oga htnom a ereh ni deklaw eH“
”.epyt taht fo stcatnoc on dah uoy em dlot uoY“
.gniht cebeuQ a s’tI“
.syawla sa ,elbaulavni neeb evah sthgisni ruoy ,uoy knahT"
”.rehtegot emoc lla dluow nalp elttil sih taht dna
.mih fo wenk I ,haeY“ .deksa I
”.enod sa doog sa saw boj eht dna eil ruoy mrifnoc ot ni senoJ rM dna flesym gnirB .htiw
.yldednim-tnesba derepsihw I
,ereh syhR dna flesym derih uoY"
"!ti enod ev’uoy senoJ syhR“
,emit eht ta hgih dna knurd saw I taht nevig
senoJ syhR evitceteD dna yalbmerT rotciV evitceteD ,emit tsaL
.htuom ym otni seirf eht fo wef a gnidiug ,deilper I ”.enituoP“ ”?taht s’tahW“
.llib eht rof deksa dna retnuoc eht no nwod ssalg eht decalp I erofeb noisseccus kciuq ni yeksihw fo sessalg wef a hguorht ti edam I
.htiw tem saw ti esnopser tahw rebmemer ot pots t’ndid I .derettuts I
.mih ta worbeye na desiar I .detnurg eH ”?ti si ,teiluJ dna oemoR yltcaxe toN .reppirts a s’ehs dna lanimirc a saw yuG ?nac uoY“
.tfarcria eht detagitsevni dah dna
.yletilop dias I ”.uoy knahT“
.gnidnuop saw traeh yM
”.gniliaf dna eid ot ton gniyrt elpoep fo sepat ot netsil ,seidob daed ta kool ot boj ym s’tI“
”?erusaelp eht ewo ew od tahw oT“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
nevig d’eh gab citsalp llams eht ni ffilps eht fo sniamer eht decalp I
,lufraF lacsaP yb ”doolB repaP
.ti fo stoL .knird
.ton era ew esuaceb ylesicerp tub
,boj knab a morf eerf-tocs ffo tog tsuj
eht dna werc eht neewteb saw elggurts ylno ehT .tipkcoc taht otni tsrub ydoboN“  2 fo 2 traP
”.ssupelggunS ardnaS“ .dehgis I
.egats ertnec eht sdrawot daeh sih gniddon ,dias eH
.bulc gnicnad a eb ot demees ti ,weiver rehtruf nopU
.taht ekil nam sselwal ,lufrewop a dnuora depparw
.mih ot ti dewohs I nehw dias syhR
”?ereht no ti tup ohw ro morf emac ti erehw ,gniog saw ti erehW
.mih ot epat eht denialpxe I
dna boj knab tsal sih fo selat duorp gnillet
"?taht wonk uoy ,rettam t’nod su ekil elpoeP“ .deffocs tar ehT
dna syhR htiw nwod tas I ,gninrom txeN
”?lausu ym fo yna toG“ .dehgis I
.smra eht yb ylmrif mih debbarg I .dias eH
.ti pots ot elbanu
”?tuo dnif uoy did tahw
:ni yalbmerT rotciV“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
.draeh dah I tahw tegrof ot gniyrt dna sgnidliub eht gninnacs seye ym
.syawriA mA htroN tpurknab-eb-ot-noos fo sretrauqdaeh eht detraped ew
”?htiw uoy pleh I nac tahW .evitceted ,hA“  .wot ni
.emoh etal os gnieb rof gnisigolopa
,tiaw nac siht ,kool …thgirlA“
d’eH“ .deknilb tar ehT
.ecarg emas eht dednetxe I dna ,em htiw luficrem neeb sah eH
.toof ym htiw tuo ti debbuts ,ffilps ym dehsinif I
.gnirolpxe htrow erew smsinahcem gnipoc ym yfitsuj tsomla ot gnihtyna tub
.seye gnimriuqs s'nitsuJ fo setihw ylraep eht otni gnikool
.seisatnaf ralimis dah tar eht noisserpmi eht tog I
.egap ytiniffaruF sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
derifkcab thgilf eht ot ssecca lagelli s'ragdE ecurB rebbor knab gnivlovni nalp pukcab ruoY
dna pils ym gnisilaer ,ezorf I
thgilf egnahc ot saw ti neht ,noscuT rof elttaeS fo tuo gniylf saw tI“ .deksa I
”.raehnu ot drah gniyrt m’I tihs emos draeH .yad roop a gnivaH“
”?tey efiw ruoy ot dezigolopa uoy evaH“
.thgilf a rof tnuoma llams a etiuq s’ti hguohT
”.reh ssim t’naC .stit suoegroG
.wodniw eht tsniaga pu gnikcab ,depsag eH ”?tahW“ .ton did eH
.delbmert luos yM
srotagitsevni eht fi
.tnedicni s'yadot ot roirp uoy tsniaga tiuswal a gnilif nosrednA rM rof tnuocca ot deliaf uoy ,revewoH" .deunitnoc I
.ni evil ew elzzup dnarg eht ot
enirevlow ehT ”?setunim 5 evah ew naC“
”?ragdE ecurB tuoba gnihtyna wonk uoy oD“
.dedaol gnieb meht dehctaw I“ .dias xof ehT
s’tI“ .erom gnihton ,yalpsid ohcam A
”.sexob eniacoc saw draob no ograc eht fo tsoM
.esac ni tsuj dnim ym fo kcab eht ni tpek I tub ,lufesu yletaidemmi eb ot ylekilnu
.etius ecnerefnoc eht deretne dna rotavele eht tfel eW
:ni yalbmerT rotciV“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
nigeb ot snalp ruoy htiw delddem dah ohw eeyolpme na etanimircni ,ecnedive fo dir teg ot tfarcria na nwod
…ruoy fo eno hguorht sserdda ruo derehtag ehs emussa I .gnitseretni …hA“
”.dnim ni dah I gniht txen eht saw tahT“
”?tseretni evol eht fo eman eht wonk uoY“
,ti til dna tnioj a flesym dellor I
?tellap eht tuoba gnihtyna
”.noisolpxe eht ni deyortsed neeb sah ti fo tsoM“ .detats eH
,deretne ew nehw elbat eht dniheb morf pu doots nooccar ehT
.syad ni emit tsrif eht rof enirevlow eht ta gnilims ,dias I
,noitanimatnoc ksir t’ndluoc I tub ,epat ettessac ym dah I dehsiw d'I .deilper I
”.wonk t’ndluow I ,esle erehwemos morf ni emoc dah ti fI
,lufraF lacsaP yb ”doolB repaP
.tseretni evol a ,tius wen a dah ,boj knab a detelpmoc tsuj dah ecurB“
”.rennid ot og dluohs ew spahreP“
”.lla eb lliw taht ,uoy knahT“
?ew evah tem ev'eW“ .deborp I ”?hO“
syaw suoromalg ssel ot nrut ot evah
.dertah htiw gnimmirb tub
,tnappilf eb ot ecalp tseb eht ni ton saw xof ehT
,enoemos ot ton fi ,tol a rettam uoY"
.regrub sih fo etib rehtona gnivah ,dias syhR ”.taht
”?redruM“ .denialpxe I
.kniht ot ecaps dna emit su evig ot
,em ta kcab derats syhR ”.epoc ot
”.mih htiw nwod thgilf a ekat ot nosaer evah dluow ragdE ecurB ton ro rehtehw si noitseuq txen eht esoppus I“ .dias eH
”.wonk ot lufesu eb dluow ti morf emoc d’yeht erehw tuoba gnihtyna wenk eh fI
”.eil meht tel ot eerga s’teL .evarg eht ot ekat ot ekil d’ew sterces evah htob ew ees I“
dna luftsiw enot siH
”.edicius ton saw ti taht feileb tcnitsid a evah I
.dnik ocsid eht ton dnA
,lufraF lacsaP yb ”doolB repaP
.erom neve tsoc seno doog eht tub ,eno tsepaehc eht yltcaxe t’nsaW
…ruoy srevocsid gnidnatsrednu ssel enoemos erofeb pleh lanoisseforp erom emos gnitteg redisnoc dluohs uoy spahrep dnA“ .deddon syhR
.daeh sih koohs dna dehgis eH
.edis eht ot smoor noitagorretni tnacav eht fo eno otni em del eH  ”.esruoc fO“
.bulc suolupurcsnu na otni dekcud I ,teerts kcab llams a nI
”.erehwemos ereh ni gnissim eceip
.deksa syhR ”?wonk uoy od woH“
gnicar saw daeh yM
”?os taht sI“ .dias tar ehT
,hcnul rof tnew eW  -  .rehto hcae ta kool ot gnilggurts su fo htob ,deerga syhR .ylmrif dias I
.daeh sih fo kcab eht debbur enirevlow ehT
.tac kcalB .namow lufituaeB
.enohpelet eht revo denialpxe tsinoitpecer ehT
".tcatni noscuT dehcaer ti fi sallaD ot detrevid eb ot ni ti dekoob ydaerla d'uoy ,esruoc fo gurd eht pihs ton ylpmis ot droffa t'ndluoc uoY
,deb otni debmilc dna derewohs ,emoh kcab devirra I
.dias I ”.ytefas ruoy rof
,yltnelis em ta kcab gnirats nooccar eht
.senilria esoht no dnuora nwolf gnieb ylraluger erew sgurd taht stnuocca s’nosrednA rM etadilav dluow sihT“ .deddon I
saw ssupelggunS sM ot gnikaepS
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.draobno sgurd eht tuoba nosrednA rM htiw rehtruf gnirrefnoc htrow s’ti eveileb I“ .dias I ”.emit
.enod d’I tahw wenk selrahC wenk I
”?si ti tahw em llet uoy naC“ ”.thgir leef
.krims a htiw dias eH ”uoy
.ylmrif ,dias
.truh eb ot ton gnidneterp s’eh nehw sekam nam a tnurg fo dnik eht saw tI
.pirt detsaw a eb ot esiwrehto saw ti ,lleW
otni erats ym deirub dna taorht ym deraelc I .derettuts eh
.ardnaS .sM morf ,deedni si tI“
,elbat eht no sdnah ym decalp I
.riahc ym ni gnilffuhs ,detnurg I
s’woH“ .noitpircsed lacisyhp reh dettif taht tohseye ni enoyna saw ereht fi ees ot dnuora dereep I
”?won od ew llahs tahW“
”.syad esoht fo eno t’nsaw yadot tsuj
”.tniop taht ta enalp eht ot ti edam tsuj ylno d’yehT
.dloc gninnur ruf ,htaerb peed a koot I ”?yhW“
”?yas eh did tahw ,emit tsrif eht uoy dellac nitsuJ nehW“
.rekihhctih flowerew
,ruolf dna ados gnikab
.dekoms I sa hguoc ot ton gniyrt ,tnurg I
.ylmrif tub ,ylmlac dias syhR ”.em ot deil uoY“
.denialpxe enirevlow ehT ”.eniacoc
”.ti tuoba deliated gnihtyna em llet ot dewolla t’nia uoy sseug I“ .deplug tar ehT
.detnurg xof ehT .denialpxe I
,pu uoy gnar eh dnA“ .dias I
.gniknird detrats dna eiv-ed-uae tsegnorts rieht fo emos deredro ,rab eht ot ti edam I
”.”tnuoma llams“ dias uoy …tuB“
,enots eno htiw sdrib owt llik dluoc uoy taht tlef uoY“
”.yug eht devol yllaer ehs ekil smees ,ylrooP“
nehw enalp eht ot deneppah tahw wonk nitsuJ did woH“
nruter ni delims dna deddon syhR ".syawla
dna moor eht fo tuo del saw nooccar ehT
.yhposolihp rof emit dab a saw ti spahreP
”ssupelggunS“ ”?…ardnaS“
a s’ereht kniht tsuj I“ .dias eh ”.lliw I
,reklaW nitsuJ ,renwo enilria eht htiw tem dah
.dnik ni detnurg I ”.taht ynnuF“
;detcepxe sa yltcaxe saw ”ydnac eson“ tub
.redrocer ettessac eht tnew nO .rotavele eht otnI
,reklaW deffucdnah dna dnuora deppets stnega owt ehT
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.taht ton s’ti ,oN“ ”.ardnaS
”.stnuocca lla yb ,dekcots llew ylriaf netfo er’uoY .uoy ekilnu ytterP“
.tfel dah I drow ylno eht saw tI
”.uoy htiw stnemeergasid dna sgnidnif gurd gnitroper fo drocer kcart a htiw eeyolpme na dah uoy ,erofeb tfarcria ruoy no dnuof neeb dah sgurD .deyortsed enalp eht tnaw ot nosaer elpma dah uoY
,srewolf emos efiw ruoy yub ot tnaw yam uoy taht tseggus osla thgim I ,dna ,hO“ .detseggus I
”.mih wenk ohw enoemos htiw tem …I“
”.htfif eht daelp ot esoohc I“ .dehguoc I
.yleerf kaeps dluoc ew fi ees ot dnuora gnikool ,dekrims eH
,xob kcalb dna redrocer eciov eht rof sA“ .deddon syhR
”.rehtegot llits er’ew …tub ,yppahnu
”.taht tuoba erus os eb t’noD“
…a evah dna setalocohc
.xobrettel ym ni eton a dnuof I ,retal syad wef A  -
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.pu gnidnats ,dias I
,sllib rallod ytnewt elpuoc a mih dednah I ”?tnaw uoy’d hcum woH“ .dekrims tar ehT ”.esruoc fO“
wonk uoy oD .dehsarc taht thgilf eht morf eniacoc fo tnuoma llams a derevocer evah eW“
,sliaf taht fi ro eeyolpme yrgna ylnekopstuo na no emalb taht nip
”.tatibah ym yllacitcarP“ .ylyrd dias I
”.emit eht lla ereh ni emac eH
”.ralimis ro evisolpxe fo mrof emoS .thgilf-dim noitanoted a ot stniop gnihtyrevE
dnif ot ecalp ddO“
.reppirtS“ .dias tar ehT
.elbat eht ta gnippat dna regrubmah a fo etib a gnikat ,deddon enirevlow ehT .denialpxe I ”.gniht
.won esnes sekam lla siht ,esruoc fO“  –  .tsaf oot raf
”.thgin taht derhs ot dednetni yeht sdeb ynam woh
”.draob no evah uoy sgurd eht ot deknil eb ylisae nac ohw lanimirc a
.sdrow rof delbmuf dna deplug I
neeb evah ot gnihsiw ssenkaew fo tnemom ylenol ynam tneps d’I tub ,ti ot timda ton d’I .dias I
naicisum ,retiusruf ,retirw a si ohw
.nis fo maerd seod dnim eht ,elytsefil tsenoh na ton s’ti fi nevE
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.yas mih draehrevo I ”.pu meht dneS“
,snoitagitsevni hsarc ria ni strepxe erew ew esuaceb ton
,noisolpxe eht ot roirp ssertsid fo dnuos on
.noisufnoc ni deworran seye sih tub ,dias kcaJ
dedeen I .tolipotua no kcehc DI eht dessap I
,ecnedive ni htrof thguorb gnieb derehtag tsuj d'I noitamrofni siht fo yna ot snrecnoc lacihte ,esruoc fo ,erew erehT
”.gninoitseuq rehtruf htrow eb thgiM
”.dnuorg eht otni gnitemmulp werc thgilf a fo sdrow tsal eht ot netsil ot evah t’nod I keew eht fo syad tsom yletanutrof ..llew
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.moor eht fo ssenitpme eht ni
.rac eht otni debmilc I sa ,dias I
,smra sih ni thgit depparw ardnaS htiw ,tius inamrA na ni egats taht no pu debmilc
.mih ediseb nwod gnittis ,dias I ”.gnineve dooG“
.tsinoitpecer eht ot sgnivigsim ym yawa evig ot ton dluoc I tahw did I
”.snoitseuq uoy ksa nac I hguohT .tcerroC“ .delbmum eH
.htaerb peed a gnikat dna pu kcab gninael ,delworg I ".pu
,ragdE .rM wonk dluow enoyna fi derugif I
.pu gnuh dna gninrom worromot gniteem txen ruo demrifnoc neht
.efil hgih eht gnivil saw eH
siht ta ssucsid ot ton eerga osla nac ew tub ,no eerga nac ew snosaer roF
ecurB ro kcaJ saw ti taht noisulcnoc eht ot emoc d’uoy gniveileb
.lwocs a ot denrut ecaf syhR
.dellacer I ”.dnaltroP revo thgilf ni edolpxe enalp a dah d’eh em dlot eH“
,flowcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
”.flesmih rumel eht t’nia ti fi ,llew ,lleW“
.ecaf sih no elims a
,ti ot no gnah ll’I“
,dedda I ”.retal erom evah
…si ti tahw tuo krow I nehW“
.pu denil d'uoy setadidnac suoivbo eht fo eno tcivnoc tsuj ot su detcepxe uoY
.did dnuorg eht no enoyna erofeb gnol hsarc enalp eht fo esuac eht wenk uoY“
stnega owt eht dna
,seY“ .dennirg tar ehT
.gnikciffart gurd dna redrum fo noicipsus eht rof tserra rednu era uoy ,reklaW nitsuJ“
–  .ti noitnem ot mees t’ndid eh tub ,edaf ot sllems eht rof emit elttil a ekat d’tI
.sreenigne eht ot gnidrocca stupni thgilf detcepxenu on
”?bulc pirts a ni evitceted A“
.mih ot txen llebpmaC airaM ,reywal sih htiw emit siht ,xof eht fo tnorf ni kcab tas syhR dna flesyM
t’nseod …gnihtemoS“
,krowrepap eht morf yawa sroodtuo gnihtemos
.dnim sih ni gnirrihw sgoc
”.snoitseuq ”bmud“ eht gniksa tuoba uoy dlot I tahw s’taht ,eeS“ .deddon I ”.yltcaxE“
”.thgirla gniod saw eh kniht d’I os
?tey xob kcalb eht tog neve t’ndah
.moor rehto eht otni kcab delbmarcs I
.sibannac fo tekcap a kcab em dednah dna dekrims eh
enim no lwocs eht was eh sa dehsinav hcihw enO
.draobno eniacoc eht fo lla etarenicni ot evisolpxe hguone tnalp t'ndid uoy nehw
.tekcop ym ni tser eht gnittup
.ti nepo ot nwod tas I
sraet htiw gnillew seye sih
”?tey epod gnikoms deppots uoy evaH“ .denialpxe eH
”.ti enod ev’ew eveileb I .syhR ,lleW“
.tihs yenom gib ,yug boj knaB
,noitcidda na t’nsaw ti dog knahT
”?siht htiw od ot gnihtyna dah I taht aedi eht uoy sevig tahW“
dna deddon I ”.tibah
.deggurhs dna dehgis tar ehT ".ni
.gnidliub eht dnuora gnikool dna esuap gnikat erofeb ,evael ot pu tog dna llib eht diap I
,egakcerw eht hguorht kool uoy fI .tfarc eht rof thgiew daol mumixam eht rof yvaeh oot t’nerew yeht erus ekam ot dah I
.seye sih fo setihw eht
.dooG“ ”.seY“ .deksa I
.dluoc I fi kcart no kcab flesym teg ot neek ,bulc eht fo tuo deklaw I dna deddon eH  .emit sih rof mih deknaht dna em
.segakcap eht lla no stset enod s’bal ehT“
.dias I ”.yhw ees nac I“
.msinahcem gnipoc a tsuj
”.uoy erussa I ,eniacoc eb lliw ,egral dna yb ,ograc eht fo tser eht
.ecnatsid eht otni ffo gnikool saw syhR
”?gnihtyna uoy teg I naC“ .deddon eH
.depsag I ”.rekcufrehtoM“
”.ot nosaer on dah eH“
.ffuts taht fo stellap 51 tuoba erew erehT“ ”.did I ,seY“
.sretrauqdaeh mA htroN ot kcab yaw ruo edam ew dna pukcab emos ni dellac I
,gninrom eht ni ruof ta uoy gnar eh nehw
.deknilb I .laitnerever
.ylmrif deksa syhR ”?uoy dellac eh
.sgnivigsim ym gnilaever ron
…sM tuoba yrros m’I“ .delbuorT
?no saw flesmih eh thgilf a otno eniacoc elggums rebbor knab a dluow yhW
.bal eht morf kcabdeef eht dna epat eht fo tpircsnart s’rotagitsevni eht dah eH
.ragdE rM tuo elur nac ew ,yltsenoh ,eveileb I .thgirlA“
:ni yalbmerT rotciV“   yojne esaelP
.em fo leurc saw sihT .koob a ekil mih daer I tub ,desnet enirevlow ehT ”.nam deirram a fo gnimocebnU
ll’I“ .enohp eht nwod syhR ot dias I ”.enalp
.dedeen I tahw s’taht dna gnibmun saw ti tub ,suoromalg t’nsaw tI