!esav ahplA eht fo esac eht sevlos
.retal tuo krow ot evah d’I ,wenk ehs htrae no woh hguoht
,deredisnocer eno tub
”?tnatsissa ruoy em llac uoy diD“
,delaeppa esav a hcus htiw selrahC fo aedi deifidom ehT
.gniht ’nikool gnol llat ,eulb krad
”.ti dah yletinifed I haeY“
,rentrap rieht decnelis dna daeh rieht koohs wolley ni eno ehT
.ydob ym tsniaga kcams pets hcae tlef I
.snraey dnim eht woh hO
”?slegna wons emos ekam ot gninnalP“
.ecalp dlo na saw sihT
”.ecnediser ni osla si yevraH noD ,tnatsissa ym dna ,seY“
.statibah esrevid ylriaf gnivivrus fo elbapac saw flesym sa hcus rumel A .desaet I
.sriatspu kcab deirrucs yeht sa nwod kcab tas dna deddon I
sesaesid noitaidar fo aideapolcycne na gnidloh eb dluoc eH
.moor eht deretne neht dna
.deb ym otni dekcehc dna letoh eht ot denruter ew
.dloc tnew doolb yM  .epocs eht nevig
.t’ndah I gnihsiw neht
.gniht fo tros taht ,semehcs dimaryp
yalbmerT rotciV“   yojne esaelP
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si
.esruoc fo ,”etamitigel“ srallod noillib a gnivah llac dluoc uoy taht toN
,wap ni eeffoc htiW  .tuo ti tiaw dna
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
”?gnissim enog s’tahW“
.sriats eht evoba tsuj desuap wolley ni erugif ehT .loof nmad A
,lufraF lacsaP yb ”nnI dewonS
.ni ereh pu gnivird no detsisni d’eh ehcsroP elbirroh rehtar s’noD gnidulcnI
,eeffoc fo puc a teg ot saw
,gninrom eht ni dna deb erofeb selrahC llac dluoc I os enohpelet a htiw ,roolf driht eht no flesym ot moor llams a dah I .thgirb dna yria ,edisni denaelc llew saw ti hguohT
nekorb gnieb morf rehtie ,yltcerroc gninoitcnuf t’nsaw ylpmis rosnes eht taht saw
,dekrims regdab ehT
,nalp deredisnoc a saw siht taht elbissop s’tI
.ereh ni eb llits t’ndluoc feiht eht yhw
.inikib eht ni ti naelc ot teg I dna esav eht snwo selrahC
,lufraF lacsaP yb ”nnI dewonS - ni
.tsieh dennalp a naht rehtar ,evom evislupmi na spahreP
.thguoht evah dluoc I
.gnissim saw esav eht dna
.metsys mrala na htiw emoc ylekil tsom dluow epyt siht fo gnihtemoS
”.tuo eno taht krow ylbaborp nac uoy ,esav a ylno s’tI .thgir er’uoy ,haeY“
.ecno ta lla etuc dna tniauq
.wolley ni nosrep eno delkcat t’ndah I
.elihw a rof meht no deniart rae ym tpek I .dloc rettib dna
.tcapmi na fo ecnedive on
…hhu eht erew uoY !hO“
.ecalp siht dekcip I nehw eruhcorb eht ni saW
.siht rof snosaer owt eb dluoC
.htrae siht no sevil eritne ruo ni ees reve dluow selrahC dna em naht yenom erom saw tI
”.enog tsuj s’ti ,enog s’tI“
.ega sti gniwohs yletinifed tub ,elbatipsoh ,yzoC
,lufraF lacsaP yb ”nnI dewonS
.wodniw siht aiv epacse ot detpmetta tnaliassa eht elbissop s’tI
.noitamrof wons eht fo erutcip a tog dna aremac ym tuo koot I
.taoc gib a gnola gnirb ot devlove dah I ecneH
.niaga tekcop ym ni ti decalp dna parw elbbub ni gniht eritne eht depparw
,yap doog erew yeht tuB .hguor erew selrahC tuohtiw syats letoH
.tepraC .sriatS .potfooR .tepraC .reyoF .potfooR .tepraC .ees dluoc I llA
.ti denepo dna wodniw eht ot elbat edisdeb eht morf devom I
”.uoy rof ti naelc ot sebab inikib emos eriH
.nepo saw rood moor ehT .dnuora nups I
.egdab ym tuo koot I
ylekil dluow ecrof yb esac eht gniyortsed ,niagA
”.yalbmerT ,siht eldnah ll’I“
”.lortnoc rednu ti tog ev’ew yrrow t’nod ,on ,hhu hO“
,tnedicni ssecxe tuohtiw denid gnivaH
.siht no em ynapmocca ot nesohc saw eh
riahc a ni kcab tis
,ti esolc ot gnivom dna
,ti nihtiw sdrahs ssalg eht decalp
fo sgnikrow eht htiw ecneirepxe fo tol a dah noD
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
evivrus ot gnilggurts ecalp llams eht gnidnif elihw
,deknilb I .deltrohc noD
rehtaew hguor rof ydaer ylgnimees ,raewsroodtuo ni dalc htob erew riap ehT
daor rehto eht ot yawliar eht revo gnissorc efas a edam eW
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.wons eht dna dniw eht morf devaw dna derettulf sniatruc eht dna nepo ediw erew moor eht fo swodniw elbuod egral ehT
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,sboj yenom gib rof ”sdnah fo riap detsurt“ a sa nees saw dna
.gninialpmoc tnatsnoc s’noD yb siht morf detcartsid saw I
,deraeppa seitriht dim reh ni knuks a ,renwo ehT
.dluoc I erehw yap ym gnitteg ,rotcartnoc tnatculer a tsuj saw I
”!ti dnif uoy litnu gnidliub siht gnivael si uoy fo eno elgnis a toN“
.serutaef rehto yna teg t’ndid I .taoc wolleY
.tuo swalc dna hteet
noitca fo esruoc tseb ruo taht noD ot raelc edam I ,yawyna edisni kcuts erew ew taht dna
,erihppaS“ .dekrims eH
8891 ht21 yraunaJ  2 fo 1 traP
.ylkciuq dias ehS .”reinaL teragraM“ ”…hhhU“
.eralg a em evag ehS
.gnitcepxe saw I yaw eht ni ton hguohT
.pu gnidnats ,dias I ”.em esucxE“
.gnidliub noitats llams a dna
.thgis ni gnihtyreve detaoc dah wons fo doolf yvaeh ,kciht A
,htuoy ym gnirebmemer
.reyof noitpecer eht fo tnorf eht ta srood elbuod eht ot gnirutseg ,detnurg eH
.krof a htiw kaets nagev sih gnikop
ti tsniaga gnidiced neht
,nopaew yramirp yna ees t’ndluoc I
.noitcetorp dnah yna desu t’ndah feiht eht ro
.telracs yltcefrep tnew I
.derepsihw eulb ni eno ehT
,esav eht otni dna otno sdrahs ssalg pord
riahc kcabgniw a ni kcab tas I ,ports a gniworht regdab gnilbmurg a dna
”.nwo sih no enif etiuq ti eldnah nac rotciV erus m’I“
”.esac ssalg a nI .edis htron eht no rodirroc ertnec ,roolf poT“
trats ylrae na eb dluow worromoT
,tnemtnioppasid ym ot ,hcus sA
.llet gib eht eb dluow doolB
,yenom fo selip egral
.enola mih rof thgis gnilaeppa na eb llits d’ti dna
,esav eht fo noissessop ni saw eno ecnO
,dias eH ”.hguone dekooc ton ro hcum oot dekooc si kaets siht fi llet t’nac I ,naM“
.sirbed eht htiw decaf noos saw I dna roolf driht eht ot pu ezisrecxe thgil elttil A
.did eh yaw lufwa taht ni ,elkcac ot detrats noD
.kcapkcab a hguorht gnigammur
.yad gnol ,gnol a dna
”?citirc doof a emoceb uoy did nehw ecniS“
ecnerefnoc tnemtsevni na etagitsevni ot gnola thguorb neeb d’eW
.tfeht a fo trela ot gnihtemoS
,esirprus otni denrut hsulb yM
.egatnavda na saw ,timda ylgnigdurgeb I ,hsac ni dnuorgkcab sihT
.esuac ot tnaw ot ylekilnu eb dluow
”.thgin tsal ni dekcehc ohw yhtoroD fo dneirF
hguoht ,enohpelet a no enoemos htiw tnemugra trevo na gnivah taoc wolley a ni tar a deciton I ,gnitae elihW
”?enog s’ti ,naem uoy od tahW“
,daor eht pu rehtruf elttil a nehT
”.evitceted a flesruoy llac ,rotciV nom’C“
.dnarre s’loof a eb dluow woleb knab wons a htiw neve ,wodniw roolf driht a morf gnipael ,hguohT
.moorhtab etius-ne ecin yrev a sa llew sa
.evom lacigol eht eb dluow elbissop sa tsaf sa yawllah eht gnivael
.tnaruatser eht ta rennid evah ot detcele dna
.tpel I ,hateehc a ekiL .ton saw I
.etamitigelli dna etamitigel
ssalg fo sdrahs erew ti dnuorA
.desserd gnitteg dna enohp eht nwod gnicalp ,detcurtsni I
.woble sih htiw egdun a em gnivig
.seldnahrood eht fo eno no der fo spird wef a dettops I ,tsal ta erofeb
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,flesti esav eht ot egamad ksir dluoc nopaew a htiw ssalg eht gniyortseD
.swap eht htiw tcejbo eht pu kcip neht
,gab ecnedive rehtona otni ti decalp dna
.ti sreggirt tahw eb ylpmis thgim sihT
,dnats eht fo esab eht nI
.yawllah eht ssessa ot nageb neht
,ssalg eht rettahs ot desu
enil yawliar kcart-elgnis a tsap tsuj detsixe esehT
.adanaC htiw redrob eht tsniaga pu thgir erew ew dna
.woleb wons eht otni nwod
.tenibac yhport ruoy ni tnaw d’uoy gniht atroS
”.taorht ym ni ti kcuts dna enalporea na saw ti em dlot ,noops a pu dekcip ’aM ecniS“
.rewohs eht rof dedaeh dna deb fo tuo derebmalc dna dednetni sa mrala ym ot pu ekow I
.retsasid ym fo erutan eurt eht dootsrednu I dna tlah a ot delbmut ew tsal tA
”.enasni yletulosbA .esav nmad a rof 000’07$“ .deksa noD ”?tuoba gniklat erew yeht esav taht rebmemer uoY“
yrots s’yadoT dna
,yawa secap wef a doots selom fo riap A .dehctiwt rae yM
,lennahC kramllaH eht yb detcejer yldnuos saw ”samtsirhC gnikcuF yreV A“ rof tpircs s’ohw
.waht ot wons eht rof detiaw dna
,rodirroc eht nwod dna pu devom I
.dereggirt neeb ton dah tI
,gnirednual yenom fo knatS
ohadI htron ni dloc ylralucitrap saw retniW
.deilper I ”?seY“
.erugif ym revo kool a koot ehS ”.esaV ahplA ehT“
.knalb saw DEL ehT
.em goj ot kciuq saw regdab eht hguoht ,ti dellacer yleugav I
,sroolf eerht ,roiretxe kcirb deR
deddon I .denialpxe ehS
,fo ruovaf ni saw I eno eht ,owt nosaeR
.dloc citcra rettib htiw yltnatsni detsalb saw I
,enecs emirc eht fo shpargotohp yranimilerp wef a koot I
.pu raelc sgniht litnu tneve eht dnepsus ot gnivah er’ew diarfa m’I ,rehtaew eht ot euD“
.llac eht koot I ,sdnah yrd htiW
.dnats eht htiw tniop noitcennoc eht dnuora tcatni deniamer ssalg eht fo noitces mottob ehT
.llaw kcab eht tsniaga pu rodirroc eht fo ertnec eht ni dnats nedoow A
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.nwod dettam yats ot gnisufer tsafdaets ruf emos dna wap eht fo kcab eht no racs llams a htiw hguoht ,ruf tpek-llew yllareneG
.tnemelpmi na rof kcehc ot yltsriF
”?yalbmerT evitceteD“
.llewriats eht rof detraped ylksirb dna
.loof a saw I .ecnahc ym was I
,esruoc fo tey retteB
su ot tog d’eh ecno yltneregilleb delbmurg noD
”.nepo rood nmaddog eht teg neve t’nac eW“
:ni yalbmerT rotciV“
kool gnol a gnikat dna
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT      .owt delkcat d’I
.taht rof yaw tseb eht neeb evah dluow esab eht morf tnemhcated hguorht esac eht gnivomer hguohtla
,ti dehpargotohp I
.etutitsnI ygolonhceT emyzneB eht yb detsoh
.gniht elohw eht tuoba pmurg rettu na saw regdab ehT
wodniw eht sdrawot spets wef a gnikat dna em dniheb desolc rood eht gniggut ,detnurg I
nosaer on saw erehT
.ngised raw-erp a fo ylgnimees
.trams neeb evah dluoc I
.krims a htiw deriuqne I
.rosnes ynit a dna DEL der llams a was I
,gnidliub eht fo tuo demrots dah tar eht gniton ,dias I ”.gnimrahC“
.ni kcehc eht revo kcab daeh ym depparw I
.deedni boj yddohs a demees siht hguohT
.spets eht nwod gnilbmut meht dna flesym delruh dna erugif wolley eht delkcat I
.tnemom a rof tsael ta
.detamina erom emaceb eh sa enohp eht no tar eht ta gnirats ,dnahffo deksa I
.dehcaorppa dna pu doots I .delworg ehS
.nur a otni tuo ekorb I
.egami sih dekovni niarb yM
.selrahC saw ti esuaceb saw taht niaga neht hguoht
.enoz trofmoc ruo dnoyeb tahwemos saw wons tuB
.taht edisgnola eciffo ecremmoc dna edart a dna eciffo tsop yerg llams a
.letoh eht etisoppo yltcerid tnaruatser llams a fo gnitsisnoc
mraerif a dah ecneh ,ycnega evitceted ecilop eht htiw saw eH
.roolf eht fo dne htron eht ta hguoht ,esav eht sa roolf emas eht no gniyats neeb dah I
,denoptsop neeb dah ecnefnoc taht neviG
.ti no doolb ees dluoc I ,ssalg eht fo noitcepsni resolc nopu ,tub
,flesti letoh eht etisoppo egalliv llams eht otni dna letoh eht fo tuo yaw ruo edam ,yevraH noD ,noissim siht rof rentrap ym dna flesym ,lavirra ruo fo eve eht nO
dnah yb nekorb rehtie saw ti detseggus sihT
nopaew yramirp a evlovni yllausu dluow epyt siht fo barg-dna-hsams A
baws a otno elpmas a detcelloc
feiht rotcelloc a taht egamad gniod
.niaga tfeL .rodirroc eht fo dnE .hguone saw tahT
.ecnaraeppa rieht fo eton koot I
.sseltniop tahwemos ssalg eht gnihsams ekam dluow taht hguoht
.em derussa ylksirb wolley ni eno ehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”?tpek yllausu esav eht si erehW“ .detnurg I
,tfeht ot roirp delbasid saw rosnes eht taht saw eno nosaeR
.pihsnamkrow yddohs fo gnieb ro
”.tatibah ruoy yllacitcarp si siht ,lamina retniw a er’uoY“
”…esoht fo eno eb ot neppah t’ndluow uoY“
.gnir ot nageb enohpelet etanro ,dlo eht nehw oopmahs fo lluf llits saw ruf yM
”.ylefas etis eht ot nwod enoyna teg t’nac eW
.nrut tfeL .llaw raF
.ni gnisolc saw I .elcric A
.tsom dedeen ew tahw saw taht dna
.segap yrruFoS dna ytiniffAruF sih no
.krims gniwonk a htiw mih derussa ehS
.moor eht fo tuo gnimrots ,delworg I ”!canrabaT“
yalbmerT evitceteD woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.noitisop ym tsap evom ot nageb yeht dna
.rodirroc eht fo dne eht ta cirbaf fo hsalF
.moor eht nellafeb dah taht muinomednap eht eciton ot deliaf I taht tnemrag a hcus ni eb d’I yppah woh ni tsol nettog yletelpmoc d’I
”.sruoy fo niarb retupmocrepus taht xat si od ot tnaw d’ew gniht tsal ,esruoc fO“ .deddon I
,otni epacse ot noitacol doog a eb dluow flesti moor letoh a dnA
.puos ym ot kcab gninrut dna
.deppots evah dluoc I ,tnemom siht nI
,ecivres dna doof fo ytilauq eht yb demlehwrednu gnieb fo kcirt lausu sih deganam noD
- ni yalbmerT rotciV“
”.stnempoleved yna fo wonk uoy tel ll’ew dna demrofni su peek ,llew ,dootsrednU“
,gab ecnedive na tuo koot dna sevolg emos no dellup I
,demrofed taht mees t’ndid wons ehT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
”?pleh yna eb I dluoC“