.sedis ym ot llaf smra ym gnittel neht
.ohw saw ohw aedi on htiw
,203 mooR ni gniyats saw ardnaS
”?tirpluc ruoy si su fo owt eht fo eno taht hcnuh a no
,maercs mih draeh I
.ecnedive eht evreserp ot nepo meht evael ot gnivah tub
.elims lufepoh a htiw dias ehS ”.haey ,od I“
,edisni meht thguorb dna seceip eht pu derehtag eW
,rotaderp larutan a t’nsaw I
.niatrec ssel saw I woN
seednetta fo thgiew eht no yenom ekam stneve esohT
”.nwot ni pohs a morF“
.delrans I ”!poc a ton ma I“
.tluciffid sgniht ekam ot dah noD dnA !esolc sihT !esolc siht erew eW
detrons elom ehT
,hA“ ”.taht lla dna gnivil yteicos hgih ,wonk’y ,snmuloc reh daer I“
.elom eht ot denruter seye yM
.yllacitsacras dias noD ”!ris sey riS“
”.tnaruatser eht ot txen tub lla
htaerb peed ,gnol a koot I
.603 mooR saw sihT
delbmut dah ew erehw spets eht fo elbram eht nO
,ta doog ylurt saw eh gniht eno eht did noD
.ezag reh teem ot delggurts I
.ylsuoiverp ni neeb d’I taht moor eht sdrawot rodirroc eht ssorca yaw ym edam I
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,sevlesmeht tuc dah ereh ni saw revemohW
.detnurg elom ehT
.gnitirwdnah eht esingocer t’ndid I ”.esav eht em teG
.repsihw raen a ta deksa I ”?yvaeh eht s’ohW“
,dluoc I ecivda tahw meht evag I
.sselhceeps ylrettu
.desum I ”.esruoc fo
siocnarF dna ardnaS rof
”?ti si reniatnoc ssalg a hcnup ot esiw toN
,srieht fo rehtieN
,swap sih tuo dleh eh ,yltnatculeR
”?won sneppah tahW“ .deddon I
,sriatspu kcab deklaw eh sa mih derongi I
.ecnahc lanif ruoy si sihT
.dnaltroP ni nwod ecar rotom a ta selrahC deman xof teews a tem I“ ”?wonk
.tneilc ytrap driht a roF“ .denialpxe eH
,niaga sriats eht pu og ot gnikool dna
tniop yna ta eciton uoy diD“
”.eb ot hguone hserf t’nsaw tI
.stekcop sih ni llits sdnah sih
.detnurg eH ”.enog ,foop
.derednop elom ehT
”.ti dnif ot tey dna eno tsol dah uoy ,seY“ .desuap I
”.dneirfyob rumel siocebeuQ sih htiw saw eh yppah woh tuoba lla em dlot eh dna sknird wef a daH
.pots a ot dils I  .part A .oN
”.reciffo na detluassa eh dna evitiguf detnaw a s’eH“
elttaeS ni ton er’ew tub ,erofeb tnemtrapeD eciloP elttaeS eht rof krow tcartnoc enod ev’I“ .dias I
”…elpoep rehto ot gninetsil fo elbapac era uoy ebyaM“
,yb-ressap tneconni na dna
,yletaidemmi wap reh no tuc eht was I
”?letoh siht otni dekcehc uoy ecnis emityna ta enil yawliar eht ssorca nwot eht tisiv uoy did ,yboT“
”?wohs edart a morf toN“
.dah eh htap epacse ylno eht saw pU
,ti otni thgiew ydob sih gnirettalc
.esoppus I nwod sesolc ecalp sihT“
rac a otni dedaol teg yboT dehctaw I ,wodniw yab tnorf eht morF
,nepo ti hsup ot elba eb ot su rof hguone dewaht gnivah wons eht
dias ti ,txet hguor nI
,ecnerefnoC emyzneB eht morf llac a toG“ .dias noD ”.no evom a tog dna pu dekcap ew emit s’tI“
.tfeht elbaulav ylemertxe na rof detagitsevni yllamrof uoy evah dna
.eulb ni elom eht ,ecilpmocca reh otni depmub I ,moor s’ardnaS ot yaw ym no elihW
.tlah a ot emoc dna
,sleeh sih no dnuora gnitfihs
”.eciohc hcum em evig yltcaxe t’nod uoY“
delbmessa elpoep fo dworc eht sa gnihca
.demriuqs dna dehcnilf eH
”.laed eht rekorb ot emac I oS .t’nsaw ehs
.eye eht ni enoyna gniteem ton
.saw wodniw nepo eht erehw woleb tsuj knab wons eht ot dnuora deklaw dna
.yllamrof elom eht desserdda I
”.etal oot er’ew sseuG“ .denialpxe eH
,gninrom siht neht dna reniatnoc s’ti ni saw ti ,thgin tsaL“
,esu fo tuo nehw dekcol eb ot ti demussa evah dluow I
.dehcnilf ehS .detseuqer I
htiw decaf erew yeht tahw esilaer neht
,wodniw roolf tsrif A
.sreciffo raluger tsuj ,ni stinu reffins gnirb ot ton detcele dah yeht
”.did ew ,seY“ .deireuq I
”?eb dluow eman ruoY“
,sgniht reh dna taoc reh hguorht egammur ot nageb dna detnurg ehS
.sreh tuo dleh ardnaS elihw
yletanutroF …wons eht hguorht teg ot snug esoht dedeen yeht spahreP
”!wohs edart a ekil si pohs A“
.ralimis dna nenildeb no sraems wef a ,yltbus ylno
.yawa teg ot gniyrt saw eh taht ees dluoc I hguoht
leeh gninrut ,detnurg I
”.llac enohp eht nialpxe dluow taht ,thgirlA“ .dedulcnoc ehS
.don naht erom elttil od dluoc I
,haeY“ .decamirg eH
.roolf eht ot delpmurc dna delworg I
.”.wasdnah“ eht dna esav ehT
.sriatspu kcab gnidaeh dna
”.hcum yrev sknahT …hhu …I …llew hO“
.deddon I .dias ehS
,403 ni yboT
.detlob yboT ”-I dik netsiL“
.ehcsroP eht otni sesactius sih gnidaol saw noD erehw gnidliub eht fo tnorf eht ot tuo dedaeh I dna evaw a htiw detrap eW
,reyof eht ot ereht morf shtap rieht no dna
.lanif si ecirp ehT“
”.tserra na no reciffo na demrasid uoY“ ”?no oG“
,flah ni naelc dekcarc ti
”.swap ruoy tuo dloH“ .dias I
.tuo gninaeL .revo nar I
”.thgin tsal tnaruatser eht ni rennid emos dah I“
gnissim saw esav eht taht deciton I“
.eb dluohs ylbaugra yeht sa ssuf a fo hcum sa gnikam ton yllauqe dna ,egde no yllauqe ,pu dehcnuh yllauqe erew yehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,gninrom yb dehsams saw esac eht dna
.teragraM ot kcab yek ym dednah I ,retal setunim wef A
.deciton saw esav eht fo ssol eht taht ylrae saw ti dna
,hhU“ .delims I ”.lliw uoy fi
,gnihtemos gnidih htob erew yehT
.revo meht derutseg dna ardnaS dna yboT ot revo dekool I
.deddon ehs ,esirprus ym oT
.yawyna tpmetta taht ni hcnerw a tup dah flesti wons eht yllaitnetoP  .reveostahw enon
”.yad lla tog t’nia ew ,nom’C“
”?ti od ot tnaruatser cilbup a ot tnew uoy oS“
.kcarc llams a saw ereht
ssenisub nwo ym gnidnim tsuj saw I“ .delrans eH
…tub gniog ecalp eht peek ot gniht taht fo elas doog a no gniknab saw I
…ll’eh ,daol lluf eht fo trohs gnihtyna htiw yvaeh eht ta evirra ew fI“ .deddon I
,enil yawliar eht ssorca eno eht ,seY“ ”?eciffo tsoP“
,serutcarf su gnivig yllaitnetop
”.taeh yna saw ereht erofeb ylkciuq dna ,ereh fo tuo teg ot dedeen ew desilaer ew tniop taht ta dna
.em retfa gnol ton ni dekcehc eH“
.nosrep a dleh ylisae evah dluoc tub
.wons etihw eht ni deirub tcejbo gnitnilg eht ot gnirutseg ,dias I ”.erehT“
”?esav eht si erehW“
.erofeb morf wodniw nepo eht htiw moor eht sdrawot kcab detlob eH ”!edraM“  ”!tihS“
,gninrom eht ni gnillaf deppots dah wons ehT
.gninrom siht morf draehrevo d’I noitasrevnoc eht hsalf a ni derebmemer I
,hguoht ylgnisserp eroM .esav on llitS
.ssecca fo noitseuq eht tageb nehT
”!?mih no nug a llup uoy did kcuf eht yhW“
”?deneppah tahw neht oS“
.roolf driht eht ot pu kcab nar eW
,mlac niamer ot gniyrt ylraelc saw tar ehT
”.uoy fo riap eht ,em esucxE“
.dnah ym tuo dehcaer I
,nwod ti etorw yehT
”.ti eb dluow taht
.meht hsurc ot metsys eht rof gnitiaw tsuj dna
”.ssenisub nmad rieht fo yna t’nsi siht os stcartnoc rieht fo eno no ton m’I dna
.llits doots wodniw eht tub
.ecno ta llA .niarb ym hguorht dehsalf seisatnaf rewop citsidas fo htrow s’tes xob csidresaL elbuod A
”.rrrE“ .ylmrif dias I
.niatrec rof saw taht
”?raeh uoy’d ,etalp a
”.wohs t’ndid ehs tub
”?ti dnif uoy did dnA“
,rood kcab eht fo tuo detraped eW
,swap s’knuks eht ni flah pot eht gnivael
.ecilop eht fo erutan eht saw taht neht tub
,thgirlA“ ”?kniht uoy t’ndluow ,em ot trams ytterp smeeS“ .delworg eH
ytiniffAruF sih no
,mih dniheb dehcaer I ,ylkciuq gnitcA .tpew eH
,yas ot retteb gnihtemos dah I gnihsiW
.rehtruf denael I
”.evitceted etavirp a m’I .poc a ton m’I“
”?ti teg uoy did erehW“ ”!was A“
.em ta dekool dna nug eht derewol noD ”.gnihtyna enoyna llet t’now eh mih netaerht uoy fi dna si esav eht erehw s’wonk eH“
”?noD ,snoitagitsevni erom od ot deen I“
.tar a saw rehto eht dna elom a saw enO
.eerht fo eno s’ti
”?ti tsol uoy dnA“ .denialpxe ehS
”?esav eht ees tsal uoy did nehW“ .detnurg eH
.nac I sa tfos sa eciov ym gnipeek
.esav eht fo weiv ysae ni erew smoor rieht fo htob hguoht
.dias eH ”.did I sey ,seY“
,deb eht no nwod mih tas dna su dniheb rood eht desolc I
no uoy evah ot gniog m’I ,siht htiw od ot gnihtemos dah uoy taht tuo dnuof I fI“
,nosrep ni ereh dnuora saw I
.noitnetta hcum sa ward ro ecnartne tnorf eht esu ot gnideen tuohtiw gnidliub eht fo tuo ti refsnart ot rO .ylekil tsom
”!eid em tel t’noD“ .deggeb eH ”!pleH“
”!siht htiw od ot gniht nmad a evah t’ndid I“
.delworg regdab ehT
.boj ruoy od ot uoy ekil d’I .oN“
.lagelli gnihtemos ot pu era ardnaS dna uoy taht erawa llew ma I“ ”!oN“
”.tcerroc s’taht ,seY“ .deplug I
.sriatspu kcab deusrup dna seitlucaf ym derehtag I
”?on dias uoy ti ekat I“
”!spets nmad esoht nwod em delruh uoy nehw emoc adluoc tuc tahT“
.sriatspu kcab depollag eh sa tar eht retfa ffo gnitnirps
”.oga syad fo elpuoc a wohs edart a ta ti thguob I
yboT ot kcab gninrut yllanif ,dias I
”.wen gnihtemos dnif ot evah ll’I sseug I
.nosniboR yboT ,eman s’tar eht sa llew sa
,lufraF lacsaP yb ”nnI dewonS
”.etavacxe ot sdimaryp emos tog ev’eW“
”.nosrep ni ton ,llew
,stekcop sih ni swap sih dah eH
,wolley ni serugif owt dna
”.noitcasnart eht etelpmoc ot ereh s’eh syas dna
.erehwemos deppord
,teef ym ot dereggats I  2 fo 2 traP
”.yaw taht epacse ruo ekam d’ew dna reh retfa tuo pmuj d’I nehT“ .derettulps eH
.tfeht trams …ylralucitrap
”!daed er’uoy dna hcni eno evom uoY“
,taht sey-y ,waS“ .deralg I
”.ti detacol ton llits ev’ew ,oN“
ereh eno gnittup os rebmun fo thgiew dna
,”hctiP giB ehT“ s’ecallaW kciR no derutaef yltnecer saw ohw
”!edram à siapé'd itsE“
,ssalg eht yb doots eH
”.ecirp taht rof ti thguob d’ehs dias ehs ,lleW“
”!sriats ruoy nwod em werht fao siht nehw
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT     ”.ton yletulosbA“
”.dluoc uoy tahw did uoy
”ytiC kroY weN morf rotcelloc ,sggirB yllaS“
.taes ym ni elbatrofmoc tog dna kcab denael I
.mih derussa I ”.wonk I“ .dias eH
.moor eht hcraes ot nageb dna dnuora denrut I
”?ti thguob ydaerla d’ehs dias ehS“
,dias I ”.dnatsrednu I“
,detnurg yboT ”?yhW ?tahW“
.mih thguac dah I desilaer I sa derevihs tug ym I dna derednuolf eH
.htuoy ym ni enod d’I gnihtemos ylniatrec s’tI
.kcab sih dniheb mih deffucdnah I sa tsiser t’ndid eH
”.ees uoy esav eht yub ot gniog saw I“
”?won od I od tahW“
.tsal ta deksa elom ehT
”?reyub eht saw ohw ,llew
”.gniht nmad siht nelots gnivah fo desucca gnieb m’I won dnA .ni emac wons eht nehw evael ot ydaer saw dna thgin eht deyats I“
”.era uoy evitceted emoS“
.sffucdnah ym rof gnihcaer ,detnurg I
,nosniboR yboT“ .stuc hserF
.og ot erehw ediced ot elbanu ,gnitfihs
,yltnelis noitcejbo sih deggol I .detcejbo yboT
.edam d’I ekatsim eht desilaer I sa sniev ym ni tnemssarrabme htiw gnitepmoc enoretsotset
,gninrom eht ni ereh evael ot gniog erew eW“
.elbanosaernu mees t’nseod
,repap eht ni saw siht fo draeh I tsriF
,tnenoppo sih ta egnul demrofni-lli na koot evitceted eht sa ffo tfel eW
,gnidliub eht otni pu kcab mih luah ot nageb I .mih toG .debbarG
ecnerefnoc a ot etuor no
,enon saw ereht tuB
.ereh deppart erew ew dna ni tes wons eht tub ,nwod rehtruf gnitteg no trats ylrae na teg
”.diap era uoy hcihw rof eno ehT
”.timil reppu reh saw tahT
.stnirptoof eb dluow ereht ,ti deviecer dna ereht saw ecilpmocca na fi ,htrofecneH
.fo dir teg t’ndluoc yeht taht tcejbo na dah enoemos ,evirra t’ndluoc ecilpmocca eht fI
.mih ta delworg teragraM
”?I t’nera ,ot deil gnieb m’I“
”?eman ruoy s’tahW“ .desuap I
,sriats fo thgilf a nwod su fo htob lruh ot detcele uoy oS“
?lla ta esav eht tuoba gnihtyna wonk uoy od ,em lleT“
.dehgis dna deddon siocnarF ”.em tsurt …tsuJ
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.su ot pu gnippets ,dias teragraM ”.did ehs ,seY“
.noitcelloc eht ni sesav eht fo tser eht tog s’ehS
.tekcap gnissim taht dnif t’ndluoc tub
”.uoy dettops I nehw nur ot detrats neht ,esav eht nekat dah uoy fo enO“
.gnidliub eht fo edis rehto eht
.esav a ees t’ndluoc I tuB
.stcejbo owt rof gnikool won saw I
.wodniw eht fo tuo gnilbmut ,htrof llef eH
”!kanrabat ed ecilâc ed itsE“
”.yltrohs nruter ll’I
”.tsol ev’uoy tahw em llet nehT .eruS“
.deilper eH ”?wasdnaH“ .deksa I
”.adanaC morf ni gnilggums ,ohadI ni yvaeh a rof gnikrow er’eW“ .debbos eH
.dedda I ”.pu yaw rehtO“
,nur dna yrt ot demees htoB
”!esahcrup eht ot deerga ydaerla dah uoy dlot saw I“
.ti htiw sevael dna ti sehctac ohw ,dnuorg eht no toirtapmoc a ot deppord si esav eht dna denepo si wodniw eht
.dnats esav eht morf ssalg morf t’nsaw tahT“ .nageb I
,ria eht ni dleh saw ti sa ,nehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
”.esaV ahplA eht fo tfeht eht fo noicipsus eht rof tserra rednu era uoy
”!ti tuoba gnihton wonk I“
.stnirptoof fo kcal eht saw siht htiw melborp tsriF
,ecilop eht htiw decafretni noD elihW
.sdnah ruoy ni stuc eguh htiw dna
”?esle gnihtemos rof gnikool uoy era rO“
!mih gnitoohs saw noD .stohsnuG
”.uoy knahT“ .deddon I
,lleW“ ”.moor letoh ruoy ni enohpelet a saw ereht ,egnartS“
”?esaV ahplA eht fo tfeht eht tuoba wonk uoy od tahW“ .deborp I
.detraped dna denrut I
,evivrus dluow esav eht fi tegroF
.ebordraw eht ni dih dna ereht ti decalp I ,spetstoof draeh I nehW
”?tahw nI“ .deksa I ”?laed A“
.ylereves dna ylnepo tpew eh erehw
,reh ot wodniw eht fo tuo ti pord
uoy fo riap eht tserra ot noitamrofni hguone evah I
.delworg I ”!hturt eht em lleT“
.regdab eht ot revo gnikool ,decnuonna I
.yvaeh eht deliaf ew emit tsal eht taht tog ehS“
.dnuora gninrut ,dias I ”.ahA“
?boj edisni na eb ti dluow os
dna ni dekcehc ew nehw letoh eht ni mih was I
gnihton meht gnivig naht retteb tsuj saw tI
letoh ohadI llams a ni denoitats erew
,egdel eht ees dluoc I
,pots a ot dils noD
,retneprac a m’I ,was dnah a
”.yboT ,sriats esoht no segde prahs on s’erehT“
,yrd ot tuo gnuh uoy tfel ehs dnA“
”…niaga liaf ew fI
.ylmrif yboT deksa I
.detcennoc ti nehw eenk eht tlef I tuB
tug sih ot eenk ym desserp I erofeb ,dnuora dna lliswodniw eht ssorca mih gnitfil
.ecnaraeppasid eht gnitagitsevni krow nageb yalbmerT .gnissim dnuof saw letoh eht ni esav a nehw
”.su rof ydaer er’yeht
.taht saw taht dna ,elbmurg a evag
,syek fo tes nelots a rO
.pirt mih dehctaw
”.thgir s’taht ,haeY“
.selom owt eht dehcaorppa neht
”.yub ot gniyrt saw I gniht eht denwo ohw nosrep eht gniniatnoc ton gnidliub a ni ,haeY“
”.htuos gniog dah I laed a htiw od ot saw taht
”.ti ssim t’nac uoY“ .denialpxe eH
?rebmem ffats a fo noicreoc
.nekorb si esav eht rof reniatnoc ehT
.htuoy-os-ton ym dnA
.deb eht rednu dereep dna sruof lla otno deppord I
,seY“ ”?was A“ ”.was …A“
”.ereht ni tnemugra na gnivah uoy rebmemer I ,sey hA“
”?swen dab eht reviled ot dah uoy dna dab tnew laed eht ,ees I“
.deretsulf yllarutannu emaceb I .dennirg ehS
,gnisahc saw eh nosrep eht htob
…uoy did woh …ksa ot tnaem I
.aera eht fo yhpargoeg eht ot thguoht ym tup I
”.retfa esav eht rof kool dna sriatsnwod yboT gnirb ll’eW“ .detnurg I
”?nruter uoy nehw stoob ruoy kcil ot em tnaw uoy oD“
.suht sa ,nalp laitnetop A
stros lla dna snoissucnoc
”?taht rof esigolopa annaw uoY“ ”.sey ,did I“
.elbmut-tsop neve ,sthguoht sih fo emirp eht ni eb ton ot demees em ta yrgna gnitteG
- ni yalbmerT rotciV“   yojne esaelP
.esiwekil gniod eulb ni etaicossa reh
”?won esav eht si erehw oS“ .dias I
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
”.nar dna tfel I nehw s’taht ,wodniw eht tuo denael uoy nehW
”.draehrevo eb …hhu ot tnaw t’ndid …I
.t’ndluow ehs dna ,ti rof erom yap dluow yllaS fi ees ot deirt I“
.feiler htiw demrifnoc teragraM ”!esav ehT“
”.deneppah tahw nehT“ .dias eH ”.tcerroC“
”?deretne eh nehw mih htiw gnihtyna evah eh diD“
.erofeb rebmun taht draeh dah I
.boj eht no gnisucof daetsnI
”?wasdnah eht gnitacol kcul ynA .noonretfa dooG“
”.erusaelpsid ruoy eciov ot tnaruatser eht ni pu meht gnar uoy suht dnA“
,wodniw roolf tsrif a dehcaer tar ehT
.gninrom eht dna ni gnikcehc su neewteb tsol tog stekcap eht fo enO
”.dnah s’ardnaS no tuc ehT“ .deddon I ”…ll’eh
wons eht otni ffo erutraped rieht edam dna em deknaht yehT
.tneve edart a yrrac dluow eciffo tsop dna tnaruatser eht htiw eno eht ekil nwot llams a kniht t’ndid ylniatrec I
.taes regnessap eht otni debmilc dna
…tub laeh ot gnitrats ,dlo
.detnurg I ”.ecnerefnoC ygolonhceT emyzneB eht rof esruoc teS“
.krow dluow ro doog saw ecivda eht fi erus t’nsaw I
taoc sih gnippiznu dna pu gnihcaer ,delworg eH
.wodniw eht fo tuo daeh ym dekop dna worb ym deworruf I
.ti fo tuo depacse dah tirpluc ym taht tesolc eht ni dekool I
,yvaeh eht ot sgurd eht teg
.regdab eht ot denrut I
”.ma I tub ,t’nia uoY“
,tar eht retfa detnirps I
.delbmum regdab ehT
.neeb dah esav eht erehW
.doolb fo stelpord tsellams eht sa
.moor siht otni thguorb dna nekat si esav ehT
.llib eht gniyap ,dias I ”.uoy knahT“
”.yrros m’I ,em no gnihtyna evah t’nod I diarfa m’I“
.tnemom eht rof tsael ta
,000’07$“ ”?niaga ti saw tahw ,gninrom siht ti em dlot uoy ,esav taht fo ecirp ehT .noD“
.dellac tbuod on dah noD taht ecilop eht yb ydotsuc otni nekat saw eh erehw
,lufraF lacsaP yb ”nnI dewonS
,tnedive saw remrof ehT
,213 ni yaw eht lla flesym dna
.thgieh taht morf llaf a troppus d’ti stbuod ym dah I taht yas ot tnaw t’ndid I
”.gniht nug eht tuobA“ .nageb eH ”.hhhu ,oS“
.erusserp ylppa ot os did ehS“
”?dnim ni gnihtemos evah uoy oD“
”.ereh fo tuo teg s’teL .eerga I“
:ni yalbmerT rotciV“
”!?gniod er’uoy kniht uoy od htrae no tahW“
,mih ni tellub a tup tsuj d’noD gnisilaer tub ,yboT htiw tiaw noD tseggus ot tuoba saw I
.hcae no dnah eno ,seldnah-edis eht yb pu ti dekcip dna htrof deppets ehS
.ksed ybraen eht morf repapswen a tuo gnillup ,delkcuhc eH
.tsrif ta sdrawnwod gnicaf
,meht nwod gnillaf retfa spets esoht otno nwod doolb deppird enoemos esuaceB“
”?ti degamad ohw ees uoy diD
,tfeht esav a sa laivirt sa gnihtemos rof meht fo tnuoma evissecxe nA
”.pleh dluoc uoy fi deksa uoy nehw rof gnikool erew ew tahw s’tahT
pu snrut yug siht neht
.flesym yboT retfa gnisahc dna sdnah s’noD morf nug eht gnippir ,niaga dekrab I
.yawa tup nug sih tpek d’eh yllufknaht hguoht ,deraeppa yllanif noD
,selrahC ekil xof a neeb dah I fi
ro tseug rehtona yb dehcnip neeb d’ti ylekiL
.rood eht rof gnidaeh dna pu gnidnats ,dias I
.deddon dna detnurg ylpmis noD
”.lleh ot lla ti nmad hO“ ”.gniklat tratS
delkcat d’eh revocsid ot ylno
”.srehto eht htiw sriatsnwod daeh neht dna tsomerof dna tsrif pu deppiz tekcaj taht peek uoy dnemmocer I
.morf nelots saw esav eht erehw ot ybraen saw dekool I ecalp tsrif ehT
.daor yci eht nwod ffo evord ylidaets dna deddon noD
,gniyats erew tar eht dna ardnaS erehw fo srebmun moor eht tog I
.detatsaved ylbisiv
.tpew ehs sa knuks eht dloh saw od dluoc I gniht tseb ehT
,dias ehS ”.uoy knaht ,oN“
”.gniht taht gnilles fo kcab eht no gnidliub eritne siht fo tnemhsibrufer eht dnuf ot gnipoh m’I .yletulosbA“
”.siht fo tuo teg uoy pleh nac I“ .deddon I
.edisni eht em gniwohs dna
.eno taht fo kniht ot emit deen ll’I …lleW“
”?uoy ekil poc a tsurt I dluohs yhw ,oN“
.seye ym otni thgir enohs thgil sa deknilb dna
.yawa selim wef a nwot regral hcum a saw ereht hguohT
wons eht tih ,tuo pmuj
,ydaer si dnuorg eht no ecilpmocca nA
,doots I .detnurg tar ehT
.edistuo teragraM koot I
”.doom luof a saw tfel eh nehw dah eh gniht ylno eht dna ,oN“
.swodniw eht fo esab eht dnuora gnir etercnoc eht
.elbissopmi t’nsaw ereh gniyatS
.demees ti esrow ti gnireffus saw elom eht hguoht
.gninnur peek dna
.won rof mih derongi I .detnurg eH
,tar eht dehcaorppa I
smoor rieht fo hcraes hguoroht erom a enod d’yehT
,ytpme won saw tI
.rae na dehctiwt I
yawa gninrut ,delbmurg I
”.esav ruoy tuoba gnihtyna wonk t’nod I“  .deknilb I
”.saw ”gnihtemos“ taht tahw ot sa em mrofni oD
,pu denrut ehs nehw yllaS ot ti dnah ot desoppus saw I“
.niatreC“ ”?erus er’uoY“
,redwop etihw fo lluF .stekcaP
.hcrul mih ees t’ndid I
.flesym desopmoc dna
,raelc ti detfil ehs sA
”.siht otni teg ot tnaw t’ndid I“
.kcap ot sriatspu kcab tnew I dna
”.eciffo tsop eht otni gniog niaga
”.reffo ot gnilliw saw tneilc ym naht yenom erom detnaw teragraM ,haeY“
”.ris ,srennur gurd tsuj er’ew …eW“ .dias eH
yevraH noD eugaelloc tnatculer sih dna yalbmerT rotciV evitceteD ,emit tsaL
.noisicerp detimilnu em nevig evah dluow tcnitsni gnitnuh a erus m’I
.gnissim ylbaton eno rof tpecxe
”.esolc pu won ereves ytterp
edart taht fo trap fi
,yletamitlu hguohT
dnuorg eht sdrawot nwod yltcerid dekool I
”.nwod denrut neeb dah uoy reh dlot dna sggirB yllaS pu gnar uoy oS“
a eb ot mees t’ndid siht
.segap yrruFoS dna
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
…tub esuac tsol a si esav ehT“
,tcejbo detnawnu na pmud oT ?yhW
.mih ta thgir nward nug
,enecs eht morf gninnur enoemos was eh nehW
.rood eht dna mih neewteb roolf eht no tas I
.sreciffo eht ot noitcurtsed rieht detroper dna rehtegot meht derehtag
”?taoc wolley a ni tar a
.stcepsus eht noitseuq ot eunitnoC“
teragraM no eye ym tpek dna
.noisiv ym gnirrulb egar ym
.woleb nwot eht sdrawot kcart eci eht nwod traped selcihev eht dna
.teef rieht ot delbmarcs ,dnuorg eht ot esacriats eht gnillaf morf dedniw htob
”.esac ssalg eht dna bonk rood eht dnuora lla doolb saw ereht dna
.meht esahc ot nageb eh
,seceip derdnuh elpuoc a otni gnirutcarf dna
”?htrow s’ti hcum woh wonk ehs seod woh os dnA“
,ardnaS dna tar eht htob gnillirg noD dnuof I erehw ,yawllah eht ni kcab devirra I
”.edistuo egdel eht no s’tI“
,lufraF lacsaP yb ”nnI dewonS
?moor siht ot ssecca niag eno did woH
”?wohs edart eht fo noitatnemucod yna ro ,ti rof tpiecer eht evah uoy oD“
,detca I naht erom kniht ot devloser I dna
,noitasucca ym ni dah I nilanerda fo spord tsal eht pu gnisu ,denialpxe I
moor s’ardnaS otni rood eht gninepo
,thgim sih lla htiw gnidliub eht fo edis eht otno gnignilc saw eH
”.yawliar eht ssorca eciffo tsop dna tnaruatser eht yb nwod noolas a gninepo fo snoitibma tog I“
,ammaG dna ateB ehT
”.yas ew fi su llik ll’eH“
.retteb eht yawa rehtruf eht
:ni yalbmerT rotciV“
,wohs edart a morf tnempiuqe gniyuB
”?morf rebmun taht teg uoy d’erehW“ ”?yhw
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.gnihtemos tsol gnivah noitnem gninrom siht ecilpmocca na dna uoy draehrevo I ,ardnaS“ ”.ardnaS“
.deppilS .dehcaer eH
.taorht s’noD thgir ,delrans I
,elbissop sa tsaf sa senil etats ssorca teg neht
knurt eht ni sgab dna esactius ym tup I .detnurg eH
”?siht fo tuo teg ew retfa dnA“
,siocnarF lleW“ ”.siocnarF“
.ksa ot deracs oot saw I
.depsag dna detnurg eH
,emit dnoces a rof dloc rettib eht htiw detsalb saw I ,ti gninepO
.gniretlaf dna gnideelb sdnah
,aH“ ”?reh wonk uoy hO“ ”.sggirB yllaS“
wons eht gnittih tnenopmoc mottob eht
.ekatsim a fo egatnavda gnikat tsuj ebyaM
.rae ym otni denael knuks ehT
.rood eht no rebmun eht dekcehc I
rehtona eno ta delworg riap ehT
.ssalg dna doolb gnitcepxe saw I os
”.noitats eht ta kcab siht tuoba klat a evah ot gniog er’eW“
,krad eht ni wobniar elttil A“
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.deksa sa did dna demriuqs eH
”.noolas eht htiw kcul doog dnA“ .dias I
.edisni mih dna flesym gnidiug dna
seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
”000’07$“ ”?ti rof yap ot gnilliw ehs saw hcum woH“
.deddon tub gnibbos tpek eH
,ti draeh d’ehs fi wonk t’ndid I
.nepo saw wodniw ehT
.roolf eht no gnihtemos deciton tub
.evitiutni-retnuoc smees klof wef erew ereht erehw
.eton llams a dnuof I
,sriatsnwod mih thguorb dna tar deffucdnah eht pu detfil eW
.ylffurg dias eH ”.did I sey ,seY“
.tsopdeb eht tsniaga mrif mih dleh dna