.gnaB  2 fo 1 traP
,lufraF lacsaP yb ”doolB repaP
.dias syhR ”.gnihtoN“
”?44 thgilF tuoba wonk uoy od tahW“
hcihw ,elttaeS ni devil syhR
”?ycnetepmoc tcepxe uoY“
.knat elttab a ekil tliub ,seye llams ,yug giB .enirevlow A
”.senoJ syhR evitceteD dna yalbmerT rotciV evitceteD .nosrednA rM olleH“
.seciffo ruo ot kcab dedaeh dna rac eht ni kcab tog ew ,dnah ni noitamrofni s’llebpmaC airaM htiW  -  .denialpxe eH
.deksa I ”?yako uoY“
.em ot txen syhR ,nwod gnittis ,dias I
.kcolb eciffo ruo edistuo dekrap I
erew tser eht dnA .draob no enoyreve fo tsil lluf a gnivig
”.noisurtni tipkcoc a ton erew ti fi
”.sraey 8 fo trap tseb eht rof syawriA mA htroN rof reenignE thgilF .nosrednA kcaJ“
.elbat eht ssorca stnemucod wef a gnidils ,dias eH
t’ndid eh fi taht detseggus eW .yppols emaceb krow fo dradnats siH
.ti gninniw fo ecnahc doog a sah ekaJ taht smees ti ,trepxe lagel on m’I hguoht ,dna ,laer eb ot smees esaC“  .su dlot dah nosrednA rM tahw demrifnoc ohw
”?taht s’yhW“ .dias eH
”.sserdda na pu kool t’ndluoc I fi evitceted a fo hcum eb t’ndluow I“
.noitanimaxe hguoroht erom a esnecil s’revird eht evag dna nwod tas I
,lufraF lacsaP yb ”doolB repaP
.dray kcab sih ni thgir esac ruo edam
.gniwollof em ,yletaidemmi koobeton sih tuo koot syhR
,seye sih otni derats I ”.yalbmerT rM
”?xob kcalb eht evah ew oD“  .denialpxe eH
dna ograc ,stnemucod fo smret ni selbat otno ro
.koohs dna koot I taht ,em ot wap a tuo gnidloh ,dias eH
.draobno ograc lla gniliated ,tsefinam eht saw nwod eno dnoces ehT
.dias eH ”.yletulosbA“
-  ”.rehtegot skcor gnignab eb llits d’ew nehT“
”?I llahs ,seciffo daeh ruoy ta uoy teem ll’I“ .MA22:40
.deddon eh ,syhR ot dekool I
.eno tsrif eht revo kool ot nageb I .tseretni fo slaudividni no selif
.deedni edoba hcir a saw tI
,diviv dna elbisiv llits saw ekoms fo emulp ehT
–  .niaga teef ym ot gnitteg ,dias I ”.doog sdnuoS“
-  .rac eht ot tuo yaw ym gnikam neht ,ssik a mih evig ot kcab daeh ym gninael ,dias I ”.esimorp I“
”.ni semoc ti nehw wonk em teL“ .deddon I
.”ydnaC esoN“ dellebal gab rehtona tuo dellup I erofeb
.tfarc gnieoB llams a ,noitseuq ni tfarcria eht no sliated saw tnemucod pot ehT
,gnitsil regnessap a saw driht ehT
”.tfarcria eht ot deneppah tahw em lleT“
,meht ot gnignoleb enalptej a pu wolb eh dluow yhw ,ti gninniw fo ecnahc doog a tog s’eh dna ,mih degnorw taht ynapmoc eht htiw etad truoc a tog s’eh fi dnA“
”.seeyolpme ruo fo eno ,nosrednA kcaJ“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.sevisolpxe fo lluf toN
.noisacco eht tnemucod ot ydaer saw I dna nottub yvaeh a fo kcilc llams A
.euqisyhp rednelS .nooccar A
,gninimaxe htrow saw tlef I taht ecnedive eht detcelloc I
dna ereht gniog enalp eht otno meht daol tsuj d’uoy ylerus ,lizarB
,oS“ .deddon enirevlow ehT ”.ti od ot syaw eltbus erom hcum
,trihs ym ot ti gnippilc dna enohporcim llams a tuo gnillup ,tekcop tius ym otni dehcaer I ,rac eht gnivaeL
.egde nO .trela saw eH
”?meht tuoba od ot desoporp uoy evah tahw
ro ragdE .rM tuoba erom wonk thgim
.deksa I ”?stnemgarf hcihW“
.rM fo seceip artxe yna dnif dna enalporea eht otni kool ot emit erom maet egavlas eht seviG
,ados gnikab erew nwod rehtruf wef a
.spotllih eht revo elbbird ot gninnigeb nus
.yaw eht no deksa syhR ”?kcaJ fo kniht uoy od tahW“
.stcepser ynam ni tcepsus emirp ruO“ .dias eH
gniltsub t’nsaw ti tub ,swerc swen htiw llif ot gninnigeb ylwols saw truocerof ehT
”?esac sih gnisidrapoej ylivaeh
era erehT ?ekil t’ndid yeht enoemos fo dir teg ot tsuj
,gniteem a pu teS .dootsrednU“
”.tsil eht no tcepsus txen eht fo noitacol eht dnif nac uoy fi ees uoy ,ti otni kool a
.rac eht otni gnibmilc ,dias syhR ”’meel gninroM“
”.ti ta kool a ekat dna emoc ot uoy
.ti eman uoy ,sniks lamina ,sgurd fo lluf era senalp esoht ,seY“
”.thgilf eht draoba teg ot hguone ylgnicnivnoc DI gnikaf fo elbapac enoemos morf yllaicepsE .cigol tcepxe I“
ti gnikcajih neht dna sgurd htiw enalp a gnilliF“
.sredluohs ym dnuora parw smra ’selrahC tlef I
.em dlot yeht tahw deveileb tsuj I
dehgis dna deplug syhR
eht ta secnatsbus eht ffo gnippord
.hguorht kool ot detrats dna pu meht dekcip I ,htaerb deneteiuqsid ,peed a htiW .selbat eht fo eno no meht fo kcats llams a saw erehT .s’DI eht erew enimaxe ot tnew I gniht tsrif ehT .keew siht retal tae ot dednetni I .seidob eht ta kool ot rehtob t’ndid I
.ybburg erew yehT .sllarevo sih gniraeW
”?snoitcerid deen t’nod uoY“ .dias I
,tfarc fo sknuhc latem
.elor ylno dnuorg-eht-no na emoceb evah seitud sih
.ti htrow si
”.noissucsid ot detius erom s’ti erehw sriatspu em nioj
.dias I ”.stsoc tsol puocer ot detnaw ydobemos dna erehwemos dab tnew laed a yllaitnetop ,erus toN“
.nwod gnittis dna elbat eht ot eeffoc a gnignirb ,deddon I
.enohp eht pu gnuh I dna deerga eH
”.eusrup ot tnaw yam uoy tseretni fo elpoep elpuoc a sa llew sa
”.mA htroN tsurtsid I“ .detnurg eH
nevig saw I ecnerefer esac eht tuoba struoc lacol eht htiw seiriuqne edam I sa stnemucod eht hguorht dekool syhR ,eciffo eht ta kcaB .dias I
.eno trams eht er’uoY“ .meht gnihsinif ton
,dnaltroP fo tsae-htron
.nihtiw reniatnoc renni enerytsylop eht otni gud saw lenparhs dna roiretxe eht fo slenap delgnam eht derevoc skram hcrocS
,ti revo dekool ,ti koot I
gnilbmut ,edolpxe ot ti desuac dna deneppah esle gnihtemos ro derif saw tellub a rehtie
”.ot stseretni sih ni ton s’tI .ti did eh kniht t’nod I
,god.ecioveht ta
”.ytilaitrapmi rof hcum oS“
”.suolucidir si ,sthgilf esoht no delggums gnieb si eniacoc hcum woh nevig ,hcihW .niaga revo dna revo kcab tuc era stegdub dna semit ecnanetniaM
.flesti enerytsylop eht ta won saw I
.yltcaxE“ .dedneppa syhR
.trihs-t a dna snaej ,tekcaj ytisrav etihw dna der egral a ni desserd saw eH .larenuf nwo ruoy gnikoob ekil si enola emirc gnivloS .tnatsissa yM
.sroirepus ym ot lla meht detroper I“ .riahc
”.elif gol a htiw ,metsys eht ni s’ti dna nees neeb s’tI .ti depmats
dluow I .rozaR s'maccO .tpecnoc-hgih oot
a saw ereht ,stroper laitini morF“
flaheb sih no edicius-redrum a no rre
,dah ew sdrocer eht rep
.tfarc eht fo etaf eht rof tnaem egamad fo sepyt tnereffid tahw wonk ot meht detsurt I
,enod eb ot dah ti ,tuB .I did rehtien dna ,siht od ot tnaw t’ndid eH
”.eno-on rof stiaw ecitsuJ
”?elif sih ni seitiddo lacsif tnacifingis ynA“ .dias I
.kcirb a sa tnulb gnikaeps rof tibah a dah eH .dias eH
,nep dna dapeton a dah I
.moor egral a ot rodirroc nworb eht nwod deklaw eW .roolf hgih a ,rotavele eht fo tuO .I did
,thgilf eht no enoyreve fo seman eht dna tsefinam eht tog ev’I“ .dias eH ”.seY“
,decnavda erom nettog evah stej obmuj ni srellortnocorcim sa hguoht ,senalp eht edisni ylf ot desu eH“
”?uoy dluow ,elttaeS fo tuo dna ni sthgilf gurd
”.sesac ruo ot gnihtyna etubirtnoc I ekil leef t’nod I“
.rehtegot deksa eW ”?eniacoC“
.delbmessa d’eh stnemucod fo elip egral a morf gnidaer ,nageb syhR
”.uoy ekaw ot yrros ,rotciV olleH“
.dleh gnieb saw nosrednA .rM erehw moor llams a otni nekat erew ew ,noitats eht edisnI  -  ”.ragdE
.gnidliub mA htroN eht sdrawot ffo gnivird neht
.gnidraob erofeb revokcehc eht did I“ .dias eH
.ot emit nevig saw I gnihtyreve dekcehc I
.yltaen rehtegot stnemucod eht
”.yb-enod-drah sleef dna yap ot sllib fo tol a sah ylbaborp
.tius depirts eulb elaP
,yltaen nwod ti gnicalp
.ot netsil ot em rof ydaer saw redrocer eciov tipkcoc eht taht demrofni saw I ,pu ti gnikciP
.yenruoj s’ti no ti ynapmocca ot ,rettam taht rof
evah ll’I .tiuswal siht no segnih yllaer tI“
.ecnedive elbatuferri ekil detcivnoc gnihton tub ,syhR did sa
.”smailliW hctuB“ ot gnignoleb
.srotagitsevni eht fo emos htiw pu tem dna
”.revir siweL eht raen ,dnaltroP fo htron tsuj dehsarc dna
potnO .edisni yal tahw ssecca ot elba saw I dna devomer saw tnemges esool ,dezis yltsedom A
”?evah ew od esle ohW“
.tcatni saw ti tub ,secalp ynam ni derrahc saw tI .mih saw ti hcnuh a dah I
”.enilepip eht ni seitiddo lacsif wef a evah t’nseod eh naem t’nseod taht hguohT“
”.eniacoc fo tnuoma riaf a ,eveileb od I ,dna tfarc eht draoba noisolpxe na fo ecnedive
.elbat edisdeb eht no kcolc latigid eht no stigid dloc eht ta gnikool ,dehgis I
.tnemucod dedlof a revo gnidnah dna tekcop a otni gnihcaer ,dedda eH
”.tsrif eno ksa em tel tub ,eruS“
,elbissop sa elttil sa ti brutsid ot sa
,retiusruf ,retirw a si ohw ,lufraF lacsaP yb
.deborp syhR ”?evitoM“  .dias I
-  ”.sevirra xob kcalb eht nehw su mrofni dna hcuot ni peek oD" dias I ".krow
.llikrevo eb dluow hsarc enalp
”.yrruh eht etiuq ni s’reklaW .rM“
,dias I ”.gninrom dooG“
,kooh eht no kcab enohp eht decalp dna meht deknaht I
.tekcop tekcaj ym ni redrocer ettessac a ot trihs ym nwod eriw eht dih I
”.epat siht ot netsil og ll’I
.wodniw eht fo tuo kcab neht
,reklaW nitsuJ fo eciov
.ssecca rehtruf rof hguone demrofed dah ti fo emoS
draoba noitanoted
.tcejbo ot nosaer oN .gniggurhs ,dias I
,DI lautca sih no ragdE rM fo erutcip eht taht si esruoc fo gninmad tsoM
.thguac steg ti esac ni elbissop sa ti morf yawa raf sa eb ot tnaw d’uoy yleruS
.yas ew gnihtyreve erongi yeht ,diaprednu ,dekrowrevO“
.tniap gnippihC .swodniw yniT .serauqs detseN
.moordeb eht tuohguorht swodahs gnitsac ,sdnilb wodniw eht hguorht delb thgilnooM
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,nehT .elffucs a ni tog esiwrehto ro
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”.snoitseuq revelc eht lla ksa uoy ,tekcop ruoy ni redrocer ettessac a tog ev’uoY
,notgnihsaW ni snoitacol morf dna ot elttaeS fo tuo gninnur renilria tegdub a
.deksa I ”?tniop siht ta evah uoy noitamrofni rehto ynA“  ”.tcerroC“
deen ew ,dnaltroP fo htron thgilf-dim edolpxe enalp a dah tsuj ev’eW“ dias eH
,roolf eht otno ylluferac sgniht gnitisoped dna ni gniklaw ylraluger erew sllarevoc etihw ni elpoeP
”.meht derhs ot ton meht tsurt t’nod I ecnis tuB
,seidob ehT“ .deplug eH
.deriuqne I ”?esuac eht fo wonk ew od tahW“
.stekcap llams elpitlum ni derots ,redwop yrekooc saw
ll’tI“ .teef ym ot dereggats I .deilper eH
,thgir eht no nus gnimoolb eht ni ytic eht fo weiv a
ereht fI
,ti dengis roirepus ym ,oga shtnom 3 troper siht meht dednah I“
,syawriA mA htroN fo OEC
.nruter s'ti eviecer ot dehctertstuo wap ,emit eritne eht ti ta ylgnihcnilfnu erats seye sih was I ,ti peek em tel ot gniog t’nsaw eH .kcab ti dednah neht
.enod eb ot gniog saw ti dna
.eciffo eht sdrawot dedeecorp dna enigne eht detrats I sa
.maet noitagitsevni eht morf stnemetats emos detcelloc dna sesac xob eht fo shpargotohp emos koot syhR dna sgab detaicossa dna ”ydnac eson“ eht ,esnecil srevird s’ecurB
,stnemom tsal sti tuo gnittolp fo smret ni tnaem siht tahw wonk d’yehT
.ekaf etinifed A .esnecil srevird eht no yltcefrep hpargotohp eht dehctam
,stleb ym didnu dna rac eht dekrap I
,gnihtemos detpmetta eh fi taht eugra d’I tuB
”.mih htiw trats uoy tseggus I .sdef eht ot revo denrut neeb s’eH
.yks eht otni pu gnirettulf
nageb yeht dna htaerb peed a koot I .tuo dapeton
.rehtegot kcab tnew ti woh fo eton a gnikam
”?reywal ruoy s’ohW“
s’erehT“ .deddon dna dengis eH
.keehc ym ot eson sih gnisserp
”.elttaeS detraped ti erofeb revo enalp eht dekcehc eh dna tennob sih ni eeb a tog s’eH
,syhR ta revo neht
,tsefinam eht ot seman eht gnirapmoC
.eltbus yltcaxe t’nsaw lebal eht tub ,deriuqer eb dluow tset lamrof A
,mA htroN htiw smelborp ruoY“ .deddon I
.enalp eht kcatta ot ylno gnola sgurd
.tnelis saw moor ecnerefnoc eht ot pu pirt ehT
.nosirapmoc yb dehtacsnu ylevitaler sgniht emos
”?noisolpxe na s’ti wonk uoy od woH“
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
cilbup ,ssam a ni mih gnillik kniht I hguohT
”?em tsurtsid uoy oD“ .worbeye na desiar I
.rekihhctih flowerew ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
.detseggus eH ”.era ew ria emas eht gnihtaerb llits s’eh ecnis ,nosrednA .rM htiw trats ew tuoba woH“ .deddon syhR  .denialpxe syhR ”.dnuorg eht otni
,bal eht ta ni kcehc uoY“
,yalbmerT rotciV ,hA“
.degavlas neeb dah ffuts elbaifitnedi fo tnuoma egral rehtar a taht saw eton fo yletaidemmi saw tahW
.lamron naht teiuq eroM
,dias I ,”snoitseuq ”bmud“ eht deksa ydobon fI“
.teiuq deniamer syhR .tey tsuj
”.yregrof a evorp ot elba eb ylbaborp d’yeht esuaceb ecnedive doog edam evah t’ndluoW .ti gnipeek em
-  .yaw eht gnola noitcepsni rof yrotarobal
,ti kcajih ot deirt ,enalp eht no tog ecurB taht si noitpmuserP“
.elcihev eht evael ot deraperp I sa mih ot revo gnikool
.dias nooccar ehT
.eeffoc fo pis a gnikat ,delbmurg I
”.DI dekaf a no ,eveileb ew ,enalp eht draoba ti edam ohw ,lanimirc detnaw A“
,ragdE ecurB fo ecaf eht dehctam hpargotohp ehT
sih ot segnahc eht htiw yppah mees t’nseoD
,tius ym otni teg ot moordeb eht ot denruter neht ,dehsaw I
,dias I ”.os yltnerappA“
.yleritne rucnoc I
.regnol hcum boj taht gnipeek eb t’ndluow eh taht pu saedi sih kcub
”.ti rof oG“ .dias kcaJ
.retne ot kcehc DI na gnissap ,ot devom neeb dah ecnedive eht erehw ragnah ybraen a ot nekat erew eW
”.raf os tfarc eht morf dnuof ev’yeht ffuts tahw hguorht kool ot si aedi tseb txen eht kniht I“ .deddon syhR ”.yna
”.snoitseuq emos ksa ot ereh er’eW“
”?taht yas uoy sekam tahW“ .dlog dilos ekil deulav I ytilauq a saw tI
.kcaJ htiw emit hguot a dah ev’eW“
egral fo sesac ni
.dliub rednelS .xof a saw eH
dna yltnelis em deknaht syhR .pu gnidnats ,detcurtsni I
.denaorg eH ”.seY“ .deksa eH
dna lenap hcae gnikat ,nepo reniatnoc eht desae I ,sevolg emos no gnilluP
.tfel eht no senalporea suoirav fo sledom elttil htiw
,dnA .luah rieht htiw nwod og dna yrt ot enoemos rof egnarts s’tI
.eno taht ot yek eht dloh dluow xob kcalb eht ,dias gnieb tahT“ .detats I
eht htiw tem saw I ,enohp eht pu gnikciP
.moor eht gniretne syhR dna flesym htob fo erawa yletuca demees eh
.noitseggus etutsA“ .delims I
esnecil gnivird a ssorca emac ylkciuq I
”.ylevitinifed tuo elur ot eno drah A“
.tnorf elitcat ylerup a no ti ot ssenpaehc lareneg a dah ti ,gnorw saw tnof ehT
ohw dlrow emirc ro gurd eht ni enoyna wonk ohw sdael yna evah t’ndluow uoY“
,wonk t’ndid I tnatiseh os saw eh yhW
,enihcam leer ot leer eht htiw moor eht ni nwod tas I ,etis nO
”.sruoh wef a ni tsinoitpecer ruoy htiw eb ll’I
,airaM htiw ekops ylretal dna
,eciffo eht ot denruter ew dna ,yawa nekat dah I tahw nwohs dna demrofni erew maet ehT
,nemeltneg ,esaelP“
,elbat lavo gib a deniatnoc moor ecnerefnoc sihT
”?mA htroN yb derih uoy erA“
.mA htroN fo seciffo eht gniraeb teerts eht otno gninrut
”.elbissop sa noos sA .seY“ .dias I
.noitaiva fo tnemtraped eht fo seciffo eht dna rac eht ot tuo yaw ym edam I
.edis tfel eht no ralloc ym rednu guns
.su rof gnitiaw saw reklaW rM
.detcennocnu era sgurd eht dna eh taht ylekil erom s’ti regaw d’I
hguohT .seye sih ni etah dah eH
.reniatnoc degamad ylivaeh rehtar ,egral a delaever elbat eht fo tuocs rehtruf A
.spil sih no deraems llits etsaphtoot ,delbmurg eH
.derevocer d’yeht enalporea fo sknuhc egral eht ni tseretni hcum ekat t’ndid I
”.delbuort mees uoY“
.etis hsarc eht fo noitacol eht dedivorp neeb dah eW
”.daolnu dne rehto eht no enoemos evah
.dias syhR ”.ragdE ecurB“
,reviR siweL eht morf raf ton daorkcab a no pu dekrap eW
”.krow sih htiw noitcafsitassid desaercni sih htiw etalerroc ot smees sihT
,derepsihw eH ”.luferac eB“
,derrahc sgniht emos ,tneb dna delkcub gnieb fo sngis dewohs sgniht emoS
,ni parts ot mih rof gnitiaw
.dab enog gnikcajih a tseggus dluow I ,nibac eht gniretne ecurB fo sngis swohs redrocer eciov eht fi
.stcejbo lacituanorea-non rehto
.sgurd fo lluf erew yeht derugif tsuj I .mA htroN rof
,ruolf erew wef pot ehT
.krad saw moor ehT .ekowa I
.raelc erom saw ekaf eht ,esolc pU
.enohp eht yb detpurretni saw I tniop siht tA  .deil I ”.oN“
,llebpmaC airaM“
.tekcop ym ni ti tup neht
.derongi saw dna dnah sih tuo dleh syhR taht deton I
.ecno ta gnineppah sboj tnereffid owT
.deifiralc enirevlow ehT ”?xob eht no gnitiaw era dna seidob eht derevocer ev’yehT“
.yrassecen yltcirts si naht krow erom ekil sleef ti tnaw uoy erehw ot ti teg ot
”.tfarc taht no klof daed fo tol a
”.tneilc detalernu
”.gnimoc rof uoy knaht
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
:ni yalbmerT rotciV“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT     .epat eht
.yna era ereht fi ,ereht sgurd eht tup evah t’ndluow eh neht
eht ni kcab gninael ,dias kcaJ
lamron saw taht tuB .htiw erefretni ot dewolla t’nsaw I dlot saw I taht stellap nezod a revo gnidulcnI
dna tnemom a rof sregnif ym ni ti delriwt I  .retal ecnedive ni sesu evah yam yeht hguoht ,tey lacitirc oot kool t’ndid srehto eht fo snacs rehtruF
.redrocer ettessac eht ffo denrut I dna rac eht otni debmilc ew sa syhR ot dias I
rehtien dna ,kaeps t’ndid eH
”.seno bmud eht ksa ylno I“ .dias eH
.rotavele na sdrawot reyof trams eht ssorca su gnidael dna gninrut ,dias reklaW rM
nipgnik lanimirc a fo edicius ro redrum detpmetta nA
tsoc ehT“ ”.sruoh raluger fo tuo artxe tsoc
,redrum a saw ti fI
…ot tuo sniks dehcaop dna eniacoc ylf ot gniyrt saw eh fI
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.esitrepxe fo aera ym morf raf saw tahT
”.gab ydob a ni saw noitacol nwonk tsal sih ,mih gniksa emit hguot a evah ll’uoY .ylbissoP“
,boj sih esol ot tuoba s’eh ,reyolpme sih setah eH .evitom elbissop a s’tahT“
”.won ti gnirevocer er’yehT“
”.enuJ ni truoc ot gniog er’ew dna reywal a evah I ,oga htnom a tiuswal a delif I“
.noitpecer eht otni spets eht pu deklaw eW
.krow ot teg ll’ew ,thgirlA“
.gnirrits ,selrahC ,rentrap ym leef dluoc I dna em ot txen elbat eht no gnar enohp ehT
”.enif m’I“ .deddon eH
.naelc ylsseltopS .desserP
delbuort demees uoY“
dednim evah t’ndluow eh neht ,ekaf si sroirepus sih ot no dessap d’eh sgurd eht tuoba tnemucod taht fI
.tsilaturB yzaL .erutcetihcra s’0691 .kcolb eciffo egral A
:ni yalbmerT rotciV“   yojne esaelP
.ti no dellebal stnetnoc s’ti dah tekcap hcaE
thguorb evd’eh erus ton m’I ,ragdE .rM rof sA” .detseggus I
tnedicni lanoitan a esuac dna tcudorp fo tnuoma doog yltcefrep a yawa worht letrac a dluow yhw ,dias gnieb taht
.tcefreP“ .deddon I
”?draoba gnihtyna delggums eh kniht uoy oD“
,hguohtlA .spahrep ,htiaf fo tset a sa desiugsid part A“
”doolB repaP :ni yalbmerT rotciV“
”.dnuorg eht otni detemmulp enalp eht dna
.mih pots ot koob eht no dnah a detser I tub yawa sih tup ot tnew ylhsipeehs eH
,taht fo sngis on era
...sterces tuohtiw era sevitceted ruo neve ton woh
na yb nur gurd a dna
.revo ti llum ot demees eH
.rehpargotohp yawliar dna naicisum
.krowrepap hguorht gnitfis saw syhR erehw elbat eht ta nwod tas I .denialpxe I
”.gninrom siht rac eht ni tog uoy tnemom eht morf
”?oiranecs demuserp eht s’tahW“ ,rednop I
.etisoppo eht deilpmi ylivaeh taht yaw a ni ,dias eH
”.noscuT ot elttaeS morf snuR“ .deksa I
”.ylroop koot eh taht deton si ti gnihtemos ,mA htroN yb tnemyolpme fo noitanimret htiw denetaerht yltnecer saw eH“ .dias eH
.htrof os dna sruoh sih ,elor
.syhR ot noitamrofni eht deyaler neht
.elggurts rehto yna ro ,tipkcoc eht otni tsrub eh fi raeh ot elba eb d’uoY
”?erehwesle nekat eb ot ti dedeen eh sselnU“ .deddon syhR ”.thguac
.ainrofilaC dna anozirA ,adaveN
,secnetnes gnitrats mih raeh dluoc I
.nwod gnittis ,dias nooccar ehT
,muigleB ,ailartsuA ,napaJ
”.ecalp eht revo lla morf tuo dna ni gnimoC
,DI ekaf a no gniylf drocer lanimirc a htiw enoemos tog ev’ew ,noisulcnoc ni ,oS“
”.ecnerefer esac eht dna noitamrofni reh uoy evig nac I
.deilpmoc ew ,detcurtsni reklaW rM ”.taes a ekaT“
.retal htiw tlaed eb dluoc taht tub
,noscuT rof dnuob ,elttaeS morf ffo koot ,44 thgilF saw tI“ .dias I
dna seceip eht levarnu syhR dna rotciV woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.egap ytiniffaruF sih no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
.dias I ”.taht erofeB“
”.snrub evissecxe wohs derevocer ev’yeht stnemgarf ehT“ .deksa syhR
,selbairav ynam oot ,gnorw og ot hcum ooT .tnemnorivne dellortnoc a ni tohsdaeh teiuq a eb dluow ti kniht I
derehtag neht ,dereffo neeb dah I stcepsus gniniamer eht revo gnicnalg ,dias I ,"detoN“