- llaftoof tniaf a ,neht dnA
,dnas no swap fo dap ydaets
.gnirb thgim gninrom eht tahw yb denepmad senot rieht
,yawa ezag sih erot hteK
.deziremsem ,dehctaw hteK
,meht nopu yvaeh yal egdelwonk tahT
.ebirt ruo gnillik si marA esuaceB“
,sedis ffilc kcor eht dehcuot emoS
dehcnerd eht tsniaga thgirb
.wohemos tnereffid tub
.hteK morf htrof detaludnu
,ecnelis nedoow htiw tem saw eralg gnignellahc s’hteK
.enog saw tekeM tub
,uoy ot kool taht ahewB gnilliK
,seert dna snroht eht gnoma repeed reve gnivled
;mih deppirg ssenthgit A
,cra deggaj egnarts a rof
,erif eht morf gnignits dna degnis ,taeM
,ecafrus sti gnola gniyalp sregnif reh
rehto hcae tsgnoma evaew
,ereht derorrim erif eht fo snoitcelfer eht htiw thgirb
,esir sraet eht tlef hteK .sselnoisserpxe ecaf reh
- nosaes tsap eht revo sehsimriks dna sehsubma ni s’hteK gnigagne neeb dah
.tegrof ot mih dewolla tsomla devol eh esoht fo ygrene dna rethgual eht dna
.tsehc sih ot mra degamad
,tfihs dna egdun A
,nrow dna detum dednuos yeht srae s’hteK ot tub
,repeed a otni gnillitsid
.nees dah eh sdnuow rehto ynam os ot ralimis ylbirroh saw edam dah edalb eht raet eht
,hteK ta dekool eH
,sdaerht revlis kciht fo riap a ot detniop ehS .delims anM
.tnecserc detcelfer s’noom eht yb detanimulli ylmid regnarts eht
,epahs s’lakcaj sih tsol tekeM
.seinomerec ralucitrap rof tuo meht thguorb tekeM sselnu
.ezag s’tekeM teem ot elbanu
,ecaf s’hteK nwod yltoh nar sraeT
.regnol elttil a thgin eht yojne meht teL .tiaw nac tI
.yawa meht tae sdnas dna sdniw eht ,tor semoh ruoY
,daeh sih tsniaga talf srae ,deppots eH
,mih gniynapmoccA
,tresed eht fo sdnas eht dehcaer evah tsum ereht neeb dah reveohW
,dnim sih ta dehsup surtic dna
.tnet eht fo renroc eht ni swodahs eht ni kcab mih tes eh os
,tnuag ylbirroh dna dekan
,wam suonrevac s’täA nihtiw deraeppasid retaw fo stnuoma eguH
,deneppah dah gnihton fi sa ,lluf demees tI
spetstoof eht htiw gnidnecsed ylwols
tuat tnew selcsum sih
,mih ecaf ot denrut dog eht sa dehctaw hteK dna
,ssol fo niap gniworg eht htiw gnixim thgil s’rU fo bats prahs eht
”!htiw marA thgif nac eh eno ,esu nac eh enO
,dloc dna knalb ylgnizinoga won erew
.seye sih gnirevoc swap sih fo sleeh eht
.tnelis saw hteK
,selbmurc dlrow ehT .hteK detairufni
.wonk I lla rof ,daed rO
- rehtona yb dewolloF
,raor gnidoolf neddus taht htiw dnA
.mih sdrawot detnirps dna ,hteK deirc ”!potS“
?uoy ot flesmih wohs eh dluow yhW“ ”?spahreP
,egnaro tfos a htiw roiretni eht fo hcum desuffus
.kcart ot ysae saw htap s’dog ehT
revo deklaw hteK .gnihctaw llits
.mih ta yltnetni dekool dna
,gnivomnu doots lakcaj ehT
,asem eht fo egde eht ta tas tnet ehT
,ereht saw ti tuB
,niaga kool ot derad eh
,gnivomnu dna devomnu deniamer sdog eht
.tnegru dna dekcinap
.yllufyalp hteK gniwoble ,iroaP dehgual
,neerg ylpmis ,eye rehto sih noos dna
,desuap dna hteK dehcaer eH
,tnelis saw dog ehT
,tnet nwo sih naht emoh ekil erom tlef syawla ti
.gninruter eb tsum eH
,setib egavas htiw epahs sti degrof dah tsaeb taerg emos fi sa
.thgil s’noom eht ni enohs ruf erab reh dna
?suollac os uoy era yhW“
,ffilc eht raen enohs gnihtemos ,denrut eh sA
,sdrawpu yaw rieht edam tsoM
,sdnas eht ssorca yldeirruhnu deklaw eh
;derolocsid saw edis sti deciton eh
.sisao s’ebirt eht fo erohs eht ta doots dna
,hcuot tserab eht
,sevlesmeht ahewB
ezeerb tfos eht yb peels ot dellul ,ffo dezod yltnerappa dah tey
.ycnetop sti tsol ylraelc s’ti ;krow t’ndid ti desirprus toN
.nees dah hteK enoyna naht rellat dna ,niht demees saw siht reveohw
”.yaw emos ni ,llew sa sevil rieht hcuot lliw uoy ylraelC
.ria rof gnipsag ,tuo drow hcae dehsup hteK ”!täA uoy eman I“
,lakcaj regnuoy eht ot ezag sih detfil tekeM ”!gnihtoN
.nrael dluoc eh mohw morf eno ylno eht suht dna ,thgisretaw eht
,snoitcerid lla ni detfird rewop gniredduhs fo slirdneT
,drawkcab pets yratnulovni na koot eh dna
.gnikcinap er’uoY
.mih deksa ydaerla ev’I“
.weiv sih ssorca detcarfer dna derettilg ,gnihctaw reve
egassap s’täA fo skcarc derehtaew eht
”?tekeM no pu nevig uoy evaH
,tcafitra tneicna dna derehtaew a ekil
- enecs eht ni koot ecnalg kciuq A
,tfos eht saw erehT
,renroc eht ni foola deniamer lalT dna
.ahewB eht fo stnet deroloc ylthgirb eht lla yb degnir
,redips derruf krad a ekil ,ereht dehcuorc eH
.tnet s’tekeM ot revo derednaw niaga dah eh dnuof hteK *** .yrros ma I
,anm-a sih htiw enohs retaw eht ylneddus dna
,derekcilf sdaerht revlis ehT
eciton ruoy htaeneb raf os era eW
.evom ton dluow sgel sih tub
.worbeye desiar a dna
emit txen ni enuT
.swen s’hteK emac nwad htiW
.detarepsaxe saw hgis reH
.semalf s’erifkooc eht fo pordkcab eht tsniaga
,pu dekool hteK …erugif A
.dnuora deppihw daeh s’täA .dehsup dna
?gniod neve I ma tahW
,ereht saw rU taht mih dednimer
.feiler s’hteK ot ,ti tfel dah eh sa saw asem ehT
,deunitnoc ylkeem neht
,tesnus eht yojnE
.tekeM si esoht fo enO“
.gnikahs ,desuap dna
”!uoy ekil ,ahewB era eW
.dewohs ehs tahw ees dluoc eh
,snoitcerid lla ni tuo dehcterts taht gnibbew remassog a
,delbmuts dna tuo deirc hteK
- ti ot wap suoiruc a detfil eH
,ebirt sih dna ,hteK woh tuo dnif ot
.tnesba saw erifnob s’tsaef eht fo wolg elatllet eht tey
,lalT fo swap nedoow eht
,knird ot gniunitnoc
.degnahc gnihtemos
.ecalp-gnileud eht ta ebirt s’marA teem yeht sa eraf
,dessap stnemom gnoL
.ffins doog a edisni deraems etsap neerg eht gnivig
.dednamed hteK
,slirdnet eht fo eno gnola psarg dehcterts s’hteK dexaoc ehS
,stnet rieht ot deriter dah ynaM
.derevocer saw ydob s’tekeM sa dehtees yruf deniatnoc yleraB
sepahs lakcaj derrulb dehctaw eh sa desucofnu seye ,tas hteK
.deleviws ti htaeneb elzzum tcefrep eht sa neve
.ylsuoiruc ,reh ta kool ot denrut hteK
.erac ton did eh tub
.dnuos eht htiw gnitarbiv senob sih
.cirbaf s’tnet eht tsniaga pu gnihsurb
,mih ta syawedis dereep htotA sa
.detanoser eciov s’täA ”,tekeM-toN“
.noitseuq ni reven erew ti fi sa ,detats rU
.lakcaj a doots ybraen ecaf kcor eht ot txen dna
,delbmuts yldetcepxenu hteK
,dnuora kcab gnilrihW
sdnarts fo edutitlum a ot detniop neht anM
,mih hguorht pu delbbub raef dna noitazilaer sA
”?elbativeni eht yaled ot hsiw uoY“
.loop eht morf htrof ti gnigru dna gnillup
.tekeM neeb dah tahw nopu nwod gnikool ,deniamer hteK
,ereht tuo si tekeM
,dehcuorc ylluferac
.deneffits eh dna
,ecaf sih ot esir taeh eht tlef hteK .teiuq saw anM
,hcuot s’täA fo rednimer a
.neesnu yats thgim eh sepoh ni os did eh sa edis s’asem eht gnigguh
,ydob eht ta derats eH
.peelsa ro ,gnitsaef ro ,rehto hcae gniyojne
,ediw gninepo swaj sih
,swap sih ot tfos dna looc
.emit eraps sih ni gnitirw dna gnidliubdlrow syojne tub
”.eb ot evah I esuaceB“
,tnelis saw tekeM tub
.drawrof dekrep srae gnol sih ,tnemirrem eniuneg htiw enohs ecaf regae s’lakcaj rehto eht dna
.saw ylurt ehs ohw rof reh ees dluoc eh
?nopaew lufrewop a ti ekaM“
,detlit dlrow eht dna
.ecnelis dna ssenkrad ylno saw ereht tub
.ti htiw debbur erew sesnes sih lla fi sa
.dniheb nopaew releurc raf a gnivael
”,evivrus nac ebirt ruo woh tuo erugif ot deen I dna
.tnemesuma htiw demaelg seye s’täA
”.uoy wohs em tel ,ereH
.tekeM ta ssorca dekool dna
.edis s’tekeM ssorca raet peed eht deredrob taht ruf dettam dna
,dreh eht gninniht si eh spahreP .regnorts si eH“
,sruoy yb dehcuot era sevil riehT
redniamer eht fo naelc wap sih gnikcil
.roolf tresed tfos eht no esahcrup dna deeps rof gnihsup swap sih
tsav ylneddus erew seye tilnoom s’täA
;retaw eht ssorca derettiks selppir dna pu gnarps ezeerb a ,dehctaw eh sA
ediw ylbissopmi gninepo elzzum sih
,rehto sih otni takok fo lwob a dna wap eno otni tsurht saw
,ylluferac ti gnildarc dna pu ti gnikciP
- erif eht dnuora sdog detplucs eht sa gnignahcnu dna derramnu dna dednuorg sa ,niatrec
.tsaef eht yojne ,og
”.thginot srentrap retteb raf ekam lliw ohw srehto ynam era erehT“ .yawa dekool dna
dehcuot yeht erehw dna
)2 fo 1 traP( unutU yb ”retaW“
.mih demialc peels erofeb
.ydob sih fo smsaps eht htiw gnihcra enips sih
sih gnirevoc llits swap
.edisni nward saw hteK dna
.noitamrifnoc etaidemmi erew ybraen yaw rieht edam taht stnirp wap egral eht dna
,irkuk sih fo edalb devruc eht dehtaehsnu hteK noitarepsed ni dna
,deganam hteK
.emocrevo tsomla saw hteK taht lufniap os ytuaeb a
…su htiw emit dnepS .emoC“
,ecafrus s’retaw eht sdrawot rehtruf denael täA
.deriaper saw erutan s’täA yb thguorw egamad eht ,dehcuot yeht reverehw dna
,nwod detrats dna
.detnioppasid eb dluow tekeM
,lartuen saw eciov reH
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,esnopser teiuq sih saw
.wap sih ni ynoga eht gnirongi
,sessarg tresed fo stfut erew erehT
.railimaf ssel dna
,wam s’lakcaj eht fo ssyba kcalb eht otni gnimaerts retaw eht ta gniratS
,hteK delims ”,htotA“
.oot ,ti esnes dluoc I wenk eH
,derotser neeb dah ecafrus derram dna dettip sti
.dnif dluoc ti lla gnibrosba
.dniheb noom tnecserc eht yb denmil srae sih ,rewot lakcaj a
.retaw ekil yawa dewolf niap eht dna
,wap s’hteK sserac ot htrof dekans enO
.mih ecaf ot daeh sih denrut ylwols rU dna
;revo dekconk neeb dah enO
,smrots gnillac dna
!su ot tnereffidni era uoY“ ”?os woH“
,ruf sih delffur sdniw emoclew ehT ?wollof I dluohS
”!ydaerla takok fo ytnelp dah ev’uoy ekil kool uoY“
.hteK sdrawot kcab ylwols daeh sih denrut dna ,deldnips dna gnol sbmil
,tekeM fo wonk I
,redluohs sih revo ti gnuls dna gab breh sih depsarg eH
.ruf sih no steluvir krad
.rU fo eye eht dezalb htap eht no daeha rof
,derotser saw sisao eht stnemom nihtiW
,redluohs sih no detser nihc A ”!hteK“
on dnA .desolc llaf palf tnet eht tel hteK
.teef sih ot tog dna
,gnorts si thgisretaw ruoY“
hteK nopu dekool netfo os dah taht seye eht dna
,tuo denrub evah serif ehT
:yojne esaelP   .GNAF noos dna
,kcurts gnieb tcejbo na fo duht eht saw erehT
ekorb kcor eht dna
,detrulb hteK ”,uoy naC“ …tey
,nekorb dna delpmurc
,ecnesba s’dniw eht yb rorrim larutannu
.asem eht fo htuos sdnalburcs eht sdrawot sdnas eht ssorca hteK morf delevart taht ,gnislup
,enohs revlis fo seniL
ll’yehT“ ”.evil ot ebirt ym tnaw I
.mih devrennu seutats tauqs eht dna
,emit eritne eht htaerb sih dleh tub lla dah eh gnizilaer won ylno
;nihtiw dereep hteK
”.od uoy tahw yb dna
.erugif eht doots ,yks eht tsniaga deniltuo ,ereht dnA
,ezingocer t’ndid hteK taht etsap neerg diviv a fo lluf-flah saw tI
.deknilb rU neht dnA
,htuom sih otni ti devohs eh
,slirtson sih dedoolf yruf dna noitarepsed fo tnecs ehT
strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,mih gniyduts seye sih
.deniamer senil emos tub
.ylbatrofmocnu detfihs hteK dna ,tekeM deriapsed
,desirprus dekool rU ”.oN“
.weiv morf tsol noos saw dna
.trapa edis sih deppir dah ti taht
,redluohs sih no hcuot thgil a saw wap reH
,bir desopxe dna deretnilps a fo etihw krats eht detanimulli thgilnooM .doolb hcum oS
,gninruhc dnim sih
thgis sih fo tfihs kciuq a htiW .mrif dna prahs
,dehcraes eh sa dessap stnemom etarepsed dna gnol lareveS
.knird ot detrats eh sa
,gnilgnim seciov rieht
.feiler emoclew a saw ria gnineve looc eht ,tuo deppets eh sa dna
,derrulb noisiv s’hteK .efil fo dioved
.sdneirf ruoy era seno esohT“
.yarg ddo na saw neerg krad yllamron eht thgilnoom eht ni
,deniamer hself ehT
,traeh sih fo taeb eht saw raeh dluoc hteK lla tub ,deleviws dna dekcilf srae lakcaj evitisneS
.asem eht fo egde eht gnola nwod del taht htap depols ,laudarg eht sdrawot gnidecer ,won spetstoof raelc
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.enot reh ni noitcelfni ddo na saw erehT
;emit on saw ereht tuB
.yltnereffid ees ot deen uoy tub
,thgin tresed eht fo ytiliuqnart ehT
,mih tfel thgisretaw ehT
.ebirt s’marA s’tahT ?esoht dnA“
.teef sih ot tog neht
,htuos detrats dna
,erutplucs eht ni elbisiv saw kcarc thgils A
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.niaga ehtaerb ot elba yllanif
.tuo deppets dna edisa palf tnet eht dehsup eH ?em ekow tahW
.sisao eht sdrawot dezag hteK
.ti tfel dah eh sa saw ti
”.llew sa retaw uoy gnirb maerts eht tel
.hgis tfos a htiw tsud otni gnispalloc
htap eht nwod kcab yaw sih edam täA
.pil eht revo raeppasid ot sllaw s’asem eht pu gnidniw
”.siht ekiL .ti tsiwT
”.mih rof krow neve t’ndid taht edam eh sbreh emos fo esuaceb
,tsap gniunitnoc ,deddon hteK
,stsif sih dehcnelc hteK ”.eid
,shgual dna selims erew erehT
.emac eh yaw eht kcab
,eltneg saw eciov s’anM
,weiv otni emac lakcaj A
.ratrom eht deveirter ylteiuq neht ,eltsep eht pu dekcip dna
,tnednopsed ,tas tekeM namahs eht
,ybraen nwod edispu yal ratrom enots a dna
,kciht emos ,niht emos
.raef sih ekopseb tnecs siH
- sdog lakcaj eht fo serutplucs devrac ,tauqs ,llams eht erew
,trats a htiw ekowa hteK
,eye sih fo renroc eht fo tuO ?rehto eht dnA
,nosmirc tsekrad htiw dehsalps ruf denekrad-thgin fo bolb gnirevaw a mih gniredner sraet s’hteK
,dniw eht no thguorb repsihw a saw ereht ;desuap hteK
,tnet eht fo sessecer rehtruf eht fo stnediser yllamron
.eciov s’anM desnes ylmid hteK
,swap sih tsap detfird dnas eht sa detiaw eh
”,ylbaborp ,hguone toN“
.rebmemer ot staebtraeh lareves mih koot ti dna
,ylniatrecnu stnetnoc eht denimaxe hteK
.edisni deppets eh sa ylsuovren gnireep
,derettilg seye nedloG
,dias eh ”,uoy knahT“
.ecnatsid eht otni tresed eht ssorca dehcterts taht
.htuom sih ni sbreh fo etsatretfa egnarts a
,ereht tas llits ratrom ehT
,esion eht sdrawot detrats eH
.feiler ni delahxe eh dna
.sraet sih fo rulb eht hguorht detfihs dna tneb saw egami reh dna
gnivomnu wohemos eye nedlog eht
dloc eht nopu desolc sregnif sih dna
,täA yb dehcuotnu ylgnimees
.ecracs saw retaw erehw tresed eht fo egde eht ta ereh eno derever hcum a dna
,tsehc sih ni duol oot gnipmuht traeh
- enola ereh neeb reve ton dah hteK
.flehs eht no ratrom eht gnicalper dna
,sdnas eht ni snrettap nwolb-dniw eht gnola yaw rieht dedaerht emos
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,taeH ni deraeppa sah krow dehsilbup siH
,yaw taht yppahnu dekool dog eht dediced hteK
,yks noonretfa eht fo eulb eht tsniaga noilimrev fo hsalps a
,hteK hguorht gnitanoser sdrow eht
.ekat ot sih saw ti ylneddus
,elzzum sih dedoolf surtic dna nori dna htrae fo etsat ehT
,tnet sih dnuora gnivoM
,dennirg täA ”!tey ton tuB
.krow t’ndid sbreh ehT .gnihtoN“
,mih dniheb lla meht tup hteK
.od ot tahw wonk t’nseod eh wonk I
.desolc dna dehtooms
,ekaw ym ni gnola wolloF“
,pid elzzum sih tel hteK .skcarc dah
.worrom eht no emoc ot saw tahw wenk ereht llA
.dnim sih deppirg taht ynoga desucof erom
pu kool ot flesmih decrof dna
,asem eht fo retnec eht ni yal tI
,ssargdnas eht fo eltsur dna repsihw eht dna
”?ton marA tey ,egatnavda na tekeM evig I dluohs nosaer tahw roF
?tekeM ot evig nac I enO
.nwo sih tsniaga dehsup elzzum s’htotA sa
,hA“ .elbadaernu noisserpxe sih
”…spahrep ,sbreh emos era erehT
seye sih ssorca wap sih debbur hteK
.tniaf saw tnecs eht esolc pu nevE
,gnigdun dna gnipsarg thgis nwo sih ,tuo dehcaer eH
,ruf s’lakcaj daed eht ni sevaw dna selppir mrof dniw eht gnihctaw ni flesmih tsol eh dna
,egassap sih morf detliw
;ecnelis otni dennuts ,tas tsuj hteK
tlenk hteK ”?tekeM“ .ecaf
,sbreh eht ezingocer t’nod I
.rettam ton seod tI .yawyna won denmad ma I
.mih dniheb rU fo emalf eht ot tsartnoc prahs a erew seye elap esohw etteuohlis tnuag a
.kcalb denrut revlis tnecsenimul eht dna ,ehtirw
,sevlehs eht ot revo ylregnig deppets hteK
ezeerb tresed toh eht
,hguorht dna dnuora gnikans slirdnet eht
noitcarfer derettacs a ylpmis saw tnecserc thgirb eht noos
.kaeps t’ndid sdog ehT
,eutats eht denimaxe hteK
.dlog gninrub eno ,neerg eno
,tsiwt rehtona htiw dna
,detiaw sdog ehT .detiaw hteK
,devirra dah ti sa ylneddus sa tfel surtic gnissapmocne-lla ehT
.sisao eht fo swollahs eht ni swap sih gnicalp ,drawrof tneb dna denrut neht
.niatrec saw hteK
deppots neht ,dedda tekeM
,thgis sih detfihs hteK
,redluob eht pota llits
,eciton on evag täA
,dnalburcs eht deretne eh litnu ton saw tI
tresed eht otni tuo tes ebirt eht
.htrof demaerts retaw dna
”.eveileb I ,sbreh rof gnikooL
.kcab sih tsniaga gnisserp ezag esnetni s’dog eht
.llits dna devrac dna trohs
,seno deirrow s’htotA tem seye neerg siH
,thgieh s’hteK niaga flah saw eH
,enog saw ti hsalf a ni tuB
.sisao eht fo tfel saw tahw otni gnihsalps erofeb ,tnemom a rof ria eht ni gnuh retaW
.stnet eht ta deppans dna dekculp yeht sa asem eht pota sdniw tneserp-reve eht dna
…ereht saw ehs ezilaer neve t’ndid I
,uaetalp eht fo egde eht evoba elbisiv erew srae s’tekeM ylno litnu dehctaw hteK
.rehtona ro yaw eno ni ,uoy ot detcennoc lla era yehT
tnet eht fo cirbaf niht eht hguorht thgilnus ehT
,tnelat etanni na saw tI
”.t’now I tuB .esruoc fO“
.degnahc anm-a sih dna
,ebirt regral s’marA
,mih ekil lakcaj a saw ti
.nwo s’hteK otni derats ,noom eht sa elap ,seyE
?og dniw eht did erehW
,elims a htiw hteK detfig dna denrut ehS
.ekaw s’täA ni klaw ot nageb eh dna
,leef dluoc eh dehsiw hteK ssenippah a htiw decalper
,no deunitnoc srelever emos tub
.deraeppasid surtic fo ssenevisavrep egnarts eht dna
strap 2 fo 1 eht eht saw sihT
.rehtegot dnuob sevil rieht ,asem taht no pu srehto eht lla dna ,uoy fo
”!tey daed ton era yehT
”,gninetsil ton er’yehT“
,dilos neeb syawla dah namahs ehT
,degamadnu saw ti taht deciton ylerab eh dna
,htap eht fo mottob eht ta tuo dehcterts roolf tresed ehT
.rehtruf gnihton dias dog eht nehw regna ot degnahc ylkciuq hcihw
,esir cinap dna esnet selcsum sih tlef eH
,nar eh yletarepseD
”.deraperpnu ma I dna ,resolc reve speerc worromoT .hteK ,yrros ma I“
ta revo decnalg täA ”.ytsriht ma I dnA .rehtona ot gnoleb lliw sisao siht nooS .gniyd si ebirt ruoY“ ”.retaw taht sdeen ebirt yM .esaelP“
”?deeccus lliw eh kniht uoy od dnA“
gnilbmurc cidarops eht etadommocca ot thgiew sih tfihs ot decrof yllanoisacco
.gnihton dias tub
.sretaw gnildniwd yldipar eht morf yawa täA hsup ot wap sih htiw gnihcaer
.elbativeni si tI“
.lufniap eb ot sa prahs os saw tnecs eht dna derrulb noisiv siH
,revo decnalg eh ,nur a ta llitS
,sgnivrac dog eht ta ecnalg syawedis kciuq a htiw neht ,desuap eH
,sllac yletarepsed tekeM
noisiv sih fo egde eht ta thgil fo tniopnip eht litnu
,das seye neerg reh
”?siht uoy wohs ton tekeM diD .lluP“ ”?tahW“
.egnellahc s’tekeM eussi-er dna marA teem ot
.niaga pu elbbub ot detrats yruF
.suorednuht saw ti sesnes devrennu s’hteK ot tey
,enots eht ni kcarc a tsniaga gnippils wap sih
,ffo deliart eciov siH
,unutU yb ”retaW“ fo
,cirbaf nopu wap a fo
.dnas eht no talf delwarps flesmih dnuof hteK .krad dna thgirb
.dnas no wap fo hsurb tniaf a
dekcirp ,surtic htiw degnit
.eutats dednepu eht ot revo devom dna
.dessap eh sa rU ta tnemgdelwonkca ni gnicnalg
rae na fo hctiwt feirb a saw ti fo ngis ylno eht ,desirprus saw anM fI
.noisiv sih fo egde eht ta tnilg prahs a
,mih ta gnirats yltnelis
.swap s’hteK raen gnitser
.dootsrednu evah dluow tekeM erus saw hteK dna
,noitcafsitas fo esnes llams a tlef hteK dna
.rehtie taht wonk t’nod I“ ”?I dluow yhW
,drawrof dehsur hteK
,yltnetsisni sih tsniaga desserp mrof rednels s’htotA ”!em htiw
.gniyd si ebirt ruoY .tekeM-toN“
.doolb sih htiw krad saw dnas ehT
.nwad gnihcaorppa eht litnu edisa tes selbuort
?I dluohs yhW“ ”?ton yhW“
.sbreh fo noitcelloc tsav sih gnihsinelper lufsseccus tsom eht neeb dah namahs eht erehw secalp
,tnet sih ot kcab derednaw dah eH
,lwob ytpme sih nwod gnitteS
.thgilnoom fo htaerb a ylerab
,ediw ylbissopmi denepo wam siH .mrof sselnoitom s’tekeM ot txen dnas eht ni dehcuorc dna mih dnuora deppets täA ”.yrros ma I“ .täA deerga ”,hteK“ .hteK dias ”,hteK“ ”.won tekeM-toN-toN .tekeM-toN
.tnet eht detixe eh sa dewollof hteK dna
.neppah t’nseod tahT .dniw
reworran gnimoceb shtap eht
.dloc sehsa eht
tuo dehcterts gnieb sih fo sderhs eht
.kcor eht nopu erus dna teiuq swap nwo sih
,raf ton saw tnet nwo s’hteK
.mih ot faed era uoy tub
.resolc ni gninael ,detrons htotA
.noom dnoces a saw ecafrus sti fo rorrim eht dna
.mih teerg ot denrut taht secaf eht ni ssenippah eht ta elims tub pleh ton dluoc eh tub
,dehgis hteK ”,yrros ma I“
yawa denrut eH .em sdeen dna
.tnemssarrabme htiw dehsulf eh dna
.dniw eht yb derettacs saw dna llef tsud kcalb
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.anM ta kcab gnikool ,deirc hteK
,ecnetsisni mlac sih rednU
,anm-a htiw detfig egalliv eht ni eno rehto ylno eht saw namahs eht rof ,s’tekeM ni emit hcum tneps eH
.sraet eht morf ruf sih ni skaerts ,ecaf sih ni dehcte yresim
”?erac ton seod täA kniht uoY“
.tsud dna yarg eb lliw asem ruoy pota stnet lufroloc eht ,nooS
;edisni kcab ylfeirb decnalg eH
tnesba edam tops eht ni tas eh ,ylevitatneT
”!em llet uoy t’ndid yhW“ !on on oN
.mih nihtiw liob ot detrats noitartsurf dna
.teef sih ot esor eh sa ti derongi hteK tub
.etihw gninekcis yb detpurretni
.regnol elttil a stiaw täA tsael tA
,yal tekeM erehw ot htap eht nwod rehtruf gnikool
lalT dna eh htob won dna
.hteK ot kcab seye elap sih denrut täA dna
”!gnihtyreve ton ,oN“
.uaetalp eht ot pu del taht htap eht fo enilcni eltneg eht dethgis noos eh
.enog erew oot yeht neht
.deitpme ylwols sisao eht dna
,elbats dna mrif niaga spets siH
,tiaw ot evah dluow feirg
,niatruc krad s’yks eht dehcuot egnaro gnirekcilf oN
,dettip dna llud won saw edalb eht fo ssenprahs gnitnilg ehT
.ssendas elbarettunu taht otni espmilg a
,htreb ediw a sdog eutats eht gniviG .eson sih ta
,flesmih deidaets hteK ,gnisucoF
…tsuJ .oN“ ”?pleh I naC“
ecrof hcum os htiw dereviled neeb dah wolb elgnis ehT
.skcatta tnatsnoc s’marA yb delluc dna dewonniw neeb dah taht ebirt a
.seciov on era erehT
.tekeM saw taht lla ni dellup
.eye tfel s’rU fo bro gnizalb eht morf yawa kool ot troffe sih lla koot tI .hguone dah evah I
.wap derujni sih ta gnicniw
,etelpmoc ksat siH
,sthgil elap dairym fo
.egral oot raf htuom a ni etihw hteet sih
.woleb tresed eht ot htap ykcor eht fo epols eht nwod gnitrats erofeb tap mrif a redluohs s’hteK evag eh dna
,reh ta yltnaifed deralg hteK
…esuaceb won uoy ees ylno I
.egalliv ruoy fo wonk I
.mih htaeneb kcor dilos-ecno fo
.dootsrednu tekeM ylno ylbaborp redro na ni smeti fo selbmuj htiw yldrazahpah dekcots
,htaeneb snroht eht revo gnilgnad swap
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.htuos gnidaeh dna htap eht morf yawa gnilgna
.flesmih marA morf detanigiro ylniatrec tsomla taht noissergga citsiretcarahcnu fo yalpsid a
!wonk t’nod I“ .deksa anM
.ereht dessot neeb dah eh fi sa
,ria rof delggurts hteK dna
;raelc saw hcum taht ,krow s’marA saw tI .dehcnelc elzzum
,täA delbmur ”,tsriht I“
.sgniht ynam ees I ,hteK“
.dilos neeb syawla sah htap ehT
.ssenthgirb sti ni gnimlehwrevo
”,od ot tahw wonk uoY“ .seye s’rU teem dna
.ecruos eht saw ehs dna
- seye sih denrub regnol on revlis eht ylneddus dna ,elkcuhc A
semitemos ,tnaillirb dna gninihs dna dilos semitemos
.tnecserc tcefrep s’noom eht gnirram selppir
,ria rof depsag hteK
.swap fo daert eht dna dnas dna dniw fo sraey dna sraey yb detplucs dna htoomS
.dereggats dna deredduhs eh
”.ecnelis lla si tI
”,ytsriht syawla ma I“
.tnet ym dehcuot uoY !taht did uoY“
,teef sih ot ylikahs gnireggatS
,llaw tnet sih ecno saw taht diov deggaj eht hguorht dehcaer hteK
.suoivbo lasuora s’lakcaj gnuoy eht ,kcab ot tsehc
,dnim sih egnahc dluoc eh erofeB
,thgis ni saw roolf tresed eht ot nwod del taht htap eht dna retal spets wef A
.suoires noisserpxe sih
”,era uoy sa erutuf eht fo niatrecnu sa er’yehT .egnahc yeht ,seY“
,stops etirovaf s’tekeM rof yllacitnarf dennacs eh
,tnet s’tekeM fo tuo ylitliug hsur ton ot od dluoc eh lla saw tI
.ytniatrecnu ni daeh sih gnikcoc
.ecnelis s’thgin eht no degnipmi sdneirf sih fo rettahc on
- gnol tpels ton dah eh
,nwod daeh ,kcab srae sih
.tip erif eht ot txen tops sti ni kcab ti decalp eh
.mih tfel hcuot s’rU taht
”,rU“ ”.hteK“ .oot mih ta derats
.daerd fo tnerrucrednu taht
.sey ,yllautnevE“ ”.eid lliw llA
;elttab gnisol a saw ti wenk tekeM
.etsap eht tuo depoocs dna
.egasiv nedoow s’lalT revo derekcilf semalf fi sa mees ti edam dna
,tnegra fo snoitcennoc ypsiW
,ebirt eht fo tfel saw tahw evas ot troser tsal sih saw egnellahc siht
,ralugna dna llat gnimool
,dehctaw eh sa gnivlossid segde deyarf eht
,llaw s’asem eht gnola gnitnirpS
.htap eht nwod dekool eH
,sehsurb fo tsetniaf eht …litnU
”,em morf llup ,ereH“
,eye s’rU fo ssenthgirb eht dna
.ksud fo hcaorppa eht htiw won eniltuo na tsuj
,tsacnwod seye dna kcab srae ,desuap tekeM
.asem eht fo mir ykcor eht woleb deppid yeht litnu
eltsep gniynapmocca sti
.secnahc sih ssimsid I ylkciuq woH
.deklaw dah täA noitcerid eht ot noitnetta sih denrut hteK dna
,edis eno ot palf tnet eht dehsup hteK .decniw eh dna
”!gninetsil neve ton s’eH
.esahcrup dnuof swap sih erehw dnas otni derettahs dna
.yrrow t’nod ,hteK ,gnihtemos dnif ll’I“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.meht desu eh erofeb sega rof ereh tas evah tsum yeht
.dnas dna doolb htiw ti gniraems ,wap sih fo kcab eht htiw elzzum sih gnipiw
,mih sdrawot htap eht nwod yldeirruhnu deklaw täA .denrut hteK dna
”!täA ekil tsuj era uoY“
.stnet eht sdrawot kcab detrats hteK
?esle gnihtemos ees I oD
,tip erif eht dnuora detaes
,erab dial flesmih tlef eh dna
,hteK morf yawa gninruT
”.thginot rehto hcae ni lever ,sdneirf ruoy yojne
.surtic fo yltniaf gnillems
,teef sih ot tog eH
- irkuk eht ta dekool eH
.sgniht egnahc ot hsiw I .oN ?yaleD“
.rettam ton od ew taht
,won ytpme stnet ynam ooT
.ereht t’nerew taht sdnuos rof deniarts eh sa
,seert detnuts dna selbmarb eht hguorht del taht shtap ydniw railimaf dairym fo eno gnola gnidnuop swap sih
,elib dna dnas dna surtic detimov hteK
,ligiv nwo rieht dleh tiperif llams eht dnuora sdog devrac eerht ehT
”.worromot marA egnellahc ot skees eH
,denruter ytiralc dna
,dehcaorppa eh sa hteK thguoht
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,ecnartne sti ta desuap hteK
.delkcirp thgis sih dna
daerht-tekeM eht was eh
,yltneg dna ylluferac dna
,ereht pu eb dluow setamebirt siH
,eb dluoc lakcaj a lla saw mrof dekan siH .tcefrep saw eH
eht dehctulc eh sa psarg sih morf llef irkuk eht dna
,dehcaorppa ehs sa derumrum hteK ”,anM“
,tas eh redluob a nopU
.erif gnikooc egral eht dnuora derehtag dah ebirt eht fo tser eht erehw ot yaw sih edam eh ,gnihgiS
- desirprus yleritne ton saw eH
.siht ekil tekeM nees reven dah eh
,pu dekcip ezeerb tresed looc ehT
.anM ta pu dekool dna
gnivil a rof semag setaerc ohw flow detniap a ,)unutUgoDdliW@( unutU yb ”retaW“ fo
,seno eulb s’iroaP ot revo dekcilf
,ereht llits erew anM morf gnitaname rewop fo slirdnet ehT
;edirts deirruhnu sti deunitnoc erugif ehT
.su tcetorp lliw tekeM“
noitceffa dna htmraw hcus htiw
,ruf s’lakcaj eht dehcuot spitregnif sih sA
,ereht saw ytisoiruc fo llup eht teY
.nihtiw morf esruc derettu prahs eht ta gnileviws srae lakcaj gnol sih
,thgilnoom diuqil erew seye s’täA
,dnim s’hteK no desserp ylneddus surtiC
.yllufyalp gninnirg
,dednecsed ylkciuq hteK dna
,denway dna denrut eh ,tuo gnihctertS
?gnineppah si tahW .kcarc a reveN
talf a edam saw dnop llams ehT
- noisiv sih no skcirt deyalp
setamebirt sih fo rettahc tnatsid eht erew sdnuos ylno ehT ”?tekeM“
”.lla fo htlaeh eht rof kcis dna kaew eht gniwonniw
.detseggus anM
,ahewB eht fo enO
,detator elzzum sih sa neve ecaf s’hteK nopu dexif deyats rebma gniwolg fo eye siH
,no gnilbmutS .tekeM rebmemeR
,flehs a no kcab sloot drawyaw eht decalp eH
ruf sih ta gnilzzun ezeerb eht
- eloh egnarts a saw tekeM fo ecnesba ehT
”!sdog eht lla ot kool taht
.tnemirrem eurt naht ecnaifed a erom demees thginot gnitsaef eht dna
”?dehsinup gnieb ew erA“
,kool lanif a hteK evag eh doots eh sa dna
.flesmih thgir ot tpmetta niav a gnikam erew eh fi sa syawedis yldrawkwa dehcaer won ,dog niar eht
.ebirt sih ton tub
.ebirt eht fo tser eht tsgnoma degdew riaffa depmarc ,llams a
niaga pu ti dekcip
.evloser htiw denehtgnerts eciov siH ”?reprahs ti ekam“
.sllaw sti ta gnilppir dna gnippans
.kaerb dluow yeht thguoht eh litnu
- gnineve ylrae fo ekops srats ehT
.das yletinifni dna peed dna
.asem eht fo evruc eht dniheb tsol saw noos dna
,deniamer taht ruf etihw fo tfut eht denimaxe hteK
.setamebirt sih fo seciov detum dna
.hcuot sih morf tuo gniretnilps skcarc rehto
,namahs eht ta revo decnalg eH
,worromot egnellahc eht ta em gnitiawa eb lliw marA“
.irkuk sih fo pirg emoclew dna
,thgis fo tuo ,asem eht ot meht evoba detaolf emos
,ecaf sih ni nus a saw eye tfel siH
,hteK hguorht dna otni gnirats
,deniamer taht retaw eht
.deniatnoc ylerab ereht rewop fo revihs a saw ereht tey
,deeps dna htlaets neewteb detcilfnoc
,detargetnisid cirbaf eht dna
,gnitoof gnitfihs ylneddus eht tsniaga flesmih gnicarB
htap eht fo elgna dna ssenkrad ehT
,pu ti dekcip eh dna
,wap s’hteK hguorht deohce tsriht s’täA
irkuk lanoitidart eht fo evruc htooms eht edisa tup dah marA taht nwonk-llew saw tI
.llaw s’asem eht dnuora delcric hteK
*** .renroc dewodahs eht ni elbinrecsid neve regnol on lalT
,tnecs yhtrae ,thgils A
,ecaf sih otni devrac noisufnoc dna esirprus fo kool eht
,ezag sih tem ehS
.ezag sih deppord eh sa kcab denettalf srae sih dna
,yldrawkwa tneb ydob
.tleftraeh saw ti dna
.nwod kcab ratrom eht tes neht
,devom ehs sa ecaf kcor s’asem eht dehsurb wap reH
snevaeh eht ot desiar gnieb fo daetsni
,nur a otni gnignahc klaw sih
.enog dah täA noitcerid eht morf kcor fo evruc eht dnuora yldeirruhnu gniklaw
;delbmurc ti ,htgnel sti gnola llA
,lufituaeb saw ehS
,srats eht tsniaga detteuohlis srae lakcaj owt htiw gnola
.erom ecno hteK ecaf ot kcab gninrut ,dedda eh
.nwo sih morf sehcni elzzum s’renwo sti
.degnahc sah gnihton fi sa si ti dna
,drawpu ylgnieesnu dezag tekeM