,selppin sih gnicreip naidisbo prahs-edalb fo sdiohcnoc eht ffo egnaro yreif detnilg nus gnittes ehT
.ynomerec dna lautir fo ecalp gnirehtag siht ot
,eyE lufhctaw s’rU htaeneB .marA
,neht dna delggurts hteK sa tnemom a rof dehctaw eH
.epacse ot gniyrt ,yldrazahpah ,yletarepsed degnul hteK
.tresed eht revo pirt rieht no tnelis mih tpek dah taht sucof eht niater ot gniyrt
.dleh eh retaw fo sebolg taerg eht nihtiw meht gniwollaws
.mih dnuora retaw eht htiw elgnim ot nwod gnippird doolb
.uoy yortsed lliw I“
,denwad noitazilaer sa
sreej dna sreehc riehT
.hcum oot gnidloh si eh
.kcatta txen s’lakcaj reggib eht degdod ylerab dna
,wap tfel s’eof sih ot txen
!sucof …sdog ho sdog hO
sligis ,devrac yllautir emos ,snoisserped dna
.tsrub ot tuoba mrotsrednuht a ekil ,esimorp htiw thgit
,detapissid niater ot drah os thguof dah eh mlac ehT
.daeh sih depolevne serehps retaw eht fo eno
.lliw sih tsniaga rednerrus llams a
,ecafrus nevenu eht ssorca flesmih dehsup hteK dna
,dah eh lla desucof hteK .marA ,tsriht I
,wena sreggad eci sih demrof marA sa ;lavivrus dna
”,htob su egduj rU tel dnA
,ecnagorra dna ,tnemeticxe
.enots eht fo egde eht raen
,hgiht sih ssorca dehsurb ,dloc ylgnicreip ,ssenprahS
.deklaw ew sa em ot klat ot deirt htotA
.egar ni detsiwt elzzum sih
.wap sih ni edalb degde-laturb sih ,meht dleh dna
,dellup eH .dellup eh oS
.eirever sih morf hteK
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
…ynam os era yehT
,kcab meht dellup marA
.pu ti detfil dna
,gnitiaw tas yehT
kcab sih ta tnecserc llams a ni detaes
derevoh ssenkrad gninruhc a fi sa saw ti dna
.emit on detsaw marA
,deraeppa dah srevils eci eht sa ylkciuq sA
,nettogrof yliratnemom niap siH
,taeh tresed eht ni gnitaews ydaerla tub oga stnemom tsuj demrof
- ti tnes eh ,niagA
.ebirt sih fo stnanmer eht fo ecnalg derrulb feirb a gnihctac ,edis eht ot daeh sih denrut eh dna
.hgih dleh liat sih htiw detturts marA ,kcor eht ssorcA
sevlesmeht tsgnoma gniklat
.did eh ytiralc eht leef ot desirprus ,sdnuow sih fo niap eht edisa tes ot deirt eH
,latem eht ffo gnirettilg thgilnus
,hgih dna drah gnuws eH
- sthguoht sih denrub redluohs tner dna tsirw derettahs eht
– niwt sti rof deraperpnu saw eh teY
,retaw prahs-nus fo stecaf ehT
,spil s’marA devruc elims A .tekeM ,hO
.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,emit eritne eht nwo sih neeb dah sthguoht siH
,enots eht fo egde eht ffo dils wap kcab s’hteK dna
.ymene sih ta pu ecnalg a decnahc hteK dna
.meht ot gnikaeps neeb evah dluohs I
.ydob s’marA ot revo yaw sih edam
,noissimbus rof dnamed eht tsniaga gnilggurtS
.tuc suoiciv a tfel dah nopaew s’marA erehw redluohs sih ni hsag peed eht ta yldezad derats hteK ,dennuts dna enorP
,tnetni htiw divarg
,mih dnuora erehps yretaw eht tpek marA .dleh hteK tub
.desu eb ot deggeb ereht rewop eldi eht dna noitcennoc nwo s’marA otni deppat hteK
,dnas eht otni gnivled
.ylthgit mih degguh retaw eht tub ,edis eht ot elzzum sih dekrej eh ,gnikcinaP
,gnilennahc nwo s’marA fo htgnel eht gnola derucsbo gnidils
slennahc eht dnuof steluvir eht ,tuo gnidaerpS
,htgnerts htiw war dna kciht
.dettirg hteet ,taps marA
,deppid elzzum sih dna
,ereht saw ti tub
.reens tnahpmuirt s’marA fo weiv sih edih ot hguone ton saw retaw eht hguorht noitrotsid eht dna
.lliw sih ot ti tplucs dna dlom dna
.doolb htiw mirb dnuow wen eht tlef eh dna
.dilos dna delcsum ydob sih
,enots eht fo edis sih sdrawot kcab deklaw eh sa derutseg marA
:yojne esaelP   .GNAF noos dna
,hcuorc a ot pu flesmih gnihsuP
tnenoppo sih no ylluf desucof won saw hteK
,dekcinap ,kcab decnalg eH
,rethgit deppirg marA
.ecneserp sih fo ytisnetni eht yb dewob tsomla saw hteK dna ,deraor marA
,kciht a dedurtxe dah eh serehps eht fo eno morF
,enots fo tsaeb cinatit emos erew ti fi sa
,yltfeD ?anM ,os ekiL
nwo sih tem seye krad s’marA
hsals tnalahcnon a yb dereves ylisae eb ot ylno
.erom gnihton ,tuat dna yrd ,ksuh a
.ekaw sti ni stelpord doolb gniliart pit eht
.ydob s’marA morf yawa htgnel s’reksihw a ylerab
ruf sih morf ti gnillup
,kaeps ot denepo swaj sih sa dna
.tpecca I ,eyE lufhctaw s’rU htaeneB
,kcalc elbidua na htiw tuhs deppans swaj s’marA
;hguone dah dah eH
.troffe eht htiw gnidils dna gnihctarcs swalc
,duorp dna hgih elzzum sih gnihsup dna
.devom ton dah marA
,ereh mih thguorb dah stneve fo lrihw eht dna
lortnoc s’marA fo ecrof dna retaw eht fo ssam eht
.ylsseltroffe ereht mih gnidloh
.ni teg ot gniyrt ,dnim sih ta delbbarcs sdnuow sih fo niap eht dna
,marA nopu ezag sih decrof niaga hteK
?ereht uoy era ,rU
,tnatalb ,detaeper eno
– revelc nevorp dah hteK
.sdniw tresed yb debrutsid retaw llits ekil
.gnilwarps mih kconk ot gniripsnoc
.dezilaer hteK erofeb revo saw yenruoj eht dna
,gninraw a demaercs noisiv s’hteK fo yrehpirep eht ni rekcilf a
.ymene sih detiawa
.devlossid noitcennoc s’hteK dna ,pals latnem A
.yawa ti llup ot hguone gnorts ton ma I dna ,lla ti sah eH
knird lliw sdnas ehT
,demrof neht marA taht noitcennoc eht dewohs thgisretaw siH
?rU ,gnihctaw uoy erA
.ti rof flesmih detah hteK dna
,mih ta dehsup ecnanimod dna regna s’marA
.mih desselb sah rU
,rehtael detaroced fo htolcniol a erow eH
.dnuora dna pu dekool hteK dna
.pu kcab elzzum sih tlit ot flesmih decrof eh
.ytniatrecnu fo olomert thgils eht ,gnirevaw eht
,elbmarcs etarepsed a ,yrrap rehtonA
,niap eht tuo tuhs ot detpmetta eh sa snoitaludnu dna selppir eht gniwollof yltnesba seye ,dehctaw hteK
.regna dna stnuat htob ot eciov elirbef gnivig gnidnatsrednu dna noitazilaer
,prahs dna etihw sgnaf
.esnopser lautir eht ekops eh sa
,yrrap detcepxe eht ni detluser selubolg eht fo eno sdrawot hcaer evitatnet A
,noitcennoc rehtona htiw tuo detseuq eh
,seye s’hteK ot sraet thguorb dnas dna dniw toh fo tsug neddus A
”retaW“ fo trap lanif dna dn2 eht si
.htrof dna kcab decap eh sa erats eht gnikaerb ton
.gnirutsop tsuj si tI
.meht demialc marA sa
.rehto hcae tsniaga dleiw ot marA dna mih rof ydaer
,htrof dna kcab edorts marA sa dehctaw dna
,tsirw sih thguac ylpmis lakcaj regnorts ehT
,dehcaer hteK niagA
.edalb sih tsniaga tcapmi gnirraj eht ta mra s’hteK pu tohs niap dna ,kcurts eh niagA
.edis eht ot edalb nwo sih gnissot
,ylneddus drawrof degrus marA .evil lliw ebirt yM
,detlit dna ,pu detfil
,noitidart tsniaga kaerb eht fo
.tsehc sih ot ylleb s’marA pu
,ti dexaoc ,retaw eht dellac dah eh nehw
,kcab deppets ylmlac hteK
?stuc edurc hcus ekam uoy did yhw ,irkuk laitselec ruoy htiw
,setamsebirt dna sdneirf sih ta kcab ecnalg lanif a tnes eH
;hteK detcartsid tnilg A
.yltnereffid depoh dah eh hguoht
.nials ro detagujbus naht rehtar
.enots eht gnola deparcs selkcunk sih sa
,teef sih ot tog ylikahs dna ylwols eH
.elzzum gnitiaw s’hteK ot sdniw eht htiw detfird
.kcolb ot pu irkuk nwo sih gnirb ot od dluoc hteK lla saw ti dna
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.kcor ydnas eht nopu talf flesmih worht ot gninraw hguone tsuj
,sehcnuah sih no nwod dehcuorc ylwols eh sa dehctaw yehT
?etsat I surtic taht sI
,swaj sih ni rae s’ymene daed sih pirg ot drawrof tnael
.dlog yvaeh fo dnab a gnuh rae sih ta dna
.tnelis ,tas sebirt htoB
,swolloh gnitiaw eht otni dewolf dah retaw fo selkcirt tsal ehT
.esirprus yb mih nekat dah lavirra rieht fo ssenneddus eht dna
,irkuk sih dleh eh wap thgir sih ni dna
,kcor kcils-dnas eht no esahcrup rof gnilbbarcs dna syawedis gnignuL
.gnitaludnu dna gnilppir retaw fo erehps a
,ria tuohtiw gnol oot enog dah eH
sa kcor der eht nopu mrif swap sih ,doots eH
,suoregnad gnitoof gnikam ecafrus nevenu eht
niaga tey deffuber eb ot ylno
.erofeb thgin eht
,mih erofeb derevaw egami s’marA .flesruoy mlaC
.ti ta depsarg hteK dna
stelpord llams rehto dairym gninioj
- ereves saw niap ehT
– denetsil yllanif dah ti dna ,ti htiw dedaelp
,retaw ekat ot woh mih wohs dluow tekeM nehw semit eht ot kcab gnikniht
,dnuora dna tuo detseuq thgisretaw s’hteK
rosseccus s’tekeM sA
pil sih delruc regna fo eralf a dna
,flesmih ekil ahewB saw marA
,raeb ot ecnedifnoc sih lla gnilluP
,ti desnednoc dna tnemssarrabme s’hteK fo taeh eht koot yeht
.edih nworb krad fo htolcniol elpmis sih fo tnazingoc yllufniap
,sedalb nezorf fo essenif dna kcilf eht gnidracsiD
,flesmih thgir ot deganam eh
.dereves yletaidemmi
,mih ta hsup ot detrats cinap dna noitarepseD
,hcum thguat neeb dah eh
.serehps eht ot mih gnitcennoc
,derehtag esoht fo seciov deticxe eht fo erawa yleugav saw hteK
sloop wollahs llams lareves otni detcelloc retaw eht lla nooS
hteK .od ot krow llits saw erehT
.nus gnittes eht ni dlog-yddur dna thgirb
,dnas htiw yreppils
.sdniw tresed sseldne eht dna noisore morf demrof ylpmis emos
.sdniw eht otni tuo sdrow nwo sih delruh hteK
,dezeeuqs marA .sebirt derehtag eht fo srumrum niatrecnu eht tsniaga duol kcor tsniaga latem fo gnignir neddus eht
,dluoc eh sa ylmlac sA
.tsap sraey morf thgif deirots a fo otnemem a
,niarts dna yruf fo sutcir a saw elzzum s’marA
,raef htiw dellif seye s’marA
,seye sih dekcirp sraet eroM
ylfeirb daeh sih detfil hteK
,uoy egnellahc ,hteK ,I“
ecaf sih ni esir taeh eht tlef eh tub
.edis eno ot flesmih gnulf eh dna
,tlusni raelc nevig dah hteK
,yldliw edalb sih gnigniws
”,eciohc ruoy tpecca ,hteK
.sdnas eht hguorht ekorb ylerab kcab depols sti taht peed os deirub
,doolb deird fo nworb-der krad eht roloc sti
,sloop rehto eht rof dehcterts hteK
– noos revo eb dluow ti wenk eH
.dedragersid tub lla won sdrow lautir eht
.sebirt htob hguorht delppir noitaralced ehT ”.retaW“
,kram rieht tfel dah
irkuk sih dnuora thgit llits pirg sih
”,esufer I“ ”—b llahs retaW“
.tfel marA on saw erehT
,wols oot si eH .ydaer saw hteK
tug sih ni gniwang eht
tresed eht morf pu detserc
.wollof ot meht gnuws marA sa yltnetni dehctaw dna
,neht doots hteK .deppir dna
slwob wollahs dna ,sevoorg
.won detcepxe saw ti
,stip htiw ecafrus sti detaroced gnivah noisore fo seirutnec eht
,flesmih tekeM sa gnorts sa ton ylniatrec
ti derutcip dah hteK sa yltcaxe cra suoiciv sti
,yletarepsed gninnacs llitS
.evloser s’hteK denehtgnerts noivilbo erofeb stnemom tub gnivah fo noitarepsed eht tub ,mih gninword
.klofsebirt derehtag eht tsgnoma thgil-rehtaef gnihcuot ,ria eht gnitset
.htgnerts htiw dereviuq dna demmurht noitcennoc sih dna
,mih thguat dah tekeM sa
,enots eht ssorca delwarps dial hteK
,nellaf dah ti erehw morf dna
.rehcaet sih neve desirprus taht syaw ni
,I“ .doots eh ,ylwolS
.egar s’marA htiw gniredduhs retaw fo serehps yvaeh eht
.hteK enorp eht gnissim ylerab ,ria eht hguorht gnuws ti ,esicerpmi dna suohpromA
,tnadrocsid dna reduol werg sgnirettum fo surrusus ehT
.noisiv s’hteK ni ssensuoicsnocnu tnenimmi fo stops kcalb elatllet eht htiw derraw thgilnus detcelfer fo skcirpnip thgirB
,ylthgils delbmuts eH
.hteK ,egnellahc ruoy tpecca ,marA ,I“
?ereh gniod I ma tahW
gniddib sih ot retaw ecrof ot elba tey
,ereh detartnecnoc saw llA .gnihtoN
.stelpord – neht tuB
.yruf redloc a otni ti denethgit
,htrof dellew doolB
;ereht deredloms yruF
.lufniadsid ylsuorougnal
erehps rehto eht sdrawot ylsselepoh gnihcaer
irkuk s’hteK fo pit ehT
dnas hcum os ekil pu dekcip
,ecnavda ot deunitnoc marA .tekeM dnA
,edis eht ot niaga degdod hteK .htrof gnarps
,yawa sedirts ytnewt spahrep
.secalp tseddo eht ni retaw dnif dluoc I dias syawla tekeM
.rehtegot dnirg tsirw sih ni senob eht tlef eh sa repmihw yratnulovni na dedleiy hteK dna
.redluohs derujninu sih htiw pu flesmih gnihsup
.tsif sih htiw elzzum eht fo edis eht ssorca mih dehsams
,pu daeh sih detfil eh dna
.mlac tnedifnoc s’marA ni detnalp dah eh sbrab eht ta llirht eht yb derepmet
.dedeen saw tnief a ,noitcartsid a tub ;demrof aedi nA
.tnemele eht fo erom gnidnammoc dna troppar sih gninehtgnerts ot
!ha …ecruos a deen I
.dnim ot noitcefrep s’rU thguorb mrof s’marA
.swap rieht ni yvaeh sreddalb dna sniks gniknird
.pirg lufrewop s’marA ni ria eht ni yvaeh gnuh lla ti dna ,thguof yeht hcihw no enots fo telbat derehtaew eht no
rehto eht ,lliw s’marA fo
.seye s’marA nopu dekcol deniamer sucof sih lla tub
,gniht eltbus ,eligarf
,taeH ni deraeppa sah krow dehsilbup siH
.nus gnittes eht fo egnaro eht detcelfer naidisbo fo drahs a
.enots eht fo sloop wollahs eht otni kcab ti dexaoc dna
.swap s’lakcaj rellams eht ot txen kcor eht no detaniru dna
,tniopretnuoc ni sdnarts eht gnitalupinam
,wap rehto sih htiw
,tnecs sih fo gnat prahs ehT
sloop tsesolc eht ni retaw eht lla deldarc eh sa ,rewop htiw gnislup dna gniwolg yltniaf
.llew sa msinogatna dna ytniatrecnu fo tnecs ylkcirp eht saw ereht tub
,noonretfa saw ti woN
,teiuq ylegnarts saw llA
,dekrow yltbus shpylg dna
.yks eht ni rewol tperc nus ehT
,htolcniol sih pu detfil dna revo deklaw dah ,elihwnaem ,marA
- detaccised ereht yal tI
.won ti esnes dluow marA
,noisicerp gninodnabA
,diov eht llif ot ni dedoolf ssenevissimbus dna cinap
.tnenoppo sih tsniaga raeb ot ti gnirb ot
,ezag sih gniteeM
,hteK no seye sih dekcol eh sa drawrof dekrep erew srae sih dna
.rewop s’marA ot delkcahs ,ereht gnitaolf
– noitcennoc eht edam eH
,dereppotsnu yeht esehT
.dnas eht otni peed
.htaeneb ruf eht morf ereht gniraeppa
dnim s’hteK ta dekcirp raef teY .ti erongI
,marA detpurretni
.wef os era ew dna
taeh fo hsulf eht tlef hteK
,ylthgils detrap saw elzzum siH
?anM ,woH .liava on ot
.ylreporp enod eb ot dah lautir eht tub
.mih rof kaeps setamebirt detairufni sih fo seirc detlusni eht tel hteK
.rettam ton did taht tub
.sgel sih neewteb dna dnuora evow dnas fo slriws
noisufnoc ot denrut reens ehT
,enots eht fo der detum eht tsniaga nosmirc tnarbiv
,eciov evag sebirt sih sa llat dna thgiarts
,esir ot delggurts hteK ,gnipsag ,dennutS
,ti psarg ot htrof ylkciuq gnikans noitcennoc sih
”,uoy llik tsuj ton lliw I“
,rehto eht ot wap eno morf thgiew sih detfihs hteK
.noitazilaer neht dna
,meht gnidiova ylisae
.marA gniypucco saw tI
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,unutU yb ”retaW“
.emit eraps sih ni gnitirw dna gnidliubdlrow syojne tub
.elzzum sih depahs lrans a sa
.ssenkrad dna nori gnitsat
,elbaplap ecnedifnoc sih
.dnas eht no mih dniheb delwarps srewollof ynam sih detrohxe eh sa
.sdniw eht fo smihw eht yb htooms debbur
.sselerutaef morf raf saw kcor ehT
,marA ta pu gnicnalG
.ylkciuq dnuorg evig ot decrof saw hteK
,detcepxe saw tI ”.edalB“
gnivil a rof semag setaerc ohw flow detniap a ,)unutUgoDdliW@( unutU yb
.ecrof eturb ot detroser dah marA
.enots fo telbat talf eht ssorca derettiks taht slrohw detaerc sdniw tresed gnitfihs-reve eht morf demrof sryhpez llamS
,ria fo splug ni gnivaeh ,gniredduhS
,tlih sti dnuora ylthgit wap sih gnihcnelc
.tnenoppo rethgils sih revo ezag derob a dekcilf dna
,yllamrof dias eh
.yldnilb tuo gnihsals ,marA drawot tpael eh neht dna
.yalpsid gnikcom s’marA sdrawot kcab denrut eh dna
!gnihtemos deen I
.ymene sih teem ot drawrof detrats neht
.mih ta hsal ot kcab devruc ti sa degdod hteK
,tnedifnoc dna gnorts ecaf lakcaj sih
.mih htiw seye gnikcol
,traeh s’hteK ni truh eht ot etsat rettib a dedda nrocs s’tnenoppo siH
,yb deps sruoh ehT
,retaw eht rof gnileef
,drah-dnomaid dna nezorf
,ecnadiug s’marA ta
mlac nommus ot gnilggurts
– ssenevissimsid sih ,niadsid sih ,ssenderussa siH
,drawtuo gnilppir
,tresed gnivigrofnu eht ni efil fo ecruos tnatropmi-reve taht
fo strap 2 fo dn2 eht eht saw sihT
.retaw fo tfahs gnitaludnu
.regna sih nwod pmat ot delggurts marA sa ylmlac dehctaw eh dna
.dnas ytsriht eht ot gnillaf stelpord
,sebolg lacitnedi tsomla owt erew ereht nooS
?nopaew fo eciohc nwo ym htiw em gnillik yb em etailimuh ,hA
,yawa dellup yeht
.meht rof taht oD .llew eid tsuJ
.yruf dna ytisnetni ni gniredduhs htaerb sih ,ni denael marA
,tsurt dna troppus fo sllac htiw mih sdrawot denrut secaf
,delbmuts hteK dna ,kcurts eh niagA
,redduhs hteK edam raef fo nossirf A
tsehc sih gnitaeb
,taefed dna cinap dna noitarepsed fo gnitsat ,suoivbo
,niadsid htiw taps marA ,gninethgiartS
;raelc llits saw thgisretaw sih teY .detrotsid
,mih ot retaw eht derehtag eh oS
,rU ,em depahs uoy nehW
.nirg gnitnap a ni gnillol eugnot sih ,dekrims hteK
tsirw s’hteK ni gnihtemos dna
”.doolb s’ebirt ruoy
,tsehc eht ni ylivaeh mih thguac ti
yrots s’yadoT dna
doolb fo elkcirt eht gniwollof
.oot em desselb dah rU taht dluoW
.deworran seye sih dna
,sreehc derettacs ’srotatceps eht tuo gninword tuohs sseldrow sih
sdnas hsrah fo sedit eht fo wolf dna bbe ehT
stsif dehcnelc sih dexaler hteK .mlac yatS
.ebirt rehto eht morf seirc gnikcom eht ta
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,gnislup lortnoc s’marA fo senil eht ees dluoc eh
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,lrans flesmih tlef hteK ,yldehcateD
,enots eht ssorcA
,erehps rehto eht fo tuo dehsup
?gnihtyna od ot desoppus I ma woH .gnorts os si eH
,emos gnoma yoj tnecs dluoc eH
,hteK no dekcol ezag sih
deraelc ylneddus ,niap htiw yzzuf ,dnim siH ?rU
,redluohs sih etib gnihtemos tlef eH
.tnenoppo sih fo kcots koot dna
,neddih ,teiuq dna niht
,mih teem ot teef sih ot tpael hteK dna
.yltrohs mih nopu eb dluow marA taht niatrec
.kcor der eht no hsalps ot htrof dehsug retaw fo smaerts eht dna
yaw s’marA nworht brab rehtona
,kcor eht no esahcrup dnif ot detpmetta swap sih sa gnirettiks swalc ,gnilbmarcS
,hteet sih morf yvaeh gnuh gnirrae s’marA dna
.dias eh tahw rebmemer neve t’nod I
,gnicselaoc ,gniloop ,gnilkcirT
,lliw sih htiw ti ta yllacitoahc gnihsals ,daerht eht ta derettab eh dna
,devlossid sdrahs eht dna
,llew eid ot saw won dah eh lortnoc ylno eht
,ecaf s’marA fo ecafrus eht htaeneb tsuj
*** .kcalb werg dlrow eht dna
,ecnedifnoc fo erutxim a
,ereht derevoh tI
:owt eht neewteb dnim sih gnidivid
”?egnellahc ruoy kcab uoy llahs woH“
dellup ebirt nwo sih fo selzzum eht morf yruf gnirewsna eht dna noisired fo seirC
.wohs ot seihport on dah eh
,tsehc sih ssorca racs gnol a yb ylno derram erew ruf sih fo segieb dna syarg ehT
,edis eht ot gnilwarps mih dekconk wolb eht dna ,hself dna ruf tuo gnippir ,gniraet
,sloop tsesolc eht no gnisucof
,flesmih ta nwod decnalg hteK
,erom ecno devlossid psarg sih dna ecils A
,gniht yvaeh a eciov sih ,derepsihw eh
- ypoc detrotsid a tsuj ma I ,I elihW
,laerehte enil kciht eht
,irkuk sih gnippirG
,elzzum s’marA no demrof retaw fo sdaeb yniT
,cigam eht gnidaerht ni seiteltbus eht morf
.srae sih ni gnignir ebirt s’marA fo sreej eht
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,suorednop tsomla erew stsurht riehT
,emit tsrif taht fo llirht ehT
,ebirt nwo s’hteK morf esoht tuo denword
,ria eht ni dednepsus gnignah
,ronoh htiw nwo s’marA nihtiw demusbus eb dluow ebirt sih taht os
,tuo anm-a sih dehcaer hteK
thgirtuo mih gnignellahc dna sdrow tsrif s’lautir eht mih gniyned yb
,noitarepsed eht raeh dluoc hteK tub
,tnetni fo espmilg a mih evag tI
.won em llik ,daeha oG .uoy dekraM
,ynohpocac eht dima tuo gnar eciov s’htotA
,drawrof deppets setamebirt sih fo rebmun a dna
,eci fo sdrahs gnitnilG
;mih detaroced stnemnroda oN
.sebirt derehtag eht ot ezag sih denrut hteK
,sgnicreip s’marA fo eno yawa decils dah
,dnarts gnitset dna evitatnet rehtona tuo tnes eH
.mih revo dehsaw emahs sa
.ecafrus eht ssorca
.htgnerts s’marA yb dehsad yletaidemmi
.hguone saw taht dnA
)2 fo 2 traP( unutU yb ”retaW“
.uoy tiab ot siht seod eH
,ecnesba sti htiW .derettacs dna
,lirdnet lufepoh rehtona htrof tnes hteK
,enots eht ot derettalc irkuk sih sa yrc a evag eh – yaw evag
,rednels a saw ti
– irkuk eht htiw lliks s’marA rof hctam on saw eh
,secruos rehto rof ybraen gnihcraes yllacitnarF
.llup ot detrats hteK dna
ecaf kcor derracs ehT
.dekaos ruf sih
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht
”.htob su egduj rU tel dnA .uoy egnellahc I
.reve sa gnorts sa saw yromem eht
.detacav dah hteK ecaps eht hguorht tsurht
,sa detcarfer dna derrulb noisiv sih ;wols oot saw eH
.thgisretaw sih fo weiv fo tuo