.remrahC eniuqE eht
nwaD eht fo thgiL ehT nI ni
dias saw meiuqer a dna
:daetsni ereht yretsym a tfel
,nepo gnidnats saw evarg ehT  .daed t'nia eH
...delf ylluf si efil nehw nam a sevom taht si ti tahw dnA
,spahrep ,noitaripsa na
,foohnorI mok’aT yb daeR
,daeh sih nopu semirc on ,tneconni saw eh wenk lla ew dnA
.erats ot emac erom hcnub a dna
:nedraG eht ni eniledaM ekil tsuJ
sa 'suoyoj' hcum os t'nerew ytrap larenuf eht tuB
,floWcaM boR yb meop a tneserp ew thginoT
,rewsna on evig t'ndid eH .tsewhtron-tsew ro
.delecnac s'larenuf eht diarfA"
.delecnac saw larenuf ehT
thguoht gnitrofmoc a eb ot esaec yam
?erow surazaL .tS duorhs eht fo sciler eht niater llits yeht
desaeced eht rof sreyarp dna yteip rof dellac rehcaerp eht lleW
,deludehcs saw larenuf eht roF
,gninnur emac reggidevarg eht lliT
.dias enoemos sa ",ton em hcuoT"
,daert ot raef sluos evil erehw tnew
.detcepxe evah ew sa
,gnisselb ro esruc a s'ti rehtehW
.eye reh ni erif a htiw
.suoiruf s'rekatrednu eht woN  ".daed t'nia eH
,ytpme yleritne htob tuB
t'nia I .larenuf ym lecnac og uoy woN
",tnemom a ref ,mih was I"  .daed tnia eH
enog evah ton tsum ,ssecorp taht ni ,gnihtemos tsixe ot gniht a hcus rof redro ni
,denrut rekatrednu eht nehT
”noitallecnaC larenuF a fo uoY mrofnI ot tergeR eW“ saw sihT     .daed
t'noD .erofeb gniht fo tros siht fo seirots fo draeh ev'uoy sseug I lleW  ".daed t'nia eH
.tsud eht ni ,swollag eht no ,mih was I tsal rebmemer I
ediseb ereht teksac eht
.tey tsuj daed eb ot mees t’nseod ohw
.yrc thgim eh ekil skool rehcaerP
dias eb yam emas ehT
,woh mih ksa ot erus eb ll'I mih ees I nehw esimorp I
.delecnac slarenuf rieht dah yehT
,niffoc eht fo tuo debmilc ev'tsuM
,enotsevarg a ekil ,daed eht
.delecnac saw larenuf ehT
.daeh sih koohs dna denrut tsuj eh
teksac tnuocsid a thguob yehT
.ereht gniyl mih tfel d'ohw
,rof derac erew yeht taht noitressa na ,detraped eht fo yromem eht ot tnemunom a sa
.daed saw eh erus edam ew oS
,tsew nikam ,spotllih eht drawot gnidirts-A" dessefnoc reggidevarg eht
floWcaM boR yb meop a ,”noitallecnaC larenuF a fo
:gnilttesnu si enotsevarg suomynona nA .noitcerruser
.yrellag yrruFoS sih ta ro
.drayevarg eht ot deirruh ew lleW  ".daed t'nia eH
:trofmoc a eb yam enotsevarg A
uoY mrofnI ot tergeR eW“   yojne esaelP
.goD fo ecioV ehT no goD fo tsohG ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.tseirp eht tpurretni ot rof
.delecnac s'larenuf eht wenk I nehw'S
,daerps sah su ot htaed sih taht
.won mih dnif og ll'I ebyaM
.evarg ytpme na fo
og ot sesaec ti nehw
ro lanrete efil fo rennam emos ot
.daerd eht yawa yarp ot deirt dna yaw eht del rehcaerp ehT '.desufnoc'
.tsum ew sgniht eht od ew erehw
.erehwemos ereht tuo s'eh esoppus I
dias eh dna ,sehsa lla ecaf sih
fo noitcerruseR
eht ,foohnorI mok’aT yb uoy rof daer ,floWcaM boR yb
,dias ehs drow a ton dna ,yawa deklaw dna liev reh deppord s'ehS
.daed eht gniyrub rof
.ydaer saw larenuf sih tuB
:suehprO s'ereht dna ,redlaB s'erehT
,nesir s'namow-wodiw eht tuB
.delecnac s'larenuf ,emoh oG" tuB
,yteicoS noitciF lacirotsiH yrruF eht yb
,derehtag srenruom elpuoc a lleW
.daed t'nerew yehT
,emac srellik lausac eht lla esruoC
.edisni gniht elgnis a ton
krow sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
sdaorssorc eht no saw mlac A
.swen suoyoj ylbaborp saw sihT
.ot desoppus saw ti sa