”?taht naht erom oN“
,rallip tnereffid a dniheb morf tuo deppets eH
ecaf yhs a delaecnoc riah ygnirts ,gnoL
.deddon tnarraT ”?dnatsrednu uoy oD
.thgil ylno rieht saw erif eht dna ,tes dah nus eht
,noitnetta s’enoyreve rof gnimaercs gnisitrevda ,erehwyreve sthgil gnihsalf
.retlehs regaem edivorp ot doots llits hguone tub
.su ot dnik erew snamuh eht ,tsael ta ,ereh dnuorA“ .dias eh
,prahs dna suonimul demees stniap rieht ,thgilerif eht nI
.yratnulov ylluf eb ot sah tI
.og uoy tel ot evah I
,enilpicsid tuohtiW
,renniht tib a daerb levart eht ecils ot evah d’eh
,thgilerif eht ni gninetsilg kaolc tew
.degludni snoisseforp dna seibboh rieht dna tem era sdeen rieht erehw ,segalliv eht edistuo meht ees netfo t’nseod enO
.tseug ruo er’uoY“ .dias eh
.tnarraT dias ”,ris ,seY“
.rallip eht dniheb llits ,remuR dias ”,tnecrep enin-yteniN“
”.thgin eht rof pu em tup lliw ebirT a semitemoS
,rehtaeF kwaH dias
.nwod remuR wols dluoc gnihton
.gnirob dna talf s’tI“
.rehtaew eht gnitciderp ekil s’tI
ma I“ .etunim yna ti rof hsad a ekam dluow tnarraT taht 05-05 tuoba derugif remuR - gniht esolc a saw ti tub ,nur t’ndid eH
”.tib a ffo yrd ,ecalp a ekat ot emoclew er’uoY .mraw
llits s’erif eht tub ,enog s’doof eht lla diarfa m’I“
.kool lufemahs s’tnarraT thguac eH .remuR derettum
,ereh yats uoy fI
,emit gnol a gninnur neeb d’eh
.noisserpxe sih derucsbo riah ygnirts siH
.luaP dias ”,mih dnim t’noD“ .depmuj tnarraT
eht dna ,yks eht ni serif erew erehT
noisseforp a hcus retne ohw elpoep taht neeb sah ,revewoh ,ecneirepxe yM
”.sniur eht ni deid yeht semitemoS
;noitsuahxe sih dezingocer remuR
.luaP dias ”,snoitatcepxe esoht gniganam peeK“
.nac I nehw ,egnevacs I“
”,puos eht ni tol uoy tup nac diarb eht nopu gnirif tuoba gniklat neve
”?yks egnaro eht rebmemer uoy oD“
.rallip a dniheb flesmih gnilaecnoc dna teef sih ot gnirebmalc
.diarb eht ta erif ot gniog ton er’yehT
.denrecnoc dekool llits remuR
”.noitcetorp ym rednu saw eh taht draeh uoy esoppus I“
.remuR dias ”,ereh m’I wonk uoy tub
.gnirps ot gniraperp saw eh fi sa pu dehcnub gel sih ni selcsuM
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,ssendam lufrednow a hcus saw ti
.egalliv ruo rof tuo tes ot gniog er’ew ,tser s’thgin doog a dah ev’ew retfa ,tcaf nI“
”.kcirt taht sevol eH“
.reppus rieht depperp eh elihw regnarts eht ta ecnalg a deraps luaP
.niar eht revo draeh eb ot hguone ylduol trap siht ekops eH
”.won uoy stcetorp ylerab tI“ .dias eh
sbals etercnoc tsaV
.tlef ti woh s’taht tsael tA
.enimrE eht ta decnalg luaP
,hguorht dekaos nehw neve doog kool ot hguone emosdnah saw remuR
.tey yrd t’nsaw ruf siH
,etavele dluohs noisseforp ehT
”?uoy ot ti evig ebirt ruoy did ro eman ylimaf a taht sI
”.gnola semoc retteb gnihtemos litnu teef ruoy rednu dnuorg eht teg ot yaw doog a eb nac ti ,lles ot esle gnihton ev’uoy fI
.yllacitirc stnetnoc eht gnidrager
.snoitrop eerht otni doof rieht dedivid-er eH
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
”.era sregnevacs woh wonk uoY
- siht ot tcaer t’ndid tnarraT
.emas eht od ot enimrE eht gnigru dna nwod gnittis ,remuR dias ”,otatop eht no sbiD“
,ssendnik wohs ot ytinutroppo na neviG
”.efas“ naem t’ndid ”deifirret“ tub
.ecnetnes ssap dluoc ew erofeb ytivitpac depacse ohw feiht a s’eH“
.maj dna daerb levart eht ffo dehsinif flesmih eh elihw
,enam yarg thgiarts siH
”?ebyam ,oihO sa raf sA
”espylacopA eht fo slesaeW“
.remuR dias ”,yllis eb t’noD“
.ton ro yrd erew yeht rehtehw derettam yldrah ti taht
”,esuoheraw eht ni swap fo riap artxe na esu dluoc ew swonk doG“
”,uoy fo lla teem dluoc ew os ,did eh dalg m’I ,lleW“
.remuR dias ”,tsael ta ,awoI ,hO“
.niar eht otni tuo dellorts eH
,hO“ ”.ylknarf ,noitarenev erom tib a dnats dluoc I hguohT“ .luaP dias
.snopaew rieht werd dna
.selppa devreserp wef a dna hciwdnas eseehc a naht eulav erom raf evah uoy ,sulP
,thgil eht ot pu meht gnidloh dna kcap doof rieht morf sraj gnillup saw terreF ehT .dias eh
.enasni erew uoy thguoht evah dluow
.luaP dias ”,evol ym ,llew os etarenev uoy esuaceb s’tahT“
.luaP detsisni ”,tnecrep evif-yteniN“
uoy naC“ ”.deksa m’I nehw esivda dna
.yawyna tiforp a ni gnirb ot deganam yllausu remuR tub
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
htolc a ni wap sih depparw eH
.gnihton ,eugalp taerg on ,retsasid lacigoloce on ,sraw yreif oN
”.kniht I ,xis ,hO“ .luaP dias
”,uoy tcetorp ot gniog syawla ton s’tahT“
.dessarrabme ylneddus demees tnarraT ”…hu ,I .hO“ ”?yb
.rof gnikool eb thgim redliub ro redart a tahw yltcaxe saw gab taht ni erehwemoS
.fo draehnu ton s’ti tuB
.tnarraT ot evag eh hcihw
.neetnac a morf retaw knard eH
”,ereht tuo llits s’eH“
.lufthguoht dekool luaP ”?ekil ti saw tahW“
”,yaw regnevacs eht ton s’tahT“ .dehgis remuR dna
.srae sih dekcilf remuR ”.yb teg I“
,retlehs ruo gnidnuorrus ssaP sugamacnaK morf setoyoC xis era ereht won thgir tuB“
.liat sih gnola lla wolg tnecsediri na gnitsac dna
.rehtaeF kwaH dias ”,laicos eb ot ereh ton er’eW“
”,snamuh fo lluf erew seitic eseht nehw rebmemer uoy oS“
.nomannic fo llems eht htiw retlehs eht gnillif
,niaga retlehs rieht gnihcaorppa saw remuR
- saw ti thguoht eh sa regaem sa t’nsaw tI
.gnihtyreve wonk uoy ekil dnuos ot ysae yllaer s’ti
.luaP dias ”,gninevE“
.su htiw dehctaw yeht semitemoS
,werg ecno nroc erehw sessarg gnivaw fo selim dna seliM
”.pu hctac ot su rof hguone gnol deppots s’eh emit tsrif eht si sihT
.rehtaeF kwaH dias
evag…tsuj yeht ekil s’tI
,ygolohcysp tnecrep ytenin
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,ti fo flah yfitnedi t’ndluoc luaP
.tseb ta troffe nekot a neeb dah sgninraw s’luaP
ekil si tehporp a gnieB“
.esnefed naht deeps rof detius erom
”.llef ecnelis eht erofeb sraey ytnewt tuoba rof elbirret erew sgniht dnatsrednu I
.daerb hguot dewehc luaP
”,dedeen si ydob mraw sih erehw sdleif eht s’ti kniht t’nod I“
.seilppus rieht gnitidua deunitnoc luaP
”.ffo seog ti erofeb ti tae dluohs eW
deb ot uoy ekat od ohw esohT
.tar denword a fo ecnaraeppa tcnitsid eht dah
,erif eht dekots remuR
tnarraT ”.tuo ti klat nac ew
.deggurhs eH ”…fo tros…tsuj I“
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
,snug deirrac yehT
.revo lla gnikahs saw
”.srerutnevda rof moor sah syawla eh syas eH
.thgiew sih ti evag eh nehw edolpxe dluow etercnoc eht taht diarfa fi sa os did enimrE ehT
.rallip eht tsniaga kcab denael dna
,esolc teg uoy sa noos sa uoy bats ylbaborP“
.denil dna esool saw ecaf sih no niks eht dna
,lwob a otni nomannic dna selppa toh depoocs dna
.ti otni debbur emirg eht rof esrow eht lla dekool ruf etihw sih dna
,stunaep fo gab egral a dna
.ereh m’I wonk uoy tuB“ .tnarraT dias ”,on
,dlrow eht revo llA
.diarb sih pu dleh remuR
.tnarraT dias ”,yrd dnA
”.noitavresbo yna tuohtiw ereh m’I taht gniwonk eb dluow ycehporP
,wonk uoY“ .derepmihw
”.thgin saw ti erehw neve
,eye eulb lufelab elgnis a rof tpecxe
,remuR ta decnalg luaP ”?ysehporp
,steerts eht gnola gniwolf srac fo sreviR .thgin dna yad
”,dehsinupnu og emirc sih tel t’nac eW“ .luaP dias
.noitseuq a ton ,tnemetats a saw tI
”,reve gniht tseb eht…saw tI“
”?dneirf wen ruo rof ykrej tar fo pirts a dna daerb elats fo tsurc a eraps dluoc ew enigami uoy oD“
”.htraE eht tirehni ot tuoba erew yeht ecnis
”.gninialpmoc uoy raeh t’ndiD
.parcs fo ytitnauq evissam a rehtag ot deganam dah remuR
.eekuasepenniW fo redrO eht fo namahS a
.evitcaer dna lamirp erew won leef dluoc eh snoitome ylno eht dna
.sniur eht ni sdoog dennac fo stol llits era
.meht dednuorrus taht niur detatsaved fo selim erauqs derdnuh eht ta yllareneg fo tros wap sih devaw eH
.eman fo tros gnitseretnI“
.selppa eht dehsinif luaP
.evol ,lavivrus ni ecargsid on s’erehT“
,stessa sih derevoc ylerab erow eh gar eht
”.elbailer taht lla ton s’tI
,eekuasepenniW eht ot secnatsmucric ruo laeppa yam eW
.niaga deddon tnarraT .ecneliS
,thgilerif eht fo egde eht ta doots taotS ehT  2 fo 1 traP
.ti was enoyreve tub ,uoy dnim ,neht yob a saw I
.niaga denethgit dah ecaf esohw
.selppa eht gnirrits ,luaP dias ”,seY“ ”.ebyaM“
”.elpoep ruo gnoma uoy rof ecalp a dnif nac ew erus m’I
.edaced a rof etihw neeb dah taht riah fo enam yggahs a dna
.remuR dias ”,ydeepS ,nwod wolS“
,saw lesaew a sa ehtiL
srewot gnirettilg tsav htiw seitic lufituaeb ,gniknits ,gninetsilg ,gniltsuB
.erehwon ot syawhgih dekcarc ,gnol
ruf yarg sih tuohguorht skaerts thgil htiw ,remuR naht redlo hcum saw eH
.retal emac seitic eht fo llaf eht tub ,yks egnaro eht retfa sraey thgie nrob saw I“ .remuR dias
.thgilerif eht otni enimrE godgnah eht gnirehsu
.dereweks ti gnitae dna efink a htiw etalp a ot ti gninnip erofeb
”.ti sdeen eh sa gnol os rof
.dah yeht dezilaer reven yeht htgnerts a dnuof elpoep ruO
.gnimaercs dna gnitaews ,thgin ta em detsuor
”,taht htiw gnorw gnihton s’ereht ,lleW“
.dias eh ”,llew ytterp eganam nac ew kniht I“
,eno on tub ,llaf dna esir sgnidliub
”?yako eb ll’ew erus uoY“
.detarenev era ylredle eht ,elpoep ym gnomA“
- gninihs dna kcils erew seidob riehT
,esruoc fO“ .remuR dedecnoc ”,thgie-yteniN“
.elkna s’tnarraT no depmalc deniamer wap sih tub ,redluohs sih detacolsid ylraen dah tnarraT
.tset fo dnik emos dessap d’ew ekil tlef ti dias eh nehw ti ot wap a tup yllaer eh…rehtaf yM
”.nepo seye ruoy peek t’nod uoy fi gnihtyna htrow si ycehporp on
snoitacilbuP laoG rof ”alekA“ etorw ohw ,egdirdooG neB yb
.remuR dias ”,tset a saw ti dias rehtaf ruoY“
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,egdirdooG neB yb
,egdirdooG neB yb
deggar dna ytrid os erew sehtolc nenil siH
.meht dloh t’ndid tub
”.dlo yrev mees od I
.dniw eht fo tsrow eht dekcolb
.remuR detsisni ”,ebyaM“
,lleW“ ”?em ees uoy naC“
”.diarb eht evah uoY“ .tnarraT dias
.deworruf worb s’remuR .dias eh
.tehporP a dna namahS a m’I“
retsloh sih gnippansnu
.selppa dennit fo raj lluf a dna ,maj fo tib a
,ereh rentrap ym ekil regnevacs a yltsom m’I .ma I“
,em ees t’nac uoY“ ”.uoy raeh nac I
”.eerht rof doof hguone s’erehT“
wap ot wap morf sih dessot remuR elihw
,remuR dias ”,ereh s’ynapmoc
.ereh dnuora hcum enod ton s’tI“
,secnalg degnahcxe remuR dna luaP
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,dliuber tsuj dluow snamuh taht eb ot desU
,ecno ta noitcerid yreve ni ees ot gniyrt ,dnuora deppihw eH .depmuj tnarraT
,ylluferac remuR dias ”,lleW“
.hguorht gnikael tnecca nretsew sih ,tnarraT dias
”.ykcip s’eh tbuod yllaer I
”?uoy did ,laem a rof flesruoy edart ot ereh ni emoc t’ndid uoY“
.slliks emos uoy hcaet dna no uoy ekat ot gnilliw eb dluohs enoemos ,ebirT on evah uoy fi ,llitS“
”.lla su llik ll’yehT
.keew a rof yrd deyats wohemos dah taht etalocohc nekorb dna ,snisiar
,stnorf owt no raw a thgif eW
.rehtob t’ndid yeht won tub
”.snug evah yeht dna
”.niaga rehtegot kcab em tup yehT
,sniur ni eil dluow seitic tnecifingam esoht lla sraey ytfif nihtiw taht em dlo-raey-net dlot dah uoy fI
.dednetni d’eh sa ,etalocohc eht fo erahs s’noil eht flesmih evig ot gniliaf
sretsloh rieht deppansnu setoyoC eht ,eno yb enO
.tser on meht evag niar eht
.luaP dias ”,eman a evah uoy taht dnuora gniog romur siht s’ereht oS“
,eseehc prahs llits saw ereht tub
,mrots eht dnoyeb erehwemoS
.timmoc ot dekil reven remuR
- thgir saw remuR
”…detciderp ,snamahS ruo neve ton
”?ni uoy ekat t’nod yeht dnA“
.ssenkrad eht morf degreme setoyoC eht noos dna
,won ksa ot snamuh wef suoicerp era ereht tub
”,lamron s’ti ,ereht pu worg uoy fi esoppus I ,lleW“
”,htiaf elttil a evaH“
,llef snamuh eht yhw nrael ot
.sdrawretfa rethgirb hcum os demees gnihtyrevE“ .dias eh
.niar gnivird eht otni tuo gnizag
,erahs sih deruoved tnarraT ,detcepxe sA
”,yob elttil a saw I nehw ti fo emos rebmemer I“
.os hcum yrev ,hO“ .tnarraT dias
.]dauqs gnirif yb htaed fo tuo
”.gniklat ton er’yeht dna
tnarraT ”.ton ro mih tcetorp uoy rehtehw mih llik lliw tellub A“
.tpmeknu dna ybburg mih gnivael ,sniur eht gniruocs keew a tneps d’yeht tub
.enimrE eht detrulb ”,dlo yrev er’uoY“
.snoitcasnart rof seidob ruo gnisu ekil t’nod sebirT ruO
.noitcetorp ym rednu eb ll’uoy ,taht retfA
ylleb sih fo evruc eltneg eht ot gnignilc ruf yssolg sih
,oot ,gniht doog nmaD
?dnatsrednu uoy oD .uoy ot noitcetorp ym dnetxe I nehw gel ruoy gnihctulc eb t’nac I tuB
,eid dna evil elpoeP
.elpoep ruo rof semit evarg era esehT“
uoy ot tfig ruo eb ytilatipsoh ruo teL“
.tsew eht ot levart ot detnaw syawla ev’I“
.kool latnemgduj a mih evag remuR
.tsol er’ew ,ecitsuj tuohtiw
.ti denimaxe dna raj a pu dleh luaP
.tnarraT dias ”,mret gnol ,rof gnikool er’yeht slliks fo dnik eht evah yllaer t’nod I“
.eruS“ .tnarraT dias
”.ssapsert ruo koolrevo yeht taht ksa dna
.ruf rieht no neve
.nepo srae dna seye ruoy gnipeek tsuj s’tahw dna ycehporp s’tahw llet ot drah eb nac ti ,nos ,si hturT“
,revol ,wets eht ni retaw eroM“
.secivres rieht rof ylpaehc oot raf retrab ot dnet
.pu kool t’ndid luaP ”.siht evah I“
,srotcart daed dna smraf ytpme
,thgil dna esraps saw gnihtolc riehT
.reneerg erew seert ehT
.seert ekil gnispalloc sgnidliub taerg
,semoh ,sloohcs ,spohs
”?namahS a uoy erA“
.pu ylf skraps fo niatnuof elttil a dna pop gol a gnikam
,tnarraT ot redrO ym fo noitcetorp eht dnetxe I
,demoorg-llew dna suoiditsaf saw remuR ,lareneg nI
”espylacopA eht fo slesaeW“   yojne esaelP
”.tellub a pots dluoc diarb yM“
,dias eh ”,kooL“ .dehgis remuR
”.sdleif eht ni seidob mraw rof llac a syawla s’erehT .gnimraf ro
.lotsip sih gniward dna
.plug a ta sih deruoved tnarraT tub
.dlrow eht ees ot emoh tfel tsuj dah yllaer eh elbissop saw tI
.rof ezigolopa ot gnihtoN“ ”.ris ,yrroS“
,elddim eht dnuora netfos ot gnitrats tsuj saw eh
”?ti erahs ot tnaw uoy diD“
,remuR ot evag eh ,otatop ehT
.remuR dias ”,eurt eb yam tahT“
”,namahS ,sdrow htiw mih dnefed t’nac uoY“
.em ni tfel sraey doog wef a evah I sepoh eno tub ,yadhtrib tsal ,eerht-ytxiS .luaP m’I
.remuR dias ”,hA“ ”.ecnetnes
,uoy sa gnuoy sa enoemos ot esoppus I
”,dedisdnilb erew ebirT ruo ni snamahs ehT“ .enod tsomlA
.ytic siht hguorht tnarraT deusrup ev’ew syad evif roF“
.revir eht otni devohs neeb d’yeht fi sa dekool htoB .wot ni enimrE
.tenalPruF rof ”espylacopA enO dnuoF“ dna
.deliaf snamuh eht yltnerappA“
,pu mraw ot skcor eht no selppa eht detser eH
.yrgnuh skool eh ,sediseB
.deddon tnarraT ”?tnarraT“
,deifirret saw enimrE eht
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.deliocer ohw ,tnarraT ta deddon eH
”.slicnuoc ruo esivda dna nerdlihc ruo hcaet yehT
.rae sih ot dennip rehtaef kwah kcalb a dah enO
lesaew sretcarahc eht fi[ tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.eman nretseW a s’tahT .tnarraT“
.niar gnivird eht hguorht gnihton ees dluoc eh tub
.enilyks eht morf werdhtiw kramdnal rehtona dna ,tsud fo emulp a ,ekoms fo emulp a ,yad yrevE
.senioM seD morf retirw a htiw hcuot ni m’I“
”.ytlayor ekil uoy taert ot lahtiwerehw eht evah dluohs
.noitavresbo s’taht ,ycehporp ton s’tahT“
,gab eht fo mottob eht ni otatop dlo na saw erehT
”,tey ereht etiuq ton m’I ,lleW“
,tseW eht morf relevart
.semitemos daer ot drah mih edam ecaf s’luaP no ksam ehT
.tnarraT deirc ”,og em teL“ .tsud eht ni delbmut tnarraT
.uoy llik dna uoy hctac lliw yeht dna
.epor pmad ekil tlef llits
”,gnihtyna od t’ndid I ?did I tahW“
.ereh morf yawa teg ot evah I“
”.dnats uoy reverehw ,emoh ees llits dna yad lla klaw dluoc uoy dias redart enO
erehT .doof dnif I semitemoS
,gninraw sa gniteerg hcum sa saw tI
,dnah rehto eht no ,tseug siH
”?rof mih deen uoy did tahW“ .remuR dias
,elbbur ot despalloc dah gnidliub eht fo tsoM
.rallip eht dniheb og uoy was I ,lleW“ ”?woH
.tnemom a rof krow sih ni esuap t’ndid luaP tub ,digir tnew ecaf s’remuR
teg uoy od woH ?nos ,uoy tuoba tahW“
.gniht fo tros taht ,worromot niar s’ereht fi uoy llet yadot sduolc ehT
,xim liart eht tuo denoitrop eH
.elkna sih no ,drah ,nwod ti depmalc dna tuo wap a dehcaer remuR
.dewolf retaw eht yaw ehT .renaelc saw ria ehT
reppus sih dehsinif eH ”.edarged ton
,yks egnaro eht ezylana ot tseb rieht enod evah dlrow eht revo lla elpoep ruO .pu
.elixe fo snoissefnoc ro sgninraw evarg on
,tsiaw sih ot gnuh taht diarb kciht a otni deit
I…stresed dna stserof eht ni rolauqs evitaler ni gnivil sebirT elbmuh eht ot revo tenalp eht fo tfig eht dnah dluow snamuh eht taht
”.era sregnevacs woh wonk uoy oS .esruoc fO“
,smelborp rieht lla htiw uoy ot gnimoc ebirT elohw eht evah uoy nehW
.gab eht fo mottob eht ni artxe elttil a dnuoF“
”?ereht era ynam woH“
.ylthgil luaP dias
?yas uoy t’ndluow ,hguone si xis ,lleW“
taht sgniht ,peels ym ni sgniht ees ot detrats I“
.selppa eht dekcehc dna otatop eht revo denrut luaP
”espylacopA eht fo slesaeW“
.remuR dias ”,tnarraT s’eman sih syas eH“
,tsael ta ,gnikooC
.luaP dias ”,ti tuoba erom on flesruoy elbuort dna
.ekawa mih gnipeek gniht ylno eht saw raeF
.dedeen si egatnavda yreve dna
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.krow sih morf pu dekool eH
”.did eh tahw rednow em sekam rehtaR
.luaP dias ”,ycehporp tnecrep net
”.mih ot klat og ot gniog er’uoy esoppus I dnA“
.kool a evah ot tsuj ,gnirps siht ereht og lliw I dna remuR ebyam tuB“ .luaP dias
.suoirolg dna gnitacixotni
.seye sih ni kool hsipmi na
.pleh ot snamahS eht thguos stnerap ym oS
.erehwyreve meht gniees deppots ew nehw ydegart evarg a saw tI
.sdoohrobhgien eritne deruoved sdoolF
,gnidart neeb d’yeht eeffoc eht ot txen
.yawyna ,eerht rof hguone htmraW“ ”.yllaer toN“
,repeekecaep a sa sthgir yb dna ,ebirT ym dna elpoep ym fo eman eht nI
,slaem raluger ot desu taotS a ekil eta remuR ,meht fo hcae ot eseehc dna daerb tuo dednah eH
”?tnarraT ,sniatnuom eht revo yaw eht lla emoc uoY
.ni gel sih werd tnarraT dna ,wap sih detfil remuR
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
nac I nehw pleh I tub
.thgin tsal eciwt uoy detarenev I ,lleH“
”.sregnevacs er’eW“
.remuR dias ”,ytnelp detarenev teg uoy
.yawa wap ym gnikat m’I“ .remuR dias
.yllufthguoht swalc sih denimaxe eH
,uoy tcetorp t’nac I ,tlob uoy fI
.egaruoc eht pu skrow eh nehw thginot retal em neht dna