,ydaer saw eh ,thgif a ot emac ti fi
”.hctarcs a tsuj s’tI .enif m’I“ .luaP dias
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.lluf sesuoherots ruoy ,hcir era sporc ruoY
.rehtaeF kwaH ta decnalg eH
.meht gnipleh elpoep ym fo egatnavda lluf eht evah dluow seirasrevda ruoy ,esruoc fo ,dnA
;saw tnarraT seiteixna dna sterger fo egakcap xelpmoc a tahW
,won tser nac uoY .wonk I“ ”…derit oS“
”.rovaf ruoy ni eb ton dluow emoctuo eht dnA“
”.uoy ta kool em teL“
”?flesruoy esoht od uoY
.luaP dias ”,revo si etamelats eht dna namahS a truH“
.dias eh ”,thgir llA“
.deworran seye s’luaP
gnilaets rof uoy llik ll’yehT“
,nwod meht fo eerht lla nekat evah thgim nem s’rehtaeF kwaH
.lrans a otni delruc ecaf sih
.luaP dedda ”,nolem a revO“
”?mrofrep ot mih rof robal on ,ytlanep ressel on ereht sI
snoitacilbuP laoG rof ”alekA“ etorw ohw ,egdirdooG neB yb
,tehporp yna morf pleh on htiw
”.noitisop ruoy fo ecitsujni eht ees uoY“
.gnikniht er’uoy tahw s’taht fi ,feiht roop siht gnirobrah toN“
.nomed retaw ro regneva deggar emos ekil kool mih gnikam
;noitcerid gnorw eht ni ffo delbmub stoidi owt esohT
”’…thgin eht ni mraw ,gnihtemos gnihtemos derehtag ew ,yks eht ni ekal eht yb
.delwocs eh ,yllaniF
.tnegnat eht ta tnemredliweb sih gnibrosba ylfeirb
.ti rof nur a ekam ot ydaer dekool tnarraT dna
tsae eht ot thgil tniaf a saw erehT
.kees uoy ytnuob revetahw tcelloc dna ecnetnes ruoy tuo yrrac ot noissimrep lanimon ym evah uoy ,sey taht snaem hcihW
,esruoc fo ,gnimussA
”.elbissop sa noos sa sugamacnaK eht ot nruter tsum ew ,oN“
”.uoy gnirobrah rof em llik dna
.retaw yhtlif fo teef owt ni hsalps a htiw dednal dna
- ssecorp eht ni nwo rieht fo wef a tsol tub
,etoyoC ot etoyoC morf devom seye s’remuR  2 fo 2 traP ,egdirdooG neB yb
.derif era stohs litnu revo ton s’ti tuB
”…gniniar dna ,krad s’ti ,wonk uoy ,tub ,meht nraw ot deirt I
.meht dniheb deredliweb setoyoC eht gnivael
,lleH“ ”.ecitsuj gnicaf tuohtiw gnieelf dna ydotsuc ruo gnipacse fo rettam eht osla s’erehT“
”.uoy rof retteb teg ton od sgnihT
.mM“ .derettalf ylthgils dednuos rehtaeF kwaH
.luaP dias ”,thgin eht pu mraw dna seciov ruo hgih esiar ot ,rehtegot derehtag ew ,yks eht ni ekal eht yB“
.snwot dna segalliv rieht ni efas peels seilimaf ruoY
drawrof denael eh ylnedduS
,mih no nwod taeb niaR
,dnuora dereep dna level dnuorg evoba daeh sih desiar luaP
.tuo traeh sih gnibbos saw dna remuR dnuora smra htob dah eh ,retal tnemom A
;lausnesnoc yleritne si noitcetorp s’remuR
”.rellik a si ssertS
.thgit mih gnidloh dna smra sih ni mih gnirehtag
.spil eht no luaP dessik dna
”?etats a hcus otni flesruoy
,mrots eht dna thgin eht htiw secnahc ruoy ekat nac uoY
.sreusrup rieht fo ngis yna gnikees ,gnihctiwt
,gnorts yrev ton s’tI ?yeksihW“
.deirc eh ”?nolem enO“
.delworg eh ”,loof gnuoy uoY“
.tcepxe I ,no deniar gnitteg tuO ?luaP“
,gniffins ,gnileviws srae
”.nolem A“ ”?doof tahW“
”.namahS a fo noitcetorp eht rednu enoemos demrah evah reven dluow setoyoC esohT
.daeh sih ot nug a htiw ksalf sih morf pis a gnikat ,remuR dias
”–fo elbapac yltcefrep si tnarraT taht niatrec m’I .wonk uoy…ot ton
”.deksa I tahw toN“ .tnarraT ot txen
.etacovda ro rosivda lautirips ,rolesnuoc
”.noitcetorp ruoy wardhtiW“ ,dias dna
”.feihC eht rof rettam a si ecitsuJ
”,noitcetorp ruoy detcejer eH“
”.smrots tsrow eht ni neve
”espylacopA eht fo slesaeW“
?raw fo emit a gnirud diarb eht no gniriF“ .remuR dias
.ecaf sih morf trid dna emirg eht desnir retaW .gnihctiwt srae
.yaw eht yb ,stniap ruoy ekiL“
”,sruoy naht ytud rehgih a evah I“
.meht htiw emoh gnimoc saw feiht eht dalg saw eH
.ebirT ruo ot dna elpmeT ym ot htob
”?laets enimrE roop siht did yltcaxe tahW“
.ega sih detcidartnoc taht elcsum fo bals a
,tnarraT ta decnalg remuR ”.ti s’tahT“
,emirc eht dekoolrevo evah thgim niatfeihC ehT“
tas eh erehw morf mih detlupatac sgel gnol siH
”?yawyna ecnetnes eht tuo yrrac ot erew ew fi dnA“
.won egaruoc ruoy deen I tuB .thgir lla s’tI
fo trap lanif dna
,nialpmoc ll’yeht ,esruoc fO“
”.gorf eht eb rehtar d’I kniht I woN“
,tseug dezilivic a ekil tca ot deraperp era dna
”.deksa I tahw toN“
,deffins ,deddon tnarraT
.ecnahc mils a tog ev’uoY
,nug lufrewop ylralucitrap a t’nsaw tI .ylwols
,erehwemos tuolc sih tsol neve d’eH
.selzzum rieht pu gniwercs eb tsum elddup siht ni parc eht
.gnixelf erew yehT“
,remuR dias ”,deedni eerF“
,remuR no erew seye lla elihw niar eht otni tuo gnihsad
,snopaew rieht gniward morf meht deppots t’nevah
.rehtaeF kwaH ot ksalf eht dereffo eH
.tnemom a rof desum remuR
”.eerht rof moor s’ereht tub ,guns eb ll’tI
.lworg a saw eciov siH ”.redisnocer…ot
”.sruoy sa lufecaep sa erew sraw lla hsiw I
.ssaP sugamacnaK ni ecaep rof moor fo ytnelp s’erehT
”.neht ,no emoC“ .delbmum eh
.raey a ni slavir ruoy htiw elttab a thguof ton ev’uoY
sehcadaeh rieht deileb snoisserpxe rieht tub
,niar eht yawa deknilb tnarraT nehW
,ton ro nug nward
thgiew sih detfihs luaP dna ,deirc eh
,epols a revo deppilf ,delbmut yehT
.ebirT ym ot ytud a evah I“
.dnuorg eht otni knirhs ot ydaer dekool tnarraT
.nepo llordeb eht dleh remuR
”,repeed flesruoy gniggid pots tsum uoy ,etoyoC raed yM“
”.noitcetorp ruoy wardhtiW
.regnol elihw a thgilerif eht yb tis oD“
,detlob ohw tnarraT saw ti tuB
.erif eht ot gnidnet ,remuR dias
,ereht regna on dnuof dna seye s’luaP otni dekool tnarraT ”.evarb eb ot uoy deen I dna
”.erus tnecrep yteniN“ .deggurhs remuR
.stegrof eno ylisae woH .thgiR“
”.detsuahxe hcum ytterp kool uoY
.oot ,eloh eht otni llef sroirraw ruoy fo elpuoC“
,dlihc a ekil mih dekcor dna
.bos a tuo tel tnarraT
”,raw ta er’ew tub
”.teiuq eb tsum uoY“ .dessih eh ”,teiuQ“
,noitcetorp s’namahS eht dootsrednu ylluf evah ton thgim rehtaeF kwaH
.erif eht dnuora staes ekat ot setoyoC gniniamer ruof eht rof derutseg remuR
”?thgir ,selur eht era esohT
- dnim s’rehtaeF kwaH ni yawa gnidnirg snoitaluclac eht dezingocer remuR
”espylacopA eht fo slesaeW“   yojne esaelP
”.sretnuh eht tcartsid ll’I
”,meht retfa ,uoy dna uoY“ ”–si ti swerb ohw yug eht tub
,tfel doof on ev’eW
.daeh sih dniheb swap sih gnikcut
.remuR dias ”,siht elttes ll’ti fi nolem nmad eht rof yap ll’I
,sebirT rehto erofeb ecaf esol d’uoY
.revo saw mrots eht dna wol denrub erif eht litnu lenitnes a ekil pu deyats luaP
.esneterp a sa raw gnisu si feihc ruoY
”?eerf m’I ?revo s’tI“
.redisnocer…ot niatfeihC ym ksa dna ,elpoep ym ot nruter…lliw I“
.deracs er’uoy wonk I“
,smra sih ni drah dna doog tlef luaP
”.yob eht rof namahS eht mosnar nac ew ,mih dnif t’nod uoy fI
.gnicnetnes si ytud ruO“
”?nolem ysuol eno revo syad rof sniur dna sniatnuom eht hguorht yob siht gnisahc neeb ev’uoY“
.rehtaeF kwaH deppans ”,semag s’namahS diputs eseht fo hguonE“
.taoc dekaerts-htlif sih ehtab ot elttil enod dah niar eht dna
ti htiw tlaed s’eh yaw eht
”.efil s’nam roop siht rof eef llamS
.ssem etulosba na saw eH
noitcetorp rieht rednu tnarraT feiht gnuoy koot remuR dna luaP sregnevacs[ ,emit tsaL
.thgilerif eht otni elffuhs ot tnemom taht esohc setoyoC gnissim owt ehT
,esruoc fo ,detcetorp s’eh erusne oT“
.htuom sih revo wap a gnipmalc dna tsehc sih no thgiew lluf sih gnittup
.niks sih ni gniknirhs eb ot demees ohw
.deggas tnarraT ”.od syawla yehT
”?flesruoy ot gninetsil neve uoy erA ’.namahS eht mosnaR’“ .remuR dias
.meht ta pu dekool redaeL ehT
.pu ecnalg neve t’ndid remuR tub
,meht neewteb tas
.su htiw emoh emoc nac uoY“
,repmet dna erutan ni elbairav meht dnuof eH
.namahS a toohs uoy fi sneppah tahw wonk uoY
.tpmetnoc fo senil ni nettirw saw ecaf s’remuR
.elots yeht tahw rof yap sessapsert ohw feiht yreve tel tsuj t’nac eW“
”,uoy rof llew og t’ndluow yllaer taht ,hO“
,mih ot txen yal dna
.ti elbuod ll’I ,ecirp ruoy emaN“
stnorf owt no raw a gnithgif tfel eb dluow sugamacnaK ehT .elpoep ruoy fo ynA
.swap sih daerps eH
,pil sih dna daeherof sih no tuc a dah eH
.ecnalab ffo mih gnitteg
llordeb eht otni gnidils ,remuR dias
.ecniw mih gnikam
.dednefed erew uoY“
.uoy gnisahc eb llits ll’yeht tub
?thgir ,seilppus rof neerg ,lacidem rof der ,esnefed rof eulB
.pu mih dewollaws niar eht litnu thgilerif eht drawot kcab yltnatculer deggoj eH
”?diarb s’remuR ni htiaf hcum taht evah uoy oD“ .tnarraT tpew ”?taht tuoba erus uoy erA“
.nirg-flah kaew a deganam eH
.nolem a revo selim ythgie enimrE gnivrats a esahc ot
teg uoy did woH .siht ta kool ,ym ,hO“
,mih htiw pu thguac enoyna erofeb yawa elim retrauq a saw
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,egdirdooG neB yb
.niw uoY .thgir llA“
.luaP ta gniddon ,dias eh
,epols eht tsniaga mih devohs rekcatta s’tnarraT sa meht dnuora lla nwod deraor niar ehT
.ti otni gnimaercs dna gnikcik rovivrus gnilliwnu na gard tonnac I
,meht htiw pu thguac evah sreusrup s’tnarraT woN
.namahS a fo edis gnorw eht no teg ot reven em dlot rehtom ym ,wonk uoY“
,deifsitas demees eh ,tnemom a retfA
”.og em tel uoy fi enola uoy evael ll’yehT .og em teL“
.erif eht ot kcab uoy gard t’nac I“
.dneirf ruoy no dna mih no nosaes nepo s’tI
;nam eerf a ekil tpels dna ylthgit mih dleh tnarraT .remuR dedecnoc
”.erehwyrevE .snamahS llA
mih llik annog erew yehT“ .derepmihw eh
.seitluciffid gnivah neeb ev’uoy taht raeh ot yrroS“
”.erofeb semit derdnuh a
.ffonur dna noitullop htiw derehtal erew yeht dna
.eruliaf laitnetop fo tsoc eht gnitnuoc rossergga eht dna
.rehtaeF kwaH detsisni
”.raw fo emit a gnirud lattiuqca on si erehT“
.deifirret ,deddon tnarraT
ti od tsum uoy dna
,erofeb ti nees d’eh
”,remuR ni htiaf hcum taht evah I“
.niaga tnarraT no denael dna
.won thgir ksa ot ereh ton s’eh dna
.rehtaeF kwaH detsisni
?llordeb taht ni elpoep eerht dah ew emit tsal eht saw nehW“
.su fo tseb eht ot sneppaH“
lesaeW ot lesaeW morf dekool rehtaeF kwaH
.lla s’tahT .elcsum gniwohS
.yhw swonk droL .nam taht ,ffo gnihsur syawlA
,daeherof s’luaP deddorp eH
”?ereh dnuora tehporp eht s’ohw ,yeH“ .luaP dias ”?taht tuoba erus uoY“ ”.enif eb ll’eW“
.sregnif sih delpeets eH .remuR dias
,tnarraT otno flesmih derewol dna
.tenalPruF rof ”espylacopA enO dnuoF“ dna
,demrahnu ylevitaler dekool yehT
delaecnoc erew yeht taht deifsitas demees eH
.rethgual otni tsrub remuR dnA
.snairabrab ybburg fo daetsni stsaeb dezilivic ekil ,wonk uoY
.daeh sih koohs eH
”.ffo diarb ruoy wolb ll’I ro won thgir si dneirf ruoy erehw em llet uoY“
.did eH“ .deddon remuR
.nekcirts dekool rehtaeF kwaH
.dias eh ”,ereh m’I“
.selpicnirp lareneg no slesaeW eerht eht toohs thgim eh demees ti ,tnemom a roF
.eepissO ni esuoheraw eht ta kcab snavarac gnidart ruoy detsoh ev’eW .lufituaeB
”?eno rehto eht s’erehW“
.remuR derumrum ”,won yako s’tI“
.noitcetorp ruoy rednu regnol on s’eH“ .dias eh ”,nar eH“
.rehtaeF kwaH ta nwod dna pu decnalg eH
.rehtaeF kwaH ta decnalg eH
,thgilerif eht otni deppets dna reirrab etercnoc eht dnuora deraeppa eh sa detrats rehtaeF kwaH
remuR pleh og ot evah eW
”,niw lla ew ,modsiw ruoy ot sknaht ,raed yM“ ”.niw uoY
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
.ecnereffid ega suomrone eht etipsed
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.setunim wef a nI“ remuR dias
.noitsuahxe yhtaerb a htiw ekops tnarraT
.ylraed ebirT rieht tsoc dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.kcen dna ecaf sih no doolb hserf saw ereht dna
.teef sih ot gnipmuj ,remuR dias
.dnabsuh sih ta nopaew a demia ohw enoyna ot dneirf on saw eh dna
.rehtaeF kwaH dias ”,feihC ruo yb tes era selur ehT“
.retlehs eht ot gninruter
,enola thgilerif eht ot kcab klaw ot nees eb tsum uoY
”.srednefeD sa dekram er’eW“
.teef sih ot yliraew tog rehtaeF kwaH
.niaga elpoep ruoy htiw krow reve dluow namahS oN
.tsrif thgilerif eht ot denruter
.daeh s’remuR ta yltcerid nug sih demia rehtaeF kwaH ”.ti s’tahT“
.ksalf sih desiar eH
.luaP dias ”,taht fo hguone ,thgir llA“
,reusrup sih fo smra eht ni delggurts eH
”?kaerb moorhtab a dedeeN“
.rehtie ,ekuasepenniW eht tsuj ton dnA
.revo dna revo eman sih ekops eciov a sa htrof dna kcab flesmih gnigniws
,daeh sih detfil eH
”.kcurt pukcip eht htiw redart gnuoy ffub tahT .tsuguA“
.nolem diputs a revo snoitcetorp ym gniwardhtiw ton m’I ,lleW“
.ytic denodnaba na ni mrots tneloiv a gnirud
,noitisop ruoy etaicerppa I“
.delttar sdaeb siH
,siht htiw laed remuR tel nac uoy rO
.derepsihw eh ”,thgir lla s’tI“
.rehtaeF kwaH dias ”,esuoherots s’niatfeihC eht morf dooF“
.deffins tnarraT ”.esimorp I
”.htmraw fo ytnelp dna llet ot seirots doog evah ew tub
”.taht no ni sleeh ym gid ot evah ot gniog m’I tub ,yrroS
.elddup eht fo tuo dehsols dna
,edis etisoppo eht no tas slesaeW eerht ehT
”?gur a ni sgub eerhT
.enimrE gnivrats a rof nolem eno s’ti ,yltsenoh tuB
.noitartsurf yratnemom neve ron
.sugamacnaK eht fo swal eht yb ediba t’nod I fi diarB s’namahS eht yb ediba ot uoy tcepxe yldrah nac I
””,eloh a otni lleF“
dleif gniyalp level a sa delaever sddo roop
.deifsitas ,ffo dezod dna
,tnarraT gnillabeye erew setoyoC eht fo owT
.ti ekat tsum uoY
”,ecin sdnuoS“ .deddon tnarraT
tnarraT .luaP dias ”,gnihtemos yrt yeht esac ni pu yats ll’I“ ”.pan a ycnaf I
xelf ot gniyrt tiuq uoy t’nod yhW
.tnuh eht ot tnemtimmoc rieht gnissessa
tnarraT ”.tluser eht htiw yppah eb ot em tcepxe t’nod dnA
”.pleh ruoy deen eW
?tuo siht klat tsuj lla nac ew dna
”.su gnitnuh era taht sboob owt eht yb derutpac gnieb tuohtiw
,kcab denael dna dehcterts eH
.mih thguac dah terreF eht rednow oN
].erif fo enil eht ni eerht lla htiw
,nopaew sih desiar rehtaeF kwaH .remuR dias ”,oN“
.kcohs htiw kcals ecaf sih
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,noissimrep s’dnabsuh ym deen ll’uoy ,rehtraf yna sserp uoY“
.tnarraT ,taes a evaH
”,neppah ot siht fo yna rof tnaem reven I“
,luaP saw ti taht ees ot desirprus saw eh
.noitartsurf fo lworg detaehc a delbmur etoyoC ehT
”,yawa seog aionarap sih litnu pu yats ot gniog s’eH“
”.emoctuo devorppa na gnikees ton era uoy tub
.syug ,ysae ti ekaT“
”.gnihtemos ro gorf a otni em nrut d’uoy esuaceb saw ti thguoht syawla I
,tnarraT retfa retlehs eht morf detlob eh dna
,nettims tib a flesmih dnuof luaP
- elkcat drah a saw ti dna
,detullop dna cillatem detsat meht gnikaos retaw ehT
.luaP dias ”,su htiw ni elip ot evah ot gniog er’uoy diarfA“ ”.tseR“
,dnuorg eht ffo yleritne mih gnuws rotpac siH
sdrow etilop s’remuR dna
.slesaeW eht fo yna ta kool ton did yehT
.rovaf sih ni era sddo eht tub ,rewoperif eht evah yam setoyoC ehT .tehporp a si eh
meht htiw llordeb eht otni delwarc yllanif eh nehw
,hO‘ ?eno taht saw tahW .gnos a devoL
”,mih llik annog erew yehT“
,yawyna dessik yeht tub
.mih morf dniw eht dekconk taht elddim sih dnuora wolb a
?tnarraT ,kniht uoy od tahW
?thgir lla ,niw uoY“
,remuR dias ”,sliat ruo gnisahc lla ton er’ew taht woN“
.efil sih htrow ton s’taht yleruS
.setoyoC sih fo owt ot gnirutseg
”.mih gnidloh dna su gnitnuh er’yeht woN
.teef sih ot tog dna htuom sih depiw luaP
.egamad emos od ot deetnaraug saw ti ,egnar siht ta tub
.elcsum degdelwonkca eh tub
.uoy htiw edart ot tnaw yllaer t’now ohw
,luaP dias ”,ereh thgir m’I .enoyreve ,xaleR“
.etal nettog s’ti ,ssendoog yM“ .remuR dias ”,taht s’taht ,lleW“
tnarraT .devivrus lla yeht
.meht neewteb tnarraT
.tnatsni na ni degnahc snalp s’luaP dna
.srecnad eciN .esnetni yreV
.sevlesmeht tiuqca ot serots ruo tuo gniyub seveiht yb teseb eb d’ew ,taht did ew fI
.esruoc fo ,selur era seluR .thgir lla ,thgir llA“
”?uoy ot deneppah tahw ,raed yM“
,rebmemeR“ .luaP detsisni
”espylacopA eht fo slesaeW“
.thgiew no evas ot llordeb a erahs I dna remuR“
”.su dniheb gnola thgir eb ll’yeht tcepxe I neht dna ,tser emos gnivah tsuj er’yehT
thgit mih dleh remuR
,rehtaeF kwaH dias
.noitanimreted s’rehtaeF kwaH gniyned on saw ereht tub
selur eht wonk uoy taht doog s’tI
sroirraw tsegnorts sti fo xis eraps nac ebirT ruoy fi raw gnixat ylralucitrap a eb t’nac ti tub
dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
”?thgir lla eb yeht lliW“
.namahS eht htiw ereh yats ll’I“
,yltneliS ”.klat s’teL
,gnirps ot ytiliba sih delaecnoc erutsop ysae s’luaP
.sredluohs sih morf llaf ot skeew wef tsal eht fo thgiew eht lla rof gnitiaw
”.tihS“ .dehgis remuR
- tas eh erehw demriuqs luaP ”.oN“
.niar eht ni ffo hsaw t’nod yeht dnA
”,thgie-yteniN“ ”.thgie-yteniN“ ”.evif-yteniN“
”,erutcip eht teg ot gnitratS“
.t’nac ylpmis I ,tnuh ruoy yfitsuj ot em gniksa er’uoy fI“
.feiht eht no thgiew lluf sih gnittup
”.emos dnif uoy gnipoh s’ereH
”.esivrepus ot gnola emoc dluohs I ,hguoht ,emit txeN
ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.won thgir yenom eht deen ew naht erom doof eht deen eW
.remuR dias ”,taht fo dnuos eht gnikil ,hoO“
”.uoy dna em neht dna
.mih retfa delffuhs setoyoC siH .tfel eH
”?lavitsef cisum eht gnirud ,enuJ
,trapa su stes tahw si ycreM“ .remuR dias