.derekcilf redluohs reh revo tsuj detcejorp ehs lleps thgil naerypme eht taht hguone reh deretsulf dah noitseuq ehT
.emoh kcab seno devol rieht fo meht dnimer ot tnaw t'ndid eH
.eroc s'esineD evom ot hguone peed eno
,petsrood rieht ot thguorb eb dluow raw eht neht
.noissefnoc a gnitiawa
.derehtag ehs cigam eht elttes ot hguone saw hcuot sih fi ro
”.stekcop ruoy ni meht tup t’ndluow uoy hsiw yllaer I
redluohs sih revo delwarc nrevyw ehT
.ecnayonna ni dias tab eht
,gnuoy ylbissopmi
.yrarbil s'oetaM gnisworb saw ehs elihw
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.meht neewteb derahs saw gnidnatsrednu na
thgil fo tnemhcrap a pu derujnoc etoyoc eht
,ecnetnes reh dehsinif ehS ".rehto
****** .etaudarg d'eh erofeb erehpsotarts reppu eht otni thgiarts mih hcnual tsuj thgim ehs tbuod on saw ereht dna
.nwod delttes nrevyw eht litnu nihc reh ekorts ot ylkciuq pu dehcaer oetaM tub ,reh ta gnilworg
seenk sih ot dehcuorc eH
.erom ecno flesti otni kcab despalloc ti litnu lleps reh denehtgnerts ssertsimdaeh ehT
.rats gnitoohs dnoces A
.nos ym htiw gnilaed nehw seciohc ruoy dnim ot uoy ksa lliw I tub ,setamdeb fo secnereferp ruoy htiw melborp on ev'I .noitatuper...ruoy ot yvirp m'I" .nrets sdrow reh
.ni pu werg eh smaerts mraw eht ot gniraeppasid
.elat sih dehsinif eh dna
tlef ehs tahw sdrow otni tup ot elbanu
.srekcins s'oetaM revo ylduol gnihgual ,t'ndid eH
redluohs sih no tser ot
.taht yb decnivnoc oot mees t’ndid eH ".ssertsimdaeh
”dutS ruoY tsuJ m’I“
.ti esnes nac klof revir sU
.ehcnalava gnidnepmi na pots ot
.tnatsni na ni edolpxe ylerus tsomla dluow
.dehtorteb si natsirT taht uoy dnimer tsum I tub ,sduef s'owt ruoy gniwonk
,tneduts a sa ereh yaw ym dnuof yllautneve
”.ylsuoires seiduts ruoy gnikat ton er’uoY
.ylhsipeehs nwod dekool esineD
.htmraw sih erahs ot ni etoyoc eht dellup tub ,dekoj noremaC
.swalc reh morf ekoms deweps lleps noitarecsive ehT
.pmuls seye sih tel eh os dna
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.reh fo tnorf ni yltfiws devom dna
,detadimitni eb ot gnitnaw toN .gnimool
nem dnasuoht ytnewT
.ecnecseloda ot buc llams a morf denoitisnart sah
.lla meht fo tseggums eht ,yletinifeD
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,rehtafdnarg reh saw etoyoc eht ediseb gnidnatS
.mih gnisol saw htebazilE
,hguone esolc saw ehs nehw dna
”.snehctik ym gniyrrucs dnif d’I tsep a ylno s’ti tub
,rewsna t'ndid eH
nrevyw suoicoref a eb ot desoppus s’tI
.dennalp saw tI ?lleps tsrif yM"
,edis eht sdrawot denrut ezag s’oetaM
sevlesmeht revo kcab teknalb eht dellup yehT
"!—tub ,cigam fo stca taerg mrofrep ot tnaw I .uoy ekil eb ot tnaw I" ,tuo deirc ehS
sesruoc gnikat neeb ylno ev’uoy tub ,raf os enod ev’uoy gnihtyreve ta doog neeb ev’uoY
,dnim reh ffo ertceps eht htiW
.wap sih gnivaw ,teknalb sih detfil retto ehT
.gnizilaiceps ton er'uoy tub
tlef yduts s'oetaM
esool gnihtyreve tel ortseaM reh ,taht htiW
.mih nommus d’ehs yhw ton s’tahT
.retrauq a neve ton ylbaborP
,denalp-artlU eht
.mrofinu detaroced sih ni gnilims retto na
.mih trofmoc ot kcab daeh sih gninarc
.htaenrednu gnirrits ti tlef I nehw ,neves ro xis ,em sa ega emas eht saw ehS
.od ot gniworg fo tol a tog llits s’eh tub
.saw siht tahw wenk esineD dna
,denekrad daehrevo seldnac eht morf thgiL .dezalb
,worromot ekil tsuj ,gninniw on saw erehT
.flehs eht ffo eno debbarg dna
.etoyoc eht ni ehca na ees dluoc retto eht dna
.ria eht ni elbisiv htaerb dellihc sih ,dehgual noremaC
.elbat eht otno knil eht dessot ehs
,pu tuhs ot meht rof llac a
,gnol koob eht ta derats eH
.gnitavargga saw tI .sedisni reh ta gniraet
,drawrof dehcaer dna
,edih ot deirt eh elims hsilived eht deciton ehs
.gnivorpmi trats ot mih dedeen ehs yhw nosaer a saw erehT
,rood eht ot denrut etoyoc ehT
,reh deticxe thgis ehT
”.ereh roinuj a saw I ecnis doof hcum sa tropelet enoyna nees t’nevaH
,cigam sih fo tser eht dellepsid oetaM
.bmil yreve fo tuo epacse ot gnitnaw ,em fo edisni gniraor saw cigam ehT
,teef sih ot ylwols esor eH
,talf saw eciov reH ".dehtorteb
.kcen sih ssorca ydob reh depard dna
.deppots eh dna sregnif reh deppans ehS
,denepeed moor eht fo srenroc eht fo swodahs
"!stnerap reh ot gnimaercs tnew ehs dna dehcnerd erew sehtolc reH .hsalps a htiw nwod emac dna ria eht otni pu dekconk ehS
.enola reh tog I erofeb keew a ebyam rof ni ti dleh d'I
.nepo gnuws yrarbil eht fo tser eht ot rood eht dna
,htaerb peed a gnikaT
.larrefsnart esruoc s'etoyoc eht rof noitadnemmocer reh gnilbbircs
,lleW“ .seye sih erofeb dessap hsalf a ,did eh sA
toh werg ecaf siH
.taht fo flah t'nerew yehT
.od ot evah ll’sruoy tub ,won thgir em tsniaga stit pmulp emos evah rehtaR .ereh ni teG"
.sraet kcab dloh dluoc rehtien tey
.gnirettahc hteet ,deggurhs oetaM
,sdrows htiw demra
,ylgnisucca deksa ehS
,seciton eno on kniht uoy hguoht ,dnA
.keew txen stra evisnefed trats ll'uoY
,dluoc ehs thguoht ehs naht rehtruf neve ,niaga knurhs esineD
.llew sa ni denael eH
,tneduts melborp a dah raey yrevE
roloc fo lluf ruf
.redluohs s'etoyoc eht revo gnikool
,levon a gnitirw si
.htreB natsirT etal eht htiw swap gnipsalc
?ymehclA lacinatoB ot scisaB
.cirbaf eht otni nevow sknalp otni spihs ythgim deretnilps yeht sa
.ssucsid ot sgniht rehto dah ehs wenk ehs tub ,tsrif ta lavorppa ni dennirg htebazilE  .deddon eh
,taht ekil etiuq nemiceps rehtona teg dluoc ehs erofeb htnom a eb d’tI
snairasnoM eht dna
,ekops ehs sa htrof dna kcab daeh reh koohs dna
,rednaw ezag sih tel noremaC
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
,esneffo koot nommus ehT
.spoort eht morf tuo gnar
",thginot peels ll'I kniht t'nod I"
.yddub ,neppah annog toN"
.llew snaem eh tuB
.lanoisuled ro elbuort gnisuac saw I thguoht yehT
,tsael yrev eht tA“
.enin naht regnuoy tlef ehs ,ezag s'etoyoc eht rednU
sesruoc sih ffo gnitsil
,triuqs a eb ot ti rof tnaem ylnO"
,emoh rieht dnefed ot nrows sreidlos ,nem erew yehT
.won tluda na er’uoy tub ,enipdloG ta erew uoy elihw evisserpmi neeb evah thgim ehS .uoy
.lortnoc t'ndluoc ehs semalf ni tuo emac ti litnu edisni cigam eht gnirrits
egdir a ffo llef I litnu t'nsaw tI
”?dah ev'uoy seitinutroppo dna secruoser eht evah elpoep ynam os kniht uoY
.pu saw gnihtemos taht
.yadretsey eybdoog dias ylno d’yeht ekil
.elkcuhc a htiw ffo ti devaw tsuj ehs tub
.srennigeb rof tnaem
,detseretnisid demees oetaM
,yrros yllaer m'I"
,taes sih morf esor oetaM
.yracs s’ti wonk I"
.pihsnoitaler lufrednow a fo
.thgin yeci eht ni dloc gnitib eht ffo evats ot hguone ton mrofinu yratilim sih
.reh ta nwod gnikool
.meht yas ot tnaem eh erofeb htuom sih tfel sdrow ehT ".emoh
.pu thguac tog I ,tsuj s'ti
,ria eht otni tuo deweps sroloc ehT
,dias dna sdrow reh fo thguoht ehS
.hguone doog eb nac I fi wonk t'nod I" ,dias dna taht
,gnizilaiceps eb dluohs edutingam ruoy fo tneduts raey driht A
?ti lortnoc reven nac I fi tahW
.setirps dna skraps gniylf fo yrrulf a otni tsrub nomed eritne eht ,etoyoc eht no regnif a yal dluoc ti erofeB
.ksed eht otni gninael ,dias ehs
,tuo dellac noremaC "?oetaM"
sregnif sih deppans oetaM ortseaM ,ylprahS
?trats neve I dluow erehW
.ti dehcaorppa dna flehskoob a ot flesmih denrut eh nehT
.uoy pleh ot ereh m’I .t’nac uoy
.edis eht ot seye sih dekcilf dna
.doots yeht erehw sreidlos eht ezeerf ot
,kcen s’etoyoc eht otni denael eH
.seye sih fo sedis eht gnola gnidliub sraet ees dluoc ehs raews dluoc esineD
,ti eb ot gniog saw siht fI
.ksed nwo sih no ylmrif dniheb sih detnalp dna
,elzzum htaenrednu elzzuM
.eert a fo doow eht morf devrac ffats a saw
.mih revo gnippils rebmuls eht morf mih esuor ot hguone t’nsaw tI .edis sih ta gnibbaj ,detrons etoyoc ehT
.mih detpurretni sevaw gnihsarc eht tub
.skram ruoy nees ev’I dna seiduts ruoy wonk I“
.seye sih ni deremmilg thgil fo kraps s’tnilf a ,ega sih etipseD
.gnitsugsid tub evisserpmi s'tI"
.htiw railimaf saw eh sloop tsum dnaldoow eht otni demrofsnart aes hcir tlas ehT
.reh ta revir lluf a tohs evah llew sa thgiM
.ylralimis tab sih tuoba gnikniht saw oetaM wenk eh dna
”,uoy ssucsid ot ereh er’ew ;em ssucsid ot ereh ton er’eW“
.gnisarhp reh ta gnitsiwt elzzum reh
.segap eht otni delb tons dna sraet
,pal s’buc eht otni txet eht tes eh ,ylluferaC
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
cigam gnileef ydaerla saw ehs tub
,eson reh gnilknirW
,dnuora ti delriwt ehS
.senur yb til emarf
,daeh sih deddon etoyoc ehT ".od
sebor sih otni swap sih dedlof eh ,gnituoP
” ?llepS tsriF ruoY saW tahW“   yojne esaelP
,segde eht ta deyarf ,nrow saw tI
.sraet ni tuo detrulb ehs
.drow a tuohtiw eciffo reh tfel neht
.yks eht ssorca dekcilf hsalf rehtona
,ecnelis ni tas owt ehT
,yenruoj ym saw tahT“
.enilerohs eht sdrawot ecar mih gnihctaw
.taes reh otni rehtruf gnidils ,denihw ehs
",su neewteb syats taht gnihtemos uoy llet ot deen I ,oetaM"
.erutinruf yrarbil eht fo sniamer dehcrocs eht gnidnem
,ria eht otni gnulf smra reH
.eno siht sa gums os detca taht eno reven tub
.xaler dna seye reh esolc ot reh dlot I
,ohw ,etoyoC triD yb
.sroloc fo yrrulf a ni dessimsid saw wohs thgil eht ,wap reh fo evaw eht htiW
.sseniraew eht tuo deknilb dna
seye reh dna deffocs oetaM "—
,taorht s’noremaC morf dekaorc gnikohC
.1202 fo yrotS trohS tseB s’ltoyoC rof detanimon saw
,mih desiar I ,lleH .tluciffid eb nac nos ym wonk I"
,etoyoc detfig cigam a ,oetaM ,emit tsaL
sebor nwo sih otni dehcaer eh erofeb ti ezingocer ot dnoces a gnikat etoyoc eht
.nommus ruoy ta kooL“
.yrdnabsuH cinohcysP fo tuo uoy gnikat m'I"
.taht ekil enutni tsuj er'eW
.draob ajiuo a fo tuo
.ecnats sih esae t’ndid tub
.elbissop thguoht ehs taht
"?sruoy fo loohcs ycnaf taht tfel uoy erofeb latnemele erif a nommus ot denrael evah ton uoy dluoC" .naeco nepo eht sdrawot ffilc eht tsniaga skcab rieht htiw
”,em ta seye ruoy llor ton lliw uoY“
.ylduol gnippalf sgniw dna sebor reh htob
",uoy rof thgir eb ot gniog er'yeht fi
.nwod elttes ot nageb retto eht dna ,sehsuh dna snaorg eroM
,epahs sti morf denepo eye der doolb A
trats eht saw tI
.anemonehP citsejaM fo seitreporP larutannU dna larutaN eht dna
,seenk reh ot swap reh dehcnelc ehS
.seiduts ruoy ni enoh uoy pleh dluoc ti fi neve
.htiw stnemom tsal sih dneps ot dneirf retteb a rof deksa evah t'ndluoc eh neht
,dias dna drawrof elzzum reh denael ehs ,enot suoires erom a htiW ".gnizilaiceps
meht revo teknalb eht epard mih gnittel
,dehsiugnitxe neeb dah serifpmac llA
.redluohs s’retsam sti otno kcab yaw sti edam daetsni dna
.sdnah neddir reggad sti fo htob htiw tuo degnul neht dna
.gninrom yb hcaeb eht gnola pu gnirohs eb dluow teelf nairasnoM ehT .diarfa oot
.tes moor gninid lluf a otni eert kao na derettahs uoy ,retsemes tsrif ruoY
htaerb eci gnihtaerb dna staob neewteb gniylf hcrairtam ekard eci na gniwohs ,devom yrtsepat ehT
.yltneg psarg sih otni stsirw reh gnikat
ezigolopa dluoc eh erofeb tub ,ssuf a hcus gnikam gnitterger saw oetaM taht llet dluoc ehS
feiler fo hgis tsegnol eht tuo tel dna
nworc derettahs eht saw flehs a nO
.hguoht mih tpurretni t'ndid oetaM
,ssendnik emos htiw seye reh otni pu dekool eH
ni htaerb peed a gnikat
ot nialpxe ot gniyrt ma I taht gniht eht yltcaxe si tahT
uoy llet t'ndluoc I tub
.pit degnis sih ees dluoc retto eht os drawpu deppilf liat siH
.enasni gniog saw I thguoht I nevE
.eb nac eh suopmop woh nees ev'I
,laitnetop hcum os evah uoY
detnelat er'uoy ,niagA
evissam eht saw lla ti evobA
,ti timda ot tnaw t'ndid esineD .spitwalc reh sdrawot gnimraws zzub railimaf eht gnileef
.sreksihw sih rednu hsulb thgils a
kcen s'etoyoc eht morf devom nrevyw ehT
.naeco eht gnissorc ymra nairasnoM eht
,esotamoc decudni lleps fo etats a ni yal retceps eht taht niatrec saw ehs nehW
,ylsuoicsnoc seciohc sih gnikam neeb evah ton thgim eh fi nevE
llits dloh ot reh dlot I
srae sih dekcilf neht dna
.rehto hcae no ffo bur nac owt uoy ebyam dna
.nihc s’etoyoc eht tsniaga kaeb deggaj reh dehsurb ehs
swap reh ni etingi ot gninnigeb cigam eht deciton eh nehw s'tahT
,hguoht tfel eh sA
”.em yrram ot reh ksa annog m’I raews I ,kcab teg I nehW“
?snoisullI esahP elgniS ot noitcudortnI  .sessalc elpmiS
.mih ta sreggad derats tab eht elihw delbmurc edutitta s’etoyoc ykcoc ehT
,tnemhcrap a tuo dellup ylkciuq ehS
.erofeb nees reven d’ehs koob a tas swap s’retto eht nI
.eciov ym fo dnuos eht ot esolc ni nael ot reh dlot I
.epacse dluoc ti erofeb tsuj thguac
.ni lecxe nac uoy wonk ydaerla uoy sgniht no ti gnitsaw er’uoy dna
”.dessip elttil a s’ehs kniht llits I ’na
.nwod reh elttes ot evaw llams a reh evag tsuj oetaM tub
.ekal a fo emulov eht niatnoc ot raj cimarec a fo sreirrab laitaps eht dednapxe uoy ,dnoces ruoy nI
.dleif a otni peed t'nera ohw esoht ta gnikool eb annog er'yeht dna
.flesruoy gnithgif er’uoY
.swalc reh htiw elbat eht deppar dna dexaler ehs ,niaga gniyrT
.ycrem rieht rof nwonk ton erew
ni denael htebazilE
.esnefed fo enil tsal eht erew yehT
,no gniog eb lliw gnihtyna kniht I taht toN"
.yar reh htaenrednu daeh elttil sti ekop dluow nrevyw eht fi derednow htebazilE
.yvaeh gniworg erew seye sih tub ,peels t’ndluow eh dias eH
rettel eht detpecca eh sa daeh sih gniwob
.noitcif yrruf trohs dna ,seires a
)2 fo 2 traP( etoyoC triD yB
,noisserpxe denekrad reh ni dna
.daetsni mih ot txen stit esoht dah eh gnihsiw yllaer ,dehgis noremaC
sraey rof em ot klat t’ndid ssaC .htnom a rof em dedlocs moM .taht rof edih ym dennat ad yM“
dnim sih no hserf llits elims reh ,desuap eH
.elbat eht tsniaga walc reh deppat dna
,pu dekool oetaM ortseaM
ria eht otni gnah sdrow reh tel ehS ”.uoy s'tahT
.tuo emac stsrif ym nehw em fo ekam ot tahw wenk eno oN
,moor siht llif ot hguone egral eb dluohs gniht tahT
,ygolopa na tuo delbmum eh dna
,ti thgif ot detnaw eH
",ortseaM ,yrros m'I"
ria eht otni swap htob tfil oetaM dehctaw eh dna
taes sih fo tuo tog etoyoc eht ,taht tA ".lortnoc
,kaeps dluoc eh erofeb ffo mih tuc tub
.syawyna ytsief gnimoceb saw gniht nmad eht tub
,dragersid sih dekcimim redluohs sih no nrevyw tsorf ehT
dnegel cinatit eht ,oreh eht ,reidlos eht saw enog gnoL
,su fo htob rof hguone naht erom saw emit eno tahT
.ertceps eht fo ecnetsixe eht fo deniamer taht lla saw
demees meht fo llA
.ereht dna ereh egam gnissap eht snas ecneirepxe lacigam elttil yrev dah egalliv yM"
"!sdnah ym morf retaw fo hsalps a tuo deyarps I
;em gnithgif ton er’uoY “
,lleps tsrif ym wonk ot detnaw uoY"
.selbmurg s’retsam reh htoos ot
.snoisiced sih tuoba gnikniht saw eh
.wap reh desiar tab eht
,dnuownu ylwols oetaM
.sehcaorppa raw sa stiurcer hserf rof gnikool
.nwonk ev'tsum etoyoc eht llew lluf gniwonk ti dias eH ".taht
.hguorht gnitteg saw ehs wenk htebazilE dna
.dednamed htebazilE ”,taht potS“
denommus eh tserof ritne a fo eno tsuj saw tI
"?ydaerla uoy dlot apdnarg t'nsaH"
.cigam dna ,sraeps
.depsirc flah ria eht ni gnidir ,gur a emac nI
.nwo reh fo noitseuq a htiw noitseuq eht derewsna ehs
.hsa ni moor eht gnitnecs
.niaga gnikaeps erofeb flesreh deidaets ehs
,flesmih gnimrofrep saw etoyoc eht lleps a saw ti fi erus t'nsaw ehS
.rood eht sdrawot denrut dna
,niaga dewob ,denrut eH ".nos
,pu dekcolf redluohs sih no nrevyw ehT
.deyonna erom neve htebazilE edam tsuj tahT
.ssertsimdaeh fo elor eht gnikat erofeb rosseforp a emaceb dna
.ssenlufthguoht emos htiw pu dekool eh litnu desae erutsop sih ni noisneT
,taht ta pu dekcilf srae siH
,ylgnisucca ni denael gur ehT
,yad sa raelc fi sa ,erehT
”?llepS tsriF ruoY saW tahW“
tsehc reh morf detarbiv srruP
,gnitib saw ecnelis eht ,woN
,goD fo ecioV ehT no derutaef yrots siH
,spets ym ta gnipoons neeb sah yrtsinim ehT"
”.semoc gninrom erof‘ htiw yalp ot gnihtemos evah nac I os stsaerb emos rof hsiW“
,gnihtemos derumrum eH
,uoy sa thgirb dna detnelat sa tsuj s'eH
elddim eht ni oetaM
.ecitnerppa na emoceb ot ytic eht ot yaw ym edam dna navarac gnidart txen eht htiw gnola dehctih I ,erehT"
,gniddew a fo saw enecs ehT
.tsrubtuo eht ta desirprus elttil a
elzzum s’htebazilE no daerps nworf suoregnad A
,rettiwt no elbuort fo stros lla gnisuac ton s’eh nehw
***** .sevlesmeht srats eht morf cigam ward dna
.pihsdneirf rieht fo htmraw eht gniyojne
.reh rof terces a dah I reh dlot I"
.meht gnidnuorrus ria eht sa dloc sa sdrow yci ni dias ehs
,dluoc I gnihtyreve deiduts I
ettehcnalp eht ekil mih sdrawot gninrut
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,lacisyhpateM eht fo seidutS
erus rof wenk I taht dnuorg eht ot ylefas detaolf dna
,elzzum sih no kcuts elims yrw a htiw daeh sih nrut oetaM was eH .dias noremaC
.riahc nwo reh otni kcab depmuls ehs
.ti no rednop mih tel t'ndid ehs tub
yad sih fo tser eht dneps ot reh ssimsid ot ydaer tuoba gnikool
rof gnikool saw eh tahw gnidnif erofeb stxet eht fo senips eht gnola deregnif eH
.eralg s’ssertsimdaeh eht rednu derettups lleps thgil naerypme eht neve dna
ediced ll'ew dna ekat ot dnetni uoy sesruoc eht em wohs ll'uoy
.lleps gninekaew eht rednu efil ot gnimoc elbat eht no ertceps eht deciton eh sa mih fo tuo gnihsur emac seigolopa dna sdoN
"regnol yna ni ti tpek I fi peels ym ni tuo toohs annog saw ti raef a saw erehT
sih ot dexif ecaf reH
.gniunitnoc erofeb
.meht ni gnitteg neeb d’eh skram eht dna
.sregnif reh neewteb egasuas a delddiwt ehs ,ria eht otni wap reh gnisiaR
,etoyoc eht did sa
.niaga swap reh ot rehtag
erutcarf dna nooram ot
,pu thgil ot nageb yks ehT
.ni elttes dluoc ti dnas eht ni tops a dnuof ti litnu dnuora gnirettulf
.srae sih dekrep dna tuo denethgiarts oetaM ,pu gnittiS
,ereh teelf eht dloh t'ndluoc yeht fI
,ssenevisiced emos htiw dna
esac ssalg a dniheB
strA evisnefeD nainacrA rof natsirT htiw riap ll’uoy
,ria eht ni sregnif sih gnilddiwT
.edahs eht dnuora elcric ot elbat eht otno gnipael
.htrof dna kcab daeh reh koohs dna drah deffocs htreB htebazilE ssertsimdaeH
.meht ffo pu ylf ot teknalb eht gnisuac ,rehtegot swap sih deppals noremaC
,derevaw ti taht dnocesillim eht nI
rewohs roetem a gnirud denommus eh sekard eci eht fo yrtsepat lacigam
.syawyna esruoc yllis taht reffo ew yhw wonk neve t'nod I
.emoh ta tab ruoy tog ev’uoy dna
,ydob nwo sti fo kcalb eht otni knus ,ecno deknilb tI
,haeY“ .dewap ytpme
,kcab dellup ebor sih fo mra ehT
daeha sretaw dloc eht
,thguoht dibrom yllacitsidas a nI
.serutnevda dna selat llat sih lla gnirahs ffo srae reh gninnur eb dluow etoyoc eht ,yllausU
,oot ti deciton etoyoc ehT
.noitavrats morf sdnasuoht evas ot thguord a gnirud demoolb etoyoc eht stiurf citoxe fo nedrag sih saw erehT
.mih htiw sretaw wollahs eht ni gnidnats ssal retto eht ees dluoc eh
.ylthgit steknalb ni eldnub ot saw feiler ylno eht
,t'ndluoc tsoM .tpels emoS
.dessap gnol dah em derussa enoyreve regnarts a ot gniklat eb d'I ,semit rehtO .wap
",tluaf ym t'nsaw tI"
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.sdrow eht dessecorp eh sa deworruf worb
.ti otni llef eh sa ecaf sih dessapmocne wap siH
.enot yrd a ni dias ehs
,gnineppah saw tahw ezilaer dluoc eh erofeB
,gnitniap a saw oetaM dniheB
,ni mih dellup noremaC
,semit lareves eltit eht tsniaga walc sih dekcilc oetaM
.tuo llif etiuq t'ndluoc ehs taes eht ni llams gnileef ,demriuqs esineD
.ylsseltsil dias retto eht
.daerht a no gnilgnad saw rof derac yeht enoyreve dna gnihtyrevE
.setadpu erutuf rof rettiwT no etoyoCtriD ta mih dniF
.hteet reh tirg dna tuhs elzzum reh deppans ehS
ym ni ecalkcen lraep s'rehtom ym htiw gninrom eht ni ekaw d'I semitemoS
.esnopser reh draeh t’ndah eh fi sa retceps eht gniyduts
noitcurtsed 'stsaeb eht ni gnikat saw ehS
dekcirt eh gnik revals eht fo
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,etoyoC triD yb ”llepS tsriF ruoY saW tahW“
.ardnassaC si eman reH"
,strats retsemes txen ruoy erofeB
”.flesruoy egnellahc ot deen uoY
.wap reh dloh ot tnerap a fo deen ni dna evif ekil eroM
.steknalb eht fo tuo depmuj dah etoyoc eht
.gnol oot rof ni ti dleh d'I tub
.giwt liarf ynniks a gnilaever
,gniredloms llits saw ti fo traP
kaew taht railimaf A
.wap dednetxe s’tab eht morf yawa noitcerid hcihw yreve gninrut
reverof ot elba eb t'now I tub
.tnerappa ega dlo sih ,dehgis oetaM
,cigam sih ni ygidorp eht etiuq eb ot nevorp s’eH
,seye sih ni ssendas a saw erehT
.syad sih fo dne eht ta eninac dlo derit a tas ylno woN .dewa saw taht
.ecnerefsnarT gnihctanS s’yoliM ta tpeda etiuq er’uoy
.ssenkrad eht ni elbisiv ylerab sreidlos rehto yb dednuorrus
.ebor ruoy rof yrossecca etuc a eb ot desoppus ton s’tI“
.tnelat ruoy nees ev'I tub
?seilamonA lacimonortsA
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
.erats teiuq emas taht ni dexif elzzum
.peelsa tneps sruoh tsal sih gnitnaw ton
hguoht t’ndid tI
,retto eht otni dezeeuqs oetaM
,hguoht esolc ylluf dluoc yeht erofeB
.dehguoc esineD ",yltsoM"
.tsehc sih ot ylthgit koob eht gnulc  eh sa dehctaw ehS
”,rats gnitoohs a ,taht ta kool
.retto eht ot kcab deklaw dna
,ffo deliart retto ehT "…saw I
,rae sih ni gnilffinS
.laivirt era sesruoc ruoy llA ?yrdnabsuH cinohcysP
.yerg ni tuo dehsaw tey ton
,sreidlos rehto morf snaorG
,sgniw s'tab eht ot dekool eh sa worb s’oetaM desiar ytisoiruC ".pu
.htaed eht ot elttab a otni
”.gniyfisrevid ton
,repap a sa talf sa elbat eht no yal tI
,raf os kcab meht peek ot elba neeb ev'I
.teknalb eht rednu tsehc sih dnuora depparw wap a htiw no denetsil tsuj eH
"?saw lleps tsrif ym tahw wonk ot tnaw uoy dna ,eid ot gniog er'eW"
.lortnoc rednu ti tog ev'I"
.etats tnamrod sti morf derrits htaenrednu retceps wodahs eht
nrevyw eht ta regnif a detniop htebazilE
dootsrednu esineD .gniyas saw ehs tahw eunitnoc ot reh rof gniksa fi sa
.mrof sti edisni morf tuo dehcaer yliraew walc dehctolb kcalb kciht a ,ekowa ti sa tub
.noituac dna tcepser htob srenrag taht