niatniam dna tsac hateehc eht dluoc lleh ro nevaeh ni yaw oN
”)2 fo 1 traP( ?llepS tsriF ruoY saW tahW“   yojne esaelP
,oetaM naht retrohs toof a flah gnieb yob rehto eht etipseD
.steehs reh ni pu delruc reh ees ot moor reh otni deklaw I ,yad htfif eht nO
,ksa uoy gnihtyna uoy rewsna ll’I ,oetaM suoicerp ym ,thgirlA“ .pot no ylmrif detnalp dna
.ksed eht otno yltaen sevlesmeht werht dna tuhs
.erif fo llab llams a detingi eh
.htaerb peed a koot dna
;meht fo htob yb tlef eb ot hguone saw taeh ehT
,tespu em ekam tsuj dluow ti dias yehT
rehcaet sih tsol eh fi taht llew lluf gniwonk
,dnoces a mih dellats rehtegot swap sih gnibbuR
.wap s’oetaM ot no dleh dna
,htaerb sih dleh xaJ ".sdneirf
.reh rof tuo ti dleh dna flesym edisni morf rewolf a dellup I"
ksed eht hguorht thgir desahp ti litnu drawrof ti gninokceb
.eenk s’etoyoc eht ot txen steehs eht no gnittis wap sih
.pu dezies taorht sih sa tsuj
nrevyw eht evag dna
.enips sti fo kcab eht nwod ekorts elgnis eno
.detnaw yeht tahw koot dna srood nepo dekcik ylpmis yeht
.siht hsilpmocca dluoc tneduts raey htfif a kniht t’nod I
”?uoy evas lliw taht kniht uoY
hgual a pu krow ot gniyrt
.edis rieht ta meht nioj ot ylsseldnuos welf swap sih ni tnempiuqe gnirusaem ehT
,oetaM ,erofeb mih nees d’eH .noitats s’draug eht fo hcrop eht no
,ksed eht dnuora yaw sih depool dna
,htuom sih evael dluoc drow a erofeb tsuj dna
.ria eht otni detaeper
.nisiar a ekil pu gnihcnurcs elzzum sih
.xaJ ta gnikool ton
.anemonehP citsejaM fo seitreporP larutannU dna larutaN eht dna ,denalp-artlU eht ,lacisyhpateM eht fo seidutS“
,flesruoy dnefed ot woh uoy hcaet ot gniog m’I won
wenk xaJ ,revewoH
em ot emoc uoy nehT
,dootsrednu xaJ
gnirons sbuc owt fo sdnuos eht noos tub
daeh s’buc gnuoy eht ot nwod dehcaer ylsuoituac otsenrE ,yob eht nethgirf ot gnitnaw toN
.seigolopa yM .thgir ,hO“
kcab dedlof srae siH
,yawa ezag sih denrut yob ehT
,ohw ,etoyoC triD yb
dedlof smra sih htiw taorht sih gniraelc
lworg a edam fisA
,stsermra eht fo htob gnisu flesmih tsioh ot mih deriuqer teef sih ot gnitteG ”.uoy eveileb I
,gniunitnoc erofeb selcatceps sih morf sehcni tsuj ti gninimaxe
.snoitcerid etisoppo ni tuo smra htob gnulf oetaM ,tsaf gninethgiL
.etoyoc eht fo tnorf ni yltcerid tas dna
em taeb yeht dna em koot yehT
,seye sih gnitreva deirt oetaM
.wap s’xof eht ni gnitser
.kcen sih dnuora tfel ralloc latem eht sracs eht gnilaever
.mih fo tnorf ni gnilffins etoyoc eht ta worb sih deworruf fisA
.enola moor reh ni yrc tsuj dluow dna deb eht evael t'ndluoc ehS
,dnuorg eht no das erew uoy nehw ,yad tahT"
eveels tfel sih kcab dellup otsenrE ,taht tA ".neppah
”.sdeed elbirroh rieht rof cigam ym desu dna
.erutaerc eht evael ot elbanu seye sih
htrof dna kcab delggirw avral eht sa ylsuoiruc daeh sih dekcoc eH
”.decalper eb dluoc tsol ew gnihtyreve
.detnaw eh yaw eht gnidnats saw eh litnu mih detsujda dna drah pu mih deknay raugaj eht os dna desufnoc dekool yob ehT
.elzzum s’etoyoc eht fo tnorf ni thgir gnippots erofeb ria eht hguorht gniraos
,derepsihw otsenrE ,yenoh sa teews dna
emoh og ot detnaw tsuj ohw yob raugaj ynit a fo sbos eht raeh dluoc eH
,kceH ?dleh ev’uoy stcejbo fo seitreporp laitaps eht fo segnahc yna deciton reve uoy evaH
tsrif ta detsiser eH
.yob rehto eht htiw swap depsalc etoyoc eht
.diarfa eb ot evah t’nod uoY“
,flehs a ot deklaw eH
.regnol hcum siht romuh ot dnuora kcits ot evah t’ndluow eh dna noos gnidne saw tfihs siH
”.enog erew uoy wonk neve t’now ehS
?tem tsrif ew nehw rebmemer uoy ,lleW“
.tsehc sih ni murd a ekil drah taeb traeh siH
,pu stsif sih gnidloH ”.cigam tuohtiw
smlap sih desiar otsenrE
.s’hateehc eht no thgir spil sih detnalp dna ni denael eh
.raob dliw lanoisacco eht dna ,srecnamorcen citohcysp
.epan sih nwod rae sih fo esab eht morf mih dekorts dna
drawrof wap nwo sih dehcaer eh ,sredluohs sih gnixaleR
,feiler fo hgis gnol a tuo tel nairarbil ehT
.etoyoc eht htiw gnola nettog dah enoyreve ,esruoc fO
”?llepS tsriF ruoY saW tahW“
.teprac eht revo gnihsoows sebor elprup gnol sih
.s'oetaM tsniaga wap sih tser ot yldab detnaw eh dna
.teem dluoc seye rieht os elzzum sih detfil dna
”.su neewteb seil on era erehT
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.ebor s’xof eht fo gninepo eht neewteb thgir elzzum sih evod dna
,resolc detoocs xaJ
.pag rood eht htaenrednu sdraob nedoow eht gnitanimulli
.dellems etoyoc eht taht yaw eht devol eH
,yadot niaga taht od t’ndluoc ylniatrec eH
,dias otsenrE ”.lleps tsrif ym erofeb thgin yreve emulov yrev siht htiw tpels I
dnuorg sih doots esiwrehto tub ,taht ta delevirhs etoyoc ehT .taps fisA
.nwo sih ot ezag s’yob eht gnignirb ,dias eh
.hcuot eht ta thgiled fo sooc tuo gnittel
.tsehc sih otni smra sih detaerter buc eht ylkciuq woh htiw otsenrE gniltrats
railimaf gnihtemos was otsenrE
",em hguorht eybdoog gniyas fo yaw reh saw tI
,detiaw eh sa tnelis saw etoyoc ehT
ti od ot gniog er’uoy dna
,deworruf sworbeyE
.flesmih rof pu dnats naht rehtar dnuora dehsup dna detnuat eb ot flesmih dewolla etoyoc eht
.elzzum s’yob eht ot regnif a decalp ylkciuq xof eht
.dehcra worbeye na
dehgual otsenrE .seot sih dna
.reirrab elbisivni na tih ot ylno
.eson gnihcuot tsomla eson
,eson s’etoyoc eht fo yhs tsuj desiar walc sih htiW
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”?llepS tsriF ruoY saW tahW“
,toh nrut flesmih tlef otsenrE
.tsehc sih ot nwo sih dleh dna
,dooG“ .yletaidemmi tsomla os did oetaM dna ,delworg eh
,deb eht otni llef yeht sa dna
,kcab daeh eritne sih dellup fisA
.neppah thgim ti nehw ro eb thgim ti elbatciderpnu syawla s'ti tub
taes eht neewteb decnad seye s’buc eht
.hguone noos kcab reh gnirb ot woh uoy hcaet ll’I .yrrow t’noD“
seye sih desolc raugaj ehT
,nwod dna pu daeh sih gniddon oetaM leef dluoc eH .guh a htiw
derebmemer eh tahw revo ssenlufthguoht ni nihc sih dehctarcs otsenrE
.rehto hcae desahc ew elihw swap reh morf detpure gninthgil fo tloB
.setadpu erutuf rof rettiwT no etoyoCtriD ta mih dniF
.dnoces rehtona rof taeh eht dnats neht ruf ym lla ffo evahs tsuj ot thguoht d’I
.psarg sih morf werg mets a litnu sregnif sih dnuora derettilg selbram fo ezis eht sblub neerG
.ydob sti fo tuo deppir sgel owt dna
.otsenrE ,xof eht ,ortseam ruoY“
.sredluohs s'yob eht dnuora smra sih depparw dna
.skaeps eh revenehw eltsihw gnitatirri siht sekam taht edis thgir sih no gnaf esool a tog s’eH
”.ffuts evisserpmi yreV .lliw ruoy ot erutan
,tsrif semoc ylimaf ruoY .emit ruoy ekaT
.daeh sih ni ti raeh llits dluoc eh
,tuoba deppalf yeht ,daetsnI
deppals ylduol skoob eht lla ,sregnif sih fo pans eht htiW
.wap s’yob eht fo edisni nommus elttil eht decalp ylluferac xof eht ,taht htiW
,dneirf tseb dna etammrod sih
.retsis ym sa detatsaved sa etiuq enon tub
,elbapacseni saw tI
sduolc sa eltneg sA
,saw eh sa dlo sa leef ot gnitnaw toN
.thgir uoy ot ti gnillet m’I erus ekam annaw I dna emit gnol a neeb s’tI —tsuj I .sey ,seY“
buc eht htiw gnilims
.sraey owt tsap eht rof elbarapesni tsomla neeb dah dna
oetaM laever ot hguone detrap yeht dna swap sih devaw xof ehT
,ylthgit desrup spil s’oetaM
.gnireffus siht erongi ot redrah dna redrah ti gnidnif saw eh tuB
,spitregnif sih neewteb rewolf eht delriwt eH .ekat ot etoyoc eht rof tuo yppop eht dleh xaJ
.yrarbil eht fo tuo kcab klaw ot ydaer tuoba gnikool ,ylhsipeehs
.uoy rof tiaw ot gniog er’yeht kniht uoY“
flesruoy evas ot evah ot gniog er’uoY
.rehto hcae rof smelborp ekam ot evah uoy ,ysae os ti evah starb deliops uoY“
.cigam morf emac I ,egalliv siht ni seilimaf tsom dna ylimaf ruoy ekilnu ,ees uoY
.denimreted saw otsenrE tub detaerter htoB
”?saw lleps tsrif ym tahw wonk ot tnaw uoY“
,tsap sih morf gnihtemos derrits tI
gnol tuo dehcterts sdnoceS
.sniev rieht hguorht gnisruoc cigam htiw nrob neeb dah no os dna stnerap s’tnerap rieht ,stnerap rieht ,mom ym ,dad yM
.drawpu gnicaf saw mlap sih litnu
”,thgiarts pu dnatS“ .eb ot desu eh
mrow eulb ynit a
.liat sih fo esab eht evoba tsuj tops eros a debbur dna sebor sih ffo dehsurb otsenrE .mih fo tnorf ni etoyoc eht morf ecnatsissa elttil a dna
,yawa ezag sih denrut oetaM
.daeherof eht no flesmih gnippals erofeb dnoces a gnisuap
.detseuqer yltneg otsenrE ”,tsenoh eb ot uoy tnaw I ,sbif gnillet er’uoy fi ,ojiM“
,gnibbos regnol on saw oetaM hguohT
noitaretla lacisyhp fo noitalupinam eht htob gninibmoc
mih rof degnul dna
naht tnereffid saw mih htiw derahs eh tahw
.dah esle enoyna gnihtyna
.meht ees oetaM tel t’ndid eh tub
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT    .emit lanif eno
.uoy truh yeht taht yaw eht sdik esoht truh ot ysae gnihtemoS ?saw lleps tsrif ym tahw gniksa
,tcefrep saw lleps eht taht erussa ot htaerb tfos a gnikaT
.wap sih tuo gnidloh erofeb dnoces a rof stekcop sih dnuora delddif oetaM
”?uoy t’nod ,wonk ot tnaw yllaer uoY“
,foog a hcus er’uoY .snoitseuq yllis hcus ksa syawla uoy ,oetaM“
,etoyoc eht saw mih morf ssorca yltceriD
.deb sih no deggel ssorc htrof dna kcab gnikcor morf peek t’ndluoc hateehc eht ,os nevE .gnilggig sih elfits ot elzzum sih no wap sih tup ot dedeen xaJ ***** ”.daeh
?lleps tsrif ym saw tahW“
.dah uoy tahw yvne I dna mih fo yldnik os kaeps uoY
.uoy gnisaet ton m’I ,hhS“
.srosivrepus llah eht fo eno yb thguac eb thgim yeht gniwonk ,depsag xaJ
,yltfos kcen sih dnuora sregnif sih gniliarT
.sevil ruo tub gnihtyreve gnikat ,esuoh eht no dednecsed yehT
,repsihw a ni gniunitnoc dna ylwols ti gnisaeler erofeb eson sih hguorht ni htaerb a koot hateehc ehT
”,si taht lleps tsrif ym ,erofeb ti nees ev’uoY“
.ria eht otni skoob gnissot nageb eh sa
”.tfig lufituaeb a si cigam ruoY“
.ezag sih otni oetaM decrof eh ,dehsinif raugaj eht erofeB
.mlap deppuc sih sdrawot ti dellup dna
.dnuos gniggag a ekam dna seye sih llor raugaj eht ekam ot hguone saw tI
”,niaga em ot kaeps ton od dna ereh fo tuo teG“
.no dekcip gnitteg syawla er’uoy yhw gnirednow ereh gniyrC
.lirtson sih htaeneb niats doolb a saw ereht dna
?taht wolla dluow I kniht uoY
”—llew sa thgim ew neht ,taht od ot gniog er’ew fi
.hguoc eltneg a thguac eh
,semit elpuoc a deffins dna eson sih ot latem eht thguorb xof ehT
.erats s’nairarbil eht teem ot gnirad ton
.nori yleritne tsomla ;erup os s'tI“
”,das erew uoy yhw dnatsrednu nac I
”?ti enimaxe I yaM“
.taes sih ot gninruter erofeb koob elgnis a tuo gnillup
,tsrow eht rof flesmih deidaer xof ehT
.gnihtyreve em sllet kool tahT
,daetsnI .t’ndid oetaM
.no delbmar nairarbil eht elihw
.ti ekat ot etoyoc eht rof detiaw eh sa
.drawrof baj tsaf kciuq a edam raugaj ehT ".skaeps
,buc eht ot revo gnippetS
,otsenrE ecaf ot denrut eh
.diputs dna gnuoy eb ot elba t’nerew yeht esuaceb sdik no kcip t’ndid sdiK
snoisulli s’etoyoc eht yb deloof saw erugif eht ,yllufknahT
.kool resolc a rof ni denael eh sa nepo gnuh wam siH
.oetaM rof noitarimda emos dah ot pu doots eh taht syob eht nevE
,sucaba na dna ,srekaeb ,selacs tuo gnillup saw otsenrE sa tsuJ
”.sbuc tsom ekil ton saw I
.thgil eht yb erom ecno detanimulli erew selims suovren
,riahc sih ni llits saw oetaM
txen pu sdne oetaM erehw tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.roolf eht dehcuot enon tub
mih dniheb gnihsal liat
,hguoht ffats sih fo evaw eht htiW
.efil ot sladep eht gnicnad
.uoy no gnikcip syawla s’taht yob eht ,eltsimocac tahT“
.esab sti morf detpure tniop gnicreip prahs a elihw
,dnuora gnuws ydob elohw siH
”,ti no laed a ekam ot evah ew tub
,eninac hsittiks eht depacse selbmum llamS
.hguoht htuoy sih ni saw eh sa tsaf sa etiuq t’nsaw eH
”,nwot eht fo klat eht er'uoy rednow oN .eguh s’tI“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.yas ot detnaw eh tahw dna
,gninraw yna tuohtiw dna
”.stekcop ruoy tuo nruT
ynoga fo skeirhs riehT
”?dnuorg eht no ti dnif tsuj t’ndid uoY ?siht did uoy erus uoy erA
.rewolf emas siht uoy evag I
.efil sih fo tser eht rof reve fi
,ylsselwalf noitom sih etacilper oetaM was eh nehW
taes sih morf gnidnats
.daeh sih tsniaga kcab gnidlof srae sih
”,yad taht erew yeht sa
,snoitces tnereffid eht ot nepo deppilf skooB
.etaf ym derussa ylno ti ,oN
.ecnats evisnefed reporp a etoyoc eht dewohs eh
.taes sih ni nwod gnippolp ,deksa eh
,delley tsomla raugaj eht ”!og dias I“
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.ssalc sih fo pot saw oetaM rednow on saw tI
.tfig tsal s'amdnarg ruo saw ti taht erows dna
,seye sih desolc hateehc ehT
s’elpoep rehto morf nrael nac eh snossel rehto tahw dna
erom xof eht deleuf ylno gnikaepS
.thgin remmus ykcits toh a saw tI“
,cirbaf eht otni selcric decart spitwalc siH .derepsihw eh
.sraet eht kcab dloh ot tseb sih gniyrt
,denrut ti noitamrofsnart sti dehsinif ti nehW
.wap ym tuo dleh dna
,ycnamoeg dna noitatnemgua fo hcnarb a s’tI“
spets sih otni efil emos tup xof eht
.noitnetta sih tog sregnif s’xof eht fo pans a tub
,detrats otsenrE ”,aedi retteb a tog ev’I kniht I
,sekorts eht otni denael
.detnaw eh yaw eht hcnilf t’ndid eh tub
.reh pleh ot od ro yas ot tahw wenk eno oN
.seiromem sih ni tsol
cigam fo sloohcs tnereffid yletelpmoc morf slleps owt
.em ees ot kcab emoc neht dna eerht hguorht eno sretpahc daeR .won sruoy s’tI“
s’etoyoc eht otni peed dekool dna
.srae sih fo edisni dna
.rehtona eno htiw railimaf emoceb dluoc etoyoc eht dna nrevyw eht taht os kcab swap sih gnillup
.srae enipluv egral sih ni yarg eht dnuora decnad noitseuq eht sa til seye s’otsenrE etoyoC triD yB
swap sih denepo ylwols otsenrE ”...dna
.ylgnihtoos kcab s’nrevyw tsorf gnol hcni owt eht gnikorts dna
,levon a gnitirw si
wap s’otsenrE fo edisni nrevyw ehT
dna gnol rof taeh eht evivrus t’ndluoc snrevyw eht ,yllufknahT
.eson sih ot rewolf eht thguorb eh sa dias eh
,denoitseuq otsenrE ”?rof kool taht s’tahW ?tahW“
,ylsuoiruc deksa xaJ
.nevig neeb reve d’eh guh tsethgit eht
”?ew t’ndid ,niagrab a dah eW
.swap sih otni meht dekcats dna
sevlehs eht ffo morf skoob debbarg eh sa
.ni tis ot yob etoyoc eht rof riahc a sdrawot gnitniop dna
.niaga ecno looc leef ot
,tsirw s’etoyoc eht debbarg eH
,feiler fo hgis a htiw slleps owt eht desaeler eH
.hcrop eht ffo mih eracs ot niaga ffats sih gnivaw
.efil otni demossolb yppop egnaro na ,gnihton morF
.ega ylrae na ta edutitpa lacigam wohs ot detcepxe erew sretsis dna srehtorb neves ym dna em ,os gnieb tahT
riahc eht otni derehsu saw yob eht ,kaeuqs a htiW
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy
.pitwalc sih ta lleps tnemhsinab a dleh eh
.seenk sih neewteb dekcut saw elzzum sih litnu nwod knurhs dna
tuo ekam dluoc yob eht ,ni gninaeL
,cigam nwo sih fo diarfa eb ot mih gnitnaw toN .tnatropmi dna
.sdap sih tsniaga ti gnillor ,demialcxe eh
.mih ta nwod deralg dna tsehc eht no drah yob eht deppals raugaj eht ,deyonnA
.em evas ot dah I esuaceb ,em evas t’ndluoc emalf ehT“
won thgir dnim ym ni hserf sa era
.niaga xof eht ot ti dewohs oetaM
.ecno ta slleps htob gniniatniam
.teggun eht pu dekcip dna
niur fo tniop eht ot dehcterts saw trihs s’yob eht fo kcen ehT
elzzum sih revo dehsulf knip fo edahs A
***** ”.pihsnoitaler lufrednow a fo trats eht eb lliw sihT“
.stxet gnitaolf nezod flah a htaenrednu
.htaerb sih dleh oetaM dna
.citehtap er’uoY .uoy ta kooL“
.ezis sti semit fo sderdnuh yob eht fo suovren yllauqe
eviecer ot dessarrabme gnileef
,detcepxe ,ah ,lleW
,gnidda erofeb elkcuhc llams a htiw desuap otsenrE ”,stsrif ruo htiw egamad hcum oot esuac t’ndluoc ew erus ekam ot esuoh eht fo lla gnipolevne sdraw dah stnerap yM
”,nruter ni em rof gnihtemos od tsum uoy tub
”.setag s’loohcs eht fo tnorf tuo gniyrc erew uoY
,dam eb lliw eno oN
hteet gnittirg etoyoc eht ees dluoc eh
dneb ot uoy gniwolla ,cigam htrae fo stnenopmoc latnemele eht dna
.mih dessarah taht puorg eht fo redael eht eb ot demees eltsimocac A .yrarbil eht morf dna ot no dekcip gnitteg syawla
.rehcaet lufrednow a dna nam taerg a ekil demees eH
,hguoht gniht elgnis a od dluoc eh erofeB
.gnirees etiuq ton tub toh
.decalretni sregnif sih htiw drawrof gninael erofeb edisni gnirepsihw
seye sih denepo fisA
.dekrep srae s’etoyoc ehT
,ylevitcetorp tsehc sih morf elbbep eht gnilluP
.enadnum gnihtemos ro ,retaw fo hsalps a ro ,dniw fo tsug a ro ,erif elballortnoc elttil a ni tuo semoc ti ,sbuc tsom ,ees uoY
.llis wodniw eht raen gnittis seldnac eht demmid eh ,wap tfel sih htiW
,drawnwod elzzum sih gnipeeK
”.ecno ta lla gnineppah si siht
.elbat eht no tnempiuqe dna skoob eht ta gnitniop dna
,oetaM truh ot detnaw nrevyw eht fI
,eenk a ot deppord otsenrE
nellows saw pil siH
,terf ot dekool etoyoc ehT
,hguoht gnihtyna yas dluoc xaJ erofeB
,uoy ekil tsuj ,yletanutrofnU“
.stnemele erutan rehto htiw uoy ezirailimaf ot truh t’ndluow ylbaborp ti neht ,si htgnerts ruoy erehw si cigam htrae fI
”,hgual tub pleh t’nac I
buc eht ot dekool eh ,ylluferaC
.moor eht edistuo
ypmurg elttil a tsuj s’ehs ,dias I ekiL .thgirla s’tI“
dias otsenrE ”,ygrullateM“
,tsop a tih kcab sih litnu sdrawkcab delbbow
.daeh elttil yzzuf sih fo tuo ti kconk ot gniog era uoY" ,dias dna
,seye s’xof eht fo sedis eht gnola pu dellew sraeT
,ezilautca ylluf ot dnoces a koot tI
.daeh sih no tep a htiw yob eht denetfos eh tub
.dessap amdnarg ym nehw relddot a tsuj saw I
.foor ym no gnittis ,xis saw I
”.mih tem evah dluoc I hsiw yllaer I
.noitatnemgua htiw ffo trats dluohs ew ebyam rO
.em ton yllaicepse
.sekalfwons otni tsrub ehs dna
.teef sih ot pu mih deknay dna mra s’yob eht fo dloh debbarg eh
,gninruom ni saw ylimaf yM
.pu reh ekow I tespu elttil a tsuJ
ees dluoc eh llA
.suoicilam gnihtyna rof
riahc eht morf gnidnats
.nwo ruoy era smelborp ruoY“
ylkciuq flesruoy etautiS
.htaerb sih gnidloh neeb d’eh tcaf eht dna
.1202 fo yrotS trohS tseB s’ltoyoC rof detanimon saw
.meht dellup dah xof eht erehw ot kcab thgir ria eht ni deppiz dna drawpu tpel lla yeht ,hsalf a nI
,dlrow eht ssorca yawflah tnes saw neht dna
.sedisni sih ta dehcti dna
?on ,gniyfirret s’ehS“
.ti pots ot emit elttil eb d’ereht
,thgilnoom fo liev eulb tfos a rednU
,egnahcxe ot sdrow erom on htiW
.tey egaruoc eht pu krow t’ndluoc eH
,drawkcab dellup oetaM ,taht tA
.ti ees ot tnaw I“
.sdneirf eb syawla dluow ew wenk I dna ti koot uoY
htuom sti ta demrof kaeb degde deggaj A
kcab elzzum sih dellup nirg yrw A
.thgin eht eb dluow thginot taht wenk hateehc eht
.llah eht nwod deunitnoc dna
.ti taeper ot semit hguone yrots eht dlot neeb d'I tub ,llew yrev lleps tsrif ym rebmemer t'nod I"
”.spup elttil morf spup elttil toN
gnikaeps dehsinif xaJ
,rettiwt no elbuort fo stros lla gnisuac ton s’eh nehw
.noitnetta eht tpecca ot wap s’oetaM otni denael dna desae ehS
.tsehc sih dnuora mra na depparw
.gninraw s’tnemom a ni
,riahc sih ot denoitom otsenrE
,goD fo ecioV ehT no derutaef yrots siH
,rehtie ereht eb ot deticxe oot kool t’ndid ehS
.noitcif yrruf trohs dna ,seires a
gniyrc deppots ehs ,ti koot ehs nehW
.traeh sih morf noitatnacni na deticer eh sa ni gnihtaerb
.noisiced eht gnitterger yletaidemmi tsomla
.nirg yls lausu sih htiw gnittis
.nwo sih sdrawot elzzum sih thguorb fisA tub
psag llams a koot etoyoc ehT
,wam ytsan sti pu denepo
sgniw owt erofeb
.seimene ym detarecsive dna swap ym tuo tohs ti taht
wap s’etoyoc eht fo dloh debbarg eh
.resolc elttil a gnihcni ,delkcuhc xaJ
sdrowyek dna shpargotcip gnithgilhgih thgil
.od ot mih detnaw otsenrE tahw dnatsrednu ot demees etoyoc eht ,yllufknahT
.hturt eht dedeen eh tuB
woble sih ta debbur eH
ediw delims fisA
.oot elttil a yrc ylbaborp d’eh
.dna rats gnitoohs a was I
”?saw lleps tsrif ym tahw wonk ot tnaw uoY“
,kcab dellup oetaM
.gniyrc deppots eh litnu
.oetaM ot kcab noitnetta sih denrut eh ,noitseuq eht tA
.liat eht yb tuo reh deggard dna rehtom ym debbarg yehT
,derepsihw otsenrE ,srae s'oetaM neewteB
.eunitnoc ot mih rof elcric a ni wap sih devaw oetaM
.otsenrE erofeb thgir efil ot gnimoc rogiv fo esnes wen a
.esoht deen t’ndid otsenrE tub ,dnim s’etoyoc eht morf detnaw eh tahw ekat ot slleps erew erehT
seltsirb ni revihs ruf s’oetaM dehctaw eH
.eye sih dnuora ruf etihw eht htaenrednu gnimrof saw gnir kcalb ylgu na dna
toh os regna tlef I ,smaercs reh nI
,raef s’buc eht nI
,slatnemele gnirednaw pots ot boj ym s’tI
.sesnes sih fo lla delkcit taht ecips a ekil
,rehtegot dekcol selzzum riehT
.ylralimis flesmih noitisop ot yrt ylwols mih dehctaw fisA
lla ti fo yteixna eht morf htob ,tuo ssap thgim eh ekil tlef xaJ dna
teef sih ot tohs eh
mlap s’etoyoc eht fo edisni dehcaer ylluferac otsrenE ,dexaler saw yob eht taht erus saw eh litnu evom a gnikam toN
.raef eht desnes nrevyw eht dna
wap s’oetaM fo og tel eh ,taht htiW ".wap
.tsrif ym sa evitcurtsed sa raen erehwon saw ti tub ,kcab werg reven ruF
,buc eht ot kcab detaeper xof eht
seldnac eht tuo ffuns ot cigam sih desu dna wap sih desiar oetaM
semit lareves etoyoc eht delddarts fisA
delims xaJ ,guh eht gnisaeleR
ksed sih ssorca gnidnats buc etoyoc ehT .hgih sreksihw sih detfil dna
,pmuj oetaM ekam ot hguone llits saw duht ehT
.yltneitapmi riahc sih fo edis eht tsniaga gnikcawht liat sih niatnoc ot elbanu saw tub
.yawa peek ot hcum oot reh dessim I tub
elbbub eht edisni wap a gnihcaer
.daeh sih koohs dna dehgual tsuj otsenrE tub
”?wonk ot tnaw uoy tahw s’tahT
walc sih fo pit eht htiw nrevyw eht dehcuot nairarbil eht
,gniunitnoc erofeb pal s’oetaM fo edisni koob eht decalp dna
.kcuts nossel siht taht erus eb ot detnaw eH
.rotnem ruoy sa ega emas eht dnuora saw ehS
,syawla sA   .lleps tsrif
hsif dettug a ekil nepo gnuh wam sih tub ,snaem yna yb ecnud on saw xaJ
buc denethgirf eht saw
yawllah eht morf kaerc a thguac htob yeht
,nairarbil ruoy sa ,esimorp I
.seye sih ni kool nrets a dna
”dutS ruoY tsuJ m’I“
.seye sih htiw gnidaelp llits
,ecnetsixe ym degdelwonkca neve ylerab ,em ot gnihtyna yas t'ndid ehS
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,etoyoC triD yb
.slleps noisnepsus ro noitaluspacne gniwonk tuohtiw sgniht eseht fo nworg lluf nezod a gninommus enigamI
reh ediseb pu gniklaw rebmemer I tub
.stnelat sih krow mih gnihctaw
,yrc tfos a detrats oetaM ,daetsnI
,dneirf ruoy dna ,rotnem ruoy
”.ti peek ton lliw I
.reh ees t'ndluoc I dias yeht tub ,no gniog saw tahw dnatsrednu ylerab dluoc I"
.roetem eht morf cigam dellup yllatnedicca d’I ,gniyas saw I sA“
nihc s’yob eht htaenrednu deppuc eh
.lleps eht tuo deffuns eh ,dehsinif eh sa
,elihw gnol a rof ypoc eht ot noitnetta sih denrut eH
,ylimaf ees ot emoh kcab tnes rehto eht dna ulf eht rof yramrifni eht ni eno
.detrats uoy erehw pu-kcip ot sepyt latem fo egdelwonk cisab emos hguorht deeps ot evah ot gniog er’eW“
dednuorrus etoyoc eht ees ot elbanu
,hguoht mih sdrawot ni denael eh sA
,nwod dna pu daeh sih deddon etoyoc ehT ”.syawla
.rehtegot swap sih htob gnipsalc erofeb teggun eht gninruter
,egalliv ym ot emac srevals eht nehW
,oetaM sdrawot gnilias ,ylduol derettulf segap ehT
.ti no ydaerla saw etoyoc eht
.emalf eht ot decudortni saw I nehw ega ruoy saw I“
.ria eht otni gnigniws ,dias fisA
deracs elttil a tsuj er’uoy dna
”,ojiM ,diarfa eb t’noD“
.oetaM ni koot eh sa slirtson sih dellif stnecs ydnaS
wap s’buc etoyoc eht detsiwt otsenrE ,taht htiW
”.evah uoy ylno yruxul a s’tahT
,htaerb sih dleh otsenrE
.draug nwot on saw ereht ,pu gniworg saw I nehW
.llew os gnola nettog d’yeht ykcul tlef xaJ
,etoyoc eht ta egnul ot dekool dna
,suovren demees eH
,gnidnatsrednu ni deddon etoyoc ehT
,tsetorp dluoc oetaM erofeB
s’yob htob litnu denethgirb yllaudarg semalf s’eldnac eht
.noitnetta rof pu siht edam uoy fi yako s’tI“
.depsag xof ylredle eht ”,ssendoog yM“
”.yrutnec a flah ebyam ni taht deksa neeb t’nevah I ,yhW“
,spil sih ta meht deppuc dna
.yssis a ekil tuo ti bos oetaM elttil tel tsuj ot detnaw mih fo traP
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ksed nwo sih no pmur sih gnitnalp ,dias otsenrE
.sredart evals yb dellik neeb dah meht fo llA
flesmih saw eh deticxe woh yned t’ndluoc eh neve ,ylgnittimdA
.rood eht fo esab eht ta gnihtemos tsac d’eh ,thgir sih htiW
.latem fo htrow s’elbbep depahs gnolbo ynihs a tas edisnI
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.retsiS“ .woble sih tsap tsuj tops dlab a laever ot
.naem t’nod uoy gnihtyna yas t’noD .ahah .on ,on ,oN“
emit emas eht ta syoB detfiG fo ymedacA s’enipdloG ta devirra dah htoB
.hgis a tuo tel ot hguone dexaler eh tub
,mih ot citoxe dna ngierof os saw tI
.niaga amam sih ees dna
,enog setammoor owt rehto rieht htiW
.moor eht tuoba devom dna
,mmH“ .step eltneg nommus sih evag eh sa
.em evas t’ndluoc emalf ehT“
.dloc gnitaidar s’nrevyw eht ta
”,hgih tsif ruoy dloh dna
.erom ecno pu gnimmalc
.flesmih os did eh sa deredro fisA
,drah yrev os ,drah os detnaw tsuj I dna edistuo neve
.spitregnif sih ta gnilgnit ygrene lacigam fo zzub railimaf eht tlef eh ,yltnatsnI
.spil sih epacse ot naorg a desuac kcab sih ni hcnip a dna dehca stnioj siH
,dias xof eht ”,era syawla yehT
.ylkciuq daeh sih koohs xaJ tub ,tsetorp ot tuoba dekool eh dna
nretnal a morf thgil eht tuo ekam dluoc yehT
.yob eht dessimsid raugaj eht
,gniwonk rehtie tuohtiW
.elzzum s’etoyoc eht ekorts ot pu gnihcaer ,dias eh