.erohw on saw ahsaS ,em ot tuB
.dah syawla eh sa
.keew txen uoy rof seirots wen eb ll'ereht dna
.egap ruFikiW ro AF sih no seirots sih fo erom ot sknil dnif nac uoY
.noitautis siht otni gnitteg emit tsrif ym s’ti taht pleh t’ndid ti dna
;lortnoc lluf rof ecnahc eht tog eh tnemom eht
.ecitsuj ti od t’ndid stigid nwo s’eno dna ,taht ekil em detartenep eh ecnis elihw a neeb s’tI
,siht yas I fi em nodraP
.gnimoceb ot esolc emac yadot sgniht woh ekiL
.ti hguorht sworruf gninnur ,ruf ylleb ym hguorht swalc sih dekar ahsaS
.ydaer saw tseuqer ym fi ees ot tnew ehs elihw
.deworran seye s’ahsaS
.enihw deniap a sa tuo emac ti tub
.detpecca ro derised rehto eht tahw gnidnif yllautneve ,ecnereferp ro knik ralucitrap yna rof ksa ot deen eht was su fo rehtieN
.em dniheb tuhs rood eht gnihsup
,trihs ym rednu swap sih dekooh neht elbas ehT
.xof yppah tsom a eb dluow I ,degdujsim I eno eht htiw thgin erom eno ylno dah I fi nevE .ot
.esirprus sih ni hctiwt kcid s’ahsaS leef tsomla dluoc I
.deilper ahsaS ”,efil fo ytilauq rieht evorpmi ot mia syawla dluohs eno tuB
”?raed ,thginot ekil uoy dluow tahW“
.esroh a neve dna ,tevic fo epyt a ,terref ,goD
,ygolohtna SEXOF :SDEERB
,irauR nosmirC yb
.sepyt eninac gnireenimod esoht htiw yllaicepse ,setamdeb ralupop era sexof ,noitseuq ruoy rewsna oT“
”.won gnitaehc s’taht eno eht er’uoy ,sediseB .ti si sihT .od ot krow tog ev’I uoy dlot I .saw I lleh ekiL“
.em htaeneb rufylleb ym gnitaoc htmraw fo tsrub a ,niap neddus eht ta niaga deppiy I
.em ta yawa hsaw dna kaos snoitasnes eht gnittel ,tsehc ym htaeneb elzzum ym deirub dna steehsdeb eht deppirg I
.won tuo kcab llits dluoc I
,nur ot rehtehw ediced t’ndluoc I dna ,won yb detcilfnoc rehtar erew snoitome yM
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
”?yot kcuf A ?sa em ees uoy tahw taht sI“
.sknik rieht dna stsul rieht ,seicnaf dna smihw nwo rieht ot tcejbus
,irauR nosmirC yb uoy rof daer ,floWisakiM yb
,s’naicisyhp ro s’tsitned a ni dnif dluow eno slairetam gnidaer lausu eht dah osla moor ehT
”?uoy no taehc t’nod I os tsuj ,pu tnep lla ti peek ot ti si drah woh wonk uoy oD“
,taht ekil gnihtyna ro gnitaehc yb layolsid neeb t’ndah ahsaS hguohT
,lley ot detnaw I
.sredluohs sih fo dloh koot I dna ,revewoh ,sih naht regnol erew swap yM
.elihw siht lla em deined d’eh tahw rof desop dna dekan won ,yad yreve dna hcae ot denruter I elbas eht
.sdrow rof ssol a ta saw eh ekil dekool ti ,ecno rof dna
,deb eht tsniaga gnitser tsehc ym htiw revo em pilf ot thguos swap sih nehT
?kcab yaw eht no uoy
.raeb dehsaba na ekil kool reh edam tub ,elggig evitunimid a eb ot dah tahw ni elzzum reh derevoc ehS ”!nuf evah ,no oG“
.yhw swonk ydobon
.gnitsrub fo tniop eht ot debbur saw tfahs ym
.ti tuohguorht decaps smoor htiw rodirroc depahs-U a saw roolf dnoces ehT
,kcab wap ym deppirg ahsaS
,gnidliub tnemtrapa denoihsaf-dlo ro letoh a ekil hcum ,derebmun saw rood hcaE
.maerd a eb ot tuo denrut ti tsel ahsaS rof gnileef
.saw reven elbas ym tuB
.efil ym ni stnatsnoc wef eht fo eno
.retsaf detnaw syawla eh esuoh
.tfahs ym revo dedilg yllacitcarp taht steehsdeb yklis htiw ,tfos erew ereh eno eht tub
.siht hguorht teg ot dedeen I lla saw taht dna ,em mih dna
.dnufer a uoy gnitteg tuoba ees nac I
.emit a ta owt sriats eht gnilacs ,eciwt gnillet on dedeen I
.did I naht erom saw ti denoitnem dleif ralimis a ni dekrow ohw enim fo dneirf a tub
.gnillol dna tuo eugnot ym ,noitom gnitator a ni dekcik teef ym
dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
”.yawyna kaerb a esu dluoc uoy ekil kool uoY
aera gnitiaw a ni tiaw ot em dib ehS
.detnaw I gnihtyna tseuqer yllanif dluoc I dna
.kcab shtnom elpuoc a zib eht otni tnew taht yob a tuoba wenk ehs etanutrof tsuj saw tI .nommoc t’nsaw
,”tekraM thgiN“ eht sa nwonk tcirtsiD thgiL deR eht ot dedaeh yffilC ,emit tsaL
,mih no citsillab lla og ot gniog ton m’I taht deveiler ,ahsaS dna ,tnemegdelwonkca ni demmuh I
.emit gnol a rof neeb d’eh naht deticxe erom saw eh dezilaer I dna ,em revo dehsaw rogiv fo
?emoh ta kaerb a ekat ot esimorp uoy od ,emit-trap uoy fo ecalp ni ereh krow ,yas ,ot erew I fI
,ssa ym nopu erusserp railimaf tsomla taht tlef I nehT
,uoy htiw ni devom I tey tuB
.eerf syawla t’nsaw xes tegrof ot ysae saw tI .snaej ym fo tuo tellaw ym dehsif I ?hcum woh ,yrroS“
.htmraw fo gniruoptuo na yb dewollof ssa ym ni sehctiwt drah lareves htiw
,llew ;gnineppah s’tahw em llet t’nod uoy nehw tub ,ereh gnikrow retfa derit er’uoy fi dnatsrednu I
.rehtegot emit ruo dah yllanif ew dalg saw I dna
,kcuf ot owt koot osla ti tub
.gniod s’eh kniht I tahw gniod s’eh fi derednow I sa gnisnet ydob ym
.rehto hcae gnicaf pu dedne ew taht hcus gnola gnillor ahsaS ,edis ym otno dellor I .derettum I ”,siht dessim os I“
.htaehs sih ta gnikool diova ot deliaf dna deirt I dna
.ahsaS dias ”,noitidnoc eno nO“
.sliated tuoba gnirac tsap saw I tub
,boj yad sih ni denrae eh hcum woh ahsaS deksa reven I
.tsaf tuo teg ot dah I esac ni tsuj ,hctocs eht ot eugnot dna rood eht no seye ym tpek I
.raeb ot drah ylbidercni siht edam gnigdol eerf ro
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,ti tsniaga kcab llaf ot nrut ym saw ti dna ,deb eht sdrawot em dereets ahsaS nehT
.ytisnetni sih ta desuap I dna ,degnellahc ahsaS ”?ot tnaw uoy dluow tuB“ ”!wonk
,deb eht ot desserP
.neppah sgniht dab ,rehto hcae htiw emit hguone dneps t’nod elpoep nehw tuB
”—ydaerla hguorht emoc stneilc ruof dah ev’I ?wonk uoy ,thginot ekil thgin a retfa gnirit s’ti taht tsuj s’tI
,elzzum sih desolc dna denepo ahsaS
.dessorc smra reh htiw delims raeb ehT
,noitrexe ruo htiw llef dna esor skcab ruO
.tnelis deniamer I
,seiceps derae-prahs su rof yllaicepse
...keew rep sthgin ynam os ereh krow ot dah llits elbas ym fi tey dnA
fo erutcip tcefrep A
.tuo kcolc yeht ecno stnemtimmoc fo eerf eb ot evresed syob dna slrig gnikrow tub ,ssenisub rof dab ti si ylno toN
.drah yllufniap em gnikam ydaerla saw tnemyojne fo sdnuos eht dna
.su rof erutuf retteb a sdrawot krow I esuaceb tub
.emit-lluf no gningis htrow m’I fi gnidiced emadam eht sdrawot tol a og sremotsuc morf sweiveR
,skeew wef txen eht roF
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na si retrap-owt s'keew sihT
”.htiw yaw ruoy evah dluoc uoy seiceps fo rebmun yna
.hsup mrif a neht
.srehto gnoma snoitacilbuP laoG ,yellaV tibbaR
,dloc gnihtemos htiw eloh ym pu debul eh sa derevihs I dna ,edis eno ot hsurb ym dleh elbas ehT
,kcab deppets ahsaS dna ,drawrof deppets I ”!oN“
”deineD era sdeeN eht nehW“   :yojne esaelP
.htimS niatnuoM eht
.deksa I ”?yrtsudni siht ni sexof der era ralupop woH“ .gnihtemos tuoba derednow I nehT .tsehc ym tsniaga kcab daeh sih yal
taht ti deen did yllaer eh spahrep taht dezilaer I tahT
,gnineppah saw siht eveileb t’ndluoc tsomla I
,ylniatrecnu kcab ym fo pot eht dnuora gnilcric ylwols swap sih ,depsag eh dna esolc elbas ym gnigguh ,tuo lla tnew I
,rehtegot dessim d’ew semit eht fo deirc I
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,dinac yna ekiL
,tenalPruF yb dehsilbup neeb evah skrow siH .)selaT dnuoB woN(
,deretne dna bonkrood eht denrut I
snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb dehsilbup
,emoh ta em rof gnitiaw saw ahsaS
.trap ym gniod eb dluohs I
.gnireenignE ni ton m’I sraey esoht lla gniod
.mih taert ot woh ediced dluoc I ,tsap eht egnahc t’ndluoc ew fi nevE
”.uoy yltsom tub ,oot tahT“
.gnidnatsrednu saw pihsnoitaler yreve fo noitadnuof eht tub ,sesoporp rehto eht tahw tuoba gnihtyreve ekil ton yam su fo rehtiE
,noitom htooms a ni ffo ti gnikat
,mhtyhr raluger tub wols a nageb dna—
.did eh sa deb eht otno kcab gnillaf
s’erehT .ereh emoc evah t’ndluow uoy ,em htiw eb ot detnaw yllaer uoy fI“
nuf fo thgin eno rof tsuj em htiw yats t’ndid ohw nosrep ylno eht ,elbas ym saw siht taht tcaf ehT
,t’ndid tub xes reffo ot deraeppa taht stnemhsilbatse ni gnineppah smacs hcus fo seirots fo draeh ev’I .hctocs eht rof 002$ meht dewo I taht tnemetats a htiw
.snortap eht fo doom eht htiw pleh osla tsum ti
,edam eh evom yreve gnillortnoc
deciton I gniht dnoces ehT
,pu rehto hcae leef dluow su fo owt eht ,yllamroN
.syob dna slrig eht fo wef a gnissarah rof sremotsuc wef a dennab iraB emadaM .si taht
;tsrif ta sraet sih kcab thguof ahsaS
.dedeen fi moor rieht ni soidar latigid eht no nrut syawla dluoc yehT
.yhw swonk doG rof sevruc reh gnitautnecca
,hguorht hsup kcoc sih tlef I nehw deredduhs I
,noitamriffa taht htiw dnA
,erutuf retteb a su teg ot ereh gnikrow er’uoy fi taht derugif tsuj I“
.syad eseht eromyna uoy ees ot teg t’nod I tuB“
,denihw I sa eerf tsrub yllanif sraet dna eromyna ti ekat t’ndluoc I
.od I sa sseccus emas eht evah ot emit emos ekat lliw uoy ekil remocwen a dna ,shtnom wef tsal eht tuohguorht stneilc fo krowten ym pu tliub ev’I tuB
.em ta pu deralg ahsaS
,emit fo tniop siht ta tub
.edistuo nid eht ot yrartnoc ,sriaffa teiuq erew slehtorb fo saera gnitiaw ehT  2 fo 2 traP ,floWisakiM yb
.esle gnihtyna naht desirprus erom ,detorrap ahsaS ”?uoY“
tnecs ehT .saw eh dezilaer I dna ,spih ym edisgnola daerps seenk sih
.ttub ym gniknis sgnaf sih ,tnemom tsal eht ta drawrof tneb ahsaS .rebmemer I naht reduol gnippiy ,emac I neht dnA
.enif saw I fi gnikcehc saw yllaer eh dezilaer I neht
.noitisop ym ni neeb reve dah enoyna eveileb t’nod I tub
.madretsmA ot pirt egelloc taht gnitnuoc ton ,deneppah taht emit tsrif eht eb t’ndluow sihT
.srae sih dekorts I os ,esnet ahsaS tlef I
,owt ot ruof morf sthgin gnikrow ym nwod tuc nac I
”.stseuqer laiceps evah ohw esoht era teg I stneilc eht fo tsom os ,tcartnoc no yllacinhcet llits m’I
.rehgih gnihcaer morf mih deppots reven taht tub ,trohs eb yam elbas yM
,eciohc a rof em gniksa saw ahsaS
.evah reven thgim I
.moor siht hguorht emoc d’ohw srehto ynam os ekil tsuJ
,etam ym dna thgil ym s’eH
,htaerb ym dleh I
.eciohc thgir eht edam d’I dias elzzum sih no esirprus fo kool eht dna ,dias I ”,tnaw uoy revetahW“
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.snaej ym hguorht gnitsrub ylevitisop tfahs
.no gniog esle gnihtemos saw ereht thguoht I
.sevlesmeht ot emit teiuq a detnaw yllareneg elpoep
.4 mooR ni s’eH .thgir nrut dna ,sriats eht pu daeh tsuJ .uoy rof ydaer s’yob ruoY .raed ,oY“
.ereh dekrow taht srehto eht ekilnu ,sriatsnwod sretsop eht ni derutaef t’nsaw ahsaS gnirebmemer ,deddon I
.derepracs I fi sgnileef dab yna eb t’ndluow ereht os ,diap neeb ydaerla dah emadam eht dna
.dennalp evah uoy revetahw oD“
,palc ot swap owt sekat ti taht gniyas a stsixe erehT .rof ereht neeb evah dluohs eh gnihtemos gnikees
.si ssenisub siht evititepmoc woh dnatsrednu uoy dna—“
,efil ruoy lla doohrobhgien elbanoitseuq a ni tnemtrapa nwod-nur a ni evil ot tnaw yllaer uoy oD
;ahpla eht yalp ot tnaw syawla setoyoc dna sevloW ,sgoD
.owt eht fo etuloser erom eht neeb syawla d’eh
.deined ylitsah I ”!raed ,oN“
.ytuaeb eniletsum
”.rof diap ev’I revetahw od ot uoy tnaw I“
.fracs redluohs reh ni erehwemos hsac eht detekcop emadam ehT ”.esuoh eht no s’hctocs ehT .derdnuh ruoF“
sih deraelc ahsaS
.ma I sa xes ni citsaisuhtne taht lla mees t’nod uoy tub
rab eht morf ogriV no hctocs a dah I
.nwo reh no srecnuob owt eb llew yrev dluoc ehs ,ezis reh morF
ot thgir a tog ev’I ,tuo flesruoy gnirohw neeb ev’uoy fI
,sredluohs ym ot sedis ym morf sih detacoler neht
.ti dnuora rebmu krad eht yb detautnecca
,kcab dehcaer I dna
,dnatsrednu
.snoitom eht hguorht og ot woh stegrof reve eno on tub ,elihw a neeb s’tI
.kcab em peek ot dehctertstuo swap sih ,pu kcab gnitteg deirt eH
,em evas ,ytpme saw moor gnitiaw ehT
.su neewteb detsixe yltnecer ylno taht murdnunoc gniylrednu eht
.mih I dna ,em ta kcab yltnetni derats ahsaS
,su rof siht lla gniod neeb ev’uoY“
deb eht morf ssorca decalp rorrim eht ni ti ees dluoc I—elims a evag ahsaS ”.enif eb ll’I
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
.eciohc rehto on dah yeht gniveileb ,rehto eht no gnitaehc saw eno derevocsid ohw elpuoc a erew eW
.did eh sa sesion gnihsuh gnikam ,kcab ym nwod dna pu gnikorts elbas ym
,mih fo tohsotohp lluf a gnitteg no dediced t’ndah rehtie tnemeganam eht os ,revewoh ,selam elbas yna ees t’ndluoc I
”deineD era sdeeN eht nehW“
fo trap lanif dna
.iraB emadaM htiw noitisop etaidemmi na uoy teg nac I erus m’I dna
.em dellif ti sa gninihw sa hcum sa gninaorg
,niorg sih ot kcen sih morf gniliart
.tnih eht teg ot em rof tnemom a koot tI .em fo tnorf ni deppets yllausac madam eht tub ,sriats eht rof edam I ”,thgir s’tahT“
htimS niatnuoM eht
,oobat saw xes taht ni devil ew yteicos eht yb pu thguorb neeb lla d’eW
.saw remotsuc txen sih ohw tlems dna was eh nehw thgirpu gnittis elbas eht ,rehtona eno ta derats su fo owt ehT
uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT
maerd a fo hcum woh ezilaer t’nod yeht tub ,ni yenom rieht tup yeht reverehw evol dnif dluoc yeht thguoht wef A
,noisseforp siht ni animats dna msaisuhtne evah ot sdeen enO
deineD era sdeeN eht nehW“
,tem tsrif ew nehw dah ew yaw emas eht hcum
.serised dna stnaw eh tahw rekrow xes a dlot dna
,lamron sa stfihs ym krow ll’I
,ti yojne I esuaceb ton erehm’I ?em htiw xes erom evah dluoc uoy os tsuj ,gnikrow morf em deppots evah uoy dluow ,emoh emoc I emit hcae doom eht ni ton dna detsuahxe m’I yhw nosaer eht nwonk d’uoy fI“ .srentrap gnirraps ekil rehtona hcae detcelfed stnemugra nwo ruo neve ,ekila hcum yrev os erew su fo owt ehT
,ti pu detnaw yeht revetahw evohs sregnarts etelpmoc tel eh taht hcus ,hcum
.edisni gnol os dleh I hcti taht ta gnihctarcs evom hcae
,dorp eltneg a tsrif
neeb ev’I tahw wonk ot tnaw dluow erutuf eht ni rof ylppa I sboj yna esiwrehto ,emit lluf krow t’nac I tub ,boj yad ym naht retteb raf syap boj sihT
.I sa tfihs emas eht no thgin rep syad owt krow ylno ll’uoy dna
.ereht morf yllarutan og sgniht tel dna
.dednetni I naht rehsah deilper I ”!oN“
,deb eht otni knas I sa denaorg I
,em ediseb elbas ym fo tnecs eht peed dehtaerb I
,taht deirt I fi nrub lufniap a em evag emoh ta sserttam eht ,yllamroN
.krow siht ekam dluoc ew deveileb I tub ,tnemegnarra siht htiw raey a fo trap retteb eht rof krow ot evah dluow eW
.detnaw I tahw tog I sa gnol sa dnim t’ndid I
.yb og ot gnihtyna saw eson ym fi ,oot detnecS .ecneibma tfos a ffo gnivig ,seldnac yb til saw moor eht taht saw devresbo I gniht tsrif ehT
.em rof boj eht fo trap lla s’ti ;serised dna stnaw rieht ,stneilc yM
,yaw siht tca ot em del d’eh taht hsiugna fo sraet
.doom eht ni sremotsuc laitnetop teg ot erew edistuo srekaepsduol eht morf dnuos eht taht denialpxe ogriV
.em morf yawa gnikool seye rebma tfos ,ffo swap ym llup ot edam ahsaS .dias I ”,ti teg I
rufrednu etihw sih ,deb eht no kcab gniyl elbas eht saw
.esle enoemos dnif retteb d’eh neht ,llew ,efil ym fo tser eht rof xes tuohtiw og ot em stcepxe eh fI
.tsehc yffulf ym otni elzzum sih gnibbur
.erofeb dah ew noisulli eht ot kcab og dluoc I ron ahsaS rehtien dna ,ereh won m’I taht sniamer revewoh tcaf ehT
lluf a t’nsaw eh ro
.desnet I sa ylf ym denetsafnu swap decitcarp-lleW
.ssalg ym fo eceiphtuom eht hguorht ylthgil gnippal ,detiaw I elihw
.detpecca yldalg I htmraw fo teknalb rehtona
,tcefrep t’nsaw gnifoorpdnuoS
.ekohc a otni gniyd-flah eciov ,delrans I ”!uoY“
.swap elbas gniogtuo yb nwod yaw eht lla thguorb ti evah ot ylno ,stnap ym ffo kcik ot detrats I
,edisni peed tub ,serised hsifles nwo ym gniusrup tsuj m’I fi mrifnoc rehtruf ot ,egnellahc a saw sihT
,eerf kaerb ot gniyrt deppots ahsaS
”.derit os kcab emoc syawla uoy dnA .enif s’gnihtyreve ekil tca ew elihw elpoep rehto gnikcuf s’dneirfyob ym taht egnarts sleef tsuj ti ,od uoy fi dedneffo eb t’now I“
.ecitcarp fo ytnelp dah s’eH
,gnisitrevda morf edisA
,htnom a naht erom rof em htiw kcuts ohw eno ylno eht s’ahsaS
.su neewteb degnahc s’gnihtoN“
.srae ym gnilkcit stnap sih tlef I llits tub ,kcab reppu ym ylno dehcaer daeh siH
.nedrub eht yrrac ot sesufer taht xof sih rof setah eh gnihtemos gniod elbas ym evah t’nac I
.ti dekil I yaw eht stsurht sih fo mutnemom eht gnillortnoc dna gnigassam ,sredluohs ym dleh swap sih elihw detsurht spih siH
”.yffilC ,uoy gnivol deppots reven I
.ynapmoc s’rehto hcae yojne ot tsuj krow s’yad drah a retfa devil yeht erehw ot kcab thgiarts emac taht
.gnihtemos rof tnuoc ot tog s’taht ekil ytlayol dna
,ereht ti dleh eh sa srae ym debbur ahsaS
,emac sraet sih nehT
.gniog peek nac I taht os uoy htiw sgniht ffo dleh I fi yrros m’I dna
.ylird detnemmoc ahsaS ”?dessim uoy xes tsuj ti saW“
.ssa ym ni ssenthgit mraw taht yb deilpitlum niorg ym ni noisnet eht
.raey eno tsal eht ni sevren ruoy no gnitteg neeb ylbaborp evah dna ,elohssa dexesrevo na neeb ev’I wonk I
.srae detfil ym ni gnilkcit mraw a htaerb sih ,em ot esolc denael ahsaS
.gig siht ni sremotsuc rieht esoohc syawla t’nac eno tub ,remotsuc a hcus eganam dluoc elbas eht woh enigami t’ndluoc I
?tey iraB emadaM diap uoy evaH“ .taorht
,etarepsed em llaC
.ylraluger desnepsid gnieb reifitnecsed gnitseggus enip fo tnecs gniylrednu eht htiw ,lasuora dna ksum fo knits t’ndid moor gnitiaw eht ,erofeb ereh tas evah dluow taht eletneilc ynroh eht etipseD
,laep laref tsomla na ni dehceercs ahsaS
.sffur keehc ym tsniaga tfaw htaerb sih tel eh sa ylthgil gnigassam
.flesym desopmoc I sa rood eht ta doots I
.meht ot traeh ym evag reven I tub ,thgir erew uoY“
.em ot pu derebmul sserd a ni madam raeb htols a dna ,revewoh ,drow reh sa doog sa saw ogriV
.deppans ahsaS ”,won era uoy erehw ta kool tsuJ .ti tbuod I“
.ffo syad ruo no rehtegot emit dneps ot elba eb dna ,smoor tnereffid ni gnieb etipsed rehto hcae no eye na peek nac ew ,yaw sihT
dluow I ,hsac artxe rof did eh tahw em dlot d’eh fi taht decnivnoc saw em fo traP
.gnisimorpmoc osla saw ti
,ahsaS saw deb eht no elbas eht taht saw dezilaer I gniht driht ehT
”?ecivres thgin-lluf a gnikoob eb ll’uoy dias ogriV
eht ni deraeppa ylremrof sah ”deineD era sdeeN eht nehW“
,4 mooR ot revo deddap I
.eromyna emoh ta uoy ees yldrah I“
”…rre ,erew uoy ebyam ekiL
,pmur ym revo flesmih denoitisop eh nehT
,edisni erew yeht ecnO
llik ro bor efilwol emos evah ot ylno
.deilper I ”,ti tnaw t’nod I“
,teef sih ot tog elbas ehT
.selims dna stlep rieht tpecxe gnihton ni desserd ,ereh dekrow taht syug ro slrig eht fo sretsop dedulcni osla tub
.sedivorp tnemhsilbatse eht ffuts edarg-hgih eht ylekil tsom
.enihw deniap tsomla na ot desaec gnipmuht ym erehw cas ym ot nwod swalc sih werd eh
.hcnilf t’ndid ahsaS ,tiderc sih oT
.eno doog a elbas ym kcos ro ,yats
.deksa I ”?ereh krow ot dnetni llits uoy oD“ ”.uoy erussa I taht ,yffilC ,evol ylno ym era uoY
.hcum os ti dedeen eh fi ,ssa sih pu hsac denrae-drah ym evohs dluoc eh elbas eht gnillet deredisnoc I ,tnemom a roF ”.dnufer
.mih tuoba stiw sih tpek syawla elbas ym tub ,taht lla retfa ypeels dna dexaler lla teg yllamron dluow I
,deggar gnimoceb detrats stnap yM
seiceps dna redneg fo noitanibmoc detseuqer ym ,snoitatneiro lla ot gniretac tekraM thgiN eht etipsed taht denialpxe ydaerla nexiv ehT
.ereh stnecs fo xim a saw erehT
,su fo htob eht rof dnA
.esnefed a sa gniod saw I revetahw esu ot evren eht dah eh taht suoiruf ,derettulps I ”—uoy—tahW“ .nmaD
evah t’nseod ti tuB
.sllaw dna sgniliec eht hguorht tuo kcip dluoc srae ym gninaom dna gnipmuht fo sdnuos tniaf eht rof ton ti erew ytiralupopnu s’lehtorb eht fo ngis a sa ti nees evah dluow I dna
.teerts yaw-owt a saw ytlayol taht flesym dlot I neht tuB
syad ruof dekrow I fi esuaceb ,eerga ylluf t’ndid I ”?laed a taht sI .tiuq ew ,erehwesle evom ot yenom hguone teg ew ecno dnA.ffo
,em fo pot no depmuls ahsaS
,dehsilbatse erom teg uoy ecnO
,sfeirb ym fo eerf gnurps htaehs yM
.eson gnilffins ym deppat I ”.wonk I“
!tnaem I tahw wonk uoY“
.hceercs a ot esor eciov siH
.gnieb sih fo strap rehto eht htiw ynohpmys ni gnikrow
,srae ym dellif skcams tfos fo dnuos ehT
”.emit gnol yrev a rof dessim ev’I gnihtemos ,niaga uoy htiw siht erahs ot tnaw hcum yrev I tuB
.did ti sa gnibbob lasuora ym fo der eht
.xaler ot flesym decrof I sa spsag kciuq ni gnimoc saw htaerb yM
.did eh sa hcum sa mih rof erac I swonk elbas ym
.derettalc sgnaf sih llit diletsum elttil ykaens taht ekahs dna drawrof pets ot hcum yrev gnitnaw ,gnilley won saw I ”!elihw siht lla em ot deil uoY ?taht yb naem uoy od kcuf eht tahW“
.em revo gnihsaw hsulf mraw a
,reve emit tsrif eht rof tuB
.yffilC ,taht wonk I“
”!flesruoy fo emos em nevig evah llits dluoc uoY“
,larrefer reh morf noissimmoc a nrae ylbaborp dluow ehs desseug I
.krow evitca morf deriter gnol evah thgim ehs gnitseggus ,tnecs a fo hcum ffo evag ylerab ehS
taht teg dluoc ew
.muc em gniees no tsisni neve wef a dna ,llew sa emit doog a gnivahs’gnikcuf er’yeht yot yob eht ekil leef ot ekil stneilc emoS
.seye ym otni kcab dekool yllanif dna
.enola ton er’uoy taht os
,revewoh ,demmirt-llew ruf reh tpek ehS
.seod yllausu ti sa ti otno gnihctac elzzum ym fo nihc eht tuohtiw
.snoitartsinim ym ni enola regnol on saw I em gnidnimer ,ecneserp laudarg a otni yawa dellud won dah tlef dah I erusserp laitini eht dna
”?em ta kcab eno teg ot gniyrt uoy erA“
.doohrobhgien doog a ni tnemtrapa rehtona su teg ot elba eb t’now sgnivas tnerruc ruO .gnidliub eht snwo taht droldnal eht tuo yub syawla dluoc tnemnrevog eht os ,aera tnempoleveder dennalp a no s’tI
,spil s’elbas ym no gnicnad elims A
.edisa ti devaw I tub ,tsetorp ot edam ahsaS
”.evom ot yenom hguone tog ev’ew llit ereh eb llits ll’I ,sey oS
.retirw yranecreM floW naeropagniS a ,floWisakiM yb
.elbas ym no gnitaehc tuoba ytliug leef ot evah t’now I dna ,kaerb eht rof dalg eb neve dluow edisni yob ehT
.em tsniaga daeh sih degguh I
.os erom neve edart eht ni devlovni elpoep eht dna
.srood eht htaeneb gniffihw ksum fo tnih tniaf eht htiw ,reduol erew snaorg dna snaom fo sdnuos eht ,ereH
,em gnitnuat saw eh thguoht I tsrif tA
.ni tes noitazilaer sa gniweks srae
,hguone noos gniraeppa srecnuob suomrone owt htiw ,no em gnivah s’ogriV ebyam rO .remit-
.em pota thgir gnillaf elbas ym
.deksa ahsaS ”?esle enoemos gnikcuF“
,saw hturt eht tub
,tsiser t’ndid ahsaS
.swap nwo ym otni srettam ekat ot thgir yreve dah I tnaem dedeen I tahw em evig t’ndid eh taht tcaf eht
.derepsihw eh ”,ot em ksa uoy fi pots nac I“
.reverof eb ot gniog t’nsi gnidliub tnemtrapa eht no esael eht ,doohrobhgien ruoy ni yats ew sraey eht lla ni deggum teg t’nod ew fi nevE“
eseht piks nac uoy
.deksa I ”?elbas elam a rof deksa I kniht uoy did yhW“
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.detcepxe yffilC tahw ton saw tI
,rehtegot gnivil elpuoc yppah a regnol on erew eW
,sedisni ym ta gnillup dna gnihcterts
.etam lufrednow a hcus ot layarteb ym dna