,thgin yreve esolc-os-ho gniyl yb em detpmet ahsaS tey dnA
.dnekeew tsol a ro emit no kcab gniog neewteb ecnereffid eht ekam dluoc noitatnemucod etunim-tsal enani emos woh sa hcus
.esuoh eht ni stohs eht dellac ehs ;am ym tuB
.ti tuoba gnikniht tsuj—redrah tnaem I—drah em edam tI
.keehc ym no elzzun a htiw tfel eh erofeb etib kciuq a dah ew erehw
ot pu neeb d’eh tahw ssob sih llet ylbissop t’nac eh dna ,tihs ekil gnikool krow ot semoc eh fi mih erif ot denetaerht ydaerla dah ssob sih dias eH
,emitefil a fo ecneirepxe eht teg eh lliW ?og yffilC lliw raf woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.tem tsrif d’ew nehw citsaisuhtne neve ,citegrene saw erus eh tub ,setamdeb fo delliks tsom eht t’nsaw ahsaS .elbaS ...elbas
,htnom lluf a rof no tnew sthgin evitucesnoc eerht naht regnol gnitsal pihsnoitaler tsrif dna ,suoiverp ym ,detnarG .pihsnoitaler a ni neeb ev’I emit tsrif eht t’nsaw tI
.lasuora ym fo tnecs eht ,enorD cillahP eht gnisseraC xoF eht fo esac eht ni dnA
.lrigwoc edor ehs nehw em fo tuo efil eht dehsauqs raen taht raeb-ehs siht neve saw ereht
.rehto hcae rof edam er’ew ekil tsomla s’tI .I dna ahsaS neewteb shgual fo ytnelp erew ereht tub ,renwo egnar eht htiw semit wef a elbuort ni em tog tahT
,ti was I yaw tub ,gnitaehc saw siht tlef em fo trap A
.thgir er’uoy ,isaK ,lleW .thgiR“
.xe taht sgniht no sgat repap evah t’nod yehT
.htimS niatnuoM eht
.sorb ym dna em evah ot did yeht revetahw delbmeser taht
,noitacude dna sboj doog gnivah no sevlesruo dedirp sexof eW
,yad eht fo ecaps eht ni semit lareves erocs dna no ppa rdnirG rieht htiw dnuora esiurc ohw syug yreviled dna seibbac fo draeh ev’I .gniklat tnemtraped elohw eht teg dna ,ot pu neeb ev’I tahw fo ffihw a hctac thgim seugaelloc emos ,srewohs eciffo eht ot thgiarts og I fi nevE .retfa thgiarts krow ot kcab nur ot tog ev’I sselnu ,ecnereffid a ekam t’ndid tI .yad rO
,yas yeht sa ,taht dnA
.gnikat erew ew sdaor eht ezingocer t’ndluoc tsomla I dna ,devil I erehw tcirtsid laitnediser eht tfel d’eW
.retirw yranecreM floW naeropagniS a ,floWisakiM yb
.erofeb thgin eht
,ylisae ylriaf sesroh dna stac fo esoht yfitnedi dluoc I
.taht lla dna sredro gnivig ot emac ti nehw niap a eb nac yeht tub
.won raey a tuoba rof rehtegot neeb dah eW
.keew txen uoy rof seirots wen eb ll'ereht dna
.seiretae dna sllats tiurf sti rof suomaf saw hcihw ,aera eht ot tnecajda steerts eht ot snoitcerid nevig daetsni d’I .ereht em gnirb ot saw ohw revird eht fo erats tnelis drah eht ecaf dna ”,tcirtsiD thgiL deR eht ot daeH“ yas ot gniht enif a eb
,rovas ot setsat ynam os ,tisiv ot stnemhsilbatse ynam os erew erehT
.kcab eht no tas I sa
,esirprus ni nups I dna ylthgil liat ym deppirg enoemoS
.noisiced ym edam I ,em htaeneb ro evoba ydob mraw a tuohtiw htnom dr3 eht yB
.fles netaeb-yldab ym yfitnedi ot dedeen enoemos esac ni ,DI s’revirD
.enim t’nsaw taht ecalp a ta revo peels enoyna evah yltcaxe t’nac I dna
.denilcni os m’I fi mih etsat neve dna ,tnecs sih ni htaerb
.eromyna mih was ylerar I taht hcus erew sgnihT
.dehgual setoyoc dna sevlow yaw eht yb tuo depeerc neeb syawla ev’I
”.ot ffuts eht su nevig evah t’ndluow eh ,gnikcuf su tnaw t’ndid evoba yug gib eht fI
.tsrif dnuora kool a ekat ot em dlot esidnahcrem tnereffid yleritne rof gnippohs fo sraey tub ,neht dna ereht thgir reh erih ot detpmet em dah
,irauR nosmirC yb
.noisneherppa ym no thgiew dah llits htuoy ym fo seirots eht tub ,won pu denaelc lla eb ot desoppus s’tI
.naem I ,ylevitarugiF
.seot ot daeh reh morf gnillevart seye ,reh ta epaga derats I
.evig dluow mih ekil enoemoS
.tfihs sih ffo saw eh nehw retal ti tuoba erom klat dluoc ew em dlot neht eH
era erehT .nos ,uoy gnigduj ton m’I“
.detiawa noitatnemucod sseltniop dna sessob enasni erehw ,eciffo eht ot tnew ew ffo nehT
taeh no nexiv a fo taht gnilbmeser
.derettuts I ”,sknaht ,oN“
edis a morf sretem ytxis doog a gnieb yb ,ssenevisurtbonu fo ecnalbmes emos niatniam ot gniyrt etipsed taht tuo denrut tI
,raeb ro god er’uoy fi rettam t’nseod tI
.em deliassa tekraM thgiN eht fo sdnuos dna sthgis eht erehw ,erauqs niam eht otni deppets I nehT
dah hcihw ,seiretae lareves morf detaname
.enoyna ot dettimmoc t’nerew uoy nehw tseb dekrow yeht taht erew sdnats-thgin-eno htiw melborp eht tuB
,doog erew stnerap yM
rehtegot llits er’owt uoy taht tcaf ehT
.drawretfa ruos dna detartsurf gnileef em tfel syawla dna
.emit hcae ahsaS htiw pu tem dna syad fo elpuoc txen eht wohS riA eht ot denruter I
,tuo thgin a rof nekat d’ew sub eht ni staes owt pu gnikat raeb a ot pu doots neve elbas ym
.em rof taht lla did regnol on eh
,ekila nrob lla t’nera sklof tuB“
.wohS riA eht ot kcab tuB
,htiw efil dna emit ruoy dneps ot stseretni ralimis fo enoemos dnif dluohs eno taht dias syawla daD
.pu rehto hcae leef saw did ew lla ,emit doog a mih wohs ot dereffo I hguoht dna
.eb yam snortap secnereferp revetahw rof srehto naht ralupop erom eb dluow seiceps emos ,dias tahT
.peels ot teg neve t’ndluoc I taht hcus
.em sekat ycnaf eht erehw no desab noisiced a ekam dna
,dlrow eht ssorca stcirtsiD thgiL deR ynam ekiL
thgiarts rehtien saw I
.stnecs gniylrevo regnorts eht htaeneb sllems renif eht tuo gnikcip ot desu saw eh taht tnaem elbas a gnieb dna
.erofeb shtnom xis tnemtrapa latner ym otni devom dah ahsaS
.gat ecirp rallod noillim 5.2 eht tegrof
.sgel ytniad dna suoutpulov lla ,flesti dewohs seniltuo seiceps fo dairym a ni detfarc sngis noen eroM
syella dna sedis eht morf gnihctaw eb thgim ohw enoyna rof dnuora gniffins ,teerts eht nwod dna pu dellorts I ,detiaw I elihw dna ,bac a dellac I
.evig dluow eno devol a ecivda gninaem-llew sa ti dootsrednu I taht tcaf eht rof ton ti erew ,seitilibisnes ym fo enoemos ot ngis gninraw a neeb evah dluow tahT
.ytiralupop tub ,seiceps ot gnidrocca decirp yllareneg t’nerew slrig dna syob gnikrow ,gnidnatsrednu ym morF
.ezoob no detsaw neeb d’eh ekil leef t’nseod eh taht os ygrene sih evresnoc ot dedeen eh syas eH
.saw yug siht rehcaerp emos ,huH
1 traP ,floWisakiM yb
.erutan evissimbus a ot eud saw ti eveileb ot hguone evian t’nsaw I dna
.taht retfa ti otni etiuq t’nsaw eh ees dluoc I tub ,emit eht fo flah detneler ahsaS ?I t’nia ,gninnuC .eno fo daetsni syad eerht ro owt yreve yalp ot mih gniksa saw I taht os segru ym kcab gnidloh ,desimorpmoc I oS
.pot a saw eh sa mottob a citsaisuhtne sa saw eh ;noitauqe eht fo edis eno no ylroop mrofrep ro ti ekil t’ndid eh taht toN
.saw I sa ti tuoba suolaez sa ton s’eh ,saw gniht ehT
.ezag eht denruter I sa ylgniwonk dennirg eH
,emoh edir eht rof hsac hguonE
,trats eht morf ffo ti tih I dna ahsaS taht tcaf ehT .eurt tub ,cigarT
.gniog gniht doog a dah eW .taht saw
,em gniyned saw elbas ym tahw em dednimer ksum nwo ym fo tnecs enol eht
,ot em dlot yeht snossel dna sloohcs eht lla eht ot tnew I
emufrep a yb detautnecca ,tnecs reH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
?yak‘ ,kcab s’rehto hcae dniheb dnuora gnikcuf oN
.efil rieht ni tniop emos ta tcnitsni eht sleef enoyreve ,erah ro flow
,sediseB .eb ti tel I
.retteb rehto hcae wonk ot tog neht eW
,gnilerrauq detrats ew taht retfa semit neves tuobA
.sdnuos dna sthgis eht hctac ot elzzum ym detfil I dna
.raef llems dluoc seninac ew—ti esruc esuaceb ,mlac yats ot thguof I .deksa I ”?naem uoy od tahW“
.esion elbigilletninu na otni gnirednaem lla ,stnioj elpitlum morf draeh eb dluoc cisum gnimoob duoL
,gniod neeb d’eh krow drah taht lla rof mih ot pu ti ekam ot detnaw em fo traP
.ytic siht ot devom I ecnis reve gniog neeb d’I os ,hsoohw dna moob seog taht dnik eht yllaicepse ,ygolonhcet rof eno syawla saw I
.gninaem ym teg uoy fi ,noitca drah yna rof elbatius os ton hguoht
,devirra bac ym sa teerts eht fo sdne htob nwod kool tsal a koot I
ylkciuq snoitcerid gnivig
.ecin yalp reve ylerar yeht dna ,erofeb srecnuob htiw ecneirepxe na ynam dah ev’I
.rehto ro ynapmoc emos yb tliub enord dennamnu na gninimaxe saw I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.taht naht rehtruf yna thguoht ton d’I ,parC
,irauR nosmirC yb uoy rof daer ,floWisakiM yb
snoitacilbuP lwoH notsruhT yb dehsilbup
.deilper isaK ”,neppah ot ti rof snosaer nommoc erom eht fo eno s’tI .dnatsrednu od I“
”,tnereffid on m’I
,lasopsid ym ta ti evah ot ekil eb dluow ti tahw gnirednow em dah ngised cillahp tsom sti htiw gnola sevruc keels eht tuoba gnihtemoS
taht si sexof tuoba sgniht ehT
,tenalPruF yb dehsilbup neeb evah skrow siH .)selaT dnuoB woN(
,revo tew lla gnitteg saw I enord esohw ynapmoc eht gnitneserper saw eH
.os erom neve eb dluoc eh
”...tub ,mih no esopmi ot thgir ym s’ti taht toN
.ton ro cibohpomoh saw eh fi eguag ot gniyrt
.tis elpuoc rehtona gnittel
;ygolonhcet yratilim no pu gnidaer sekil eH
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
,dloheb dna ol tuB
?ytirgetni sih fo tfel s’revetahw esol ro
,gnireenignE ni boj yad ym ta dnah-tsrif esu dluoc I egdelwonk toN
.kcehc ni flesym tpek I os ,I sa emas ,emit taht ta derit laer syawla saw eh tub
.kool reciohc a rof tekraM eht otni repeed daeh ot gnidiced
.dedeen nam yreve tahw emyned ot mih fo lanimirc s’ti dna
.evah t’ndid I eludehcs rieht htiw ytilibixelf a evah yeht hguoht
.tuo gniog detrats ew ,noitca eno-no-eno fo ecruos ysae na rof mih htiw pu gnikooh tsuj t’nsaw I erus saw eh nehW
.pirg s’retsocca ym fo tuo gnippils hsurb ym
.ti fo hguone teg t’nac tsuj I ,xof a sA  2 fo
deineD era sdeeN eht nehW“
.”tekraM thgiN ehT“ sa yllacol nwonk
dluow tI .flesti tekraM thgiN eht otni yltcerid dael t’ndid nevig d’I snoitcerid ehT
”.rehtona eno ni swalf dna stluaf eht gniees trats uoy nehw s’taht
ytic eht fo edis tsae eht oT
.htrow s’yenom ym teg llew sa thgim I
,knits ew taht toN
,ytfarc saw I fI .eb ti tel I oS
fracs cirbaf thgil eht hguorht elbisiv stsaerb egral ylrevo ton tub elbaeganam htiw ,detaicerppa hcum yrev htaehs dna seye ym hcihw ,erugif doog a tuc yllaer ehS
m’I gnidneterp dna ereht gniog dekil I
.dedaeh m’I erehw ees thgim wenk I enoemos era secnahc ;noitseuq eht fo tuo saw tropsnart cilbuP
.xof eht delggig ”?emit doog a em wohS ?ereh weN“
.noitaercer dna efil fo trap larutan a saw xes taht tcaf eht dnuor teg t’ndluoc ohw elpoep erew ereht
taht rebmemer ot evah uoy tub ,esle erehwemos ti llac uoy revetahw ro xif ruoy evah og uoy fi enif s’tI
.ffo evig ew tnecs elttil yreve eciton ylisae dluoc seiceps rehto tsom ,taht fo esuaceB
eht ni deraeppa ylremrof ”deineD era sdeeN eht nehW“
.stifeneb elbarusaelp ,llew ,dna
.tnereffid on saw siht dna ,sdinac eht yllaicepse ,neht dna won yreve rac rieht ni reifitnecsed deyarpssrevird bac emoS .rehto
.yenom rieht rof nur a spoort desab-dnuorg evig dluow ti llew woh htiw gnola ,daolyap
.tnedor fo tnecs gniylrednu eht htiw degnit
.ytuD fo llaC gniyalp edisgnola taht gniod dekil I
;edam ev’I seciohc tseb eht gnoma s’tI
.srehto gnoma snoitacilbuP laoG ,yellaV tibbaR
elbignat erom eht htiw gnola
dluow tI .nwonk ti ekam yltcaxe t’ndid tnemnrevog eht hguoht
.taht lla dna doom ,ygrene s’eno setelped ti woh sa hcus ,noitaredom ni nekat eb tsum xes woh detnemmoc d’eh ,pihsnoitaler eht ni ylraE
.seiceps rehto tsom naht tnecs regnorts a evah ot dnet ew
,knuks dna terref ,lesaeW
,ammelid yppah tsom A .yag ron
,yug rehto yna ekil tsuj secnatniauqca dna sdneirf dah ew
?pihsnoitaler desolc a evah ew naC  .yffilC ,yeH
.erehwesle ti dnif ot dah I
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
taht saw hturt eht tuB
.detsetorp I ”—rof deksa I ecalp eht
.spoc revocrednu yb detserra gnieb fo raef rof ,noitasrevnoc rieht ni sdrow edoc esu ot dah snortap ,neht gniruD
.dellac si gnikcuf-fles fo rennam rieht revetahw ro ylpitlum ro tilps ot deen eht ees eabeoma nevE .dedeen msinagro yreve tahw ,lleH
.yna sa enoemos ot noitcudortni na doog na saw ti dnif I tub ,deneppah tsuj ti fi em esucxe ll’uoY
.noitacramed a hcus ot deerga tnemnrevog eht taht timda ot retsinim a rof ladnacs eht etiuq eb
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY.keew
,ereht rof emac I tahw teg ylisae dluoc I ,dias tahT
.erutcip eht teg uoY
.ti ekil t’ndid I fi evael syawla dluoc eh em dlot eh llit
.neht dna won yreve eno doog a evah ot stnaw enoyrevE
.ereht neeb s’isaK dlO dna ,stneilc rieht rof dias eb syawla t’nac emas ehT .slanoisseforp er’yeht tub ,dehcatta teg ot naht retteb wonk serohW
.taht tuoba hturt eht gnillet neeb d’eh derugif I os
?he ,xof sediseb rovalf rehtona yrt ot emoC“
.ot og ot eno hcihw wonk t’ndid I dna
;depleh ylerab ffo gnikcaJ
selbategev demaets dna taem gnitsaor fo llems ehT
.edisa tnemmoc ym devaw etoyoc eht tub ,nageb I ”—ton m’I“ ”!doof eht yojne ot ereht er’yeht em llet neve emoS
.em rof eno eht dnuof d’I wenk I ,slirtson ym ni gnilgnit ksum sih htiw dna ,deifsitas dna gnippird ,taht retfa yletarapes tfel eW
,yap ot evah ot gniog m’I fi tuB
.terref gnihctins a ro lesaew gniyl a si esiwrehto syas ohw enoynA
;sesulcer t’nerew I dna ahsaS
.nees ev’I sthgis eht ,hO .rengised yot xes taerg a edam evah dluow I erus m’I hguoht
.tuo doots tahtretnuocne yna llacer t’ndluoc I ,thgim I sa yrt tub ,secneirepxe ym fo tseb eht delavir taht emit doog a detnaw I
,em ot pu deldis yerg eno dna ,cennef eno ,sexof owT
.ecalpnommoc saw tuo thgin a gnivah yug a erehw osla dna ,yek saw noitercsid erehw erehwemos ,nalp foorploof erom a dedeen I
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na si retrap-owt s'keew sihT
?kniht uoy t’nod ,hctam taerg A
,retteb yxof dlo doog wonk ot gnitteg dnim t’ndid ohw enoemos dnif ot dedeen tsuj I
.hguone ylgniralg seraw sti desitrevda tcirtsid eht ot ecnartne eht ,daor
,esiwrehto ro ssob ,enoyna gnikcuf neeb d’eh ekil llems t’ndid eH
”deineD era sdeeN eht nehW“
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,rehtie rehtegot erew ew shtnom wef tsrif eht rof em ot ti deined yllaer reven eH
.muc ot teg neve t’ndid eH .ffo dezod dah eh taht dnif ot ylno dehsinif I ,mih gnippot saw I nehw ,semit lareveS
,eil ot eno t’nsaw eH .deksa I revenehw ti deined ahsaS tuB
.xes fo noitseuq eht tpecxE
.llew sa seiceps owt esoht sedulcni taht dnA
,ygolohtna SEXOF :SDEERB
.no edir ot eb dluow ti elbatrofmoc dna htooms woh dna ,gniht siht otni tnew taht noisluporp enigne eht tuoba gnirednow osla saw I ,detnarG
.em deciton ahsaS ,srotibihxe dna srotisiv rehto eht ekilnU
.ti fo tuo teg ot em gnidiova seirt neve eH
.serusaerT fo ecalaP ehT naht rehtar
”...rre tub ,gnihtyna ro ytterp t’nera uoy
.seiceps ralimis a fo esoht rof og yllamron dluow snortap derugif I
.em ta deddon revird ehT ”,referp uoy revehcihW .eibbaC rO
”!tahw s’tahw wonk ot hguone gnol zib siht ni neeb ev’I ,noS“
.od yeht nehw sredluohs rieht revo gnikool ,yawa steerts eerht ot owt gnithgila syawlA .tekraM thgiN eht ot yaw gnol eht gnikat ,derevoc ti tog yeht skniht enoyrevE“
.lauqe on ekil daeh eviecer dna evig neve dluoc eH
.isaK em llac nac uoY“
t’nsi sihT“ .denmad eb snoitcerid ,noitanitsed dednetni lautca ym ta ffo ym pord ot dediced isaK dezilaer I neht dna ,epacsteerts eht fo hcum detanimoderp gnithgil kniP .snoitpartnoc gnithgil latigid delgnafwen esoht lla dna noen htiw detanimulli
.keew rehto yreve slrig dna syug htiw pu gnikooh neeb ev’I ,81 denrut I ecniS
;sdnuor emos pop ot egnar eht ot gniog sekil eH
.etelpmoc ot snoitavoner esuoh sih rof gnitiaw s’eh elihw hsarc ot ecalp a dedeen dah eh taht tuo dnuof retal I
.stac rellams rehto htiw tuo gnah rehtar dluow stacdliw dna ,star rehto htiw tuo gnah rehtar dluow star woh ekil hcum ,ytirailimaf seiceps rof dias eb ot gnihtemos saw erehT
.semit ta syadnuS neve dna ,syadkeew gnirud xes gnivah dekil reven ahsaS
,ot denrut I elacs eht fo dne hcihw ees ot tnemirepxe na sa ffo detrats tI
.lagelli saw noitutitsorp nehw syad lainoloc morf revodloh a saw sihT
.gnidaeh er’ew reverehw ot noitcerid etisoppo tcaxe eht ni saw eciffo ym ot etuor sub ehT
.nosrep eht fo trap sa detpecca eb esiwrehto dluow taht swalF
.”retnE“ drow eht ot worra gnitniop-thgir a morf detanretla ngis blub til gnihsalf A
.scitsitats tnemnrevog sseltnuoc ot gnidrocca ,smitciv emoceb ot ylekil erom raf erew htob su sa hcus seiceps rellamS
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
.redro ni ffuts ym tog I ,yad txen eht krow dehsinif I tnemom ehT
.tae ot ereh emac yllautca ohw gnirednow em
,srovaedne hcus rof tcefrep erew llah noitibihxe eht fo shtoob ytpme eht fo emoS
.tnemitnes eht detaicerppa eh raelc saw ti ,seye thgirb dna srae dekaep sih morf tub ,taht lla retfa niaga pu denrut I desirprus saw eH
.dehgual revird eht
,nam-sey a t’nsaw ahsaS
.s .em ekil tsuj der a
;yug knuks eht saw ereht
,eno dellems eh nehw yug pu-tnep a wenk erus ahsaS
.mih htiw deergasid I yas etiuq t’nac I dna
,thgin yreve hcae ot pu tog I tahw gnidnif dekil ev’dluow stnerap ym kniht t’nod I
?taht rof enoyna tluaf yllaer uoy dluoW
.gnihtemos ro ssob eht ffo gnikcus saw eh thguoht yllaitini os ,seugolatac redro-liam morf dna enilno elbaliava tums eht lla daer d’I
.syella eht gninil sdaehkcarc dna sraw gnag sa hcus ,ediS
,dah htob ew tahw ekil ,tsurt no tliub saw pihsnoitaler yreve taht nevig dna
,mih dloh ot detnaw I
,tekraM thgiN eht ta gnikcuf eb dluow I reveohw rof mih gnivael m’I ekil t’nsaw tI
.od ot krow dah eh taht esucxe eht htiw ,etal kcab gnimoc ot koot eh ,no neht morF
.dedaeh m’I erehw wonk yeht emussa t’nod srekoolno taht os ,sehtolc lausac gnittif esooL
”deineD era sdeeN eht nehW“   :yojne esaelP
.elbas siht saw ereht nehT
taht toN“ .tuop kcom a evag nexiv ehT
,swap dna sdrow rieht erongi ot tseb ym did I tub
.ytilibixelf eniletsum fo eutriv a ,ssa ym otni sgnaf ekileldeen sih gniknis
gnihtemos tlems dna draeh yeht fi tif a evah dluow stnerap ym tbuod on ev’I ,ekil-teiuq lla ti ta tnew ew fi nevE
.em gnidiova s’ahsaS naht rehtar gnitaehc ym tnaem eh fi ksa ot evah t’ndid I
.taht kcuF ?tahw wonk uoY
.yug txen eht sa hcum sa xes deyojne ahsaS ,sretnuocne lanosrep erom ruo rof sA
.yna teg ton ot sleef ti woh dnatsrednu t’nseod eh ,dneirfyob ym tuB“
,rae yb ti yalp ot saw nalp ehT
m’I“ .pmur tfel reh no kcams duol evag ehS
.htimS niatnuoM eht
.ti ta tnew ew revenehw snoitom eht hguorht tnew eH
,dnats ot esohc raeb eht
”.yaw eht yb ,ogriV
.em gniwollof saw eno on raelc saw ti nehw feiler fo hgis a gnivaeh ,drawno dellor bac eht sa dniheb dekool I
,dah I yaw eht dnuor esiurc dna ,stuognah lausu ym ot kcab og ot erew I fI
.rehto ro nexiv emos htiw semit fo elpuoc a mih thguac am ym ;hcum oot dnim t’ndluow ylbaborp daD
.daerps dluow sdeed ym fo drow taht ecnahc eht syawla s’ereht
”.pots ruoy s’ereh dnA
.denruter ahsaS erofeb gnol kcab yaw ym ekam dna
.rehtona eno tnemelpmoc ylbaborp secnereffid ruoy taht snaem—gniht mret-trohs a t’nsi siht gnisseug m’I—
.dnuora ssem t’nod ecim eht nevE
,egnar sa hcus serutaef s’enord eht tuoba erom em dlot eH
,thgin eht fo elddim eht ni mih gnipmuj morf em tpek sehsiw sih ylno dna
.taht ekil gnihtyna ro elbas ym gnipmud saw I taht toN
.erehwemos yella na ni su htiw neve teg ot tsuj pu ti gnikcus saw raeb eht esac ni tsuj ,kcab yaw eht lla redluohs ym revo gniffins dna gnikool tpek I
.emas eht od ot enoemos dnif ot evah tsuj dluow I
”.reisae gnitteg strats ti nehT“ .deddon etoyoc eht ”,lla fo yrettij tsom eht s’emit tsrif eht ,eyA“
,yrutnec ts12 eht ni nevE
.ti otni hcum oot gnikniht ylbaborp saw I tub ,em no sbat peek ot eye etavirp a derih ahsaS fi hctib laer a eb dluow tI
.efil rieht ni tniop yreve ,yas I dluohs rO
.em saw yaws t’ndluoc ahsaS nosrep eno eht tuB
.duts elbanoisserpmi na fo secivres eht rof erom derdnuh elpuoc a htiw
.siht evresed t’ndid eh ,serusaelp rehgih ot sdrager htiw msaisuhtne fo kcal sih etipseD
.deb ot gniog erofeb rewohs kciuq a rof og dna ,thgindim retfa tsuj nruter dluow eH
.ti htaeneb lwoh gniylrednu na htiw desrepsretni ,skrab fo otaccats a ekil tol a dednuos tI
.rogiv sih ot tnematset a pruls dna hcleuqs hcae ,tfahs ym ssorca gnicnuob saw eh nehw ti eb gnitnap em evael dluow eH
.xes hguone teg nac eno oN
.skaerb laem dah slrig dna syob gnikrow neve desseug I
,egde eht no em tpek sniol ym ni noisnet elbatrofmocnu na syawla tuB .did yllaer I ,sehsiw s’ahsaS detcepser I
?rehto eht no mrofni t’now wenk ew enoemos yas ot s’ohw dna
.gnihton rof doohtluda fo modeerf eht ti llac t’nod yehT
.meht fo eno ffo gnimoc xes fo hcnets eht ta eson ym delknirw I
.thgin eno rof tsuj erew ti fi neve
.wohS riA eht ta tem I yug siht gniees detrats I nehT .yas dluow I
,ydal regdab eht saw erehT
.em ot tog taht ti fo ycneuqerf sih saw ti tuB
,teerts til-yllufroloc tsom a edistuo thgir erew ew taht ees won dluoc I
?duol tuo taht syas yllautca ohw tsuj tub ,desolc eb ot pihsnoitaler ruo detnaw eh dias reven dah ahsaS
.erom eht lla mih etaicerppa em edam nommoc ni sgniht ynam os htiw
seirots sih fo erom ot sknil dnif nac uoY
.mih htiw eergasid etiuq t’ndluoc I tub ,taht ekil gnihtyna ro suoigiler t’nsaw I
ro tnedor emos ,staes kcab eht morf gnimoc sremotsuc owt tsap eht fo tnecs tniaf a saw erehT
.thgin eno em no liab ot ydnaR dneirfyob-neht ym rof ylno
,yawa evord isaK .dednetni I naht reduol em dniheb rood eht fo duht eht ,detixe dna sknaht ym derettum I .hsac no evas syawla dluoc I tuB
.lassimsid lufyalp ni wap reh deppalf xof eht ”,yako s’ti ,hhA“
.efil htiw deifsitas dna yppah ,rehtegot niamer dluow su fo owt ehT
.esiwrehto yas dluow stsiseiceps ynam hguoht
;noisulcnoc eno tub ot emoc ev’I ,yenruoj lauxes ym fo owT raeY fo dne eht yB
;efil eht dootsrednu ew os ,sdnuorgkcab gnireenigne morf dna ega emas eht tuoba erew su fo htoB
,nehctik eht ni ylfeirb mih ees dluow I ,gninrom eht nI
,esoprup yrev taht rof dettezag yllaiciffo eb ot desoppus saw tekraM thgiN eht pu edam taht steerts eht
ruFikiW ro AF sih no
tsaE eht ni neppah taht sgniht eht fo gnikaeps loohcs ni kcab sdik llacer ot desu I
,ekila syob dna slrig gnikrow gnippetsedis ,yawyella detanimulli-ylthgil eht hguorht deppets I
.esaeler gniyfsitas a ot gnitnap dna gnipsag
.su dnuora steerts eht deciton t’ndah I ,egaibrev s’isaK ni dessorgne os saw I
.seicepsbus fo rebmun yna ot refer dluoc seniltuo diletsum dna eninac cireneg tub
,ecno dna ,teerts eht ni ro krow ta evisausrep yllauqe eb dluoc eH
”.pleh nac I ebyaM ?rof gnikool uoy era tahw tsuJ
.gnimoc ti dah ahsaS
.em ta rorrim weiv raer eht otni dekool ruf gniyarg htiw etoyoc deroloc-ynwat a ,revird bac ehT
,xof rehtona tey saw tI
.nosrep reh ssorca depard ehs
uoy rof daer eb lliw yrots s’yadoT  .egap
.isaK deilper ”.em no s’edir eht ,won tuo pets uoy fI .nos ,ti evaS“
.snortap gnikool-dezad fo elpuoc a gnidulcni
,mih sdrawot fles yxof ym knay dna liat ym pirg dluow eh ,deppot eh nehw dnA
.ega sih ta nwod em taeb ot desserp-drah eb d’eh ,saw eh fi neve ,lleh ,derugif I nehT
tekraM eht ot revo gnidaeh er’uoy enoemos llet ot enif yltcefrep saw tI
.regnessap sih dedrager dna dnuora denrut eh ,emit tsrif eht roF
”.erauqs ti redisnoc dna ,dias ev’I tahw rebmemer tsuJ“
,tcirtsiD thgiL deR eht seil
.ytuD fo llaC gniyalp
.hgis a evag etoyoc ehT
.ti sdrawot tup emitrevo taht lla rof mih tluaf t’ndluoc I dna ,yad eno nwo ruo fo esuoh a gnitteg no detnemmoc syawla eh
.steehs eht ni taht sa tnatropmi sa tsuj si steerts eht ni egdelwonk taht yas revewoh tsum I .ti enifed thgim eno revewoh
,devlovni steg elpoep rehto nehw
.dedeen I tahw reh dlot I nehw pu til elims s’ogriV
”...rre rM ,netsiL“
.mih rof sniatruc eb yllanif dluow ti erus saw I dna
.enipluv eht fo eno rof elbatpecca tahwemos dnuof yeht taht boj a tog neve dna
.rehtona fo serusaelp eht kees ot snosaer ynam os
.esimorpmoc ni dedne syawla hctaw ot eivom ro yub ot seirecorg tahw revo ti eb ,stnemugra ruo tub ,thgir
syawla saw I tlef I ebyam ro ,ekila oot raf erew ew ebyaM
,rorrim weiv-raer eht ni isaK deye I
.lleh sa gnirob eb dluow dlrow eht esiwrehto
.riaf dna thgir t’nsaw tlef eh sgniht htiw deergasid dna ,tnaem eh tahw dias eh
eseht piks nac uoy
.sseug a drazah ot dah I fi ,emosruof tnegnup dna elbayojne tsom A