.taht ekil dnuora deirrac gnieb
tsuj naht eman lanosrep erom a evah ot ecin eb d’ti ebyaM .ti ekil I“
.erutan fo ecrof elbadimrof eht naht regnorts er’yeht taht sevlesmeht ecnivnoc oT .sevlesmeht evorp ot ereh emoc yehT
.ecnelis gnol eht kaerb ot troffe na ni pu ekops dna
emit txen ni enuT
,noitnetta s’nosyarG detcartta taht seye neerg gniwolg s’erutaerc eht saw ti ,yllaitinI
doohdlihc sih morf emit a gnirebmemer saw eh ,dnim sih ni spahreP
esae ta tup niaga ecno erew sevren s’nosyarG  ”…ekil dna
,sredluohs s’nosyarG revo mra nedoow rieht depard yehT  ”…woN
.emoh ruoy ekil I llet nac uoy dalg m’I...“
,eciov ruoy draeh ev’I
,nosyarG taht gnihtemoS .railucep
.seye sih fo tnorf ni thgir
rafa morf mih gnihctaw
.dnirg eht ot kcab tnew I erofeb daeh ym raelc ot ecalpemos dedeen I
.yaw ruo no eb s’tel ,woN“
”.ti ot mrah od ot hsiw ohw esoht morf emoh ym tcetorp ot boj ym s’tI
,fo draehnu ton tub ,erar saw rotircsE ni snamuh fo ecnaraeppa ehT
?eman namuh a taht sI ?hO“
ssenmlac fo hsur esnetni na tlef yletaidemmi tsomla nosyarG .emoh railimaf-oot-lla s’niboR hguorht
dednuos taorht dehcrap sih yfsitas ot retaw gninnur fo ecruos a gnidnif dna
.enod d’eh hsiloof gnihtemos rof mih dedlocs stnerap sih nehw
enoemos fo yrots a dlot tI
.noitasrevnoc eht liared ot edur eb dluow ti tlef tub
”?…ro ,tirips tserof fo dnik emos ro ,doG
”,ereh ni yaw eht lla rednaw ohw wef eht morf egaugnal namuh fo tib a pu dekcip ev’I“
.gnieb-llew sih rof derac niboR taht nosyarG dlot
mih reffo ylbaborp dluohs yeht dediced yehT
stoor eert eht ees ot hguone drah ydaerla saw ti ,noisiv thgin roop sih htiW
”.ecalp tsrif eht ni gnignis detrats uoy yhw s’tahT“ .flesmih dlot eh
…seutats ekil gnidnats era elttac eht llA“ .enut sih ot nruter ot
.mih deirrow thgil ehT
,denediw seye s’nosyarG
…eciov s’namow a ro s’nam a saw ti rehtehw llet t’ndluoc nosyarG .gnihtoos dna
,tserof eht hguorht no deunitnoc nosyarG  .pleh emos
.ecnelis eht kaerb ot eno eht eb dluohs yeht
.dnim yna mih yap dluow gniees ot desu saw eh serutaerc eht fo enoN
snamuh yna tuo gnikats devlovni ytud taht fo trap dna …gnimossolb dna
.dnim ym otni deppop tsuj ti …onnud I“
.ecnahc eht tog eh erofeb gnikaeps deunitnoc yeht tub
.enil txen eht rebmemer ot gniyrt niarb sih dekcar eH
”?dnim fo ecaep uoy sgnirb tserof yM“
gnileef eht devol yehT
a uoy era …ekil ,oS“
,ffo liart eciov sih tel eH
wonk ot uoy tnaw I tub
.elims evitaicerppa na htiw
pleh rof seirc suoidolem tey ,deniarts
,dekramer nosyarG
”?uoy llac slamina od tahw ,yas I dluohs rO
.ecaps otni ffo derats tirips ehT
,nosrep cifitneics dna lacigol a
.siht gniod rof hcum os uoy knahT“
.won eciov rieht ni tnemeticxe fo tnih a
.lufepoh yats ot yletarepsed gniyrt tey
.ydob sti dnuora depparw erew
,netae dna deluam eb ot yawa mih gnidael ylno saw niboR taht mih nraw ot deirt evah thgim enecs egnarts
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.gnidloh saw eh ezilaer t’ndid eh htaerb emos gnisaeler ,dias nosyarG
desu saw erutaerc ehT
.mih etadommocca ot ydaer dna
.mih gnihctaw saw gnihtemoS
”.srewolf eht elpmart ot ton luferac eb dna ,yb esolc yats tsuJ
detsefni-gub fo selip eht hguorht delbmuts eh sa
…tsol ylsselepoh gnieb fo
.eman a ekil stpecnoc namuh rof deen a evah yllausu t’nod I …mmH“
.ti ot enilpicsid fo tnih a dah dna
trihs-t elpmis a tsuj
.mrah on naem I esimorp I
,snoitcerid rieht esarhp ot yaw reisae na deredisnoc yehT
deilper nam gnuoy eht ”,nosyarG“
.seitiliba gnikkert )lufitip ylknarf(
.oga ruoh na retaw fo tuo nur d’eh ecnis saw taorht sih yrd woh dna
”…revetahw ro ,doG ro tirips
.rehto yna ot lacitnedi dekool taht
!thguoht eht hsireP“
.mih wollof dluow taht ereh tuo gnihton saw erehT
”.looc s’tahT .hO“
.saw neve ”yaw“ sih noitcerid tahw aedi on dah eH .yaw sih gniog
.meht fo emos eht no gniworg ignuf etihw eht yb eb dluow
.tnemmoc eht yb kcaba nekat tib a
,dnim fo ecaep emos rof ereh hguorht ekih a gnikat tsuj saw I
,niaga ylsuovren delkcuhc eH ”?’dlrow
.boB ee-riS ,oN .riS on
.ecaf evitcirtser rieht no dluoc yeht sa ssenrednet hcum sa gniwohs
,mih ta kcab dekool niboR
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,illetangiS yb
,yrotirret rieht deretne taht sretnuh yna ffo gniracs ot
od ot dah erutaerc eht lla tub
,erofeb nees reve d’eh s’erutaerc yna ekilnu liat a dah osla tI
.emoh ym etaicerppa yllaer t’nod yehT
.esae ta erom neve nosyarG tup hcihw
ees dluoc nosyarG dna
,evah dluow ydaerla yeht naht egnarts erom neve thgis eht dnif ylbaborp dluow ybsressap ynA
sih ot gninetsil ylurt saw ohw
ydaer snoitseuq fo tol a dah yehT
sa em ot refer snamuh emos draeh ev’I
pu demaerd eb ot laer oot
gniklaw nageb yehT
.ti ees dluoc eH .emit siht hcnuh a t’nsaw tI
.gnileef ydaerla saw eh efas woh mih no denwad ti
.kaeps ot deunitnoc yehT
,doow fo edam erew tsehc dna smra stI
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
”....yyyyyaw ym gniog s’gnihtyreve ,gniiiiileeeef lufituaeb a tog ev’I
”?niboR uoy llac I naC“  ”’.droL tseroF‘ eht
,tcejretni dluoc nosyarG erofeB  ”!t’nod uoy
”?!nettogrof evah I dluoc woH
.esac eht t’nsaw taht wenk nosyarG wohemos tub
,thgis ni nroc on saw ereht
”.daeh ym revo yaw pu dedne I dna
.feiler fo hgis rehtona devaeh nosyarG
htap sih gninil seert kciht eht yfitnedi ot elba eb d’eh yaw ylno eht ,noos ytterP
,enif saw eh detsisni dna etilop erom neeb evah dluow eh ,yllamroN
seert fo puorg a drawot ,noitcerid modnar ylgnimees a ni detniop yehT
.ereh ni emoc ohw snamuh rehto eht lla morf egnahc emoclew yrev a s’tI
leef ot nageb erutaerc eht
…a gnieb etipsed eman gnidnuos-lamron a evah ot uoy rof ynnuf eb d’ti thguoht I
”sklaW naM oN erehW“
”.uoy stif ti kniht I os
…em fo yllis woH !hO“
…efil eritne rieht tserof eht ni devil dah yeht esuaceb yltnelis mih wollof ot woh wenk yehT
,mih revo gnihsaw
.meht fo htob eht dnuora derutseg nosyarG  ”…hu ,dna ,htap eht fo thgis tsol I sseug I tub
?uoy llac elpoep od tahw dnA“
,seiponac eert eht fo smottob eht naht retrohs tib a tsuj won erew yehT
.dnim t’ndid nosyarG tub
”.noitaicerppa fo ngis a saw ti llet dluoc I
.derussaer ,dias eh
.saw eh tnemele sih fo tuo woh nettogrof dah yehT
deredisnoc neve evah t’ndluow I ,elpoep esoht fo eno erew uoy fI
”.ymene na sa ti ees yehT
,tserof eht rof tcepser peed a evah ot demees eH
”.yrrow ot ton tub ,daeh ruoy revo ni erew uoy gnileef a dah I ,seY“
.dnuora gninrut ylneddus erofeb ,detacidni yeht noitcerid eht ni
,ekops erutaerc eht ”?hO“
,revewoh ,emit sihT
,ta gnikool saw eh tahw ssecorp neve dluoc eh erofeb tub
!yrrow t’nod ,ononoN“
,eert a dniheb morf tuo gnireep saw tI
dluow ,mih tsurt dluoc yeht fi neve dnA
.laudividni suoicilam a ton er’uoy wonk I dna
,knumpihc ynit a fo kaeuqs eht ro ,lwoh s’flow a ,gnos s’namuh a s’ti rehtehW
yllautca erew yeht taht dezilaer yllautneve nosyarG .ezis ni egnahc ot mees t’ndid yeht ylegnarts tub
reggib worg ot nageb niboR
,gniklaw potsnon eht
.oot ,eciov ruoy ekil I“
.egdelwonk sih tuohtiw
.ekildlihc tsomla ,delggig
.ereh tuo yaw eht lla eb ot decneirepxeni oot raf
tnerappa s’erutaerc eht tuoba ksa ot detnaw nosyarG
,ezis ni egnahc ot ytiliba
ton ylniatrec tsom saw gnihtyreve dna
.pu til ecaf s’nosyarG
strikstuo eht fo tuo m’I sseug I“
,wodaem a ni t’nsaw eH
,dereuqnoc eb ot gnihtemos sa tserof eht ees ot sdnet dnik ruoY
.demaeb erutaerc ehT
.eciov s’namuh eht fo dnuos eht ot gniraeh rieht enut retteb dluoc yeht
niaga dlihc a ekil tlef nosyarG
klaw gnol eht rof
,enasni enog dah eh rehtie taht
ytud rieht no sucof ot dah tsuj yehT
.dednopser erutaerc eht
”?’niboR‘ ,egduj ot I ma ohw
,ylthgils dehgual nosyarG  ”.eniuneg
,sevooh etalugnu htiw sgel reed evah ot demees tI
.noisneherppa dewohs ylno hcihw
flesmih gnillet tpek eH
os gnihtemos rof eciov gnimoob
.secalp lla fo ,tseroF rotircsE ni
.klat uoy gniraeh ekil I“
,euqapo yletelpmoc saw tI
”.uoy rof yaw eht gnidael
,tserof eht fo strikstuo eht hguorht kert trohs a eb ot desoppus ylno saw sihT
”.hguone noos tuo ton er’uoy fi kcans ytsat a eb ot uoy dnif dluow seotiuqsom eht kniht I dna ,gnihcaorppa si tesnuS
”?I ma ,elpoep esoht fo eno ton m’I“
.yyyyyad lufituaeb a tahw ho ,gninroooom lufituaeb a tahw hO“
.ecnetsixe sti noitnem ot erew enoemos fi ta deffocs evah dluow
.erutaerc lacitsym fo dnik emos neeb evah tsum sihT
.gniraelc lanoisacco na ni detartenep thgilnus gniniamer eht fo tib ynit a ylno kciht os saw
.ni gnipeerc sthguoht evitagen eht fo ffo
”.yrassecen si eugnot revetahw ni dnopser nac dna ,sserpxe ot tnaw yeht tahw tciderp yletarucca ot
.esae lufecarg htiw
.epahs hsurbtniap
illetangiS yb
.gnignis s’namuh eht fo dnuos eht no erom desucof dna seye gniwolg rieht ”desolc“ yehT
emac ti nehw secnahc yna gnikat t’nsaw eh ,yldneirf gnimees erutaerc eht etipseD
.gnihctaw htrow eb ot hguone gnitseretni mih dnif dluow taht tserof eht ni gnihton saw ereht taht
.elkcuhc llams a htiw deksa nosyarG
.nosyarG naht rellat sehcni wef a
.mret thgir eht saw taht ti erusnu
”.retteb hcum t’nera srekih emos tub ,puorg tsrow eht era sretnuH“  .liat s’niboR fo ruf ytevlev eht
”…litnu noitcerid taht ni deecorp dna ,srewolf lanidrac fo wor rehtona wollof uoy tniop hcihw ta
,stnap savnac dna
niarret eht hguorht spets drawkwa sih dna
gnihtemos fo noitnetta eht detcartta ylgnittiwnu d’eh  tuB
.gnineve eb dluow ti noos dna
,htrow s’ti tahw rof tuB
,tsiaw s’nosyarG dnuora liat gnol rieht depparw dna
.ytinrete na ekil demees tahw rof rehto hcae ta derats
erutaerc eht dna nosyarG
dediced erutaerc eht ,yllautnevE
sliated dna snoisnemid dah dna
.thgieh s’nosyarG elbuod tsomla dna
srewolf etihw dna
,dehgual erutaerc ehT
taht tsuj s’ti tub ,won enola MA I taht ton ,naem I
,edis eht otni tliub evac a htiw edisffilc llams a hcaer uoy litnu srewolf esoht wollof uoy ,nehT
,dneirf raed sih morf
”?em stif ti kniht uoy oD
.noitacol suoregnad ,ylraelc ,tey lufituaeb A
.lamina raluger a naht dezilivic erom raf saw gniht sihT
,meht tsniaga gniyl nosyarG fo
.dluow ti detcepxe nosyarG ekil gnihtyna dnuos t’ndid eciov s’erutaerc ehT
mih dnuora egailof ehT
…neht ,ti ekil uoy fi tub
,nosyarG ot tsnwonkebnU
?em rof emit taht lla eraps nac uoy erus uoy era tuB“
”.ereh fo tuo yllanif m’I erofeb ecnatsid trohs a ylno s’ti tuB“
niboR  .ylediw gnilims
”?hsilgnE kaeps uoy …mU“
,degaruocsid dna das
.detpurretni nosyarG
.sreltna nedoow eht gnitnuoc ton ,llat teef 21 tuoba erew yeht litnu
.yticapac yna ni srebmun tcaxe ot dnim yap ot
.yltfos tuo detrats eciov s’nosyarG
tirips ekil-reed eht sa
”?tsol er’uoy taht gnimussa ni tcerroc I mA“
sih ni tnedifnocrevo mees t’ndid namuh ehT
.setis gnitsen rieht rednu dessap eh sa mih gnidlocs ylduol
ydob rieht ot esolc mih dleh yeht yaw evitcetorp tey
wenk nosyarG .noitanigami eht yb
,lasopsid rieht ta snopaew gnitadimitni dna gib rieht htiw lufrewop sa sevlesmeht was syawla sretnuh esohT
.tser a sgel sih evig ot ytinutroppo na pu ssap ot detsuahxe oot raf saw eh tub
.flesmih ot gniyl saw nosyarG
.mih dehcaorppa yeht sa ezis ni gniknirhs
.won did eh sa sselepoh dna desserts sa tlef tsal d’eh ecnis gnol os
”.ffuts dna seitud
”!kcuf knaht ,hO“  .ylnevaeh
”,lla ta gnikih htiw decneirepxe yrev ton m’I …lleW“
”!reisae tol a uoy htiw gnisrevnoc ekam dluow ti dnA .elihw a rof ’droL tseroF‘
”.elihw elttil a rof ynapmoc lausunu eht yojne rehtar d’I“
?meht was yeht sa noos sa did tsom ekil yawa nur ylpmis eh dluow ro
enoemos fo noisserpmi eht evag
reed A .yrotirret ym fo egde eht skram taht keerc a si noitcerid taht nI“
”klaW neM oN erehW“   yojne esaelP
,derit mees uoY ?on ,tsol er’uoY
tseb sih deirt eH
.dab m’I kniht t’nod uoy dalg m’I ,llew …mU“
…tsiaw sti no erow ti tahw saw
.yako s’tI“ .delggig
.tuo taht detros ew dalG“
...“ .meht fo owt eht gnidnuorrus neerg hsul eht ta dnuora decnalg nosyarG  ”…llew
gnikorts yldednimtnesba ,deilper nosyarG
.won saw eh hsiloof woh fo
edis eht no stops etihw dah neve dna
.dettimda nosyarG ”,yllej ekil leef adnik od yeht ,haey …hO“
,pu gnilip krow dna loohcs htiw lufsserts os neeb sah yltnecer efil ym taht tsuj s’tI“ .detrats eh
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.hsurb eht hguorht sgel derit sih klaw ot gnilggurts elihw
.retal dnoces a taorht sih deraelc neht
”.ruoh na tuoba ekat dluow ti etamitse d’I
.deilper tirips eht ”,yrrow t’nod ,hO“
,yrotirret tserof railimaf sti hguorht yaw sti gniddorp yltnelis
seye gniwolg s’niboR otni dekool nosyarG
,erecnis gnimees ta tseb eht ton m’I
,eltneg dna tfos saw eciov ehT
.yb rednaw ot deneppah ohw
,htgnel s’mra na nihtiw erew yeht emit eht yB
”.won striksni eht ni llew dna
.mih naht resiw raf erugif ytirohtua na ekil
dnuora ydobon saw erehT
.dehctaw gnieb fo gnileef eht ekahs ot flesmih dlot eh tahw s’taht ,tsael ta
”…seutats ekil gnidnats era elttac eht lla
,tsehc rieht tsniaga kcab yraew sih gninael dna
eciov eltneg sih raeh ot elba gnieb
.mih ot gnikaeps erutaerc eht raeh ot desirprus ,deknilb nosyarG
,pleh fo deen ni saw nam gnuoy eht llet dluoc yehT .detcilfnoc
meht rof erots ni seil etaf tahw nrael dna
.ekops yeht sa yltneg detarbiv dna devaeh hcihw
rO…  .skao fo swor sseldne eht tsniaga gniohce
,nruter ni dehgual nosyarG
,ekoj a sa ti tnaem I ,lleW“
stoor delgnatne fo hctap egral a hguorht teef gib rieht gnippets ,deunitnoc niboR
tsisni I neht ,sgel ruoy no gniklaw peek t’nac uoy fI“ .detroter niboR
.tserof eht ni gnieb rof nosaer sih wonk t’ndid llits yehT
.ezorf ylneddus niboR
,etal gnitteg saw tI
,illetangiS yb ”sklaW naM oN erehW“
,raelc eht otni tuo deppets ti
.esuap drawkwa na retfa kcab deilper yllautneve eh
,ecaf s’namuh eht ta kcab dekool yehT
…edirts ym kaerb annog gnihton
;llat teef flah a dna xis tuoba ylno erew yeht
.elbuort tnaem yllausu ti dna
srewsna tsenoh yletelpmoc emos teg dluoc niboR emit tsrif eht saw siht dna
gninetsil elihw lla
.hctawtsirw sih ta decnalg eH
.kcehc oge na meht evig ot gnisuma rehtar ti gnidnif syawla
psar thgils a raeh dluoc yehT
...“  .ti derevoc taht ruf tfos ylgnisirprus eht leef ot mih gniwolla
dednapxe yldipar ydob eritne riehT
.noitanicullah a ro
.ecitnerppA_retirW
,eciov tfos rieht ot
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
”,si ecnatsid eht trohs woh rettam t’nseod tI“
.niaga ecno seye s’nosyarG otni dekool niboR
siht nopu emac ohw ybressap a ,eruS
,resolc emac yeht sA
”?I t’ndluohs ,tsrif eman ruoy wonk dluohs I
.yllacificeps em eman ot gnivah tuohtiw pleh ym rof llac ot elba era ereh slamina eht fo tsoM
thgirb a s’erehT“
eciov gnignis sih otni mgarhpaid elohw sih tup t’ndluoc eH
nepo mlap tnaig rieht
gniklaw nageb riap eht ,taht htiw dnA
lehctas llams fo dnik emos dna htolcniol a eb ot deraeppa tahw
.pu dekrep ylneddus nosyarG
,siht dootsrednu yeht taht woN
...keerc taht fo egde eht ta
.ytisoiruc htiw mih ta dekool yehT
.noitatiseh tuohtiw taes a koot yldalg nosyarG
tfos saw eciov s’erutaerc eht tub ,elbadimrof
tsohg a eb ot laer yllacisyhp oot saw ti tub ,seye gniwolg dna daeh lluks eht htiw ecnaraeppa cimsatnahp a evah ot demees ylniatrec tI ?spahrep ,tsohg A
namuh‘ ,hu …eht fo sesserts eht morf ffo tuc os sleef taht ecalp a dnif ot erar s’tI
.ekops eh sa gnihsulb saw eh ezilaer neve t’ndid eH
deen on dah yehT
,deppiuq nosyarG
?namuh siht tsurt yllaer yeht dluoc tub
.reduol gnis ot nageb eh
.ereh devil taht slamina fo sepyt eht detamitserednu ylereves dah eh ro
.lirep ni regnol on saw eh gniwonk
.llew sa evil ot ecalp wen a gnidnif dna
,og ot dedeen eh reverehw
,gnola gnittort neeb d’eh gnol woh ot derapmoc gnihton saw ruoh nA
,ton ro eurt saw taht rehtehW
.neeb dah efil taht sraey dnasuoht ynam revewoh
…eyyyyyye s’tnahpele na sa hgih sa si nroc ehT“ .gnignis tpek eH
,gnol os rof ereh ni enola neeb ev’I
,yknal dna llat saw eH
.eciov gnitnahcne ylddo eht htiw namuh eht morf ytilitsoh yna esnes t’ndid erutaerc eht
.enola m’I nehw tol a raews ot dnet I !yrros …hU“
,llew sa taorht s’nam gnuoy eht fo kcab eht ta
,haeY .mM“  ”.dehsirehc ton
.yaw ruo no eb s’teL...“
.redneg ekil stpecnoc namuh rof deen on dah siht ekil sgnieb larutanrepus spahrep hguoht
.tsehc nedoow sti morf yltcerid gniworg eb ot demees taht
fo trap tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.mih morf yawa teef ytriht naht ssel on
”.oot ,sretnuh etah I
dnim sih teg ot dedeen eH
…gnos siht gnas tsal eh ecnis gnol os neeb dah tI
,ti gnidnuorrus seert eht ot yltcefrep tsomla ni gnidnelb
”,TOL a taht etaicerppa d’I“
…mmH“  .ffo deliart eciov siH
,nosyarG ot tuo dnah nedoow rieht dleh niboR
.reed a ton ,oN .gniht …reed a saw tI
”.siht etaicerppa od yllaer I
tsom eht nosyarG kcurts tahw tuB
denrael ylpmis ev’I
.yb derednaw ohw srekih tsom naht rellams raf kcapkcab a dna
syaj eulb eht morf edisa mih raeh dluow enoyna ekil ton s’ti ,sediseB
.llat teef net tuoba erew ro
”.yyyyyyyks eht ot pu raelc gnibmilc s’ti ekil skool ti dna
”.uoy rof yaw eht dael I fi retteb eb d’ti ebyam …yllautcA“
,mhtyhr mgarhpaid doog a gnidniF
dloc tub gnihton eb dluow ereht ,nehT
,y-erutan adnik s’ti ,yeh dnA“
.niaga ecaf sih no wohs ot gninnigeb raef
.reed a t’nsaw ti wenk nosyarG tuB .reed ybab no gniees derebmemer nosyarG taht
”.taht tuoba ksa ot gninaem saw I“ .detanicsaf
t’niA“  .stirips sih esiar dluow depoh eh taht gnos rehtona ot no devom dah dna gnos !amohalkO eht ot sciryl eht rebmemer ot gniyrt pu nevig dah eh ,won yB .sevael gnittor
,saw ti ereht teY
”…ezis ruoy egnahc NAC uoy oS“
,mlap s’niboR fo elddim eht ni nwod tas eH
.ta toohs ot dekil yeht reed eht naht retsaf yawa nur d’yeht dna mrof gnitadimitni erom a tpoda saw
.pu ekops ylitsah erutaerc ehT
.daeh sih koohs nosyarG   …ssenkrad
.saw ti tahw fo lla
deppots eh litnu ylduorp gnas eh
.smuinareg fo hctap gib yrev a dnif uoy litnu ereht hguorht seert eht wollof si od ot evah uoy llA“
”.uoy pleh ot ekil d’I dna
noissimmoc tra yadhtrib gnitnahcne na yb deripsni gnieb retfa yrots siht etorw ohw
.skcart sih ni daed
.luos sti sserpxe ot eciov sti sesu lamina na
,htap rieht no srewolf fo hctap a hguorht piz eeb a dehctaw eh sA
.niaga kaeps ot ecnedifnoc eht gniniager erofeb
.srewolf gnimoolb fo tsehc rieht tsniaga mih deldarc neht niboR dna
,dluoc ylbissop eh sa duol sa eciov sih gnitcejorp saw eh ,won yB
.taht ekil em fo kniht dluoc uoy esoppus I
,epoN .lla ta gnihtoN .esruoc fO
.lufthgiled etiuq dnuof tirips eht hcihw dnuos a
fo tros a gnimrof yllautneve erofeb ti dniheb raf tuo gnihcterts
,tuo deirc nosyarG
mih yrrac niboR tel ot tnetnoc yltcefrep tlef eH
,seoreh owt ruo fo sevil eht tuoba erom tuo dnif ot
,daeh a rof lluks a ro ,ruf eulb krad dah fo wenk eh reed oN
,eciov rieht sa gnihtoos sa tsuj hgual a
…mih no snopaew yna evah ot raeppa t’ndid eH
.gninnigeb eht morf wenk eh senil eht gnitaeper ot flesmih dengiser eh
,”ynapmoc lausunu“ MIH gnillac
.pets a koot eh emit yreve mih gnippirt
”…wodaem eht no ezah reppoc thgirb a s’erehT …wodaem eht no ezah reppoc
”.secnatsmucric tnereffid rednu ti etaicerppa ot nettog d’I hsiw ylno I“
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,nosyarG dehcaorppa yeht ,ekops yeht sA
,niarb sih fo sessecer eht morf enil txen eht gid ot elbanu ylgnitartsurf flesmih gnidniF
fo trap tsrif eht saw sihT     ...daeha
.mih tuoba yaw emas eht hcum gnileef saw niboR
.noitulos relpmis a dezilaer yeht erofeb
.retfa yllaer er’yeht tahw seciov rieht morf llet nac I tub ,tserof eht fo ytuaeb eht erimda ot emoc yeht yas yehT“
.emit emos etiuq ni gnihtyna knurd t’ndah eh taht gnitacidni ylraelc
.ti gnittespu yllaitnetop ot
.dnoces a rof deremmats nosyarG ”…mu ,hO“
.no gniyrrac erofeb eciov sih fo noitcerid eht ni ecnalg ylpmis dluow yb dessap taht reed ro slerriuqs ynA
.enola seciov rieht yb slaudividni gnidaer ta doog m’I tuB“
eltneg eht tuoba gnihtemoS
htap a dnif ot tseb sih gniyrt
morf saw eh derit woh etipsed
.thgir-flah saw nosyarG
.nosrep erecnis a er’uoy esnes nac I .yrrow t’noD“
…os namuh a dnif ot erar s’tI
”,dnim ruoy fo tuo thguoht taht teG .epoN“
rehto ruoy lla htiw ysub eb tsum uoy erus m’I
,mih ees ot tnaw neve namuh eht
gnitnuoc dna sruoh eviF
,dnA .drow retteb a fo kcal rof ,yhtrowtsurt er’uoy wonk em stel …tI .gnihtoos s’tI
,peed a gnitcepxe saw eH
yhtlaeh deyats emoh rieht erus gnikam fo
,og ot syaw a dah llits yeht ,noitnem ot toN .yb esolc os
,uoy rof os ,setunim evif-ytrof tuoba ni pirt eht ekam nac
”…nwod em wols annog ydoboN
.efil namuh tuoba
sevael fo htaerw egral a yb dednuorrus saw kcen sti dna
erawa yletuca demees eh
tirips tserof larutanrepus a fo ynori eht no tnemmoc ot tuoba saw nosyarG
!won yb tniop gnikaerb eht ta eb tsum sgel ruoY !hsog ,ho …tiaW“