s’nosyarG .sgel s’nosyarG nwod
edam ti fo thguoht ehT  .noos yrev
nosyarG ,gnol erofeB
.sdlrow owt rieht tuoba gniretnab
.ereh gnorw saw gnihtemoS
.saw eh sa tsuj tcefrep saw nosyarG tuoba gnihtyrevE
.ylenol teg od yehT .seY
nosyarG ot eybdoog yas ot evah dluow yeht dna
.rewsna na no elttes ot demees eh
,tnatsni na nI  !!tiaW
…ti ot pu m’I fi wonk t’nod I ,yltsenoH“
ereh evael reven ylbaborp d’I …tub
htrof dna kcab gnigniws
;ti rof ecirp eht gniyap saw eh ekil tlef eh woN
gninialpxe fo elbapac ylerab saw eh ,tcaf ni …taht od ot deen eht tlef eh yhw
”.epyt eht ekil mees t’nod yllaer uoy tub ,edur sdnuos siht fi yrros m’I
taht fo dnuos ehT
.neeb dah yllaer eh taht deveileb ylbaborp eh ,dnim sih nI
…htap eht dettod taht seert fo sepyt tnereffid eht fo ekops yehT
”?siht ekil enoemos htiw tahc dna klaw ot elba neeb ev’uoy ecnis elihw a neeb ti sah tub
,ni werg riah eht sa noitasnes gniggut dna gnihcti elbatrofmocnu na naht erom gnihton tlef nosyarG ,erofeb ekil dna
yllaicepse …nwod-edispu
…tub ,saw ti yltcaxe tahw no sucof t’ndluoc nosyarG
”.morf emac ew liart eht no kcab pu kcip ot egabrag namuh emos evah I em dlot tsuj yaj eulb a tub
.gnileef erew yeht tahw won litnu dezilaer reven yeht esuaceb saw taht tub
.niboR ta pu dekool dna
,ot klat ot slamina eht lla evah uoy ,erus ,naem I
.nosyarG ot gnikil a nekat evah ot smees niboR
.ylmlac dekramer nosyarG ”,haey ,hO“
wolley hsinnat a saw edistnorf siH
.niboR yb deirrac gnieb fo gnikcor eltneg eht morf ffo dezod tsomla dah eH
,dneirf raed sih morf
.tnemom eht derovas yeht os
,rehto hcae yb dellarhtne yletelpmoc sevlesmeht dnuof tirips dna namuh htoB
demees llits nosyarG
,tserof eht fo egde eht sdrawot nosyarG yrrac ot seunitnoc niboR sa
,no rettahc ot deunitnoc nosyarG  “…I hsiw I
deroloc-wolley a otni detfihs eson eht sa elzzum llams a otni htuom dna eson sih gnihcterts
taorht sih deraelc eH
,seohs s’nosyarG fo revoc eht rednu ecalp nekat evah dluow segnahc eseht fo llA
?saw eh dehcrap woh tegrof ot eganam eh did htrae no woH
,del yeht sevil tnereffid yldliw eht fo etips ni esuaceb
”.syaw fo tol a ni esac laiceps a er’uoY“ .deilper niboR
trihs sih htiw gnola htap eht no erehwemos
”.togrof I kniht …I
ekoj eht ylraelC
.seert esoht ni snroca edih ot dekil taht slerriuqs fo seiceps tnereffid eht fo ekops yeht ebyam ro
.yrassecen saw tahw ylno degnahc yeht erus ekam ot ylreporp
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
ruf fo taoc tnaig eht sa hsulp dna gnol sa ylraen t’nsaw ti hguohT
,ti daer yeht yltfos woh etipsed tub
noissimmoc tra yadhtrib gnitnahcne na yb deripsni gnieb retfa yrots siht etorw ohw
.mih ot gnineppah saw tahw fo
.tseroF rotircsE hguorht derednaw ohw rekih ro retnuh gniyonna lanoisacco eht ot desu oot lla saw eh ,won yB .deksa eh
.yaw ym gnimoc yenom fo tol a evah ll’I ,ffo siht fo lla llup nac I fi ,eruS
ffulf wolley yssem fo aes eht htiw dehsalc ruf nworb rieht elihw
nosyarG namuh ruo ,emit tsaL  ].detsop teg t’nseod etirw od I tahw fo tsom ecnis yllaicepse ,flesym gulp ot thgir leef t’nseod ti os eromyna tol a etirw ot emit eht
dah d’eh ecnatculer eht hguorht dewohs ti dna
niap yna leef neve t’ndid eH
,gnol eht eciton ton ot gniraeppa
.reprahs hcum dna wolley emoceb ot detfihs slian sih dna
a rof ediw ylgnisirprus saw hcihw ,revir A
…seohs ,stnap ,trihS
.osrot sih ta pots t’ndid ruf nworb ehT
.did niboR sa hcum sa tsomla meht detah eH
.ssentoh fo gnileef eht gnisuac saw tahw gnilaever
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.seicnednet evititepmoc erom ’seiceps sih fo tol a dekilsid tub
eracs ot dah yeht semit eht lla tuoba dekoj yehT
.taht gniwonk tespu em sekam tI
.gniklat eno rehto eht peek ot detnaw tsuj htob yeht spahrep ro
,drawno deunitnoc owt eht os dnA
.spitregnif rieht htiw daeh s’nosyarG dekorts niboR
”,gab taht ni saw tahw ksa ot togrof I“
htob yeht dna ,yaw siht reippah hcum eb dluow htob yehT
,ydob degnahc s’nosyarG etipsed ,taht raeh ot deveiler saw niboR
deirrac gnieb fo gnileef levon eht ni
,tseroF rotircsE ni erutaerc egnarts a tem
tpircs a ni nettirw eb ot demees ti tub
.ereh tuo evil uoy efil eht dna uoy yb detanicsaf sa tsuj m’I ,lleW“
.llorcs eht morf gnidaer ysub oot erew yehT
.mih evig ot gnilliw naht erom saw niboR taht esucxe na …efil lufsserts sih ot kcab og ton ot esucxe na saw
.emit ot tsol gnol
gnihtemos saw erehT .debircsed dah niboR tahw tuoba railimaf gnihtemos saw ereht ,tnemom a roF
.tsiaw sih ot yaw eht lla dehcaer won yb dah taht
.ydob nwo rieht fo ezis eht ot ezis s’keerc eht gnirapmoc tsuj saw niboR ebyam ,hguohT
,illetangiS yb ”sklaW naM oN erehW“
seye sih dnuora ni werg taht ruf ehT
”.ot kcab teg ot krow evah t’ndid I fi
.ekops yeht sa niaga ecno dehgual niboR
,daeh sih fo pot eht ot detfihs ecnis gnol dah hcihw ,srae sih ,yllaniF
.dne no doots ruf sih
rehtona saw ereht ,tsehc sih nwod gniwolf dna
,emit htnoillim eht rof riah tfos sih dekorts yltneg dna nosyarG ta nwod dekool
.ekops yeht nehw yltnetni dna ylpeed netsil dluow ohw ydobemos rof erised A
kcab tas eh sa ecaf sih no deretsalp elims yfoog a dah tsuj eH
,dnA“ .deilper niboR
”?sklaw erutan erom gniyojne ,yas ,fo daetsni
…ebyam tub ,ti fo trap saw tahT .elbarenluv ton …oN
,osrot dna mra sih neewteb flesti dnetxe ot demees niks sih sa
dedeen eh gniht ylno ehT
,swalc wolley gnol rieht htiw segadneppa yrruf ,nworb ,egnarts ehT
?elbatrofmoc erom hcum saw
,gib yats ot derreferp yeht hcum woh wenk eH
2 trap( illetangiS yb
,hcihw roloc der krad a ot detfihs seye sih dna
,tsehc s’niboR gnipolevne sevael fo ssem eht tsniaga kcab gninael deyats eH
,won dnA .etelpmoc os
.erutaerc egnarts eht yb sdoow eht hguorht ybab a ekil
.eciov yrotalosnoc a ni derepsihw niboR ”!hsoG“
gnignah nehw
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
,kcen sih pu rehtruf gnibmilc erofeb trihs sih tsniaga gnihsup
,cinomed ylthgils kool mih gnikam fo esnepxe eht ta
.kaeps niboR ot gninetsil htiw dellarhtne yletelpmoc saw eH
.tnetnoc s’traeh sih ot knird dna
tlef ylraelc yrev htob yeht
”.erehwemos sdoow eht ni tuo nibac elttil a ni xaler tsuj ll’I ,llew …ton fI
,won litnu ,taht tnemtnahcne nA
”,taht sa elpmis sa gnihtemos no desab nosrep a tuoba tol a etiuq llet nac uoy denrael ev’I“
,trihs sih rednu dehctarcs eH
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
kcen sih fo ffo gnignah
”?gnihtemos uoy ksa I naC“
.noitnetta gniyap yllaer t’nsaw niboR
.dekoj eh ”,etirovaf ruoy M’I
”?gnihtemos ro repparw rab alonarg rehtonA“
a saw ti dezilaer nosyarG
.deipucco dnim yzah sih peek ot gniklat yllaunitnoc niboR fo emag a emoceb won dah
”?gniksa em dnim t’nod uoy fi ,yas taht s’tahW“
,ti erongi ot deirt eh tsrif tA .toh yrev
sevorg laiceps eht lla fo
.eromyna krow t’nac dna dlo m’I nehw em tsal lliw taht
.seye s’niboR otni kool ot kcen sih denarc nosyarG
”sklaW naM oN erehW“
.morf emac yeht htap eht no kcab gnitovip
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
”…yllautca s’tI .epoN“
meht deppord eh erehw fo eton koot niboR(
.ruf wolley eht fo tser eht sa
,tub ,tnemom eht liops ot tnaw t’nod I ?niboR ,yeH“
.seltsirb dna sevael eht nihtiw flesmih gniltsen
”.taht yas d’uoy gnipoh saw I …I“ .rettulf
,mra eht otno teef sih dekooh ylsselmaes nosyarG
,sredurtni namuh morf efas tserof eht gnipeek htiw deksat era yeht hguohT
.desufnoc ,deksa nosyarG
ytpme os leef ot evah ton dna
.smra nedoow rieht ni mih gniyrrac
…detsal dah klaw rieht gnol woh yltcaxe rebmemer nosyarG edam ti fo thgis ehT
,noos os ffo uoy tuc ot yrroS“
.taht retfa ecnelis drawkwa na saw erehT
er’uoY“ .llif sih dah d’eh erus erew yeht ecno ria eht otni pu kcab
.aedi eht deredisnoc ecno reven dah eh fi sa
,yllatnoziroh tuo mra rieht gnihcterts yb
egaugnal a ni nettirw
.rof esu a dnif reve dluow yeht deveileb reven yeht
tuB…  .dnim sih fo kcab eht ta mih deggan taht ,tnecer gnihtemos …elbazingocer
”.htrow ym evorp ot evah I ,taht teg ot redro ni dnA
.mlap s’niboR fo edis eht ffo delgnad sgel sih sa
.ylisae tsom worg dluoc srewolf etaciled ylralucitrap wenk yeht erehw
.yltcaf-fo-rettam deilper nosyarG ”,eriter ot yenom deen uoY“
.meht was eh nehw flesmih tew retnuh a noisacco eno no erus ytterp erew yeht woh dna
yeht sA  ”?ereh tuo ylenol teg uoy oD“
.ecalp tsrif eht ni siht htiw hguorht og ot meht desuac tahw gnirebmemer yb
…edir noollab a sa debircsed eb ylno dluoc tniop siht ta etats latnem siH
niboR htiw yawa gnittahc deunitnoc eH .ti no gnituorps sriah wolley
?ereht kcab gniog yppah eb yllaer nosyarG dluoW
,drow a tuohtiW  .ti wenk
.emoh sih gnihcaer erofeb yaw gnol a klaw ot evah llits dluow nosyarG dna
,yhtrowtsurt dna dnik ydobemoS
.ecalp koot segnahc eht fo tsal eht sa ecaf sih no ssenihcti dna trofmocsid erom tib a saw tlef eh tsom ehT
,trohs sih gnihcaer yllautneve
,won taht gniod morf uoy gnippots s’tahW“
tseippah syawla saw eh
,uoy hcaer od sehcir elttil tahw ni gnikar
.dezilaer yllanif eH
.ti ot pu eb ot TNAW I fi neve ro
gninetsil deunitnoc dna
erutxet dna roloc emas eht ot
,ecaf sih ssorca daerps ruf nworb ehT
.efil ym fo erom yawa evals ot ’ytinutroppo‘ eht evah tsuj ll’I ,yenom htiw gnola tuB
”?gnuoy llits er’uoy elihw
.mih fo tnorf ni ria eht ni gnah ot demees tsomla …gnihtolc
,revir gnihsur yltneg eht
detsisni syawla ohw loohcs hgih morf lrig eroc-egattoc gniyonna eht tuoba deklat eh nehw ekil
.flesruoy no drah etiuq er’uoy taht noisserpmi eht tog I“
.emas eht deniamer llits eciov sih
gnileef erew yehT
.sexof tluda gninnuc otni werg
lla ti dezilanoitar niboR tuB
!nosyarG ,uoy ekilnu yrev s’tahT ?togrof uoY“
”?rebmemer ,knird a teg dluoc uoy os ereh gnimoc tsuj erew eW
.trap taht ta dehgual nosyarG
,wodahseye ekil tsomla
.sevlesmeht rof gnidnef
spup sselpleh ,ynit nehw
.eciov tfos ylgniziremsem s’niboR ot
.tnemevom s’niboR yb dekcor erew yeht sa
.hsulb tub pleh t’ndluoc nosyarG
s’rehto eht tuoba erom gninrael no neek htob htiw
.mih ekil tab rof gnittif ,elgnairt yhself
thgis eht detaicerppa yltnelis htob
.rof skrow enoyreve tahw s’tahT“
.retaw enitsirp eht ni ylnaelc detcelfer saw hcihw noom gnisir eht fo
,eciov nwo sih revo meht raeh t’ndluow nosyarG taht os hguone ylteiuq tsuj ti daer yehT
”?emoh raluger ruoy ni ekil efil s’tahw ,oS“  )2 fo
,seye sih esolc dluoc nosyarG taht hguone hgih tsuj
tnemtnahcne ralucitrap a saw tI
selcric wolley owt demrof
.efil ”dezilivic“ a gnivil fo strap dab dna doog eht tuoba mrots a pu deklat eh
,sevlesmeht rof ylno ton deirrow yehT
.gnihtolc namuh fo tes lluf A“
erew yeht desserpmi woh dna
,nrob saw eh tnemom eht morF
,emoh dellac syawla dah yeht
nworb krad a otni detfihs dah osrot sih fo tser eht elihw
?lla ti fo tniop eht s’tahW“  ”.erus …mU“
sdrawno dehcram niboR sa dehsulb yllanoisacco dna ,dehgual
,tserof eht fo trap tsepeed eht fo edistuo nosyarG wollof ot elba t’nerew yehT
.ni saw eh ecnart egnarts eht fo tuo deppans nosyarG
dnuf tnemeriter a ni ti tup dna ,teg I kcehcyap hcae fo tuc a ekat ll’I
,god.ecioveht ta
.sgniht morf nwod-edispu gnah ot mih wolla ot swalc eht htiw gnirehtet osla tub
.mottob eht ta raf deirub
tuo lleps eht gnidaer ni shtgnel taerg nekat dah yehT
sroodni emit hcum os dneps uoy od yhW
.ti etadommocca ot dnah sih morf gninehtgnel dna
devac eh ,yllautnevE
.gninraey a …ssenitpme na
yreuq s’nosyarG derewsna niboR
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
.gnixaler deunitnoc nosyarG dna
.kaeps dluoc yeht ylno
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
,esiar slamina eht nees dah yeht seilimaf eht fo ekops yehT
?ereht tuo evivrus eh dluoW
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”.emit gnol a ni dah ev’I nuf tsom eht si sihT
drawno dehcram ruf nworb eht neht dna ,dniheb sih no deraeppa bun elttil a sa
.meht fo owt eht revo nellaf dah taht ecnelis rednet eht ekorb dna
nwod dekool yehT
.eltneg os si luos ruoY
,revir eht evoba tuo mra rieht dleh niboR
ylhgih ekops niboR
”.esle gnihtyna naht erom ,eruliaf fo raef a morf semoc ti sseug I
.daeh sih fo tser eht sa llat sa tsomla erew yeht litnu gnihcterts
traeh s’niboR edam
.tceffe gnikat lleps eht
”?roloc etirovaf ruoy s’tahW“ .dessimsid niboR
.nruter ni ylitraeh dehgual niboR
,edargitigid erom emoceb ot derutcurtser senob eht dna
.detrats eh ”?…dnim uoy dluow ,yeH“
fi snoinapmoc erom emos dnif ot deen uoy ebyaM“
.riah s’nosyarG ekorts ot deunitnoc yehT
dnoces tilps a rof ti fo espmilg a thguac nosyarG
.meht no denwad yllanif ti
.tniop siht ta gnihtyna
?niaga ereh emoc ew did yhw …mu
”?uoy t’nera ,yob ytsriht laer a
,trihs sih ffo koot dna
ylbatrofmocnu dehcterts osla enobliat siH
;ti deksa d’eh tnemom eht ecnis meht gniugalp neeb ylterces dah taht
.hcnarb eert a erew ti fi sa
”sklaW naM oN erehW“
”?morf emoc taht d’erehw …tub
tsrif ta ,nosyarG roF
,nwod-edispu detovip
,gniklaw detrats d’yeht ecnis emit tsrif eht rof taht erawanu
,srae sih fo stnemevom elcsum eht revo lortnoc erom hcum dah won nosyarG
,niaga ecno wolley erew
.daeh ym revo foor a evah nac I os yenom ym fo lla laets ot droldnal a rof gnikool fo niap eht htiw kcuts m’I ,taht lla fo pot no
.niaga ecno dehsulb nosyarG ”…wwA“
.delkcuhc nosyarG  …roF  …rof llA
,illetangiS yb
.gnitacoffus tsomla saw ti gnol erofeb tub
yllarutan os eciov s’niboR no sucof ot meht detcerid eh dna
.elbarenluv ylegnarts leef niboR
yojne esaelP  .efil ddo
.noococ wolley a ekil sgniw sih ni pu flesmih depparw dna
.tsehc sih no hcti egnarts a naht erom gnihton ekil tlef ti
.efil ym fo tser eht rof em tsal ot won yenom hguone evah t’nod I“
,sruoh ekil tlef tahw retfa ,yllaniF
,cihpromoporhtna llits hguoht ,nosyarG
tfihs dna regnol hcum worg ot ti gnisuac dna riah nworb
”,deneppah sah siht emit tsal eht rebmemer t’nac I“
.si ti keew eht fo yad tahw ot noitnetta yap ot deen neve t’nod ylbaborp uoy teb I
,tuo worg ot deunitnoc riah wolley eht sa
,swalc prahs otni denehtgnel slian sih sa
.ot gninruter htrow ecalp a ekil lla ta mees t’ndid ti-
gnittis eh saw yhW
,pu dekrep srae siH
,ynahpipe taht gnihcaer retfa noos os
.mih gnidnuorrus seert kao eht dehctam taht
dezad tas llits ohw
?yltnecer lufsserts neeb s’ti yas uoY“
.mih ot ekops yeht sa etarbiv tsehc s’niboR gnileef
.gniklat taht lla morf yrd ylbaraebnu saw taorht sih
.)retal pu meht kcip dluoc yeht os
.od ot dekil syawla eh sa
”?yas snamuh ynam sa dehsur sa yllaer dlrow ruoy sI
dezilaer niboR sa gnineddas erom eht lla ti edam ,esruoc fo ,sihT
pihsnoinapmoc rof dneped dluoc yeht mohw no
-ytsenohsid dna ,sserts ,noititepmoc eht lla--dnuos ti edam nosyarG yaw eht htiW
?uoy htiw ti erahs t’now ohw elpoep rehto ot sehcir gnirb ot redro ni enihcam a ot edutivres ruoy gnireffo dna
gnileef ylneddus saw eh tub
.gnorw saw tahw dootsrednu eh tsal ta tub ,gniciton mih tuohtiw gnol os no enog dah ti woh wonk t’ndid eH
.delifed gnitteg emoh rieht tuoba saw niboR sa tespu sa ylraelc ,dehgis nosyarG
…daeh sih pu daerps tsuj t’ndah ruf ehT
,seye sih desolc nosyarG
.did eh nehw noitisop gnignah reizoc hcum eht ot detfihs dah eh taht gniht doog
,ti nialpxe t’ndluoc eH
,tab wolley dna nworb a saw ecalp sih nI
”!erehwon fo elddim eht ni dnuorg eht no tsuj ,ebordraw elohw ehT .kcapkcab a neve
,emit gnol a rof desuap nosyarG  .deksa niboR
.nepo tohs seye s’nosyarG
,noitisnart eht gniruD
.seot eht ni tnemevom fo tnuoma doog a gniwolla llits elihw
.mih gnitroppus niboR htiw
.llew saw osrot sih nwod rehtruf daerps dah ti
dehcaorppa niboR dna nosyarG sA
.thgir er’uoy ebyam hguohT“
”…snamuh dnatsrednu reven ll’I“
gniworg segadneppa-oduesp wen emos htiw
,ylsuodnemert tuo werg
niboR dna mih neewteb noitasrevnoc a yllanigiro saw tahW
.laer erew niboR ekil serutaerc taht
.sedis lla no meht dednuorrus taht
a gnieb drawot ssergorp no edam t’nevah I dnoces eno neeb sah ereh tuo tneps ev’I dnoces yrevE
,retaw eht ni daeh sih egrembus
.flesym otno decrof adnik I gnihtemos saw sihT .yllaer ,ton m’I“
.aedi on evah uoy ,hO“
,nosyarG taht tniop siht ta saw tI
riap ruo nioj eW
?emoh sih hcaer ot nosyarG tnaw neve niboR did ,tcaf nI
noitseuq s’nosyarG ot kcab thguoht yehT
.ylsuoiruc deilper nosyarG ”?gnihtolC“
.ti debircsed dah niboR sa ,”keerc“
…syadkeew no tneduts emit-lluf a m’I
lever ot deunitnoc eh sa tsehc s’niboR otni gninael ,dehgis nosyarG
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,tnemmoc hcae no yltnetni gnisucof
.sgel sih ta derats nosyarG  …sgeL
”,htiw sevlesmeht nrecnoc dluohs namuh a gnihtoN“
nialpxe t’ndluoc nosyarG
ruf retrohs fo reyal yhtlaeh
noitingocer fo ngis emos dewohs yllanif
.ti tuoba kniht neve t’ndid eh taht
.meht detelpmoc ohw namuh eht ot
.od ot flesmeht dettimrep yllamron yeht tahw naht erom raf erutan dna etaf ni gnilddem ekil tlef siht …siht gniod larommi tlef taht niboR fo trap gib a saw ereht ,esruoc fO
,meht fo htob rof ecneirepxe euqinu a saw tI
,smra sih fo htob nwod daerps tI
”.ytniatrecnu eht osla tub ,sserts eht ylno ton fo daeh ym raelc oT .ereh tuo emoc ot dedeen I yhw s’tahT
dna …egelloc ym ta bulc gib a rof yenom eht eganam
wollof ot gnihtemos niarb sih gnivig
evil ot detius yltcefrep won erew yehT
.gniyas saw niboR tahw yltcaxe gnitniopnip emit drah a gnivah saw nosyarG
.suoicsnocbus nwo sih ni tsol yletelpmoc emoceb t’ndid eh os
,ytilaer ot dah eh rehtet ylno eht saw eciov s’niboR
”.ereh tuo tem reve ev’I noinapmoc etirovaf ym er’uoY
.hcamots sih sa wolley elap emas eht gnieb niks eht htiw
.sgniht gniod fo yaw elbatrofmoc tsom eht ylpmis saw ti
evresbo dluoc yeht erofeb gnol ekat t’ndid ti
,yenruoj eht detrats tsrif d’yeht nehw
.niboR htiw ereh gniyats reippah hcum dluow nosyarG .eciov sih ni
.”niboR“ demankcin sah eh ohw
,taht etipsed teY
gnileef rebmemer dluoc niboR emit tsrif eht saw sihT
”.uoy tuoba nac I sa hcum sa gninrael ni detseretni ylpeed m’I …llew
evah yllaer t’nod I .noitces siht ni tup yllamron uoy tahw t’nsi siht fi yrroS[  .ecitnerppA_retirW
…rehtona eno tuoba ytisoiruc elbaitasni na dah riap ehT
,yrots yadyreve dna lausac erom a ni pils dluow eh ,yllanoisaccO
.noisiv thgin retteb hcum delbane
.taorht sih deraelc nosyarG  .dnal t’ndid
.sklaw erutan erom no em yrrac ot hguone gnorts eb llits lliw seenk ym neht yb yllufepoH
.yponac eert eht ni daeh rieht htiw
,niboR htiw yawa yad eht gniklat ysub oot neeb evah tsum eH
!tem reve ev’I eno tseisub eht eb ot evah uoy tub ,erofeb sevil lufsserts rieht tuoba klat snamuh emos draeh ev’I“
srae eht fo sedisni ehT
?ereh tuo ylenol teg uoy oD …mU .yrroS“
nosyarG detfil niboR
.efil elohw sih ti gniod neeb dah nosyarG hguoht sa dekool ti taht larutan dna sselmaes os saw tnemevom ehT
,traeh sih ni peed taht wenk flesmih nosyarG nevE .efil ”dlo“
,dniw eht hguorht nwolb gnieb saw dnim nwo sih fi sa
nettogrof ylkciuq saw gnisum fo tib tahT
,doof namuh deyojne yltaerg eH
tserof peed eht otni kcab taerter rieht nageb riap eht sA
.meht dnuora yrenecs suoegrog eht ot noitnetta hcum taht gniyap erew meht fo rehtieN
,nosyarG ekil tab a rof tub ,nwod edispu gnignah elihw gniknird fo tra eht ni desrev-llew ton ydobyna ot drawkwa dekool evah thgim tI
,tsehc s’niboR tsniaga kcab rehtruf denael nosyarG  ”.tluda ’laer‘
.detnemmoc nosyarG
.knird a rof emac yeht esruoc fO
:noitanitsed rieht gnihcaer yllanif saw niboR taht ees dluoc eh ,daeha pU
,yrotirret rieht fo egde eht gniraen erew yeht
,siht gniyas eb ot si ti cinori woh wonk I“
,dnuora mih gnuws yltneg niboR sa
.revo lla ruf gniworg saw eh taht tcaf eht fo erawanu yllufssilb
eybdoog yas ot evah dluow yeht
,sgniw tab gninoitcnuf tey egral fo riap etelpmoc a dah
,tlef yeht tahw ebircsed ot drow thgir eht sa ti fo thguoht reven dah yehT
,netfo yrev taht ekil retnab ekam ot teg t’ndid yehT .deppiuq yeht
!pu llits saw nus eht
.mih ot gnineppah saw tahw eciton t’ndluoc nosyarG yaw on saw ereht ,won yB
,gniklaw elbatrofmoc rof dewolla ylno ton yeht ;efil elbuod a
llorcs a dnuof yeht litnu dnuora gud dna ,tsiaw rieht ta lehctas eht otni dehcaer eht ,ekops yeht sA
.noitcennoc lautum nekopsnu na
,yrotirret rieht fo tuo sretnuh ”evarb“
.ti dehsup dniw eht erehw ylno og ot elba ,sselnoitcerid
tirips eht fo eciov eht ot gninetsil
.ralucitrap ni gnihtyna ta gnikool tuohtiw ecnatsid eht otni ffo gnirats
.edam eno rehto eht ,llams ro gib
sih ot kcab gniog yppah neeb evah t’ndluow nosyarG
.ecalp siht ni si gnihtyreve liuqnart dna wols woh htiw yllaicepsE
,rekrow a eb ot gniyduts yb ti rehtiw uoy od yhW
.pihsnoinapmoc gnitsalreve
erom emos rof kool dluohs I
,wolley s’tI ?huH“
I …noitaroproc gib a ta emit-trap krow I sdnekeew dna syadsendeW no
,nwo rieht fo tfihs egnarts a hguorht tnew teef
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,nrut s’nosyarG saw ti revenehW
.yaw gnol a emoc dah erus yehT
.tnemom a rof tsuj
…drow tahT .desuap eH
.namuh eht deksa niboR
,denediw seye sih
esoht denodnaba ecnis gnol dah nosyarG tub
,deppiuq owt eht ,elihw eht llA
,noitasrevnoc eht no detaxif ylmrif llits
,ylesnetni noiton eht derednop eH
.nosyarG rof osla tub
.htaerb sih rednu gniht eno ylno derettum nosyarG
,stnap dna ,skcos
.fles dlo sih sa elbazingocernu yletelpmoc won saw
,”foolf“ wolley diviv erom sih dehctam taht
,pu ti detfil niboR sa