hsipeehS gnileeF rof ,drofwalC ecilA
detalosi gnileef erew elpoep dlrow eht revo lla dna
sdneirF dna ikahK yb
,sevaeL fo gniltsuR eltneG A rof
/ ,hguorht nellaf s’nalp eht nehW
tseR devreseD-lleW A rof ,xoFarakaS
/ tnemom a rof tsuj tahT
,sgnileeF dessiM rof ,edniM JT
:hcihw fo gnikaepS
si yrots s’yadoT
,rehtaeL deliO rof ,yaD ecyoR
swolliW eht ni dniW ehT rof ,emaharG htenneK retniW sseldnE rof ,enrohtwaH SJ
ssiK 'sirpyK ,looF detraeH tfoS a fo tcaP elbatirahC ehT rof ,floW-pilS
.kcab emac yeht emit yreve
eeffoC gninroM rof ,sreviR neruaL
sepirtS sih gninraE rof ,naloaF
swolliW eht ni dniW ehT ,swolliW eht ni dniW ehT rof ,emaharG htenneK yb
,esrevinU eht fo egdE rof ,sicoV sumoD
,taht ot teg ew erofeb tub — sdneirf dna
srekaM feihcsiM rof ,eriD
,floWisakiM reyarP tA
enoemos taht wonk ot elpoep detnaw llits I
,”egnartS dna lufituaeB ylesnetnI“
/ retto eht fo liat eht
,yrebboR dleifdaH ehT rof ,lufraF lacsaP
,ssorC dercaS ehT
,tsiM eht ni reviR ehT rof ,elawD
,gninroM eht rof tI evaeL
,tsael ton tub tsal dnA
,pU gninaelC rof ,dloG lleyK
.raey tsal eht ni
wohS thgiL elttiL
dellotxe sesiarp dima ecarbme dna
emoH s'ydoboN
elcnU retnuH ytnuoB ,edulerP
ecnaD eM hctaW naC uoY
ecnenitsbA rof ,lardehnA
enozdneirF tnegA ,feihT a hctaC oT
/ em erofeb yrots a
rehtegot derehtag er'ew / rehtehw no segar hcihw
noitcartsiD elttiL A rof
raewrednU raeW reveN I
,hgiH enilanerdA ,srerutnevdA ehT
.keew txen rehtona s'ereht  raef ton od ,dneirf neht
”dloT erA seirotS erehW“   :yojne esaelP
,roreuqnoC ehT rof
,llaH retraC eeneR
,yletairporppa ,saw tsrif ehT
,kecluV erodoehT fO yenruoJ tsaL ehT"
,"rehtorB kcaP dna ,dnabsuH devoleB ,redaeL
dediced I   .enoynA
,floWcaM boR retaW rof ,unutU
.enoemos rof retteb ,gnihtyna
uoY dniF oT ,galF eht etulaS
detinu ereh lla er’ew
,sdoG eht fo yrolG rof
silaeroB aroruA rof
/ rehtaew eht fo etips nI
,dreH nrohediW ehT rof ,relleK nosidaM naI
t'noD rof ,ebyC nosilA llA tI evobA oS toN ,ytpmE rof ,naidireM aroaF ekaC evaH mehT teL ,annoN
teem yam / gnikees neeb s'ti srae eht
,delS naicilaG rof ,irauR nosmirC
/ sretirw er’ew ,srevol er’ew
retnuocnE railimaF rof ,sivaD suiraD
.etad ot yrots yreve dednekoob sah ratiug eltneg esohw
goD fO ecioV ehT no deraeppa evah seirots 361  .tibah eht fo tuo llef dna ,yhw denialpxe reven I dezilaer I hguoht
,srettilG tahT llA ,emoH tsevraH
.em gnidulcni ,won 38 ,llew — sretirw 28 yb ,361
/ suoirotciv,srotciv
nI dewonS ,araS raeD
.dlot era seirots erehw  ereh ,llet draeh ev’I os ro / ereh llew eb lliw lla dnA / ereh llewd ew yam gnol dnA
rednefeD ykS rof ,kcilliK
,tnalP suorovinraC eht dna ydderhS ,snoillacspaR
?sgol fo gnilkcarc eht ,rethguad s’ecnirp-raeb eht
kcehC dnuoS rof ,wahS .C.K
/ ecnaifed ni dnats oS
worromoT syawlA ,speelS noiL ehT
,driaB boR  .meht knaht ot
.gnos s’yadot fo flah gnitirw rof dna
,I retpahC drawroF paeL A ,drawroF paeL A
ruodnelpS s'elgaE
,sknahT gniviG rof ,ybigreK enoL rof
,gnuremmädrettöG ta semaG rof
snaeB eeffoC detsaoR nogarD rof ,nalhguoC "uorihS" yaJ reyalpsoC noiL eht dna xoF ehT rof
/ srethgif er’ew ,sredaer er’eW
.llew sa nettogrof dna  dlotnu meht evael dluow / ecnelis gnitbuod-fles nehw
,deifirreT eM ruoloC rof ,regguR .P .B
,emaN siH toG rednaneM woH ,dooF tibbaR rof
/ ti erahs dna ,ti etirw uoy fI
.neht ecnis seirots detubirtnoc evah sretirw rehto ynaM .epoh fo dna
— sdneirf dna ,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb
/ !seciov fo yveb ruo / si eciohc fo nopaew ruO
,yrarbiL ehT rof ,sussateM
ytilibatciderpnU
,ecaR eonaC ehT ,efaC otcE
.sselrewop dna niatrecnu dna
eceipretsam hsirI lanoitidart eht no ffir a
esuohthgiL a dna kwaH a fO rof
,ecioV s'etoyoC ,naC uoY fI eM hctaC
dlo fo secnirP dna srepuap sa seippup dna
tsoL dlroW A rof ,namssierK leoJ
/ :yroeht ni ylno fi / ,eb raen lla su tel oS  ?eeht htiw rehtegot  tub
;kool a htrow erus era gnirudne dna wen htob /  gnirussaer snray dna
,flesmih secudortni eugor enotirab  / siht sa ratiug fo murts eht / si rafa morf muh tahT
ecnaifed fo yrots a osla tub — rewop fo ecaf eht ni ssensselrewop dna ,ssenriafnu fo yrots A
stakreeM ereW eW ecnO
poT eht revO rof ,elgooM goM
xirtaivA ehT rof ,dnE kraD
erif a yb selat fo  gnillet eht yb dellepmoc / gnillepsid noisserped /
,eniatnoF eralC ymA
,saipocunroc dekooc htiW
gnos sih fo esu eht rof regniarG nosloC dneirf ym knaht ot ekil osla d’I
reyalsnogarD rof
,yojne ot meht rof yrots wen a evah ot
yuG pU-dnatS laeR A
,seirrebwartS remmuS
,gnihtemos ekam ot tsuj ,gnihtyna—
enola ,ediserif eht / ta emoh ta leef yam I
traeh a sehcuot taht yrolg a dna ecarg a fo
.egaw sraw elituf nehw cimednap fo emit ni / cimelop lufraef dna
gninaW nooM suobbiG
tuocS ehT ,citsyM nabrU rof ,suileA
,edistuO tfeL naM htruoF rof
meht tuoba hguone derac
,enim fo etiruovaf a
,gninthgiL eht hctaC oT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,locotorP htoreZ ehT
,releeH eulB eht eiuolB
!dlob dna suoegaruoc gniciojer ,wolleb eW
goD toH rof ,egdirdooG neB
ega etarepsed a no  eud eb ll’tner eht dna / ,oot nellaf s’epoh lla dna
,llaC fo troP esolC A
,kcaP ehT rof ,lerdnaK
,taobefiL ruO erA uoY rof
emaG s'rebmuN A ,niagA emoH
,dnerT eht gnikcuB
seulB etaD dnilB
,mrywkooB irikeneN skarakS eht htiW yaD A rof ,rekceB .F.C
.driaB boR dneirf ym yb ”!goD daB“
— ”ecalperiF eht fo sdneirF“ er’yehT
.oot ,uoy knaht ot ekil d'I
.dlot era seirots erehw snoisiv ruoy hsidnarb / ot snoissim ruoy meht ekam dna / snoitidart ruo ecarbmE
edalB tsetsaF ehT
/ ythguan oot eno taht ro / ydwab oot s’eno siht fI
.seirots elpoep llet ot detnaw I
ti tuoba gnihtemos od ot detnaw I esuaceb tsacdop siht detrats I
,drawroF paeL A ,enihcaM eht fo traP A ,agaS s'kayneK rof
,xorgiT naecO looF ehT ,sexoF dna sekahskliM
,sukcarD nedaJ repeeK-etaG
,negramxirF .R.W
,gnirpSyaD seyEthgiN
,sserpyC ehT nI erehwemoS
,egatsoH rof ,hcinniM dieR
.dlot era seirots erehw  ereh ecalp a dnif noos yam / ti erac laiceps ekat dna
.derolpxe morf raf sI selbaf fo elbats ruo / taht raelc s'ti ,ybab ,ho / takreem a ebyam dnA
,eiP eileesnU rof ,idraciR lliB
gnilleber snoissap ruO
/ gnikaeps eb d'uoy hceeps ehT
/ sreppoc sa stibbar dna / srekcolrehS sa ecim htiW
,llebpmaC nayR
,yadnoM yzaL A rof ,noacyL edoyaK
,doG treseD eht fo eyE eulB ehT
/ yraoh s'ti ro etsahc s'tI
,sraob dna snoil neewteb dengis secnailla / eligarf dna cigart / slamina lacigam htiW
,namretuL g7erG sgoD oN rof
senihsyeknoM rof ,llewkcoR .B.J
,”dloT erA seirotS erehW“ saw sihT
,snoilliM gnomA kcoR A rof ,bmobknukS
"knukS ekiL sllemS ainigriV ,epirtsdaorB"
,waprevliS rennaT thgiN etaD
?god eht fo eciov eht ni dnuos sdrow s’xnihps eht erehw / dnuof eb snogard yam erehW / :dnuopxe elddir siht woN
,ecnaraeppasiD ,sgiG rof
flehs sih ffo koob a morf  esorp daer ot sdeecorp / noillacspar lufetarg dna / noinapmoc lufhtiaf ruoY
,traeh ym ni evol eht lla htiW
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,dutS ruoY tsuJ m'I rof ,etoyoC triD
/ suoiroton snialliv fO
,yromeM yzzuF rof
.llet ot nraey sluos ruoy  seirots evah lla uoy tub / yrogella lla s'ti
trapa rehtraf ro
eriuqer ew tahw era seirots suoirolg
eriF esaeC rof ,negnafthcaN ztlaW wonS tsriF ehT rof ,xoF yyxiV
terceS ,gninruteR
deB ot seoG elkrapS thgiliwT rof ,yeliaB nhoJ
:solihP & sedaH ,dioV etihW eht ni erehwemoS
eiryklaV reH dna dooH niboR rof ,opmeT
ksab ot ,senohpdaeh ym ro / ,ksam ym no tup I nehw
.ot drawrof kool ot gnihtemos ,esle gnihton fi dna ,epoh ro ,egaruoc meht evig dluow taht seirotS
,azziP rof gnixoF
seviL ruO fo syaD ehT erA esehT rof ,lesaeW
,suniplA  "CK" sisiriK
nedraG yM nI saeP oN ,taR gniylF
,nogarD gnicnaD eht dna ydderhS ,egraB eht egraM ,dribgnimmuH eht dna nnyletaK rof ,dwoL .E yraM
,yrtnuoc ym ni devirra dah cimednap eht fo ytilaer ehT
:esrevinu eht fo modsiw eht la dna
,saipotooz nabru
tfiG s'taR ehT rof ,xoftiK ozirraC
.koob a nepo uoy nehw dnif ll’uoy seizood
yuG pU-dnatS laeR A
,esroH eht odeloT
kcattA allihcnihC
,esuoM .T dleiF
/ cimetsys ecitsujnI
/ elttes ot gnihtemos fo / elttek a no tup oS
,naidrauG bmoT ehT
nettogroF eht gnirebmemeR rof ,gnaP .J.H
.derahs ev’ew raey tsal siht no tcelfer ot tnemom a ekat ot ekil d’I
,raeh ew taht eciov eht
.goD fo ecioV ehT no deria
,orevO ovitlA
,traC eht dna navrolG rof
,”yeksihW fo sruomuH ehT“
,emoH gnioG ,noisneT oykoT
erutluC-retnuoC ,skcuBeulB rof
.kees uoy tahw tsuj s'ti tub  reeuq dnuos yam lla ti / cihpromoporhtna dna / cihprO
/ ksa ot hcum oot ti sI
dloc eht ffo draw dnA spihsdrah dna seirrow ruoy
.dlot era seirots erehw  sisrahtac uoy trapmi / stsitra gnihtimsdrow erehw / si sruo fo nevah sihT
gnorW si uoY gnivoL
,staR rof ,iluaP secnarF
,ffutsyttopS thseheB
,hsawetihW ,nnI ehT tA
”dloT erA seirotS erehW“
pirT gnippohS rof ,kcezzoW rreH
/ retaw eht no flow ehT
,ihcatiH roirraW ecapS
selbairaV rof ,kiavoJ dnaloR
,dniM ruoY wolB yletelpmoC lliW tahT snrocinU tuobA stcaF elbaveilebnU 6 rof
seiretsym hguorhT
tnemom a ekat ot ekil d’I dna
mutcefrepmI supmeT rof ,gnoS lA wonS retniW rof
yrots tsrif eht oga raey enO
,taht denoitnem semitemos I seirots ylrae ni
/ ymrots dna krad ,thgin sawT‘
.C eerT gnihsiW ehT rof
,yralC-ttocS nosidaM
,latsyrC ,feeB detlaS
negawskloV a gniyalP ekiL
.wonk uoy ,tsacdop siht no seirots dah ev’ohw sretirw rof eman a s’erehT
ykS ehT nI sthgiL rof ,setaoC .R.F.J
gniS yretsyM eht hselF siH fO
,issaveleT !goD daB
,seirtnuoC woL eht fo noiL ehT rof ,reetyksuH
,ecaR eonaC ehT rof ,dwoL leinaD
,snoziroH enadnuM dnoyeB
arolF ekaF dna sdueF ,dooF rof
eb dluoc taht sdlrow eht ni
!dlot era seirots erehW emoclew er'yeht revocsid / sretirw dna srevol dna / srethgif dna sredaer nehW
,!skooB cimoC ruoy tegroF
,nesneJ arhtruT rinieL naD
,rettOtnacifingiS
,seirots eht ot netsil t’ndid yeht fi nevE
seulB etaD dnilB ,seulB etaD dnilB rof ,relleK nosidaM naI rednevaL dna nomanniC fo stsohG rof ,lwoH notsruhT
.dlot era seirots erehw
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
/ gnirulla sagas esehT
dloh ew snoinapmoc  eht