,taht hguorht nettog d'eH
"?daetsni em erongi ot dediced uoy oS"
.ogeiD ta kcab kool ot flesmih decrof neht
.bmob-f rehtona tuo tel dna wodniw rac eht tsniaga denael yaF
.won thgir detacilpmoc elttil a tsuj s'tI"
.thgin dloc a no erif a fo htmraw eht ekil
.sdneirf fo egatrohs on dah netram ehT .pleh rof mih
,ydob sih fo tsom gnirevoc ruf nworb-hsidder dah yaF
".ekat ro evig ,004
.llac a elcnu ym evig ...ll'I"
.ezag sih deppord eh sa elzzum sih ssorca gnirekcilf swodahs ,dewollaws eH "...I"
.gof ylkciuq ot nageb dleihsdniw eht hguoht
,yltnatsnoc deugra dah stnerap siH
,gnihtemos ro dneirf doog a
dedne yawevird eht erehw nrecsid ot drah saw ti peed os redwop etihw ni derevoc saw gnihtyreve
.sruoh eht tes I ekil ton s'tI"
.rof gnipoh saw ogeiD naht rekrad saw elkcuhc-flah s'yaF
".ti tseggus ot tnaw t'ndid I tub ,ecalp ruoy ta moor tog ev'uoy wonk I"
.dluoc eh fi pleh dluow eH .yaF saw sihT
.rufdaeh delevehsid sih hguorht sregnif wef a nar dna ffo tah sih deggut eH ".haey ...tub
"?sgniht gniworht neeb evah I dluohS"
.t'nsaw eh detseggus eno t sih hguoht ,dias yaF ",eniF"
"?nwotnwod tnemtrapa dlo s'rolyaT ni llits uoY"
,tsrif tA" ,dehgis eH ".rolyaT
.em rof tol a llits ...s'tahT"
- rehtegot hguorht neeb ev'ew gnihtyreve retfA"
.ylpeed sa ton tub
".ti ot dnuora tog reveN" .deggurhs ogeiD ".tuo
?rewohs a ekat I fi dnim uoy od ,netsiL"
.nethgit ot leehw eht no pirg sih dna taeb a piks ot traeh sih desuac ,gniteelf neve
.tcatnoc eye edam ogeiD dna eh nehw erow yaF noisserpxe denethgirf tub derit eht saw tnemom taht ni mih deracs tahW
,taht ot yas ot tahw wonk t'ndid ogeiD
.rotanretla dab a ekil sdnuos ti ,enohp eht no dias uoy tahw morF"
.nepo neeb syawla dah pihsnoitaler riehT
.uoy fo teews yllaer eb d'tahT"
"?yddot toh a ebyaM
dah ogeiD ,nwo sih no saw eh taht woN
,gnitnap flesmih dnuof eh litnu ylivaeh os gnihtaerb saw eh ezilaer neve t'ndid eH
?evitom roiretlu na
tuo tnew rewop eht esuaceb si won desolc er'ew nosaer ylno ehT
,uoy ot klat ot ecnahc a em evig naht rehtar dnA
".nwo ym no tuo lla ti erugif ot em tfel dna em detsohg uoy
.yaF dah eh sa meht fo eno ot esolc sa tlef reven d'eh tub ,nuf erew yehT
.nretnal eht yb tsac noitcelfer eht ni gninihs seye
.retfa netfo sa doom eht ni t'nsaw I
.moor gnivil eht fo dne raf eht no tenibac rouqil eht sdrawot ezag sih detcerid neht ,dekrims yaF ".semitemos
,hcum oot s'taht fI
".taht ekil gnihtemos no yenom dneps yllaer t'nac I ,uoy dlot I"
,tnim htaerb a
.sruoh wef tsal eht revo detalumucca dah taht redwop fo toof eht yb delffum wons no serit fo hcnurc eht
".emoh tnew tsicamrahp eht dna
,dias eh ",D ,yrros ...m'I"
.trevortni na fo erom saw eh tub
"?ytrap s'raeY weN ruo rof revo detivni uoy syug xis eht fo evif wolb ot tog ylno uoy esuaceb das tog uoy nehw
.ti dedaerd osla eh
,wons dna krad eht ni neve dna
.reeb eht sediseb hcum knird t'ndid ogeiD
.ti fo lla tuoba mlac os erew uoy tub
,etelhta lanoisseforp a t'nsaw eH
.meht ni hturt eht gniees morf yaF peek ot yltsom ,seye sih dellor ogeiD
tsehc s'netram eht ni deirub eson sih
".kcab em yap nac uoY" .deggurhs ogeiD
.evom eht gnirud rac siht ni tneps d'yeht emit eht fo mih dednimer tI
.deraeppa erutcip a litnu neercs enohp dekcarc a ta dekop sregnif dewalC ".mom
.leehw gnireets eht tsniaga ytaews tlef sdapwap s'ogieD
.drawkwa ssel siht ekam ot gniyrt m'I .acihcuP"
.emac uoy dalg m'I tuB .yllaer toN"
.gnol os rof ti gnieyd neeb d'eh retfa
.saw rolyaT evitcartta woh nettogrof ylraen d'eH
,pukaerb eht erofeb derahs d'yeht
.gnisaet-flah ,dias ogeiD
.ekops eh sa noitcerid s'yaF ni ti devaw eH
,evah dluow I esoppus I .hO"
,knis eht ni sehsid ytrid eht no ylfeirb deregnil ezag siH
.neht llac ruoy s'ti ,lleW"
.ogeiD ,ekas s'kcuf roF"
.elpmis gnihtemos detnaw tsuj eh semitemos tub
.hcamots sih fo tip eht ni tlef ogeiD taeh eht dekots tsuj noitcaer fo kcal siH
.esion fo ecnesba eht morf mih tcetorp ot fi sa derewol srae evitisnes siH
.elttek pmac ym dnif nac I fi ees ll'I
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
,efil sih fo tsom rof netram siht nwonk d'eH
".hsinif etiuq t'ndiD
,wap s'ogeiD ni reeb eht ot detfird seye sih tub
.semitemos ,bons laer a er'uoY"
"?desolc era rolyaT dna uoy oS"
,ogeiD rof pu ecived eht dleh eH
.derongi gnieb fo shtnom retfa ytsud ylthgils meht fo tsom ,selttob nezod a dleh srood ssalg dniheb sevlehs eerhT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro ,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.swerb citsemod paehc rof ecnereferp s'ogeiD no nwod dekool syawla d'eH
.yas ot esle tahw erusnu
,ereh emac I tuo sdnif eh fi ,yawynA"
a fo tnorf ni kcab wap a gnittup ,tnemom a rof deredisnoc yaF ".naem
,dias saw erom gnihton nehW
wolagnub tsedom eht fo yawevird eht otni dellup yehT  .tsael ta
.won thgir uoy pmuj ot gniyrt htrow eb dluow ti kniht t'nod I dna
aedi gnorw eht teg d'eh deirrow I
.gnilf a sa ti fo thguoht dah ogeiD
,dessip erew uoy wenk I
neeb ev'I dna tol a htiw gnilaed s'eH
?siht saw kcuf eht tahw ,naem I"
.yawyna retal eeffoc emos tnaw thgim I
.pu gnikaerb ecnis shtnom xis eht ni nekops t'ndah yeht taht dna
.detnioppasid saw eh fi sa mih ta dekool neht
riaper yllanif dluoc yeht os tcennocer ot tpmetta sih saw siht fi tahW
,sraey owt tsal eht fo stcepsa ynam htiw sa ,woN
.noisserpxe sih ni htrim fo tsohg a
rehtegot sepyt tnereffid eht yrt ot nuf neeb dah tI
.edis eht morf mih ta decnalg yaF
.gnillac ro yb gnimoc tsuj tuoba thguoht I
.esle gnihtemos tuoba ksa ot dediced dna dehgis ogeiD ,tnemom a retfA
.saw eh naht redlo ,derit dekool eH
,letoh a ta ffo uoy pord osla nac I rO
?emoh em gnikat dnim uoy dluow
.msimitpo dna ygrene s'yaF fo esuaceb ,trap ni
,nrut ot detrats yaF
,tseb detsat taht seno eht dnif ot dna
,tesolc moor tseug eht ni sehtolc dlo ruoy fo emos fo xob a tup I
,rac rekrad eht morf dehsur
,moor fo ytnelp s'erehT
".aedi doog a si taht lla fo retnec eht otni gnidaeh erus toN
.deredisnoc ogeiD
.wonk ot sdeen enoyna ekil ton s'tI .hguone riaF"
.kcolc nehctik eht fo gnikcit ydaets eht yb detautcnup saw meht neewteb dessap taht teiuq ehT
,thginot gninnur rac eht teg ot elba eb ot gniog ton er'ew fI"
.naem I ,rolyaT tuobA
,krow t'ndid tahT
,hcaeb ynnus a no hteet tcefrep htiw noocar yreehc ,citelhta na gniwohs
,tneconni ylevitpeced
.gnidneterp pots uoy tuoba woh nehT"  ".em htiw kroW
uoy morf eviecer I txet tsrif eht
.tuo llits saw rewop ehT
.wodniw eht hguorht rac sih ta derutseg eh ",tsoc annog si siht tahw swonk kcuF
,yaF naht rehto enoyna erew ti fI
.eciov sih denetfos dna
.tuo lla ti werht uoy demussa I tub sgniht wef a togrof I wonk I ?yllaeR"
.shtnom eerht fo lla rof nwonk d'uoy yug a htiw eb ot em depmud uoy - elpuoc a sa meht fo thgie ,sdneirf sa sraey neetruof
?yawyna ,eh s'erehW"  .deddon yaF
tub gnihton gniraew
.tuo tnew rewop eht nehw gnikab saw I"
.elims thgils a htiw mih ta derats ogeiD
.ekatsim elbirret a gnikam erew yeht taht werg etoyoc eht niatrec erom eht
,dedis-er ro detniap neeb dah semoh wef a tub
".elihw a rof elpuoc a gnieb yojne tsuj ot stnaw eh syas eH .yawyna ,won roF"
".tsrif mih gnillac deirt evah dluow uoy emussa I
.detrats teerts eht dna
".retaw liob ot gniog er'uoy woh erus toN
".egarag ym ni krow eht fo tsom od ylbaborp nac I dna
.enot sih ni ssenrettib eht niartser etiuq t'ndid eH "?yllaeR"
".rovaf a rof gniksa si
".taht ot eerga dluow uoy desirprus m'I"
.ytic eht fo tsom hguorht tuo si rewop eht
,gnineppah saw siht yhw dnatsrednu neve ot ro
!dam gnikcuf llits m'I
.mih nrecnoc t'ndid tahT .swap gnidloh
.enot yrotailicnoc erom a ni ekops eh ,esuap feirb a retfA
roloc nworb-hsidder larutan eht ees ot gnirraj saw tI
stxet dna sliame dna srettel etorw I
...ym otni denael I taht timda ll'I"
.drawkwa si siht wonk I ,netsiL"
,oidar eht no draeh I tahw morf ,lleW"
taht dnes d'I kniht yllaer uoY"
?rehtegot kcab teg ot detnaw eh fi tahW
.yawhgih eht yb egarag s'elcnu sih ta gnikrow sremmus gniretlews wef a tneps dah
.ecnatsid trohs a neve rof tuo kcab og ot suoregnad eb dluow ti
"?ti htiw KO er'uoy dnA"
.sknurt miws trohs-oot
,ryC rohtarB yb
,ni dellup eh sa ylduol depeeb renepo rood ehT
,paehc rof strap eht teg nac I erehw ecalp a wonk thgim eH
,ytic tseraen eht morf ruoh na flah naht erom ,tresed eht ni pu gniworG
.gnitarepo llits saw pukcab yrettab eht wonk mih gnittel
.detrats ydaerla dah secivres hcruhc retfa wep kcab eht otni gnikaens deciton eb ot ton gniyrt dlihc a fo stnemevom luferac eht htiw deretne yaF
.noitacovorp elttil htiw sboj no tuo gniklaw fo tibah a edam dah yaF
.ecnelis eht rof mih emalb t'ndid ogeiD
detanimulli sthgildaeh s'rac ehT
rolyaT htiw neeb d'uoy dnA
.wons ni gnivird detah ogeiD
.suoregnad erom tol a eb ll'ti
,thgin lla em desaet eH"
,neht yawa kool did yaF
,meht tnaw uoy fI" .won saw ti
.roolf eht ot delbmut meht fo wef A
,dloc eht etipseD
.rehtegot erew yeht elihw sreeb tfarc evisnepxe thguob yltsom etoyoc eht ,noissecnoc a sA
.emit elbissop tsrow eht ta em dehsubma uoY
.suoituac erom neeb evah dluohs eh fi derednow eh
.gnihtyna fo hcum ees ot tluciffid ti gnikam
,doohrobhgien eht otni denrut yeht sA
pihsnoitaler rieht saw ti taht nwonk evah eh dluoc woH
.esnopser s'yaF rof gnitiaw
.spac lla ni tuo nettirw ,etteyafaL
.rehtie tnegilid neeb t'ndah eh tub ,yltcaxe
.htaed fo erehpsomta elbaplap a saw erehT
.sgnileef sih gnidih ta retteb yllareneg saw dna
,letoh a ot uoy ekat tsuj llits nac I
.yawa kool ot flesmih decrof ogeiD dna denihs seye s'yaF "...ogeiD"
,teem sdne pleh oT
".dloc eb thgim retaw ehT
.deneppah dah tahw sserdda ot evah dluow yeht ,ekops yeht fI
".yas ot tahw wonk t'ndid I ...tsuj I
.mih ta kool t'ndid tub ,deggurhs yaF
- tnecs s'elam rehto ehT
.nooccar eht fo noisserpmi elbassap a rof edam enot s'yaF ni tnemeticxe xuaf ehT "!ynnus dna seerged yteniN"
.drawno mih dehsup noitagilbo fo esnes emos
,skeew thgie ,tahw rof
,tsenoh eb oT .won roF"
,yrruFoS no seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,daor eht otno dellup ylwols yeht sa teiuq yllacitsiretcarahcnu saw yaF ".wonk
.ruf fo sdnarts regnol eht fo emos ta gnikculp saw dna
".tuo gnignah tsuj s'ti fi nevE
”tuO ereW sthgiL eht elihW“   yojne esaelP
.htiw pu nworg dah ogeiD yaF eht fo wodahs a saw siht ...sihT
,neht mih ta kool did yaF
".sruoh wef a rof esuoh emas eht ni rehtegot gnieb eldnah nac eW .stluda er'ew ,oN" .tnev taeh
.dessap ecnelis drawkwa fo tnemom a retfa dias yaF
.yaF ,yrros m'I"  .dehgis eH
",taht htiw pu gnittup uoy enigami ot drah s'tI"
,retnuoc eht no tas won tI
,yks krad eht morf gnillaf llits sekalf kciht fo senoc thgirb
,niaga yawa dekool yaF ".taht
.dnim sih egnahc yaF tel ot desuap ogeiD
.taht no nael ot elba neeb dah ogeiD dna
erew taht seye neerg thgirb dah eH
.yaw sih og t'ndid stnemugra nehw dedoorb syawla eH
wap eno ni knird laciport fo dnik emos dah eH
,etoyoC triD yb daeR
.sdneirf ruoy tuoba suolaej gnitteg rolyaT denoitnem uoY"
.meht rof erots ni evah yam erutuf eht tahw dna
,teerts dewolpnu eht nwod htap ylenol a degrof rac ehT  2 fo 1 traP ,ryC rohtarB yb
.tnemom a rof egami eht dedrager ogeiD
.moc tod rettiwt fo
dellac dah yaF yhw tuoba yrrow eht saw erongi ot redraH
.yenom ekam nac ew kniht yeht sa gnol sa nepo su speek etaroproC
.ecneinevnoc elpmis neeb evah yam ti os ,krow s'yaF raen evil did ogeiD
.elims a decrof yaF
,evird leehw lla dna serit wons htiw nevE
.enohp sih dekcehc ogeiD sa meht neewteb deregnil ecnelis A
,skool detseretni fo ytnelp tog ogeiD
.em htiw yats ot tnaw uoy fi mraw su peek ot gniog erif a teg nac I dna
.niaga klat ,wonk uoy
".sruoh rof nwod tuhs neeb s'ytic eht fo tsoM ?siht ni gnikrow neve uoy era yhW"
.flesmih sseug dnoces dluoc eh erofeb tuo lla ti gniyal saw ogeiD dna
raey tsal rebmemeR"
.regnarts a ta gnikool saw eh ekil tlef eh dna
".tseb ylbaborp si letoh a sseug I ,enif neht
ylremrof ,etoyoC triD yb uoy rof daer ,ryC rohtarB yb
,ezeens neddus a ekil ,dna
".tenibac enicidem eht ni
,noissucsid taht evah ot detnaw ogeiD elihw dnA
.noitnetta sih hctac ot demees secnereffid esoht
".llems ylbaborp I
,eerged sih no dekrow ogeiD elihw edisa kaerts suoilleber taht fo emos devohs d'eh
.erecnis dnuos dluow ti detbuod eh esuaceb flesmih deppots tub ,dezigolopa tsomla eH
.ecnetnes eht hsinif t'ndid dna ffo deliart eh "...htiw emit drah a gnivah
.saw netram eht ,siht ekil ti gniees ot desu saw enoyna fI
.kcab ti dleh eh tub
,wap eno htiw nepo rood eht dleh eH
.tnev eht ot kcab meht gnivom erofeb htmraw rof rehtegot meht debbur dna swap sih otni welb yaF
,serutaef sih gnirucsbo ylfeirb noitasnednoc fo duolc a
.tiaw noitasrevnoc eht tel ot tseb ti thguoht eh
.gnimoc saw ti dezilaer d'eh erofeb elzzum sih fo tuo saw krans eht
.tekcit eno rof yap ylno dluow mom siH"
gib oot ezis a dekool erow eh trihs olop eulb thgil ehT
.yawyna gniog erif a teg ot gniog saw I"
.esrow leef em gnikam tsuj s'ti tub
".ti htrow t'nsi ruoh na skcub neT
.ecnelis fo staeb lareves retfa dias eh
.lla retfa ,sraey eht revo spihsnoitaler hcus nwo sih dah d'eH
",ahsirT htiw pu dekooh neht
,krap ni elcihev eht gnittup dehsinif neve d'eh erofeB
.pu sgniht dekcuf I yldab woh yb dessarrabme saw I"
.gniht fo dnik taht gniod llits er'uoy dalg m'I"
,noos emit yna ereh tuo kcurt wot a teg ot gniog ton er'eW"
,noisserpxe s'xe sih daer t'ndluoc etoyoc ehT
.netram eht morf gnisaet suoitatrilf ro tnemeticxe ylbbub detcepxe d'eH
".gnihtemos gniylpmi ma I sseug I .haey ,oS"
yaF dna ogeiD woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
,sretniw nretsewdiM eseht ot desu t'nsaw llits etoyoc naronoS ehT
.smelborp eht htiw evil ot nrael ot saw
.tcatnoc eye edam netram eht sa deretlaf eH ".yaF
,elpuoc a neeb d'yeht erofeb gnol sdneirf neeb d'yehT
.smra sih dedlof etoyoc ehT
,floWcaM boR si sihT
",stnelat ruo evah lla eW"
".rof doog saw I gnihtemos s'ereht wonk ot ecin s'tI ?hO"
.trihs dekcut ylesool sih no gniggut
.nehctik eht ssorca gnicap ,pu swap sih werht ogeiD  "?leurc eb ot
.drazzilb gniogno eht fo slwoh eht yb eiree edam swodahs gnol gnitsac
.riahc a fo kcab eht revo taoc sih depard netram ehT
.moc tod rettiwt fo ylremrof
,yadrutaS a no thgindim raen
.denworf netram eht woN
.degnahc lla dah taht ,evom eht retfA
.wolb a dednal d'eh taht deifsitas saw ogeiD fo trap A
.hgis deveiler a tuo tel dna
,evird leehw lla dna serit wons htiw neve dna
.si moorhtab eht erehw wonk uoY" "?rewohs eht ...oS"
.sedaced owt tsomla rof noitcif yrruf gnitirw neeb sah dna
,mih rof erutnevda na neeb dah gniht eritne ehT
",uoy ekil dnuos t'nseod tahT"
.tsehc dna taorht sih ssorca egnaro ymaerc fo hctap gnirulla na htiw
nehW .keew lluf a rof pirt krow a no yawa neeb dah ogeiD retfa emoc dah pihsnoitaler rieht fo dne ehT
.tnorf eht ssorca yhpargillac ni nettirw eman sih dah epolevne yrovi dessobme ehT
.sdneirf dlo ruo lla fo suoicipsus gnitteg detrats yaT nehT
,dias etoyoc eht "?thgir lla uoY"
,degnahc dah hcum toN
".laed gib a ton s'ti
.kcen sih fo kcab eht ro
,neetriht ot pu m'I"
.stifeneb esoht etaicerppa ot gnol ogeiD nekat t'ndah ti dna
,tnarodoed larolf fo gnilgnim a
.tnev elddim eht fo tnorf ni swap etaciled sih debbur dna derevihs yaF ,ogeiD ot txeN
,wodniw tnorf egral eht ot moor eht ssorca decnalg ogeiD
.elbat gninid eht fo flah kcab eht no delip sexob draobdrac eht dna
.teiuq gniyats elihw liat sih ta gnikcip yltnesba
.mih fo retteb eht teg regna sih tel evah t'ndluohs eH
.yaF dna ytidommoc erar a regnol on erew srentrap lauxes elbaliavA
hgiht sih dnuora liat niht gnol sih delruc dah yaF
troter lufetips rehtona nwod dewollaws ogeiD
,yad taht litnu tuB
"?ogeiD ,gnihtemos gniylpmi uoy erA"
ogeiD ,neet a sA .ecnelis eroM ".suoregnad
...eb ot gniyrt er'uoy wonk I
".ti htrow eb ll'tI .D ,sknahT"
.ogeiD ta deggut tliuG
.niaga ekops yaF ,yllaniF
.emit gnol a rof uoy ot klat ot gnitnaw neeb ev'I" .wol eciov
.kcab teg I nehw gniticxe erom elttil a gnihtemos su ekam I t'nod yhW"
.meht raen gnivil elihw nwohs reve d'eh naht tseretni erom htiw ssap sesuoh eht dehctaw yaF
.repmet s'ogeiD ta hcnilf t'ndid yaF
.sraey ynam sa ni sboj eerht hguorht enog llits d'eh tub
.ecnetnes sih gnihsinif fo yaw a sa mih fo tnorf ni wap a tpews eh "...retfa
daor eht no nwod kaerb uoy fI
.mom sih gnitisiv yeK radeC ni nwod s'yaT tub
.mih derehtob taht dna
.dennuts dnA !detsuahxe saw I"
...ot deirt ew erofeb emit emos ti evig dluohs I thguoht tsuj I
taes regnessap s'ogeiD otni debmilc eh erofeb
.ycamrahp eht morf yawa dellup dna esrever ni rac eht tup eh
,moor gnivil krad yltsom a ni rehtegot ylteiuq gnittis yaF dna rolyaT dnuof dah ogeiD  .tuo nekat neeb ydaerla dah sgniht s'yaF fo tsom taht eciton t'ndid eh
pihsnoitaler rieht elicnocer
"?wenk I erus ekam ot tsuj
,eman nevig sih dah tsehc sih fo edis tfel eht no gat eman citsalp eht dna
dnuora sseug d'I .dab os ton s'tahT
.aidem laicos ot gnitsop emit fo tol a tneps ohw enoemos fo nirg decitcarp fo dnik eht erow dna
,haey ,tahw wonk uoy ,dnA"
.esrow tog ylno taht
.derettam ti taht toN
.tiw prahs a gnilaecnoc ,dnik dna egral
.htiw peels ot desu I syug htiw emit dneps I nehw suolaej steg rolyaT"
.nepo eht ni tuo ti teg nac ew os ti tuoba klat tsuj ew naC
.deirrow er'uoy fi
,sreganeet erew yeht nehW
.seye sti derewol wodniw regnessap eht no noitcelfer tnerapsnart s'yaF
,ecafrus eht ot liob shtnom xis tsal eht fo noitome pu tnep eht lla edam tsuj taht noisserpxe daed tsomla na htiw mih dedrager yaF ".elohssa nA .toidi ehcnip a er'uoY ?ti yas ot em tnaw yllaer uoY .eniF"
.deifsitas-fles saw elims s'yaF ".yawyna
.wons fo teknalb a yb derucsbo saw ti fo tsoM
.rolyaT htiw saw I taht
,mih dnuora eb ot tnaw uoy edam tsuj taht flesmih gniyrrac fo yaw a dah eh ,taht dnoyeB
pihsnoitaler mret gnol doog a ot yek eht taht dna
".yad gnol a neeb s'tI
".siht ni evird uoy gnikam rof yrros m'I
,elpuoc a regnol on erew yeht taht mih dednimer taht dnim sih fo kcab eht ni tbuod eht derongi eH
,taeh eht deknarc etoyoc ehT
,yrenecs railimaf eht morf tog yeht rehtruf eht dna
,ni gnivird erew yeht snoitidnoc eht neviG
.yenom eht esol t'naC" .deggurhs yaF
,won thgir sdeen su fo rehtien taht amard emos trats lliw ti
,em gnirongi fo shtnom retfA"
.cimanyd taht yb deifsitas neeb d'eh ,emit eht tA
,reilrae shtnom wef a tem d'yeht ecnis esolc nettog dah owt ehT
,emoh ot resolc tog yeht sA
tah dettink dna taoc etihw yklub a ni deldnub ,netram evitunimid a
.sexob fo kcats a rednu tuo gnikop saw ti erehw morf liam fo eceip a dellup dna elbat eht dnuora deppets ogeiD ".siht
.sevil rieht rof deraef dna ,sdneirf esolc dna stnerap sih tuoba thguoht yletaidemmi eH
,yrotsih ruo nevig dnA
.erom dna ,ytiniffAruF
.pihsnoitaler taht fo ycamitni eht deyojne yaF raelc saw ti dna
yarps ksum ruoy fo emos tfel uoy erus ytterp m'I dna
,lortnoc fo esnes emos tlef eh tub
.ti htiw og dluow yteixna eht fo emos gnipoh ,htaerb wols a tuo tel eH
,emoh morf raf delevart dah meht fo rehtieN
.dehgis ogeiD dna ,tnemom a rof gnihtyna yas t'ndid netram ehT  ".hO"
,og ecalp eht tel t'ndah ogeiD
.pihsnoitaler rieht ni seussi gniregnil eht erongi ot gniyrt dna boj wen a no gnisucof neeb dah ogeiD
.niaga edistuo dekool dna tekcop sih otni kcab enohp eht dekcut yaF  "?flesmih yB"
.taht rebmemer dluow ogeiD desirprus saw eh fi sa deknilb yaF
eht elihW“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.deirram teg ot tnaw t'ndid uoy dias syawla uoy ,naem I ?yhw neht
.elit cimarec no swalc s'etoyoc eht fo kcilc eht yb nekorb saw esuoh eht fo llihc tnelis eht ,retal tnemom A
.gnihtemos rof detiaw ogeiD elihw etunim lluf a ylraen rof ecnelis ciots ni doots dneirfyob-xe siH
".erehwon fo tuo niaga uoy ot gniklat detrats I fi
.niaga ekops yaF ,yllaniF
?ofihcihc wen ruoy dehcnup evah I dluohS
,wons hguorht tfel dah serit sih sworruf eht naht rehtO
,moor gnivil eht ni tfel gnihtolc derettacs eht
.yaw eht fo tsom thgitpu dna suoixna neeb dah ogeiD dna ,syad eerht nekat dah evird ehT
.dnes ot flesym gnirb reven dluoc I
,edis eht ot dna nwod dekool eh dna deretlaf elims tniaf s'yaF
.rehtie em evael d'uoy kniht t'ndid I
"!erac neve t'ndid uoy ekil saw tI
.evird etunim neetfif eht rof erom gnihton dias eh dna
.egdirf krad eht morf reeb fo elttob a llup ot yawa gninrut ,dias ogeiD
dah yaF fi tahw ,tuB
,tol eht otni dellup eh emit eht yB
,dedne dah rehtegot sraey rieht woh ta suoiruf llits saw ogeiD hguoht neve dna
,rehtegot pu delruc tneps sthgin fo etoyoc eht dednimer
.taht naht retteb em wonk uoY"
taerter sretirw cihpromoporhtna lanoiger eht detelpmoc yltnecer ohw
,sdnarre nur dna senohp derewsna yltsom d'eH
"?naem uoy od tahW
.sevil rieht fo trap raluger a naht erutnevda erar a fo erom saw pu gnikooh
,thgil thgir eht ni nedlog tsomla dekool taht ruf dna seye wolley gnikirts htiw ,emosdnah dna llaT  .degludni ...yaF
”tuO ereW sthgiL
,em truh ot ton fI
.ecnetnes tsal taht ta tnemtnioppasid dna feiler fo esnes gnileud a tlef ogeiD ".xes
.ti rof wohs ot ydob eht dah llits eh dna esolc nettog d'eh tub
.tol eht ni rac rehto ylno eht ot txen pu dellup ogeiD
.redluohs s'dneirf sih no wap a tup dna elims a decrof eH
".yawyna ffo emit eht nettog evah dluoc I taht toN
,ylthgils ,detfihs yaF
...uoy dlot I nehw nevE
?gninruom saw yaF taht
"?revo s'taht dnA" ".esahp tuls
.nottub a fo kcilc a htiw egarag eht denepo etoyoc eht dna
"!noitcaer a neeb evah dluow ti tsael tA !ebyaM"
.ereh kcab emoc ot mih detivni dah ogeiD ,llitS
.tuo llits s'rewoP"  "?tahW"
"?detnioppasid uoy erA ?yhW"
.dah ti ekil mih dedisdnilb evah t'ndluohs pukaerb eht ,thgisdnih nI
,relevart wollef ruoy
”tuO ereW sthgiL eht elihW“
.sriaper cisab fo tol a od ot woh denrael llits d'eh tub
.deipucco yeht renroc tahw rettam on emas eht dekool gnidliub yreve erehw sniahc ycamrahp evissam esoht fo eno ta dekrow yaF
knird a dedeen reve d'eh fI
"?dnim ruoy degnahc uoy ylneddus dna
,eugnot sih fo pit eht no tnemmoc dwel eht gnidih fo boj doog a od t'ndid yaF
.drawkwa leef ton dna elpoep teem ot delggurts eH
.ycamrahp eht ot derutseg neht ,detatiseh eH ".emac
.noitasrevnoc eht no desucof daetsni dna hcamots sih ni gninruhc thgils a derongi ogeiD
".kciD" .derumrum yaF
.kcab denrut ydaerla evah dluow eh
,emoh nettog yllanif d'eh
.tcatnoc eye ekam ot flesmih decrof eh ,deppart gnileeF
,taht emocrevo ot mih depleh ytiralupop s'yaF
.rehtegot llits erew yeht tub
.siht s'ereht nehT"
hteet wef a tsol d'eh fi spahreP
.dnarb s'rehtaf sih gniyub ot detrever
.thgil rof rehto eht ni dleh enohp sih
,soveuh eht ot kcik tsal enO
,niaga deppord seye s'netram ehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.ecnamrofrep a lla saw siht fi niaga derednow ogeiD dna ,taht wenk yaF
.dias elam rellams eht ",scisab eht fo tsom evah llits uoy ekil skooL"
",repmet ym tpek I yrros os m'I ,hO"
lamron tsuj erew sgniht fo sdnik eseht taht derugif eH
,eugnot reprahs eht dah yaF
.yaF ,wonk gnikcuf t'nod I"
.swodniw eht pu gnipeerc noitasnednoc htiw pu peek ot gnilggurts saw reggofed eht
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
,noitcart fo ssol lanoisacco eht
",ecin sllems ecalp ehT"
- yadkrow a hguorht detalumucca ksum larutan eht dna
.deggurhs netram ehT
.xes evah ot gniog er'ew ekil ton s'ti dna
".yap s'keew a fo tsoM
.lasrever a ekil tlef sihT
.mrots eht morf llauqs rehtona yb dekcab eciov ,dias eh
".gnikooc ruoy ssim I
.nepo llits sniatruc
.ereh tuo ezeerf uoy tel annog saw I ekil ton s'tI"
"?enorepahc a deen ew knihT"
"?dnim ruoy degnahc evah d'uoy
.moor eht dnuora derutseg eH ",naem I
?oga shtnom esoht lla nekorb neeb dah tahw fo emos
.seilppus gnipmac sih morf dediar d'eh nretnal derewop yrettab a morf emac noitanimulli ylno eht ,enohp eht sediseB