,gum sih deldarc yaF
.neht tcatnoc eye ekam ot desufer eH
".siht dekil uoy dias uoy thguoht I"
,doots eh sa hcterts a htiw ffo ti koohs eh
.deppord srae s'etoyoc ehT
.revo ydaerla saw ti litnu mih ot rucco t'ndid noitcerid taht
"?em ot gniklat neve tuohtiW ?enod erew ew taht yad eno dediced tsuj uoY
".uoy llet ot deen ew gnihtemos evah I dna yaF"
?tresed eht ni deyats yeht dah tuo denrut evah sgniht dluow yltnereffid woH
.sedaced owt tsomla rof noitcif yrruf gnitirw neeb sah dna
,elbat eeffoc eht dnuora deppets netram ehT
.eciov sih ni truh saw ereht tub
,reyrdotua eht rewop ot yticirtcele tuohtiW
.netram eht gniyllub ni "sdneirf"
",erdam óilav aY"
.tnemtrapa dlo rieht ni kcab desserd-flah tneps d'yeht sthgin fo ogeiD dednimer kool eht tub
s'yaF tsniaga deppils eugnot talf s'etoyoc ehT .dessik yehT
,spis wef a nwod plug ot netram eht ecreoc ot dah eH
d'eh dna etacilper ot elba neeb reven d'eh gnihtemos saw
.eil etihw a s'tI"
",neppah ti tel evah thgim I
,eson s'ogeiD delkcit tsud fo llems thgils A
.gninialpmoc saw ogeiD taht toN
sdrazzilb wef a hguorht neeb d'eH
yaF dna ogeiD  .ylteiuq deffins yaF ".kcab
"?elohssa na fo erom neve em ekam taht t'nseoD
pal sih otni delttes dah netram thgils eht
.ogeiD hguorht revihs mraw a gnidnes ,mih tsniaga kcab denael netram ehT  "...yaF" ".hguoht
sih denioj d'eh ,reilrae syad tsuJ
.sdnuos railimaf fo ynohpmys
,retal setunim ytroF  2 fo 2 traP
,yug thgiarts a rof rolyaT gnisufnoc enoyna enigami ot drah s'ti ,naem I
,etoyoC triD yb daeR
.llif sih dah ogeiD elihw klat llams ekam did eh tub
,thginrevo noitisop latef-raen
,ylimaf er'ew taht em llet ot etacifitrec a em evig ot krelc ytnuoc emos deen t'nod I
,gnineppah saw tahw dezilaer ogeiD erofeB
.retnuoc nehctik eht no ni deggulp saw ti erehw ot dekool ogeiD
...os syawla erew uoy ...tsuj s'tI"
- nrettap nretsewhtuos lufroloc a ni detaroced sgum fo riap a otni nobruob gniruop nageb dna ,ttim s'ogeiD detacsifnoc elam rellams eht ,dezafnU  .dedda eh
.tropria eht ot edir a em evig nac eh fi ees dna ogeiD llac ot gniog m'I .haeY"
.gnimit eht gnisseug dnoces dna
.peels erom elttil a esu htob dluoc yeht dediced
.mrots eht fo edis rehto eht no gnieb yb ylpmis tlef eh sisrahtac fo esnes eht ta desirprus saw eh
,shtnom wef tsal eht revo rolyaT etah ot emoc d'eh sa hcum sA
.evorpmi ot dedeen eh noitavitom eht eb thgim noitailimuh taht dediced dah rehcaet eht ,yad tahT
,dednuos lleb eht sa noos sA
a otni delruc
,rehtegot emit gnidneps htrow saw ti yaF wohs ot tsuj llew od ot gnitnaw detrats d'eh ,tniop emos tA
".ti dekil I yhw wenk I ekil ton s'ti ,naem I"
uoy dluow yhW" .gniknis hcamots
.telkoob elur dewolley a hguorht gnippilf ,dias yaF
,trofmoc fo esnes detcepxenu na tlef ogeiD
.hcamots sih fo ruf ynwat enif eht ta
,neht ,esuap A ".nuh ,yeH"
ydob s'yaF no gniregnil ezag sih dnuof eh
.osrot sih ssorca neht
.gnikool detrats dna revo yaw sih edam eH
.emoh tfel d'yeht erofeb neeb dah efil rieht tahw fo rednimer rehtona saw siht ekil desserd yaF gniees ,llitS
,ezag sih gniteem nI
.esuoh eht fo tser eht ni dloc gnipeerc eht etipsed
.mih gnippots ni noisiced thgir eht edam dah eh erus neve t'nsaw eH
.elzzum sih morf deppils naorg elbiduani ylraen a dna seye sih desolc etoyoc ehT
pmuht eht yb nekorb won saw ecnelis ehT
.pu-nottub eulb a dna
".emoh og uoy nehw niaga raeppasid t'nod uoy taht gnimussA .tiaw nac I
,ni devom tsrif d'yeht nehw esnepxe tnacifingis a neeb dah ecalperif eht gniriapeR
.yromem elcsum morf fi sa
,gniyonna ti dnuof dah ogeiD ,tsrif tA
.yaF sdrawot teef dna erif eht sdrawot daeh
rof rehtegot eb d'ew taht esnes sekam tI .sdneirf erew eW
.flehs eht morf ti detfil eh sa edisni eht ssorca dils xob eht fo stnetnoc ehT .dias ogeiD ",wonk I"
",flesruoy nrub t'noD"
.pal sih ni ecived eht tup dna dehgis yaF
.kcab em ekat ot uoy gniggeb dna ereh kcab gnimoc tsuj morf flesym pots ot evah I
,sgnileef ruo tuoba klat ro citnamor teg ot deirt I emit yrevE .D ,deirt I"
- tsaot deirf derettab-gge
.shpargarap gnol lareves hguorht yaw sih rettuts dna moorssalc eht fo tnorf eht ta dnats ot ogeiD decrof dah
.yawa teef lareves morf neve
,yas ot esle tahw wonk t'ndid eH
,yrroS .thgir er'uoY"
"?thgin eht fo elddim eht ni pu gniwohs rolyaT tuoba yrrow ot deen I oD"
.ti tuoba klat ot deen I"
.evird leehw-lla htiw wonk I eno ylno eht s'eH
.tuo mih worht thgim yeht taht deirrow reven d'eh
.tuo dnuof ehs woh saw taht sseug I tub
.pukooh neknurd a otni nrut ot gniog ton m'I tub
.ereht neeb dah gnorw saw gnihtemos taht sngis ehT
.ezalb dellortnoc tub ,yhtlaeh a ot gnidnet saw ogeiD
wap a tuo dehcaer yaF
,ydaer ton er'uoy fi tuB
.decseiuqca yllautneve eh tub
,niaga dekcarc eciov sih
taeh teg ot elttek eht wolla ot decalp yldrawkwa saw no detser ti etarg latem ehT
.doohrobhgien emas eht ni devil yeht tuo denrut tI
.mih tuoba derac llits eh ezilaer ot desirprus saw eh
.elims tniaf a mih evag yaF
.lausu naht retal ,krow morf emoh nettog tsuj dah aP .stonk ni detsiwt ti sa neve lworg hcamots sih gnikam saw gniremmis llits elozop eht fo tnecs ycips ehT
ybraen decalp d'eh ttim nevo eht debbarg ogeiD os
.niaga sbuc erew yeht fi sa selit gniniamer sih gniwap saw dna
ti detsioh ylluferac dna
.recnaC .haeY" .wol seye
.sdrow eht deredisnoc neve d'eh erofeb gnikaeps saw ogeiD dna
,mra sih nwod dils wap a sa mih hguorht etanoser ot demees erif ybraen ehT
.erutinruf eht fo tsom tuo dekcip
,gninrom eht ni ylraE
.hguoht slewov ynam ooT
.noitcaer fo dnik taht teg llits dluoc eh dalg
,emit hcum os retfa nevE
,yaF ,uoy evol llits I"
"?kcab em tnaw neve uoy dluoW .ogeiD ,od ot tahw wonk t'nod I"
,gnuts taht tuoba gnihtemoS
"?em fo hsifles ...taht sI
,reilrae emit emoS
.taeh eht ta deliocer neht ,dekcil
.loohcs retfa mih gnirotut nageb netram eht ,gniksa neve tuohtiW
".setunim erom wef a rof siht yojne s'tel ...tsuJ .D ,tey toN"
.tnetsisrep saw yaF tub
ecanruf eht fo ssih dna
?meht fo htob rof ereht eb dluoc eh yaw a ereht saW
srae sih ni taeh tlef eH
.ti dedne evah dluohs I
,tnemom a roF "?huh
.gnikaerb tpek eciov sih esuaceb
.tsoc eht htrow neeb dah ti dediced ecnis gnol dah eh tub
.elttek nori eht deye ogeiD
.dessarrabme dednuos yaF  "?oot srettel ym yalp ot desu uoy nehw
".sruoy saw taht kniht I"
.deb tfihsekam sih otni kcab delruc neht
"-ti yalp dluoc uoY '?neeuq' ...ebyaM"
?esoprup no knurd mih nettog yaF dah ,tihS
".ecno egairram pu thguorb ylno uoY
,thgin gnol a saw tI"
.detatiseh yaF sa
,hpargarap dnoces eht hguorht nettog d'eh emit eht yb dna
.reilrae shtnom xis tsuj moor eht ssorca deneppah dah taht enecs eht taeper ot tnaw t'ndid eh tub
.afos depahs-L eht fo dne etisoppo eht ot yaw sih edam etoyoc eht ,deifsitaS
.nwod dekool neht ,dehcnilf yaF
,esuoh eht otni delttes dah taht ssenkrad eht hguorht ekorb
skeew esoht no detcelfer dah ogeiD
,pots did netram ehT  ".pots ,yaF"
.kcab uoy gnidloh saw I deirrow I
.spil sih gnipacse gnignol fo enihw tfos a ,tuo dehtaerb ogeiD
.retaw emos evah dluohs uoY"
".wonk ot sah eno on
.yad yreve uoy ssim I
tlef I woh fo em dednimer tI
- thgil enohp a fo tnemevom eht nees d'eh
.tnemtaert fo dnik taht devresed eno on
?erom ecno edis s'yaF ta gnieb yfitsuj ot yaw a tsuj taht saw rO
.erif eht htiw od ot gnihton dah taht
dekool llits eh tub ,strap rekciht eht ni pmad llits saw ruf s'netram eht
,yaF dna ogeiD ,srevol remrof dna sdneirf doohdlihc ,emit tsaL
,niaga neetxis saw ogeiD
gnitrofmoc a gnitaerc won esuoh eht tuohguorht secived dna secnailppa cinortcele fo smuh denibmoc eltbus erom eht dna
".retal sllac rof ti evah ot tnaw uoy fi ffo taht nrut ylbaborp dluohs uoY"
"?gniod uoy era tahW"
.won ti tuoba klat ot deen ew kniht I ,llitS"
.hcamots sih ni deralf won nwod depmat neeb dah taht regna ehT
,aP htiw tsrow rieht ta neeb dah sgniht nehw neve tub
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT     ".noos
,sknird fo dnuor rehtona meht teg ot nehctik eht ot kcab tnew yaF netfo os yrevE
".amard etaerc ll'ti
.kcab tnew srae s'aP .denediw seye s'aM
"?thgin tsal dias uoy tahw naem uoy diD
taht ekil sgniht dias evah uoy t'ndluoc yhW"
".pal ym ni tis d'uoy esuac ti ekil ot desu I"
.tsud fo reyal niht eht ees dluoc ogeiD ,gnithgil mid eht ni nevE
.neht kcab loohcs ot siht ekil sgniht erow syawla yaF tub
ekahs ot nageb ydob s'yaF sa dedisbus taht tub
,klat ot detnaw eh meht dlot d'eh nehw tuB
.derewsna neht
.sih tem seye dlaremE  "?trap hcihW"
.ekatsim diputs ,diputs a saw ti taht gnikniht pots t'nac I woN"
,rolyaT ot emoh og I revenehw won dnA
,dessap dah mrots eht fo tsrow ehT
,neht kcab ,kcuf ,tuB .ylbaborP"
,siht reh llet reven dluow eH .ti dessim
.redaer a morf segassap gnidaer snrut nekat dah ssalc rieht ,noonretfa tahT
,erif eht ot resolc devom dna gum sih nekat dah yaF ,tneserp eht nI
em gnipmud dnA"
erif eht fo wolg rebma ehT
.esuoh eht fo trap niam eht ot
.tliug fo tuo enoemos htiw yats t'nac uoY"
.ti tuoba tegrof ot uoy gniksa ton m'I"
,deracs saw I .yrros m'I
”tuO ereW sthgiL eht elihW“   yojne esaelP
,emit reippah a ot mih detropsnart yenoh dna ,secips ,rettub fo stnecs ehT
taeb ydaets sti deunitnoc kcolc eht ,nehctik eht nI
"?em evael ot dediced uoy nehw
.llew ton tsael ta
,gnol rehto hcae nwonk t'ndah yehT
taerter sretirw cihpromoporhtna lanoiger eht detelpmoc yltnecer ohw
edisa taht tes yliraropmet ev’yeht tub ,hgih si elpuoc eht neewteb noisnet ehT
.rethgiarts pu tas tnemmoc tsal s'ogeiD retfa detalfed ylthgils dekool dah ohw ,yaF
,desolc erew rolyaT dna uoy taht wonk t'ndid I fI"  ".riaf s'tahT"
,eitwob wolley a
?rebmemer ,oot ecno rolyaT htiw sdneirf saw I
?ti s'taht oS"      ".revo dna revo
,erom elttil a stnerap ruo etaicerppa uoy sekaM"
.deredisnoc etoyoc ehT
.seceip gnissim neeb netfo d'yeht neht neve dna
.elbat eht fo ecafrus eht revo dap regnif a nar yaF  "?taht kniht reve
.mom s'ogeiD morf tfig gnimrawesuoh dlo na
.mih deppots yaF
,etal elttil a smees ti tuB
",dna em gnillet saw tug ym tahw htiw tnew I
.sraey rof klat t'ndid yeht dna
sknahT' ?yas ot gniog I saw tahW"
".erofeb emac taht gnihtyreve snepaehc tI
.syad tsom mih ot deklat ylerab yaF
,tahw erew eW .suseJ"
,erif eht no doow erom dda ylluferac dluow ogeiD dna
,em rof sgnileef dah eh em dlot eh nehW
,doohdlihc ecnis eseht fo tsom dah d'eH
,ereh m'I mih llet I fI
,efil sih fo trap tnatropmi na hcus saw ylimaF
rebmemeR .nuf eb lliw ti ,no emoC"
uoy eeS .nuh ,oot uoy evol
,klawedis eht no sih denioj wodahs dnoces a nehW
,yzoc moor eht tpek hcihw
.gnihtemos ro seiddub kcuf tseb
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
gniggut nageb dna retaews sih fo cirbaf nevow eht rednu desserp sregnif ,tsiser t'ndid eh nehW
,denruter evloser s'ogeiD tuB
eunitnoc ot elbanu dna sraet ni neeb d'eh
*** .tresed eht fo taeh dira eht rof gnol syawla dluow mih fo trap a fi ro
.suoires teg ot detrats
.loohcs hgih fo tuo tsuj saw eh nehw srobhgien rieht fo eno htiw mih thguac ehS"
.syad loohcs hgih rieht morf derebmemer ogeiD netram eht delbmeser eh tsael ta ,rO
,tuops detniop eht morf gnigreme erew maets fo sliart ypsiW .erif eht ni yltcerid gnieb tuohtiw
,efil wen siht ot etamilcca ylluf reve dluow eh fi derednow eH
,peels ot kcab detfird eh sA
.mih deppots yaF tub
.tsael ta ,taht htiw gnihtemos od dluoc ew teB
.ylenol eb t'ndluow yaF os rehtegot emit erom dneps ot meht fo owt eht degaruocne d'eh
,puc nwo sih morf pal evitatnet rehtona koot ogeiD
".yas selur eht tahw erac t'nod I .tihsllub s'tahT"
.dettam llits saw seye s'ogeiD rednu ruf ehT
.kcen sih fo kcab eht debbur ogeiD
"?emag ecid taht ebyaM
".taht yas syawla uoy tub
,enod saw ti nehW
,mih ta kcab kool neve t'ndid yaF
.deggurhs dna elbat eeffoc eht no emag eht tes ogeiD  "?net
,ssa ym barg dna ,sekoj ekam d'uoY .edacaf ohcam
***  .peels ot teg yllanif ot emit gnol a mih koot tI
sdrow tuo dnuos ot stpmetta wols sih detcerroc nexiv eht sa denrub skeehc dna srae siH
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.thginrevo elbatrofmoc eb d'eh erus ekam ot yawyna mih revo steknalb remraw eht fo wef a depard ogeiD tub
.gnihtemos dias evah dluohs uoy
.deneppah dah taht gnihtyreve retfa
ekil kool thgim yaF htiw erutuf a tahw tuoba yllacitsilaer kniht ot drah ti edam rehtegot emit rieht fo seiromem eroM
.wonk t'nod yllaer ...I"
.oN" .dehgis netram ehT
.seye sih ni erutsiom eht edih ot semalf gnirekcilf eht ot kcab noitnetta sih denrut ogeiD ".hcum
"'.efil doog a evaH ,sraey thgie rof
.kcab thgilf ylrae na hctac ot stnaw eH"
.ziuQ" s'ogeiD ot "Y-F-I-Z" a dedda eh
,emoh tfel d'yeht ecnis eno siht ekil
.htiw gnipeels erew ew elpoep htiw erew rehtegot tuo sthgin ruo fo tsoM .kcab dial
.ksa ot tuoba neeb dah yaF tahw wenk ogeiD
.gninrom worromot litnu tsael ta nwod tuhs yats ot gniog era stropria lacol eht llet nac I tahw morF .ti tbuod I"
.secnahc yna ekat ot tnaw t'ndid eh tub ,thgin taht noitatpmet erom yna eb dluow ereht detbuod eH
”tuO ereW sthgiL
".taht dedeen yllaer I
.ecarbme detaeh ssel a otni yaF dellup ylwols dna doots eh erofeb shtaerb lareves rof dezylarap saw etoyoc ehT
.meht htiw elbatrofmoc nettog t'ndah llits yltnerappa eh tub
.ti ot deirruh tub ,erows netram ehT
.did yeht kniht t'nod I
,rac eht ni dias uoy ekil s'tI"
.yenruoj taht hsinif dluoc ti erofeb
.lasuora denibmoc rieht fo tnecs eht erongi ot gniyrt
- nexiv dlo ,nrets a
.eno siht ekil sthgin rof egarag eht dniheb derots doow fo tnuoma tnacifingis a dah llits eh
,denruter eh nehw peels ot ffo detfird ydaerla dah yaF
.flehskoob eht fo pot no sexob lufroloc fo elip taen eht no llef seye sih ,moor eht dnuora gnicnalG
,raey eht fo dne eht yb dna
.edisa dehsup d'eh lasuora tnetal eht rits ot hguone saw gniod neeb evah dluoc yeht tahw fo thguoht eht nevE
.su neewteb gnihtemos saw ereht taht yned t'ndluoc I tuB
.erocs drow elpirt a no saw Y ehT ".ziuQ"
em evol yllaer t'ndid uoy taht flesym decnivnoc d'I
.nwod eil dluoc eh os lanoitces eht otno kcab mih desae yllautneve etoyoc eht dna
,enod saw ti nehw tuB .did yeht os dnA
,ryC rohtarB yb
.seye sih ta epiw ot wap eno fo kcab eht gnisu ,doots eH ".hcum
.yalp ot nageb dna yromem morf emag eht pu tes yehT
,moor gnivil til-erif eht nI
.eil a deredisnoc eH
tsirw rednels s'netram eht barg ot ogeiD rof troffe fo laed taerg a koot tI
.ylkciuq daeh sih koohs yaF
.ssa sih fo evruc eht tsniaga deltsen saw
?rehtom kcis sih htiw tisiv a retfA" "?haey
.tesolc nwo sih morf dezingocer ogeiD trihs lennalf dekcehc-neerg a pu gnidloh elihw dias yaF
.moc tod rettiwt fo ylremrof ,etoyoC triD yb uoy rof daer ,ryC rohtarB yb ”tuO ereW sthgiL eht elihW“
"?gnimoc retaw taht s'woH"
.ereh Q rehtona tog ev'uoY"
,yrruFoS seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,sseltser worg ot demees yaF elihw
,erusopmoc sih deniager eh sa mih tsniaga denael tsuj yaF
,sliated eht lla evah t'nod I
.retal sruoh wef a mih ekow tahw saw elddirg toh a no nocab fo elzzis ehT
.elbat eeffoc eht no knird sih gnittup erofeb retsaoc a tuo gud dah yaF
,gnilevart sih lla htiw ,lleH
".oga sruoh wef a kcab emac tsuj rewop ,haeY"
.hteet sih dettirg ogeiD ".sraey
.meht fo tnorf ni tuo deyalps saw draob emag a no dirg lufroloc a dna edisa dehsup neeb dah smeti rehto wef dna esav s'rehtom siH
shtnom elpuoc a rof sselemoh pu dedne yaT
.tsehc sih tsniaga htmraw tlef ogeiD dna
.ti rof yap ot hsac ycnegreme emos desu dna letoh paehc a dnuof I ,sksa reve eh fI .rolyaT dellac I"
.hcum oot knird flesym tel
.dekcus tI .deneppah tI
,tfel d'eh ecnis shtnom eht ni desu t'ndah ogeiD gniht rehtona tey ,elddirg cirtcele na tuo nekorb
htaehs s'ogeiD erus ekam ot spih sih delggirw yletarebiled reven dah yaF dlo-raey-net tpecxE
.esolc gnitteg erew ew taht erac ot mees neve t'ndid uoy
.smoordeb eht sdrawot kcab dehsup neeb dah mrots eht fo llihc eht dna
.rehtegot emoh gniklaw no detsisni yaF ,woN
.moor tseug eht otni yaw sih gnikam yaF
,knird sih no dekohc yaF
,kcab saw rewop eht taht won mih gnikaw tuoba thguoht eH
.liated diviv ylgnisirprus ni mih ot emac yromem rehtonA ".haeY .heH"
.yretslohpu larolf wolley sti htiw afos moor gnivil dlo eht no yaF ot txen gnittis
.erom dna ,ytiniffAruF
.nwod liat dna daeh sih
,haey ...uoy txet ll'I"
,noitaredisnoc feirb a retfa tub
.ti morf ssorca yltcerid lanoitces eht fo dne eht no gnittis
mrots eht morf dniw fo tsalb lanoisacco eht dna erif eht fo gnilkcarc eht ,sknird rieht desrun yeht sa dessap teiuq fo stnemom wef A
rof hcaeb eht pu evig ot mih rof nosaer on s'erehT .regnol ylbaborP
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.oot sgniht rehto emos ylbaborp ,dnA
.tenibac rouqil eht morf selttob fo riap a gnillup saw eh ,ekops eh sA ".kcab
.moc tod rettiwt fo ylremrof
.gnola sgniht hsup ot eno eht saw yaF
,nooccar eht ta neeb dah eh sa yrgna sA
.niaga trats ot dah eh dna
"?erom taht tuoba klat ot evah ew oD"
.shtnom xis tsal eht revo niaga revo dna revo
".em ot emas eht gniod erew uoy thguoht em fo trap a sseug I ,dnA
.gum cimarec a decudorp dna
.naelc draob eht epiws ot fi sa mra sih gnisiar ,delworg eh
,ega sih buc yna sa llew sa naronoS dna noiblA ekops eH
.tuo tes d'eh lewot hsid dedlof a no gniht eht tes dna
,tnaw lacisyhp s'rehto hcae leef htob dluoc yehT
,lanoitces eht no tops gnipeels nwo sih pu edam eH
noitatiseh fo dnoces a ylno saw erehT
.D ,gniht eht s'taht ,doG"
.pu gniworg snoitpo gnitad fo tol a erew ereht ekil ton s'tI .tneinevnoc saw ti esuaceb rehtegot ylno erew ew taht dna
,ylisae emag tsrif eht now yaF
.rekop latem eht htiw doow gninrub eht detfihs eH
.peels fo mhtyhr neve eht ni gnihtaerb llits saw tub
.seiromem etirovaf sih fo emos erew syad esoht
.detfihs netram eht sa tem selzzum riehT
".tuoba tegrof tsuj dluohs I gniht laivirt emos si siht ekil tca t'noD"
".esrow sgniht edam ylno taht raelc s'ti kniht I ,oN
.detartnecnoc eh sa tuo gnikop gnaf
,noitisop sih detfihs yaF  "...tuB .did I ...od I"
.deppals neeb d'eh ekil tlef ogeiD
,ykahs saw koot netram eht htaerb txen ehT ".ma
.uoy fo htob evol thgim I kniht I
.gnihtaerb s'rehto hcae morf edisa pordkcab ylno rieht sa
.dekil syawla dah ogeiD yaw eht spih sih tfihs did eh tub
.deneppah t'ndah shtnom xis tsal eht fi sa rehto hcae morf ssorca gnitae erew yeht noos dna
.tnemtrapa s'nooccar eht ta yawa sdnekeew tsom tneps llits yaF elihw
.sih dezeeuqs dna
"?siht worrob I fi dnim uoy oD"
.no slaem doohdlihc sih fo tsom netae dah ylimaf sih sgel gnidlof eht htiw elbat euqitna ysmilf eht ta gnittis ,dlo sraey enin saw eh ,emit sihT
drazzilb lufrewop a yb shtnom xis ni emit tsrif eht rof rehtegot thguorb erew
,shtnom wef tsal eht revo laeppa rieht tsol dah spu kooH
...dnA .esle enoyna htiw enod reven d'I sgniht deirt eW
,niagA .deksa ogeiD
.yas ot tahw wonk t'ndid ogeiD
.dehgis yaF  "?ti t'nseod
meht morf ssorca sriahc eht ni nwod tas htob d'yeht
,tuo kcab ot tuoba neeb dah ogeiD nehw tsuJ
".daetsni uoy gniees saw I hsiw tub pleh t'nac I
,ereht mih detnaw yaF
.selcric wols ni kcab sih debbur dna mih dleh tsuj etoyoc eht os
.level edarg ta gnidaer neeb d'eh
,derehtob t'ndah ogeiD
.enohp sih ta gnirats
,siht lla tuoba mih ot klat ot deen uoY
,emag dnoces rieht hguorht yawflah dna
.setunim gnol lareves rof taht ekil deyats yehT
,htaerb tfos a tuo tel ogeiD
,yggorg llits saw ogeiD hguoht dna
".gnihtemos ro em htiw peels ot uoy teg ot emehcs etarobale emos t'nsaw siht taht raews I
.pots ot flesmih decrof dna
.egral ta ssalc eht yb nwonk gnieb morf siht peek ot deganam d'eh ,troffe taerg htiW
- deerga I dna tniop on saw ereht dias uoY"
,flesmih ot delims ogeiD dna
"?retteb saw dneirf ruo rof
.ma I ohw fo trap a si uoy gnivoL
".uoy fo rehtie ot riaf eb t'ndluow tahT
.efil ot kcab gnimoc esuoh eht fo sdnuos gniltrats eht ot ekow ogeiD
rolyaT htiw sgnihT"
".derednow t'ndah I dias I fi gniyl eb d'I" .delahxe ogeiD
".ssem a hcus m'I ,doG"
.thgin tsal tuoba yrros yllaer ...m'I"
.rennid hsinif ot gniyrt saw aM
".elbbarcS syawla s'erehT"
.seye sih ni hturt eht nees ydaerla dah yaF wenk eh tuB
nruter s'netram eht dekram roolf eht ssorca swalc fo gnikcilc eltbus eht ,woN
,gnileef saw eh tahw yltcaxe dnatsrednu ot gniyrt
...saw eh dnA .emit eht lla krow rof gnilevart erew uoY
,hcum tae t'ndid yaF
,yaF rof gib oot sezis owt tsael ta saw trihs ehT
,deffins ogeiD .mih sdrawot
.gnikniht saw rehto eht tahw wonk ot demees htob yehT
.elbat eht ssorca kool a derahs
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.keehc eno fo ruf eht otni gnipees raet a ,seye sih tuhs s'yaF
.hgU" .gninrom eht ni gniht tsrif eeffoc sih tuoba ykcip saw eh taht toN
srehto hcae tsuj erew ew ekil leef ot detrats tI
?reh htiw gnorw gnihtemos sI"
.mrots eht morf denruter d'yeht nehw tlef d'eh tahw gnitsartnoc
ta eb ot gniog saw ogeiD taht stneve ot pu gniwohs deppots dah rolyaT
,rentrap remrof sih ta dekool ogeiD
.enohp gnitarbiv a fo dnuos evitcnitsid eht yb detpurretni saw eH  "--ht
ni gnivom eb thgim pihsnoitaler rieht taht thguoht ehT
gnitegdif flesmih dnuof ogeiD elihw yltneitap detiaw dna
,gnikooc dehsinif yaF elihw elbat eht deraelc eH ".eurt syawla s'tI" .deggurhs etoyoc ehT
eht elihW“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
gnihtemos tsuj s'erehT .KO s'ti
".uoy pleh ot gniyrt tsuj saw I"
gniht emas eht eb ot demees tsuj ti dnA
dah yaF  .ruf sih tuo koohs neht
,syad eseht netfo ti esu ot doom eht ni t'nsaw eh hguoht nevE
.lanoitces eht fo dne trohs eht no tas yaF elihw erif eht ot kcab sih htiw tas ogeiD
,haeY"  .noisiced sih edam ogeiD
,neercs eht ta derats eh sa
".yalp nac uoy gnihtemos tog ev'uoy erus m'I .D ,no emoc hO"
.em ot gniklat yllanif uoy etaicerppa I"
,retal sraey ytnewt nevE
.sserpmi ot gniyrt raey suoiverp eht fo tsom tneps d'eh sbuc morf stnuat derepsihw dna rethgual leurc fo ezah a neeb dah yad loohcs eht fo tser ehT
.s'rehtom sih naht retteb neve saw ti tub
,hcruhc rof ylecin taht sserd neve t'ndid ogeiD
",rebmemer I resol eros eht s'erehT"
?ereht eb ot mih rof riaf eb ti dluoW
dah yaF .llew sgniht rieht gnitaert ton tuoba suoicsnoc-fles tlef ylfeirb dna
.dnuorg eht gnihsurb dne s'ti ,edis ot edis gnittilf liat gnol sih
.kcab wap sih dellup dna deppots eh erofeb elpmid llams a evael ot hguone tsuj
"?sbuc erew ew nehw morf eno emas eht taht sI .aohW"
.elgnit sregnif sih no sdap eht ekam ot gnitrats saw taht lohocla eht sa
.trapa sehcni llits selzzum ,ssik eht morf kcab dellup eH
.ekoms etteragic fo sraey yb wolley deniats ,ebolg ssalg gnilgnad a morf deruop thgiL
.stnemom wef a rof ylno fi
.sgel s'etoyoc eht neewteb detfird wap dnoces s'yaF ,denedlobmE
.kcab teg uoy nehw tuoba uoy ot klat ot deen I
.wonk t'nod I .doG"  "?tahW"
.dewollaws eh ".yaF ,t'nac eW"
mih dniheb retnuoc eht ot noitnetta sih detfihs ylkciuq eh sa selims lla saw yaF ,mih gnicitoN
,draob eht ssorca srettel fo swor gnignarra ylsuolucitem saw yaF regnuoy ehT
.gnirettel dlog htiw xob der nrow na no delttes seye sih sa delkcuhc ogeiD  ".hO"
.mrots eht tuo gnitiaw fo tseretni eht ni
tsuj I" .deppots yaF "...I
".ecnerefnoc gnikcuf rehtona tey rof evael ot ydaer gnitteg erew uoy nehw thgir saw taht dna
,kooc doog a saw etoyoc ehT
,mih htiw ni evom ot em deksa eh nehw tuo sgniht erugif ot gniyrt llits saw I
.hcum os truh t'ndluow ti taht os uoy llet ot yaw a dnif ot gniyrt saw I dna ,desufnoc dna
,erofeb thgin eht deneppah dah tahw tuoba klat ot yrt did eH
",ffuts remmus dlo yltsom si xob taht ,oS"
.dab eht htiw ni dexim seiromem doog erew ereht tub
.deklat yeht elihw delooc dah hcihw
.tcelgen sih fo mih gnidnimer yltnegru saw ydob sih ,woN
,gum gnimaets eht dessap eh
.don elbitpecrep ylerab a dereffo dna swap sih werdhtiw yaF ,ylwolS .sih otni gnirats seye neerg ,mih ta dekool netram ehT
.em htiw nepo dna etanoissap
.gnissim neeb dah taht tnatropmi gnihtemos dnuof d'eh fi sa leef ogeiD edam esolc siht mih gnivah
,thguoht ni peed saw ogeiD
.gnihtyna yrt did yaF fi niaga taht od dluoc eh erus t'nsaw eH
.eganam dluoc eh sa smoordeb eht morf steknalb ynam sa deveirter ogeiD ,enod tahT
".em devol llits uoy dias uoy nehW"
"?rehtegot erew ew nehw
.llac eht fo dne rehto eht no eciov eht tuo ekam etiuq t'ndluoc ogeiD .esuap A ".evird
.pots reve dluoc I kniht t'nod ...I"
.htaerb s'netram eht no lohocla eht llems dluoc eH
.kcuf dna hgual d'ew neht dna
.dedisbus yllanif dah dniw fo stsug eht dna
"?naem I ,mom s'rolyaT
,skcals krad ni desserd saw eH
.taebtraeh a ni ti enod evah dluow I tub
taht ekil gnihtemos ssucsid uoy diD"
"?ecnaif ruoy tuoba gnihtemos gniyas erew uoY" .deddon ogeiD
.mom sih htiw emit dneps dluohs eh ,sediseB"
,wonk t'nod I ...ereh pu tuB .elihw a
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
- rehcaet edarg dnoces riehT
".esle enoemos ot siht od t'nac I"
doow eht otni dednetxe walc sih fo pit eht dna dexelf regnif s'yaF  ".gnihtemos
,dewollof noos eeffoc dewerb ylhserf dna doof gnikooc fo tnecs gnilgnim ehT
.elpoep ruof deef ot tsafkaerb hguone gnikooc ylisub saw dna
.swollaws wef a nwod dna ti ekat ot saw rewsna s'ogeiD
".rolyaT htiw tcennocer ot gniyrt neeb s'ehs tub
gnieb redisnoc uoy dluoW .sseug I"
".gnisufnoc eb dluow ti yhw ees nac I
.egatuo rewop gniynapmocca dna
- sajerrot s'netram eht tub
.swap s'yaF otni ssalg a decalp eh ,retal tnemom A ".retaw
"?deraeppasid tsuj mih rof dah uoy thguoht uoy sgnileef esoht oS"
.nrets dnuos ot gniyrt ,deganam eh
nehctik eht otni yaw sih edam eh sa dias eh ",em ot toh skooL" .tuo
,uoy htiw syad ylrae esoht ni
"?gniht ygetarts galf eht erutpac taht evah uoy t'ndiD"
erif eht def ylteiuq ogeiD ,oS
.eniuneg tub llams saw elims s'yaF  .dessefnoc eh
,kcits nomannic a htiw dehsinrag
,krow morf emoh gnivirD
.xob draobdrac dedaf eht deveirter ogeiD
.etal oot emoc dah troffe taht mih dlot seye gnikcilf s'yaF hguoht
.noops latem a htiw sknird eht gnirrits saw eH ".mom
.smra s'etoyoc eht fo eno gnola nar yltfos wap eno elihw s'ogeiD tsniaga nael ot ydob sih gninrut
"?emag a tuoba woH"
.denetsilg seye sih dna
,rehtie etirw ro daer t'ndluoc eh tub
.thgin lla dah eh naht flesmih ekil erom
"?ragus dna klim htiw eeffoc ruoy ekat llits uoY"
gnitacixotni sa tsomla saw tnecs railimaf s'netram eht htiw dexim noitasnes ehT
.wen dna hserf saw gnihtyreve nehw
,hguorht dehsup eh tub
dah yaF .hcuoc eht fo edis rehto eht no ruf fo llab eht ta decnalg etoyoc ehT
"?gnola teg t'nod yehT"
.elpoep owt htiw nuf hcum era taht ynam evah I kniht t'noD ?yllaeR"
.seye sih deworran ogeiD ".ti
.wodniw eht sdrawot derutseg eh ",siht
.revo enoyna dah d'eh ecnis skeew neeb dah ti dna
.syad retteb nees dah taht snaej gnigguh-pih fo riap a dna trihs sseleveels gnittif-esool a otni degnahc d'eH
siht pu tup d'uoy
,emoh sdrawot ylwols gniklaw noos saw dna ,ylkciuq tfel eh
.rethgiarts pu tas eh dna
,ti deciton eh sa noos sa gniggaw pots ot liat sih decrof ogeiD ".ti ekaT"
,ryC rohtarB yb
.niaga ekatsim emas eht ekam uoy gnipleh eb dluow taht tuB .ebyaM"
.erutarepmet tcefrep eht saw tI
,dnim ruoy degnahc uoy fI
.sruoh wef a rof yawa ti tup ...tsuJ
thguac eciov sih ",yhW"
.emit revo detalumucca dah taht ecafrus eht ssorca derettacs skramkcop ralimis lareves erew erehT
.smra sih tuo dleh yaF