sserac teews ehT :hsal pihW
,stiusrup lacisum rieht sa llew sa
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
kcalb-nworb eht fo senil eht kaerb ew sA
resopmoc tnediser rieht si dna
eno siht piks esaelp
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,eireganeM oirT fo tsiloiv eht osla era yehT
.noertaP rieht no
,kcezzoW rreH yb
,retirw a si ohw
slirdnet yb depolevnE
.evolg rehtael kcalb a fo
etsat elbawonknu ,waR eht ot nrut egnarts a ekat ot ediced snoitaripsA tsetaerg ruoy fi nwod uoy dnuoh ti lliw revE
murd tniaf eht dna
,revewoh ,noinapmoc raed a htiw dleif eht ot gnimoC
.kcart onhcet a fo
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
:lebal gninraw elpmis a htiw semoc netfO
kcab erab a nopu niar taht
,”hsaL pihW“   yojne esaelP
gninetsil er’uoY
,ylrae seirots rieht dnif osla nac uoY .yrruFoS ro
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
”hsaL pihW“ saw sihT     .ris gnirac a fo
meop a tneserp ew yadoT dna
.xofnogarD reppaD eht ,nelarD yb
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
slirdnet fo tseroF
kcezzoW rreH yb meop a
snoisnet rieht tuo krow ytrap eht ni enoyreve steL
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
ytiniffAruF rehtie no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoY .regnarra dna
:ytinilucsam fo eldnah ydruts ,kciht eht morF
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,strofmoc tsetaerg ruo dnif ew llahs ereht nI
dleif tnadrev railimafnu na ni gninnuR
;emahs tsetaerg ruoy fo retceps eht eraweB
.eniL eulB eht edisnI tsoL dna tooB dna pihW fo rohtua gninniw-drawA oeL eht era yehT .naicisum dna ,resopmoc
uoy rof daer ,kcezzoW rreH yb