.tonk ym ta em gnizeeuqs ,ti dnuora wap sih sparw ylsuoituac dna
,esolc gnitteg m'I sA
.edur elttil a sleef taht tub
.sekorts ruo neewteb rehto hcae gnikcep dna gnilbbin er'ew nehw decnelis ylno ,tnap ew ,rehtegoT
,etoyoC triD yb ”gnihT dliW“ fo strap owt fo dnoces eht saw sihT
.suoicsnocnu gnillaf dna llaw eht otni gnihsarc mih derutcip I ,daeh ym nI .lla ta neppah ot taht gnitcepxe t'nsaw I esuaceb ,tol a ,on
.enog rotatcid citamsirahc rieht htiw trapa sllaf ytinu dna seiceps retsam fo klat taht lla
.eno sulp sih sa em ecudortni ot snrut flow eht neht dna
.hteet sih neewteb em no gnilbbin strats
,erew yeht noitazilivic a fo gnorts sa roF
.mih morf ssorca em seciton eh
.ti fo edis rehtie gnikat dna rood eht ta tsuj gnippots sdraug eht
t'nod I erehw ytilaer a s'tI
,yrotsih ni selzzum noillirt a hguorht pilf ot drah adnik s'tI
dnoces a rof gnisuap
s’erehT .dnatsrednu yeht os tsuj
,ecaps dna emit neewteb dlof a otni peed ti ecalp I ,daetsnI
,gniod m'I tahw ees t'nac sretto ehT
?thgir ,keep kciuq a tsuJ .sreliops oN
,araiT dna ,ssoR ,naimaD era seman riehT
2 fo 2 traP ,etoyoC triD yb
tpecca dna xaler yllanif I
.eveihca ot drah os dekrow ev'yeht tahw gnilaets morf em gnipeek
,enod eb nac gnihtyna erofeb dna
,meht fo lla ta elims I
.rebmemer I enut a ot noisseccus ni kconk a ti evig dna rood delaes eht ot kcab klaw I ,hgis a htiW
,tenalp eht otni smals dioretsa ehT
,ria eht morf ward I nehT
,ohw ,etoyoC triD yb
.gnihton otni slarips ylizal nug elohw eht dna
.worros ni kcab srae ym dlof I dna gnimoc s'tI
,retfa dnoces a tsal t'nod I
.ruf sih otni yltfos gniknis hteet ym ,em htaenrednu sredduhs eH
.pu gniwohs erofeb trihs sih fo tuo rotcetorp tekcop gnikcuf eht ekat ot derebmemer dna
,gnihtyna od ot ecalp ym ton s'ti wonk I tuB
.ni gniztlaw tsuj pot knat a gniraew xof a eciton ot seton dna stelbat rieht morf pu kool meht fo enon dna
.yenruoj eht tuoba syawla saw tI
,mih morf tnulb sih laets I nehT
,snoitasrevnoc eht no sucof ot tog ev'I dna
,erutuf eht otni raf kool I esuaceb wonk I
,sraey stsal raw ehT
.edam gnieb era snoitcaf ,redael taerg ecno rieht fo llaw ydoolb eht ffo gninaelc hsinif yeht erofeb neve ,ylkciuQ
,gnilhctah nogard odomok llams a ees I ,yenruoj sti fo dne eht tA
,muc ot tsrif s'eH
.suovren os dna ,gnuoy ,rednels si moor eht ssorca xof elbram ehT
.niaga ti etaercer ot tpmetta reven dna eruliaf a saw tnemirepxe rieht taht edulcnoc yehT
.ylkciuq yb yrruh I ,srehto dna
,eno doog a dekcip I
.htaerb ym no hserf llits muc sih
.ezalba dlrow eht stes noisolpxe notagem noillim derdnuh a fo thgil gnidnilb eht
.innavoiG si eman s’flow ehT
,elkcuhc si od yeht llA
,niks ym no hcti na ekil s'tI
s'teL" .su fo htob eht rof hguone llew wonk I tub
,flesmih fo erusnu elttil a s'eH
.erolpxe ot em rof epir ,snoitazilivic
.srewolf knip ognimalf fo eldnub a rehtegot gnirts I ,doirep suoecaterc eht fo dne eht ta eert dezis gnidliub a no gnittiS
.deb eht ffo pu teg ot gnikool
.retfa flesym ecalp I erehw si nugliar a fo pota ,elbisivnI
,ytrap looc siht tuoba em gnillet ot kcab seog eH
I dna ,daed yrev yrev si eh ,epoN
.noitnetta ym sehctac dekcik gnieb gnihtemos fo duht latem dewolloh a tuB
em syawla saw eh taht
.esle enoyreve evoba flesmih skniht eh ,dnik nwo sih tsgnoma nevE
.niaga wen leef sedisni eht
,kniw a em sevig eH .erehwyna rekcuf rehtom taht ezingocer I dna ,kcab snrut em fo tnorf ni yltcerid eno ehT
.pag eht gnisolc hsinif ot
.ecaps dna emit hguorht egami sih retfa esahc I dna
yenruoj sih hsinif ll’eh woh dna txen od ot sesoohc eh tahw tuo dnif
.nemow dna nem eht neewteb dna dniheb gniklaw
.revo si raw eht dna ssap sedaceD
,llihc lla er'yehT
.noitom tsaf ni yteicos rieht gnihctaw ,yb esolc yats I
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.taht rof retteb s’enoyreve dna
.ylprahs tnecs sih ni gnihtaerb
.rood tnorf eht kcol ot thguoht eno a ton
.snoitartsurf lauxes rieht egdirb ot em dedeen ylno yeht ekil demees tI
,niaga dna ,trohs saw emit ruo gnileef
.meht pots syawla I
.ssilb erup ni stnerap sih ta pu gnikool dna tneserp a gnipparwnu
.emit fo lla egnahc ll'taht
.mih htiw level eye ta eb dluoc eno on os kcab gnitlit daeh sih dna ,thgiarts sredluohs ,tuo tsehc ,ytirohtua fo esnes a htiw gnivom s'eH
.raewrednu ruo ot nwod er'ew litnu ffo emoc sehtolc ruO
,em htiw emit erom dneps ot yaw a tsuj si sihT
.llew sa knups nwo ym ni derewohs ma I dna
.thgir eht ot sdaeh rieht denrut evah s'em eht lla taht ees dna
,emit eht ta noitpo ylno eht ekil tlef tI .snalp rieht htiw hguorht og meht tel tsuj t'ndluoc I tub ,ecneloiv siht tnaw t'ndid I
.ylderussa gniddon ,yas I
.yklim era seye sih dna yarg si ruf sih nehw
.yltnalahcnon syas retto na
.esle enoyna naht retteb ,taht wonk dluohs I
.tsaf oot evom ot gnitnaw ton ,kcab em sehcuot eh nehw luferac s'eH
.won thgir s’ti ,dog yalp nac I emit yna si ereht fI
.rehtegot deb eht no tneps su ees yeht nehw
,ni pils araiT dna naimaD
gnihtemos rebmemer I od
.sgnidnuorrus ym ot dna evoba ecaps eht morf yawa noitnetta ym gninrut
.tsrif erehwemos ffo pots ot deen I tub ,sey mih llet I
,kcen sih otni eson ym tser I
,yawa sraey-thgil fo snoillim seixalag dna srats eht lla ees nac I
.sdap wap ym ykcits ot hguorht spird erp fo daeb a dna sehctiwt tI
.ot og ot ytrap a tog ev'I
.deen I gniht tsal eht dnif dna rood eht tuo klaw I erofeb pmub tsif ew os ,omoh oN
.hgih ytterp m'I sseug I .yrros m'I"
,wolgretfa sih ni deye ypeels si ssoR
,em fo edisni spilc rieht ytpme ot ydaer ,emit emas eht ta snug rieht esiar htob yehT
.ylthgit ti gnizeeuqs dna wap ym ni ti gnihctulc
I dna ni dleh gnieb s'ti erehw moor a s'erehT
elzzum sih no elims yls a ,kcab daeh sih snael eH
,steehs eht no swalc sih gard mih raeh I
,moor letoh ruo ni tuo ekam eW
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.meht gnidnuorrus stseug fo sderdnuh
.ereht dna ereh levart I ,elihw a roF
,noitats eht otni flesym lliw I
.erutuf eht otni raf flesym dnif I nehT
erehwemos morf ti teg annog m'I neht thginot ti od annog ton s'eh fi tuB
.sedivorp esrevinu eht dnA"
,deticxe os eb ton osla ot tluciffid elttil a s’ti tuB .meht htiw emit doog a evah ot drah oot ton s’ti dna
,yas dna rehtegot swap ym palc I .thgir si llA
.evaw a rof seog xof elbram eht ,daeha eerhT
,psag a tuo stel eh dna ,efil ot kcab semoc rac ehT
.txen neppah ot tuoba s'tahw swonk eh esuaceb ti yas t'nseod eH ".uoy
.evael ot rewoplliw eht evah reven d’I wonk I ,ksa d’yeht fI
,elbat eht ffo llip eht hctans I
nettogrof d'I
.evoba gnihsalf sthgil htiw gnilaes rodirroc latem a s'ereht ,em fo daehA
,seires a ,allevon a
.draug ffo elttil a em sehctac eh ,serutnevda eht lla dna srevol eht lla roF
dna nwod elzzum sih spid eh nehT
,nav eht fo kcab eht ni lla meht ekorts I ,ylluferaC
innavoiG htiw ytrap eht fo tsom dneps I
,raef ot gnihton sah eH
,noitcurtsed lufwa fo loot a ecno saw
,elzzum sih daer nac I .selim dna selim rof gnihton s'erehT
.ylleb ym tsniaga lruc ot snrut dna
",eeerrrruS" ,a tuo sehcterts eh sa
.pmahc laer a ekil
,erutuf eht otni ees ot srewop ym evah t'nseod eh hguoht dna ,suortsasid neeb evah dluoc thgin sihT
.wap ym ni rellortnoc a htiw hcuoc sih no deggel-ssorc gnittis m'I ;enola ton m’I
.htuoy ruo ni rehtegot semag oediv gniyalp tsuj llits er'eW
ytilicaf hcraeser a
.noitcurtsed eht tsgnoma traeh rieht dnif yeht tub
ll’ew ,srewop wen sih htiw ni gnilttes s’eh taht woN
.ecalp s’innavoiG fo tnorf ni kcab m'I dna ,wob a ekat I
,levon a gnitirw si
.daetsni moor eht ni llaw a otni tsrif elzzum kcams I ,duht a htiW
,gnimoc si erahsedir ehT
,neerg dna ,wolley ,eulb ,egnaro ,der ni gniremmihs
,ytip fo tuo saw etivni ehT
,lla uoy evol I"
,nwo ym no ti gnihcraeser ainellim a dneps dluoc I eruS
.llew sa suoy evol em ssap dna
,kcoc sih htiw gniyalp m'I elihW
thguoht a s'erehT
.em revo gnihsaw feiler fo esnes a
.emag eht gniyalp emuser dna ,gnihgual er'eW .flow dab gib ehT
.raw eht fo tsom gnitsal ti
.eerht eht fo tnorf ni tuo sgnul ym gnihguoc erofeb sffup elttil gnilahni ,ti ekat I
,em ediseb efas sleef eH
,wap ym esiar I "?sid zi tahV"
.gnithgifni ot sllaf yxalag eht reuqnoc ot woh dna txen od ot tahw fo stnemugrA
dna muc ruo ni derevoc llits er'ew ,raewrednu ruo ni er'ew hguoht nevE
,eerht eht fo dexaler tsom eht reve ,naimaD
,etartenep tonnac I moor eht dna srosnes hcet hgih dna snugliar eht lla htiw ,kniht ot yzarc tsomla s'tI
,daor a fo edis eht ta gnittis nav a s'erehT
.ecneirepxe nac I tahw fo noitcarf a tsuj si siht dna ,erolpxe ot em rof tuo esrevinu tsav a s'erehT
.enola ton m'I tuB
,mih no gniyalp erew stcejbus sih knarp a erew I fi sa
.flesym ecudortni ot elbat sih morf ssorca taes eht gnikat dna efac eht otni gniklaw
.enihs ot tnemom thgir eht dedeen tsuj taht srepeels
,pu wohs tsuj ot kniht I
,tsom ta keew a ebyam stsal ysuolaej reH ".syoB"
.gnihT dliW eht emoceb ot
tsuj gniklaw em seciton neve rehtien taht lamrof os era stnemevom rieht tub
.emit yreve ti snaem yleniuneg eh dna
.erofeb dah reve ti naht retteb gninnur snav eht seciton eh sa gnitniuqs ,slenap eht ta serats eH ".tihs ,lleW"
,rettiwt no elbuort fo stros lla gnisuac ton s’eh nehw
.strecnoc neewteb tuo evag nav rieht dna
.thgis fo enil rieht htaenrednu
nworc rewolf a htiw enola reh hctac I erofeb
yarthsa na no ti gnicalp
.eno sulp sih eb ot em stnaw eh dna
.noitcurtsed eht morf yawa efil sti rof gninnur erutaerc eht ,suruasoihcarb eht ot tap lanif a evig I
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.niaga elohw si ti litnu lliw ym htiw desolc ti dnem I dna
”gnihT dliW“ fo strap owt fo dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
htiw gniddew a fo mrof a gnimrofrep
.reffo eht esufer ot edur smees ti tub
.em htaenrednu lerrab eht gnitarbiv ,smuh edisni rotcaer ehT
.kcen sih no ssik a mih evig dna
,moor eht ni pots I
,snoitats deniur rieht dna sgnidliub delbmurc rieht tsuj ton
,llams dna tsaf ma I
.derehtob dna toh elttil a gnitteg m'I dna ,mih ot noitcartta esnetni siht leef em sekam tahw s'tI
.em no pu kcehc ot dnoces a rof neercs eht gnisuap ,elzzum sih no kool denrecnoc a tog s'innavoiG
.pu dewohs eH .ereh s'eH
.em ediseb emit fo egassap a otni gnicnalg ,tius wollof I
.em sekil ehs gninialpxe fo yaw reh
",tuo krow lliw sgnihT"
.tey ereht etiuq ton s'eh tub ,tuo em gniksa ot esolc os si innavoiG
.edam era snoitcudortni ylkciuq dna
,si dda ot sah ehs lla tub ,snrut elzzum s'araiT
.sneppah raw livic taerg a dna retnilps yehT
.noitanimod yxalag rof snalp sih liof I sa regna ni tsif a gnikahs ,pu ekaw dluow eh dna llip eht ekat d'I nehT
.emit eht ta detaicerppa ton cisum eht
.enola ylrettu dna ,tsol ,deracs
,taht etipseD
,eloh kcalb eht ot evaw drawkwa na evig I ,niagA
”dutS ruoY tsuJ m’I“
,kcab uoy evol I yas I
hguorht decreip si lluh eht sa tsuj ecaps otni ffo gnippets ,lerrab eht morf esir I ,yllaudarG
,thgin yadirF a s'tI .mih fo duorp nmad dog os tsuj m'I dna ,flesmih ees reve dluoc eh naht ylraelc erom mih ees nac I
em ees I ,dnim sih nI
.edis sih tsniaga pu eldduc I dna
.ruf ym gnilooc ria thgin s'tresed eht dna ,mraw dnuorg eht
.noitats hcraeser eht ni yawllah a otni gnidael srood elbuod eht no drawrof hsup I dna eno otni espalloc s'em ehT .emit yrevE
.tuo seirc eciov a "!dednarts er'eW"
,syas eh ,ssik eht morf skaerb eh nehW
wonk mih tel ot naom I dna ,tsehc ym no ruf eht hguorht nur sregnif siH
,snepo rood tnorf eht nehW
.edirp hcum os htiw dellif si traeh ym dnA
.daor eht nwod thgir dna tfel gnitfihs retto tsellat eht
,syas eh ,selahxe eh nehw dna tih a sekat ,kcab ym ot wap a gnippals ,ssoR .gurhs I ,niagA
,stih eb retal dluow taht seno eht fo emos ezingocer I
,em sehcaet ehS
.flesym morf rehtegot erutuf ruo fo tser eht dleihs I dna
,ruf ym rednu hcti na tfel s'tI
.llew sa ezeeuqs a mih evig ot rebmem ffits nwo sih fo dloh gnibbarg ,ffuh I
wef eht ees I dna ,em fo tnorf ni sehcterts emiT
.krod evissam a ekil kool tub pleh t'nac I ,dogimed a sa nevE
.ekat ot em rof hcaor a gnidnetxe
,dekcom dna deoob era srehtO
.em htiw eb ot stnaw eh sa hcum sa mih htiw eb ot tnaw I dna ,gnihT
.euc ym s'tahT "?woH"
.yllausac ksa I
.ytrap eht ot detivni yllatnedicca eh renol eht tsuj m’I tub ,em gnizingocer
hctaw I .yxalag eht gnilur dna rewop fo sklat dna ,sredael citamsirahc ,srotatcid fo derit ,gnithgif fo derit meht tfel sah raw riehT
.emoh kcab lias ot flesym gnilliw ,htrae sdrawot tuo kool I ,enod ereh krow yM
,kcab ym no gniyal m'I
.yats ot em llet dna gniyas m’I tahw ezingocer thgim meht fo eno taht epoh llams a
.emos ekam ot epoh eht htiw
.semag oediv gniyalp yltsom s'eh tub ,yrteop gnitirw si eh ,semag oediv gniyalp ton s'eh nehW
,ecaf-tuoba ot dna nrut yehT
.dehcuotnu sdnal fo yreneerg tsav eht ni gnikat ,esirnus eht hctaw I
.emas eht lla stsixe tub ,nekat neeb reven sah taht daor a ees I ,ereht si tI
,ssik rehtona htiw mih ecnelis I
,noitseuq lanif sih ni sksa eh os dna
.srosiv dna staoc bal etihw gniraew hcae ,stros lla fo sdrazil era erehT
.eb ot sah ti esuaceb ,tcefrep si gnimit yM
.sdnuos rieht gnitset ,em fo tnorf ni evil gniyalp won
.erom rof tuo gnimaercs ,sdworc gniraor htiw tem era emoS
.ereht gnidilloc srats nortuen owt
.eerht eht tsgnoma ssik tsrif ym si ohw ssoR s'ti
.kaerb sih fo elddim eht gnirud ,mrofinu eeffoc neerg a ni mih hctac I
.ytrap eht ot em detivni taht erah eht s'ti
.enola yawllah a edistuo gnidnats
.em naht relooc hcum os s'eh yhw nosaer eht s’taht ,noinipo ym nI .sselwalf s'eH
,taht ta hgual yehT
.thgin eht rof edisni yats ot detpo dah ssoR dna em tub
,kcoc ym sees ,nwod skool ssoR
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.ti otni tsefinam tsuj t'nac
.neewteb-ni roloc yreve htiw gnola
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.edisni em semoclew dna ,ti otni thguoht hcum oot tup t'nseod eh ,yllufknahT
.tniop siht erofeb srewop ym detset evah dluohs ylbaborp
.flesym ot evig ot deen I
,dnuora skool tnaryt ehT .eye sih ni thguac gnihtemos eb thgim I fi sa semit elpuoc a gniknilb
,enog ydaerla m'I tub
,yas I ",wols trats
,ihsus setah dna sregrub sekil eh ,tuo og ew nehW
.em s'ti wonk I dna
,retaw htiw knat eht gnillif
,revo semit noillib a nees s'eh semina gnihctaw gnineve eht tneps evah dluoc eh hguoht dna
.txen eht otno gnivom erofeb hcnip eltneg a eno gnivig sdnoces wef yreve ,meht dnuora noitom ralucric a gnikam speek eH
.rekihhctih flowerew
,em fo skniht eh tahw ees ;sthguoht ym rebmemer I
,rotatcid eht dniheb esolc teg I
.sdneirf sih ot decudortni gnieb
.daor eht no thgin yreve tsomla emosruof a otni dellup lla er'ew erofeb elbativeni eht gniyned ton
snugliar rehto dna ,snoitats elttab ,spihs etarecsive ot sdeeps elbamohtafnu ta gnicar ,pit sti morf sehcnual elitcejorp A
rettiwT no etoyoCtriD ta mih dniF
,gninwad noisnecsa rieht fo emit eht ,gnilbmarcs er'yehT
"?thgir I ma ,seigrellA .yrros ,haeY"
.siht pots nac I taht
erew oidar eht morf wenk ylno I sdnab eseht llA
.emit ym s'ti wonk I
.emoc ot snoitareneg rof muirta nedrag s'noitats a rewop ot yawa selim fo snoillim tnes si eroc eht fo degavlas si tahW
.kool a ekat ot reffo I dna llirg eht morf gniruop llits si ekomS
.em tuohtiw enif eb ll'yeht wonk I
.etag ym egnahc t'nod I tub ,pmuj eerht llA
,drawrof wap sih sehcaer ylsuoituac
.si eh sa laiceps sa enoemos htiw eb ot ykcul os eb dluow enoyna esuaceb
em fo erutuf yreve gniees ma I
.etal oot s'ti litnu daeh sih edisni pu gnidliub tolc eht ees t'nod I
.eibeerf a saw taht ,gnihtyna fI .llew hO
mih no dnal yllautneve I tub
drawrof liat ym gnillup
.rehtona ot ti gnissap erofeb ti fo tih a gnikat
.ytrap eht erofeb shtnom xis tuoba
.tsirw ym fo kcab eht no ruf eht htiw eson dna seye ym epiw I
.esrevinu elohw eht ni krod tseggib dnoces eht dna ,regnuoy sraey dnasuoht a ,ma I erehT
.ecnetsixe ym fo foorp yna dna
detaerc ev'yeht gniht siht dna kcab emoc yeht ,thgir s'taht ,haeY
.edisni daeh ym ekop dna nepo ti pop I ,dooh eht htiw luferaC
,eulb gniht elohw eht snrut eroc eht morf gnikael noitaidaR
:niatrec gniht eno sevorp ti taht
.derettalf m'I dna
”gnihT dliW“   :yojne esaelP
guh edis a htiw innavoiG steerg eH
tnulb eht gnidloh eno ehT
.eno teg reve ew semit wef eht fo eno
.taht sekil eh dna ,hguorht walc a ecart I taht tnorf sih revo egdup elttil a s'erehT
,78-reisseM ot kcab emoc I nehw ylno s'tI
.rehtona eno no gninrut won era ,em rof tnaem ecno snugliar ehT
wap sih otno gnidloh ,mih tel t'nod I
.decnivnocnu
neppah annog t'nsi
,rab eht ta tuo era naimaD dna araiT
,dliuber yehT
!drah sa tsuj kcab em sevohs eh ,em naht rellat toof a tsomla s'eh hguoht dna ,redluohs ym htiw mih evohs I
,yltaerg meht ssim ll'I hguoht dna
,daor eht no shtnom dneps eW
.gnola wollof ot em rof tsaf oot gnivom tsomla s'ti ,shtnom ot dehcterts teg sdnoces sa neve dna ,emit wols I
.em dniheb wor a ni gnidnats sexof elbram etinifni elpuoc a gniees
.tuhs delaes si em dniheb rood latem eht sa tsuj
.si eh sa lufituaeb sa flah ton s'ti mih llet I ,nuf rof tsuJ
.seceip otni ti gnillup
,ot txen gnidnats saw gnihT dliW eht flow eht rebmemer I nehT
.syawyna em rof ti seod eh tub
;noitats terces pot a si gnir s'tenalp eht ni gnidiH
,detrats lla siht woh rebmemer ,oga gnol os ti evag I evaw drawkwa taht rebmemer I .tnatropmi
.reggib dna rellat era eerht lla hguoht
,doog sleef ecalp dna emit sihT
em ekat ot ydaer
tib tsal taht sserts dna ,yas I ",hcum os
.kcohs ni em teerg sdraug owt eht dna pu snepo moor latem eht erofeb dnoces a sekat tI
dna pals a elzzum ym evig I ,yesoog yesool gnileef m'I litnu ydob ym gnilggiW
,em sdrawot pu sromert dnuorg eht sA
,tuo em ksa seod yllanif eh nehW
.ruf dna kcab ym ffo trid eht gnihsurb elihw meht sdrawot gniklaw
,ti otni thgir pmuj I ,yrevarb emos htiW
,em fo diarfa ,ylsuovren elffuhs yehT ".ereh
,em ot ti sllet eh revenehw ydob ym hguorht gnisruoc htmraw emas taht ,doog leef em sekam tI
.nwod dna pu sdon eh dna
.gnihT dliW eht ma I .dog
noisiced eht gnikam
.tils eht hguorht spils kcoc sih litnu raewrednu eht kcab llup I sa rrup gnihtoos a tuo stel eH
.kcen gnol sti hctarcs ot tuo hcaer I dna ,em ot txen sevael eht fo etib a gnikat suruasoihcarb a s'erehT
.nworc a otni srewolf diarb ot woh nrael I taht araiT htiw si tI
s'erehT .epocselet a hguorht gnikool ekil meht ta keep dna
.fo tnorf ni gnidnats ylremrof saw eh llaw eht tsniaga hsa dna doolb fo yarps a tub gnihton si nogard odomok eht ,hsalf a nI
tnaig sag a ees I
.esirprus laer a eb ot ti tnaw I
,nugliar eht rof emoc rethgierf a
,pit eht ot regnif xedni ym tup I .hcuot a
ot fles erutuf sih morf llip a nevig saw xof ruo ,emit tsaL
.erom ecno ti deen I litnu yawa dekcol eb ot reve
.ruf rieht fo hcuot eht otno dloh ot gniyrt
.em fo ekam ot tahw wonk t'nseod ti fi neve ,hguone llew noitnetta eht sekil tI
.nworc siht gnikam nuf fo tol a gnivah ma I :gnola lla thgir saw gnihT dliW eht taht ezilaer I dna
.uoy evol I ,emosdnaH yeH"
,stib ot deppohc si lerrab ehT
.tcapmi war rieht ni meht ot netsil ot doog llits saw tI
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
.evol ym htiw mih gnirussaer
.setadpu erutuf rof
,syawyna tuo tnew eh
.dnatsrednu ot reh gnideen ton ,gurhs I
,kcoc tneps ym fo ffo sedils araiT
.etivni reporp a deen I ,oN
,tnatsni na ni dna
.ytrap taht ot kcab teg ot deen I dna od ot ssenisub
.ereh dnal ot deneppah tsuj I" ,nialpxe dna
.melborp eht wonk I kniht I tub ,srac ta trepxe na ton m'I
,erofeb top enod reven ev'I
,elihw a rof ereht yats eW
,laiceps enoemos rof flesmih gnivas si innavoiG
,efil raed rof puc a otno gnidloh ,moor eht ssorca gnidnatS .sneppah ti tuB
,sksa dna smra reh pu sworht syob owt eht neewteb lrig A
.tcatnoc eye ekam ew dna
.1202 fo yrotS trohS tseB s’ltoyoC rof detanimon saw
.s’08 eht fo elddim eht ni dednal ev’I taht nrael I .dah I oS ".sedivorp
.dnoces a rof em setadimitni tI
.eciton ot detcartsid oot elttil a tsuj m'I yhw s'taht ebyam dna
dna srats dna stenalp era dnuora llA
.ti od dluohs tahT"
sneila fo elpuoc
,yllufhsab yawa daeh sih snrut eH ".hgih
.snaom gnirettum
.noitcif yrruf trohs dna
.dekcarc si rotaidar eht erehw leef tsomla nac I ,ngised sti hguorht gniees dna elcihev eht gnisneS
.stpure lerrab eht ,toh oot teg nac ti erofeb tsuj dna
.nugliar rehtona morf tellub a s'tI
.evoba yaw yklim eht gnitaicerppa ,ereht yats I
.noisiv ym morf flesym ekahs I dna ,sksa innavoiG "?gniyrc uoy erA"
.srab dna strecnoc dna seunev neewteb gnilevart
erad I dna ,srexob sih pu stnet kcoc siH .doog sleef ti
.yawa selim fo sdnasuoht
,dloc ma I .enog s'eh
.ffo rehto hcae krej ew ,deb eht no edis yb ediS
eno siht piks esaelp
ytiradilos teiuq ni tfel m'I snoe emos dna ,srevol dna sdneirf htiw semitemoS .ton semit tsom tub
.pu gnihtemos kcip ot tog ev'I ,tsrif tuB
.enog m'I neht dnA .reverof
,em ot snrut eh nehw s'tahT
,tuo llac I "!ydwoH"
.edis sih fo rehtie ta sdraug demra elpuoc a htiw gniklaw nogard odomok llat a s'erehT
.ynitsed sdrawot elim tsal eht
ti hsirehc ot traeh ym ni ecalp a dnif dna
.ti evah meht tel t'nac I .esrevinu eht revo ecnanimod rieht erusne ot si
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.llip taht no swap ym teg
llip eht gnipoleved er'yeht erehw
.siht desuac I taht tliug elttil a leef I dna
.ylleb dna tsehc sih ssorca zzij fo enil a gniyarps
".gnihtyna od t'ndid uoY"
.retaerg gnihtemos otni mrofsnart
,ecaps otni gnikael ,rotcaer eht morf sllips wolg eruza nA .hguorht dna
.llet nac I ,eno nuf eht s'eH
,ylsuoenatnops od ot sekil eh gnihtemos tsuj s'tI
.rood eht fo tnorf ni gnidnats em fo snoisrev etinifni
,neeb evah thgim I deviecrep yeht taerht revetahw ro
.tfahs ym gnola yleerf gnilbbird erp ,tuo gnah kcoc ym gnittel ,nwod sfeirb ym llup I .raewrednu ym ni deniartser sleef kcoc ym dna gnizama os era snoitasnes ehT
.pu sbmuht elbuod a em sih gnivig yb pu em swohs eno taht ,nrut nI
,puorg eht ta elims dna dooh eht esolc I
!sizaN ecapS .sizaN er'yehT
.gnihtemos ro deifingid erom eb ot senigami eh kniht I taht noitisop a otni gnitteg ,elbat eht dnuora spets eH
.dniheb eno eht teerg ot kcab snrut noisrev hcae sa hctaw I
,em morf ti dedleihs ev’yehT
rehto hcae gnitanimile pu dne ylno yeht dna
,syas dna shgual ,citpeks eht reve ,araiT ".ti
"?dedaeh ew erehW"
.tsehc sih otni yltcerid tuo ti gnisaeler erofeb
.htrae ot denruter ev’I ,seye ym nepo I nehW
.mih syawla saw I dna
,noisufnoc emos htiw em ta skool enipal ehT
.did tsuj ew tahw suoivbo ytterp s'ti
.desopruper retal si taht latem war otni detlems noitces llams a wollof I dna
.feiht a gnieb rof em fo ssel kniht t'nod ,hO
ton gnorts oot noitcartta ruo dna esolc oot spil ruo ,deew fo htaerb a htiw em gninnugtohs retfa ni ti skaens eH
ytrap taht wonk I dna
tog ev'I .wen dna gnuoy os flesym ees dna
.stimda eh ",erofeb yug rehtona htiw taht enod reven ev'I"
,ylsuoiruc em ta gnirats er'yehT
.nwot fo strikstuo eht no doohrobhgien yttihs a ni tnemtrapa ynit a ni gnivil ,tuopord egelloc a s'eH
,syas dna moor eht otni gniklaw em sezingocer eh ,llew os em ees t'nac eh hguoht nevE
yawyna emac eh tub ,ereh dneirf elgnis a evah t'nseod eH
,kcab nrut I .su neewteb sgnileef drah on s’ereht dna
a s'ereht ,ereht revO
,tuo gnimoc si eno oN !esirprus
deb eht otno kcab llaf ew ,rehtegoT
.sdneirf eurt tsrif ym
.emit tsrif eht rof enoz trofmoc sih fo tuo pets ot nesohc s'eh
ton m'I .segnahc gib yna ekam I fi
,moor eht fo retnec eht ni elbat a ot sklaw nogard odomok ehT
,elzzum sih ni tnulb a tog s’enO
.nav rieht fo kcab eht ni gnitnap dna dekan ,tsehc s'naimaD revo gniyal m'I taht enil eht nwod raey a tuoba s'tI
.ohw morf yltcaxe wonk I dna
.ti tsniaga gninael era sretto fo puorg a dna
.flesti laeh rac eht leef nac I tub
,htrae semitemoS
.selppin ym ni detsevni erom s'eh
.rehtegot ti teg ot flesym llet
.wolgretfa ruo ni elzzun dna
,der snrut elzzum s'flow ehT
,emit siht lla retfa neve ,tniop siht tA
.nelots eb nac ti erehwemos evael ot elbaulav oot si siht wonk I ,stsicsaf eht ekilnU
.elihw a rof siht detnaw ev'I esuaceb ,dalg m'I
.mottob no eb ot ekil d’I kniht I ,emit siht tpecxE
.hguorht levart t'nac I ecalp eno eht si siht taht
.rehtegot emit gnidneps naht erom gnihton evol I esuaceb mih no nwod kool t'noD
.tihs a evig t'ndluoc tI .eloh kcalb nikaerf a s'tI .em sserpmi ot evah t'nseod ti
.gnidne na tuoba gniyrc saw I wenk eh fi tihs hcum os em evig d'eH
ecin desserd eh tub
ssap ot puorg a rof gnitiaw ,esuap I ,stniop emos tA
,llip eht ees I dna
gniyas ni gnitsrub emoc d'yeht dnoces yna ta dna
.pu snepo letoh ruo ot rood eht nehw hcnilf neve t'nseod ssoR dna
.cirbaf eht revo nwod dna pu ti gnikorts
nevo ekab ysae elttil sih gnidnuorrus gnisac eht taht wonk reven d'eH
.reh rof tsuj dediarb I
,erutuf dna ,tneserp ,tsap ni htob ,kaelb dna krad os ecnetsixe nA
.snugliar dnasuoht derdnuh a yb detibro
.elims yls a em sti sevig eno txen eht ,owT
rood eht srewsna eH
.si eh emosdnah woh tsuj ezilaer I ,thgil eht ni mih gniees dna ,deef aidem laicos sih hguorht gnikcilf elihw ettal a no gnippis s'eH
.sdneirf sih no noisserpmi doog a ekam ot gnipoh
.ereh ees ot em rof tfel gnihton s'ereht gniwonk ,evael I
.enola esrevinu eht fo sehcterts eht erolpxe ot
siht rebmemer I taht tnatropmi s'tI
,goD fo ecioV ehT no derutaef yrots siH
,hpmuirt fo tnemom sih ot steg eh erofeb tsuJ
.nworc rewolf ym stnemilpmoc dna
em hguorht gnisruoc ygrene gnileef
.sgniht degnahc evah dluoc I woh rednow I tub
.gnihcaorppa dioretsa na ees I ,pu gnikooL
.ereht mih gnipeek dna
.pu sbmuht a enim evig I ,ecnedifnoc htiW
,etunim a rof serats eH
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
drawrof kool I nehT
.hctaw ot ereht tsuj er'ew semitemos dna ,gig a yalp ot ereht er'ew semitemoS
.enim t'nsi taht gnihtemoS
.noitingi eht snrut dna taes tnorf eht ni steg ,retto tsellat eht ,naimaD
.rafa morf yteicos rieht gnihctaw ,ereht tis I
.sraet otni nwod kaerb ton ot drah s'tI .em ees I
.nwod og lliw ti woh ro nwod tnew ti woh ton s'taht tub
,wolf eht htiw seog
.gnissarrabme saw tahT
,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
dliW eht ma I :eurt sa
—dennuts elttil a m'I
.enohp sih pu sdloh dna ti tsap sehsup eh tub
,ti hsiugnitxe ot won hguone gnorts m'I hguoht neve dna ,niaga em sllif wolg mraw tahT
.eye ym fo renroc eht tuo gnimoc gnihtemos ees I ,drah oot ti rednop nac I erofeB
,dnuorg eht morf pu tfil I
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.nem owt eht neewteb thgir edistuo pets a ekat I