.dlohtoof ym dnif I ,ecno ta lla dnA
.enim ot ralimis os si
.1202 fo yrotS trohS tseB s’ltoyoC rof detanimon saw ”dutS ruoY tsuJ m’I“
,mih eb ot tnaw I
,rekihhctih flowerew ,floWcaM boR yb uoy rof daer
.ereh evil thgim eh kniht I
.em ni detseretni erom s'eh
,drawkcab dehsup m'I
.ytip fo tuo enod saw etivni ym dna ereh enoyna wonk t'nod I .swap ym ni puc
,tsirw ym fo kcab eht htiw
,elpoep laer htiw sevil laer devil yeht dna
,mih otni peed stoohs muC
,ot desu m'I naht resolc
gnihsinav rotcod a fo
,evael annaw uoy fI"
erofeb naht esrow gnikool ylbaborp
,ni em gnitivni ,snrut eH
,ebul rof erp dna tips ym ylno htiW
,oga dnoces a em gniretsulf noitnetta eht lla etipseD .puc a sbarg dna
.won yb deneppah evah ot gnihtemos gnitcepxe ,ksa I "?lleW"
thgir msagro I dna ,thgit ezeeuqs seye yM .rettam t'nseod tI
,em eb ot tcefrep oot tsuj s'eh tub ,sessalg ym gnissim eh si ylno toN .em eb t'nac eH
",won hguone tew eb dluohs uoY"
gnihtemos rewsna ot elba eb ll'uoy neht
.rehte eht ot kcab flesym evig dna
.yawllah a sdrawot edis eht ot daeh sih skcilf dna
.eson ym gnilknirw
.emit tsrif eht em no seye syal eh sa daeherof eht no em sessik
,ssendnik dna ytisoreneg rieht rof enoyreve gniknaht ,raob eht guh I
,ronaemed sih fo tser eht ekil dna
,pirg ym ni kcils si kcoc siH
.ti eciton I taht neht ylno s’tI
rof gnola sgnileef rieht dna seiromem rieht gnikat
,rood eht sdrawot pets tsrif eht sekam toof ym sa tsuJ
.flesti sevaw eht no dnats ot gniyrt ekil s'ti
,htaerb gnihsinif ym htiW
.nrevat eht ni esle enoyna naht reduol s'ti ,gnis I nehw dna taeb a fo trats tsethgils eht ta ecnad I ,sdneirf ym htiW
a ekil em retfa si eh esuaceb ,mih nevig ev'I eman eht ot pu sevil erus gnihT dliW ehT
tuoba m'I dna tnaercsim a hcus saw I .esrup
I esuaceb detaerc lla erew nnyW dna ,ailuJ ,samohT
.sregnif sih neewteb yltneg meht gnizeeuqs dna dnuora meht gnillor ,sllab ym gnildnah si rehto ehT
dna kcab sih no seog wap enO
.em ta gnimoc drapoel a tsniaga hsalc I ,mra ym dnuora depparw dleihs ym htiW
,seilper yltfos dna yletilop sdon gnihT dliW ehT ".srewolf
.rehtegot ecneirepxe eht gniviler er'eW
,emosdnah os s'eH
.siht naht retteb gnihtyna enigami t'ndluoc I dna
,tnedifnoc os era sdrow siH
em fo og stel eH
.em dniheb sdniwnu ti litnu xaler ot
.yromem eht fo thguoht eht ta kcab gnillup
tsiaw ym dnuora liat ym hsurb I
em rof wap sih sdnetxe eh
.ydob sih ot nwod gniog seye ym ,mih yduts I
dednuorrus nrevat a ta mih rebmemer I dna
,htaerb sih ffo gnidacsac semuf lohocla htiw syas eh
.noitcif yrruf trohs dna
.erofeb bojdnah a nevig sa hcum os reven d'I
.railimaf oot tsuj si taht redluohs sih no ruf fo hctap dessik nus siht si ereht dnA
.elbat eht otno nwod knird eht gnittis
.esrevinu eht fo elohw eht hguorht derettacs smota ym ees I ,daeh level a htiW
!dniweroF samohT ton m'I
,syawyna yas I ,elzzum ym no elims suovren a htiW
,regnar krap a si boj tsal dna tsrif yM
.elzzum sih ni em gnikat neve tuohtiw nruter on fo tniop eht sdrawot em gnigde mih leef nac I
:ylrae hsurc tsrif ym nrael I taht margorp regnar roinuj eht ni m'I nehw s'tI .ykcul ma I
.stenalp dna stleb dioretsa neewteb xaler ot dna leufer ot ti ta pots srethgierF
.hcaeb a no dnas gnipoocs ekil rehtegot kcab flesym gnittup
moor driht eht s'tI
.mih edisni gnitoohs ot esolc teg I sa
rorroh ni hctaw I ,meht barg ot tuo sehcaer mra ym sa tsuJ
,ylsselerac rehto hcae htiw gnitrilf ega ym nemow dna nem ,seidob eht hguorht selbma eh elihW
.esaeler gnideen em ni gnitaslup ygrene eht ,hcum oot
,gnihtemos ro yticirtcele fo zzub thgils a
.elzzum sih no yarg dna etihw eht ekil tsuj ,moor eht fo sthgil eht htiw sroloc tfihs yehT
.daeh sih no nworc rewolf eht si tsom eht tuo skcits tahW
.edisni flesym hsup I sa kcoc ym dnuora gnipparw eloh sih leef
,etoyoC triD yb ”gnihT dliW“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht eht saw sihT
.enola em dna em no gnitser tsuj
seye s’llub eht si noivilbo otni kcab dewollaws m'I erofeb ees I gniht tsal ehT
dnatsthgin a no pmal a gniees
gnitrups kcoc sih leef I
,elims si od I llA
seod ti tub ,gnihtyna ekil etsat t'nseod tI
.rehto hcae dnuora swap elgnat ew sa gnixim htaerb ruo ,sih ekil drah era sffuh yM
,syawyna yldiputs evaw
.noisiced ym degnahc ev'dluow taht fi yrrow I tub
.hguoht won ti leef I
.ecaps dna emit neewteb tuoba nworht tsuj m'I
.mih retne dna drawrof nael I
.tsethgils eht revaw t'nod I dna ,egelloc dna loohcshgih tuohguorht lla
.nwod dna pu em eye
,morf og d'uoy tsaf woh eveileb ton d'uoY
tsoh eht knaht ot emit ym eb thgim ti gnikniht ,moor eht nacs I
.loop a hguorht gnimmiws sa ysae sa diov eht hguorht gnivom ,ti hcaorppa I
,hcamots ym no syats wap enO
.flesym rof s'tI
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.dniweroF samohT si eman yM .nrob ma I
neerg dna ,wolley ,eulb ,egnaro ,der swolg ti sa esolc yrev ,enim ot ralimis si nrettap ruf siH
.em rof nosrep rehto on s’erehT
.em fo ffo ti gniknay trats dna ti htaenrednu pu wap a edils ot tsuj trihs ym fo og stel eH .tsaeb
—neht ,nisuoc ym ton s'eh fI
ailuJ fo tfel gniht ylno ehT
.enoyna evas t'nac I
.ti gnikat erofeb knilb I dna
.thguoht ro noitatiseh yna tuohtiw
ffo diuqil eht hsurb I
esruoc fo ,nworc rewolf sih dnA
.eb ot sah ti gniniatretne woh erac
,dleifelttab eht no sraeppasid dniweroF samohT
;mih leef ot deen tsuJ
,erusaelp fo naom a s'erehT
.revo ekat stcnitsni ym tub
.edam s'eh elddup eht otni sknis wap ym sa tsuj mih fo og tel I dna
.srewolf ruoy ekil I"
,pu bmilc ot elba m'I redluob a s'erehT
,emit a rof suoyoj s'tI
.niarb ym hguorht ninotores fo sevaw sdnes
,niaga wap dehctertstuo sih sekahs eH
.snoitareneg erutuf rof ytuaeb s'erutan evreserp ot nrows
.stsurht ym fo dnuos gnippals eht revo tsuj
,em ta emoc erom neT
.enog era ylimaf dna sdneirf ym fo lla ,sruoh wef a fo naps eht ni dna diar a s'erehT
.em ot ralimis oot yaw s'eh taht ezilaer I dna ,tsehc ym ni sknis traeh yM
,evaw llams a ti gnivig ,nus ym ot eybdoog yas I .kcab em gnidloh gnihton s'ereht
.rekab a fo sregnif eht ni hguod ekil htrof dna kcab em ssap snoulg fo aes ehT
.sserpxe reve dluoc esle enoyna ro I tahw naht erom semit derdnuh a dna gnitnelernu si evol stI
.pots ro nwod wols ot mih llet ot woh erus ton ,dnim ym revo gnidoolf si tnemssarrabme toh A
,elzzum nwo ym fo noitcelfer eht
,htgnel ym dnuora sparw
.wap a htiw pu liat sih gnidloh dna sruof lla no pu gnilwarc
drah nwod gnitib em htiw neve
,erehwon fo tuO .srewsna tsuJ
.flesruoy rof esac doog a gnikam ton er'uoy ,dnim ym gnidaer ton er’uoy fI"
:yojne esaelP
,detapicitna evah dluoc I naht retsaf ,nehT ".thgir hO"
.tsrif ta gniewa s'tI .78-reisseM fo
?em…ekil skool tI
,sladep eht ezingocer t'nod I
,syas dna ,kniw a em sevig eH "?efas ti sI"
a htiw diputs dnuora dnats I sa
,daeh ym revo ti llup ot yliratnemom skaerb ssik eht sa nevE
pots ro wols ot mih tnaw t'nod yletarepsed I .tsenoh gnieb m’I fi ,hguohT
",og nac ew ecalpemos wonk I
,syas eh ,efil ym fo tser eht rof snoiniuer ylimaf yna diova dna
.emit rehtona yrots rehtona rof kcab emoc dna
.drawrof flesym hsup dna ,nwo ym dnoyeb seixalag eht ot noitnetta ym gninrut erofeb
,gnihtyna ta yletarepsed hctulc I
srewop wen sih htiw syenruoj xof ruo woh tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT .nnyW sa
.yademos rotcod a eb annog m'I dna
won mih ta gnirats eno eht m'I
og ot sah eh shtgnel eht dna
.em ni detseretni t'nsaw eh nwonk ev'dluohs I
.gnirob adnik era seloh kcalb ,yakO"
,edis eht ot trihs sih gnilf I
.mih dniheb pu gnilwarc ydaerla
,yrots eht taeper ot mih ksa ot ydaer
,mih ot pu kcab nrut I
.seciov rieht htiw dellif si traeh ym dna
.setargetnisid wap ym sa
,etilop eb ot flesym esucxe ot deen I ekil sleef em fo traP
,yeriw ,keels s'eH
.dewolloh dna ,yrgna
.eniD dna eviD s'ociR dellac
,fres a ,rehtaf yM
.ytpme sleef em fo lassimsid etaidemmi sih
.gniraew saw gnihT dliW eht
.gnihT dliW a ekiL
,mih htaenrednu morf eerf sllup tI
dednetni saw ti yaw eht rehtegot kcab flesym fo trap hcae gnittup
.sdlrow rieht tuoba nrael dna dworc eht htiw noitasrevnoc ekam I
erutuf eht ni sraey dnasuoht wef a tuo
.srenetsil erutam rof rettam tcejbus tluda snrecnoc yrots s'yadoT
,lufecrof oot ton pirg dexaler sih
.llifluf ot snoitibma nwo ym dah I rebmemer I dna ,oot
.siht enod evah dluow I yaw rehto on s’ereht dna
,dnuorg eht no mih ekirts ot ydaer
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
;yaw yna ni em etadimitni ot yrt eh seod ron
.pu selbbub taht tliug fo hsalf yratnemom a s'erehT
.mih evag dog tahw tub gnihton gniraew s'eh dna seitihw ythgit ym ot nwod m'I erofeb gnol ton s'tI
.mih otni ytpme sllab ym sa kcab sih no pu em sdloh gnihT dliW ehT
gnikniht neve tub
.mih evas t'nac I
,yas dna nworc sih ta pu tniop I ,noitasrevnoc
.rehtomdnarg ym retfa ailuJ em eman stnerap yM .won knuks a m'I
,rulb a emoceb thgil dna ecapS
.tsom dedeen m’I nehw won thgir gnineppah t’nsaw ti hsiw I dna
,buc flow a ,yob a m'I
rehtorb niwt tsol a ton m'I"
,ylleb sih no s'eh litnu flesmih srewol eh ,ylluferaC
,ereht eM nodraP ,eM esucxE na dna ereh yrroS m’I ,spoO nA
,si eh sa egral sa roF
,ailuJ sa ,reh dniheb si liat esohw ,yralC-ttocS nosidaM
a neve ,htmraw s'nus ehT
.emal os m'I ,kcuF
.gnilbmert waj ,eb ot desu mra ym erehw ta nwod erats I
.stsurht ym ot mih gnipmup nigeb I dna htgnel sih dnuora sparw wap yM
.meht htiw xes evah dna moor a otni regnarts a wollof tsuj dluoc I denigami reven d'I
:detnaw I naht regnol elttil a em sekat ti ,timda I
.em htiw wap ym gnikat dna deb eht otno revo gnillor ,tuo llup I
hguorht tsuj sah eh tahw fo noitcarf a niag ot tnaw I dna
,rehto eht retfa eno
.hcaorppa I sa sdrawkcab gnilbmuts ,rednerrus ni drows sih nwod sworht neet rehto ehT
pot knat gnittif esool eht gniraew m'I won dna
.eson ym fo trohs hcni na tuhs deppals gnieb koob a ekil ,flesti no ni sdlof ytilaeR "—
.mih htiw eb ot tnaw tsuj t'nod I
.thgin tsrif ym no noisolpxe na sesuac nwot ssorca kael sag a tuB
.sregnif ym neewteb ruf eht dna sdap wap ym gniykcits erp
.edivorp nac I srewsna ynam ton s'ereht tub ,snoitseuq em ksa dna emoc wef A .ta tis ot elbat a em dnif yeht dna rethgual fo raor rehtona steg tsuj tahT
.epan s'xof elbram rehto eht tsniaga gnilbbin ,wol elzzum ym pid I
.eno ssentiw ot ekil eb d'ti tahw
ereh eb ot detnaw tsuj I
,seires a ,allevon a
,knird ym nwod tes neve t'nod I
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,ezilaer I taht tnemom taht ta s'tI
,em denraw evah dluow gnihT dliW eht dehsiw d'I
.kcab sih no nrettap eht ees I dna em morf yawa denrut ,edis sih no gniyal s'eH
.ned sih ot ti gniggard saw dna dworc eht morf yerp sih dekculp tsuj eh ekiL
.em ot eurt ylno s'taht yromem a ;ti dnif I
lortnoc dnif t'ndluoc
.sehtolc ym togrof tsuJ
,ecno ta lla ni gnimoc elpoep ynam oot s'erehT
,emoceb ev'I tahw sa ,woN
.railimaf gnikcuf oot yaW
.em dah eh fi ,sih eb yldalg d'I .dnim t'nod I
,sedis sih elddarts swap yM
,era uoy yas uoy ohw er'uoy fI" .em
,krow ym ni edirp ekat I
ton m'I" ,yltneitap
.ti htaenrednu ylbatrofmocnu tfihs I dna
,stsurht esicerp htiw em ta drows sih sgniws eH
.kert lanif siht ekam ot senob ym gnicrof
elbat knird eht ot ediseb spets gnihT dliW ehT
".kcab eseht detnaw I"
.yawa denrut llits
.ylisae yawa swolb sih kconk I tub
.wam ym otni ti polp dna ,ynitsed htiw etad eht ekat I os
.neewteb-ni roloc yreve htiw gnola
,rehtegot dleh era taht gniht ylno eht era sthguoht yM
",lessev nwo ym ma I" ,yas I
,tnedifnoc gnileeF
,samohT m'I .em s'tI
yllaer t'nseod tI
,ti evael ot esoohc dna
.trihs ograc etihw a dna snaeJ
.ssenismulc ym gnigduj tsuj ton ,em no seye s'ereht ekil sleef tI .dniheb wollof
.ma I krod eht ekil meht tsujda I dna elzzum ym no dekoorc leef sessalg yM
.niaga fo draeh ro nees eb ot reven
.moor eht fo retnec eht ni gnidnats xof elbram dekan eht ta erats dna pots lla dna
nac I .steehs eht no gard seenk yM
,em rof sehtolc emos rehtegot elgnarw ot eganam srevird thgierf ehT .pu dewohs I dna
.mih nioj I regae os smees eh taht trofmoc elttil a leef I dna
,esolc elttil a s'eH
.denigami reve d'I gnihtyna naht rethgirb gninrub
.gnizama saw tahT"
.ssensuoicsnoc ym si em fo stsixe taht gniht ylno eht dna smota fo snoillirt nopu snoillirt otni tilps neeb ev'I
.ecnetsixe ot erom ecno
,em ot kcab gnihsur semoc tI
.moor eht setanimulli noom eht fo wolg milg eht tub ,sthgil on s’erehT
.ylgnirussaer ,syas eh ",redlo elttil
.tseisae eht eb dluow eno siht gnikniht
,stsiwt dna eldnah eht sbarg eh erofeb
meht wollof I dna
,ylbmud mih ta pu erats I dna tuoba gniklat s'eh tahw erus ton m'I
.oot si sih wonk I dna ,gnihcaorppa ylkciuq si xamilc yM
em rof gnitiaw sDVD emina fo kcats a s'erehT
,seye ym ot teg I nehW
dna taert nac I ohw kcip ot edam ma I dna ,ffats trohs ,sdeb trohs er'eW
.neet suoitcnubmar eht etiuq otni worg I
.ecaf sih ffo meht ekat ot ydaer ,mialcxe I "!yeH"
,flow eht ot gnihtemos syas xof ehT !tiaw tub
.moor eht fo krad eht ni gniremmihs
.tsaf oot gnineppah s'ti dna ,esolc em gnitteg s'eH
.em ot gninrut ton
.kcen sih fo kcab eht ta
,xof a hcaorppa I
.llew os ffo ti gnillup t'nsaw eh fi
hteet ym si drawer siH
egnar gniweiv ni ylefas m'I litnu tsap zziw srats dna stenalP
,em ot raelc os si htap ehT
.gnos ym ni dnuora gnicnarp trats dna rab eht no pmuj I sa duol gnireehc dna sdnah rieht gnippalc ,gnola wollof nemow dna
.kcab evom ot sgel ym teg t'nac I tub
.ytilaer fo senalp eht neewteb thguac m'I ,niagA
.stnaw eh eno eht m’I
,gnihT dliW eht s'eH
,ylduol gninaom s'eH
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
?noitnetta fo retnec eht gnieb
ksid noitarelecca eht ees nac I
.sthguoht ym hguorht kniht ot gniyrt ,yas I ",wonk ylno d'I
,daeh ym ni gnilttes wolgretfa eht s'ti ebyaM
,meht sa dna htiw evil ot evah I ,daetsnI
,spih ym tsniaga swap ym palc I ".gnirob
.em edisni eslup sti llif llits nac I ,hcamots ym fo mottob eht ta gnittis nevE
.sthgil neerg dna ,wolley ,eulb ,egnaro ,der ni
.laer eb ot egral oot mees yeht dna
laiceps vt yretsym devlosnu na si
.em sdrawot strats eh sa
.yldrawkwa sredluohs ym gnillor
.elzzum s’enipluv eht no raef eht ezingocer I tub
”gnihT dliW“ fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
.tnerruc a tsniaga gnimmiws sthguoht ym leef I dna
.ti ees yllanif I dna
.teknalb a ni ecnetsixe ym sparw
.txen od llahs I tahw dna
.tnedifnoc s'eh dna naretev a ebyam ,nam redlo na s'eH
.em rof erutnevda hguone naht erom si sevil enasni rieht evil meht gnihctaW
don a sevig ylno eH
.tnenoppo txen eht rof kool I dna
.lessev ym regnol on si ydob ym taht tnerappa semoceb tI
,der dna ,egnaro ,nrubua ,etihw ,yarg ,ruf elbram siH
.dnal ot tops a dnif dna
.tnaw I eloh kcalb eht ees I litnu esrevinu eht ssorca sraey-thgil fo snoillim tohs m'I dna
.ecaps fo ssecer eht ni rehtegot kcab flesym tup I ,skcolb gnidliub htiw dlihc a ekiL
.daeh ym ekahs I dna ,saw werc ym erehw ro gnitolip m’I pihsecaps hcihw em sksa eH
pis a ekat dna ,elzzum ym ot pu wap ym ni knird eht gnirb I ,revocer ot gniyrT
,em ot doog neeb s'efiL
uoy dluow ,zeeJ .dnim ruoy gnidaer ton m'I dnA—" ?eh sI ".rehtie
.gnineppah eb tonnac sihT
steehs eht otno knups sih fo tsom gnipiw
.gnitadimitni s'ti dna elzzum sih ot kcuts si krims A
ot flesym tniop I ,oS
.enoyna htiw ni emac I fi ees ot gniyrt ,ecnartne eht sdrawot skool eh nehT
,llip derolocitlum a s'tI
,dnim ot semoc taht gniht ylno eht yas I
.taht mih llet t'ndid I erus m'I hguoht ,eman ym s'ti kniht I dna
ylerab tsuj ot eganam I
.setadpu erutuf rof
.niaga hsats lanosrep s'yllaS hguorht gniog neeb s'enoemoS"
.emit siht em s'ti dnA .erom ecno ma I
.em fo tnorf ni gnidlofnu si ynitseD
,etoyoCtriD yb ”gnihT dliW“
,elzzum sih otni puc eht gnippit elihw
,rab ecaps a ti llac yllautca t’nod yehT
,gnihtemos yas tsael ta dluohs I ,llitS
surohc ym ot gnola sgnis dworc elohw ehT
,eno emoceb sffuh dna stnap ruO
.taorht ym tsniaga llor ti leef I dna ,nwod ti teg ot flesym lliw ot evah
,sruoh wef a rof em sdloh
.nruter on fo tniop eht tih I sa tsuj
,tnemeriter otni dehsup m'I nehw neve dna
,em ni detseretni eb ot looc oot skool taht xof siht morf yawa repmacs
em fo retteb eht steg daeh yM
.niaga ees nac I litnu
,elbatrofmoc steg gnihT dliW ehT
yllautca s’tI .em ees I
em gnidloh gnihT dliW eht ees ot nrut I
.selkcuhc tsuj gnihT dliW eht tub
,od ot tahw fo eulc on dna smra on htiw tub
,dnoces a rof gnidnats tfel m'I
ot "eloh kcalb a ,woW"
I thguoht evah d'ohW
,denahpro tfel ma I ,sgnidliub gniredloms morf sesir ekoms sA
.steehs eht barg ot gnilbmarcs tfel m'I dna
.mih ot resolc hcni I sa spih sih sbarg rehto eht
.ylbidua nwod diuqil eht gnilzzug
.nworf a otni gnitsiwt si elzzum ym sa tsuj ,ecaf sih no deppals krims yls a tog s'eH !em
,snaom sih ni gnihtemos tuo sllac eH
.ecnetsixe morf meht dellup evah ot em rof ylno
.gnihT dliW eht ot kcab nward si elzzum ym dna ediced I
.tsiaw ym dnuora delruc liat ym htiw enola gnidnats dna ezoob gnippis eb annog tsuj saw I fi
s'erehT .ti swonk enoyreve
,ereh teg ot yenruoj ym nialpxe I sa sknird em ssap yehT
.ecaps ni ssensuoicsnoc erem sa gnitaolf ,diov eht fo pota gnittis m’I
evisserppo elttil a semoceb kool siH
eht dna kcoc ym tsniaga htrof dna kcab ward spil siH
.ereh gnitteg erofeb rotcetorp tekcop gnikcuf ym tuo koot I dalg tsuj m'I
,txen od ot tahw fo kniht nac I erofeB .luos ym sllif daerd dna ,em revo sehsaw yltnatsni oobat ehT
.sedisni s'xof rehto eht otni
.noitativni eht dnicser ot demahsa oot tlef dna
.pil ym gnilbbin ot kcab ylsseltneler si eh
.rebos m'I yas dna elkcuhc I dna ,knurd ro hgih
,semit eerht ,eciwt
,no m'I tahw sksa eH
gnittif-lli sa debircsed eb dluoc ti taht
.tfel ot thgir morf liat sih skcilf dna
.mra ym fo dloh sbarg wap a
.ediskcab sih tuo
s'erehT .eugnot ym no muh
.dias reve ev\’I gniht tsebmud eht ton s’ti ,ti tuoba kniht I nehw dna ".gnizama
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
llaf ym skaerb em htaenrednu sserttam a fo kaeuqs tfos ehT
.nisuoc ym dekcuf tsuj I
,repsihw a ni tuo tel I ",iH"
.sseworp ym ni gnilever m'I
.saedi neewteb selim gniklaw ekil sleef
dam eb ot mees t'nseod eh
tsuj m'I ,llew—m'I dna
,evah I taht seye eulb latsyrc emas eht ,gnicreip era seye siH
,hguone duol tsuj ,kcab syas dna krims emas taht speek eH "!olleH"
,edalb ym fo epiws eht yb seid eH
,esoh a ekil gnikael s’eH
.sdneirf ym dna sdiamrab eht sserpmi ot gnihtynA
a tsuJ .uoy m'I ,haeY"
,em dloh mih tel I
.dehsaba tib a leef dna
,esahp a hguorht gniog si buc raeb yranib-non elttil siht kniht stnerap yM
.mih revo pmuls I dna
,emit tsrif eht rof enim morf sevom
.ot deen t'nod I tub ,mih ees ylerab
ydob a tuohtiw tuB
em sllet kool gums siH
,sehtolc ym barg
.elyts yggod ssa sih gnikcuf
.meht neewteb gnilbmuts yldrawkwa tfel m'I
rewop dna noitcurtsed war ehT
.egde eht revo gnilgnad sgel ym htiw tser I dna
.stops evitisnes ym revo yltcefrep senil ni gniggid
.foorp yna gnideen ton ,ksa I "?woH"
,drows ym esiar I
,goD fo ecioV ehT no derutaef yrots siH
.deb a sdrawot su sllup eh sa flesym ydaets ot mih gnidloh
.spetstoof sih sa tnelis sa gninepo rood eht
,edis eht ot elttil a tfihs I
,mih revo nael ylevitcnitsni I
ereh emoc neve I did yhW
eno eht ma ,enola em
.elzzum ym fo egdirb eht ffo sessalg eht sehctans eh
esle enoemos rof em kootsim erah a nehw egelloc ym ta airetefac eht ni gnittis neeb tsuj d'I
.daeh ym ni gnitaolf llits niarb ym
,deb eht no kcab ym htiW .ruf sih dna
.eloh kcalb a tsuj s'ti tub
,syas tekcaj mined a ni raob a tub ,dworc eht ni emos skcohs ecneserp yM
.eloh kcalb a ees ot si fo kniht I gniht tsrif eht ,krod a ekil dnA
.ti gnikam nuf fo tol a dah I .sknahT"
,nur ton fi ,ffo kaens ylbissop
.os kniht I ,tsael tA
.teef sih ot sdnats dna kcoc ym ffo spil sih sllup eh ,hguoht nac I erofeB .gnihtyna
.dniw ekil stseug rehto eht neewteb gniwolf
.nwod em sdloh dna tsehc ym no sdnal wap a tub
.em dael ot stnaw eh egassap krad eht nwod ,mih revo reep I
,srobhgien gnidiar eseht tsniaga modgnik ym rof thgif ot deksa ma I
em rebmemer I tuB
,sgnidnuorrus ym evresbo I
,em ta serats eh sa seye sih ni sgnah kool dezad A
.thgirla m'I fi em sksa dna wap a pu sdloh tsuj
.emoceb ev'I tahw tsuj ezilaer I
,hturt eht taht si ylno ton esuaceb
.ylevissimsid syas eh
.gniwollof eb ot desoppus m'I ezilaer I od
,duorp s'eH .eb ot mih denigami I rellik eht
,eb lliw ro saw ro ma I tahw rebmemer ot gnipsarg ,drah yrt I
.diputs sdnuos taht tub ,em rof saw ti sa mih rof doog sa saw ti fi ksa ot stnaw em fo traP
,txen od ot gniog m'I tahw swonk eh
!siht eb ot tnaw t'nod I
.RE na fo elddim eht ni
,em ot detneserp ylluf si ediskcab siH
nuf siht eb dluoc ti em llet enoyna t'ndid yhW
.ma I ohw tsuj rednow dna gniliec eht ot pu erats I
,yrtnuoc eht revo lla em sworht margorp krap lanoitan eht hguohT.snoitareneg
em gniyzzid tsomla ,htrof dna kcaB
.detsevni si rab eht ni enoyreve dna
,liat gniwolf kciht sih fo hsiws eht htiw ylno dna
.evael ot emit saw ti dediced I dna eroc ym hguorht sefarts flesym ni regna dna tnemssarrabme fo hsalf neddus A
?looc gnihtyna od I t'nac yhW .nihc
.dehcaorppa gnihT dliW eht ohw
a nees ylno ev'I taht
.stes nus eht sa tsuj sraeppasid nnyW
.sehtolc ym rehtegot tup ot togrof ,spoO
.siht ta doog ma I
.esle enoemos rof t'nsi leef I edirp eht dna ,nnyW ,ailuJ
.ta gnikool s'eh tahw ekil ot smees eh tub ,desserdrednu leef I
.yhw nosaer a fo kniht t'nac I
.morf yawa gniklaw tfel m’I sesproc net s’ereht dna
.bmud eb d’taht esuac
si edisni leef I htmraw tahT
.spets egral ni mih ot pu hctac ot gniyrt
yllausac flesmih gnissimsid
,tuo hcaer I erofeB
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,snesool wap yM .)esuaceb ro(
.gniog s'eh erehw swonk eh ekil ,rood tsrif eht ekat t'nseod eH
smrow dna trid gnirehtag
.llihc dna kcab dial os smees tsuj eh
.mih ro em s'ti fi erus ton m'I dna
.em ta gnirats moor eht ssorca gnidnats xof elbram rehtonA
.elbarusaelp eb ot hguone kcils m'I taht wonk em stel rrup tfos A
,seye sih ni ,ti ees I dnA
a ta gniyrT ".ereht yeH"
.noitasrevnoc eht morf yawa seixalag ,tey dna ,esolc os m'I taht gnissarrabme s'tI
.ytrap siht ta ereh neeb evah t'ndluohs I  2 fo 1 traP
.sdeen ym yfsitas ot hguone s'ti dna
mih ees I dna ,dnim ot semoc xof elbram elttil A
.eye ym ot ti dloh dna wap sih morf ti kculp I ".ti htrow s'tI"
.ytrap eht fo esion eht revo ylduol tuo gninaom morf flesym peek ot od nac I lla s'ti dna ,tirg era hteet yM
esrevinu eht ot nrut neht dna
.noitats eritne eht sekahs ti ,duol os esualppa na htiw tem ma dna enola senil tsal eht taeper I ,dne eht tA
.no ti gnikcilf dna em ot txen
,noom eht no era seye esohw ,amgiS dna
.smrod eht ni ecalp ym ot kcab teg dna
:ecin si kniht I tahw ,tsael ta ,sehtolc ecin emos no tup I ,tuB
.ssik a otni em llup ot etatiseh t'nseod eh dna edisni pets I
,pu kcab flesym tsioh ot yrt I
.rehtona eno fo pot no meht gnikcats dna em ot eceip yb eceip gnillup fo sedaced wef a tsuj
,htrof dna kcab knird a sehsols eh sa mih ot gniklat ylraelc ,edis sih yb flow a s'ereht hguoht nevE
.gnihT dliW ehT emoceb ot
,thginot dworc llams a s'erehT
,flow laveidem eht ,samohT sa emit ym tuoba kniht I
.snortap eht htiw noitasrevnoc llams ot nrut I dna
ecaps ni gnitaolf eb ot sneppah taht rab a tsuj s'tI
.nisuoc nwo sih ot ytinigriv sih esol yltnedicca yletul-gnikcuf-osba dluow em ekil toidi na ,esruoc fO
,hguor oot eb thgim siht dnoces a rof deirrow m'I
:noitseuq erom eno ylno tog ev'I
:siht uoy llet ll'I tub
.erom hcum os s'eh ,em ot ralimis skool xof elbram rehto eht hguoht dna
retsaf mih gnipmup ,tfahs sih dnuora wap ym nethgit I
.yawa ylsselmia dekcik era dna ffo emoc stnap ym
regnol on ;yrgna dna ytpme regnol on ,em ni samohT leef I
nem ehT .esrev tsrif eht gnitrats elihw taeb eht gnittes ,toof ym pmots dna ssalg ym pmuht I .dworc eht delir yllaer taht gnas samohT gnos a ta kcab kniht I ,metsys ym ni lohocla eht htiW .hcus sa
,esnes ekam t'nseod sihT
ym revo elbbird ot ti fo tsom rof ylno
.nnyW eman eht flesym evig I ,gnuoy ma I nehW
.gnizama ooT .detcelloc dna mlac oot
,eloh sih tsniaga kcirp ym fo pit eht hcuot I
hgis a tuo tel I
.ta gnikool s'eh em s'ti niatrec rof wonk I dna
.niaga trapa sllaf ytilaer dna
.llew sa em rof serac ti wonk I od ,ydob sti fo neerg dna ,wolley ,eulb ,egnaro ,der eht ,srewolf eht ,seert eht nI
,levon a gnitirw si
gnikael si dees ym ,hcum os pu mih dellif I taht ssenerus a s'erehT
ylsuoicsnoc I .wollaws ot etatiseh I dna
,duol oot yas I ,em raeh t'nac ylbaborp eh gnizilaer neht dna
.no dnats ot gnihtemos rof kool I dna ,tuoba nworht si ssensuoicsnoc yM
.demlehwrevo yletaidemmi si latipsoh eht dna
.mih eciton I nehw s'tahT
,liatkcoc a flesmih gnixif tsuj s'eH
.flesti ecaps fo tniop-orez eht htaeneb aera eht tub ,retaw fo naeco na ton s'tI
,yas I ,ssenlooc sih etatimi ot gniyrt ,oS .enola sisomso
.llah eht gnillif smaercs fo snezod eht revo mih dnatsrednu ylerab nac I
,sehsinif eh litnu
gnihtyna naht erom ti evol I .erutaN
seciov raeh I dna
.noynac a fo dne eht ta thgir stes nus eht erehw yellav neerg a no elttes yllanif I
.nwo sih teg ot elbat knird eht morf yawa evom ot em rof gnitiaw ,em gnieye eb dluoc eH
ot dnoces a gnikat
eugnot tew mraw A !tsaf tsuJ
.ssadab ytterp sdnuos osla ti tub
.ylimaf ym htiw sdleif eht dnet I dna
.gniod eb ot desoppus m’I tahw won ezilaer I dna
.em revo hsaw snaom nwo sih fo htaerb mraw
,elpoep gnipleh ekil I
,tey dna ,eugael ym fo tuo os s’eH
.roolf eht tih ot tuoba m'I gniraef elzzum ym sepacse epiy deirrow a
eno siht piks esaelp
,noitatsefinam lacisyhp yna ro
.edisni flesym tsefinam ot
.dees ym htiw mutcer sih gninil
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.htaenrednu gnihT dliW siht gnimat
.enips ym pu srevihs gnidnes htmraw eht
,naeco eht ni niaga dessot ma I
,tops ym sekat eh dna deb eht ffo m'I
?rellik a eb dluoc
rekcuf rehtom uoy ,ho"
.erofeb semit derdnuh
.em fo tuo tihs eht gniyonna kool gums taht
msitamgitsa thgils eht ees nac I
.em hcaorppa ot rab eht ta taes sih morf sdnats nam gib eht dna ,shgual enoyrevE ".niaga
s’rehcaet loohcs yratnemele sih ni tup ot
,sniatnuom eht pu ekih tsal eno ekat I .ybesolc yats I
.ytefas ot em ekat ll'taht
.kcab gnihtyna dias t'nsah eH
.yawa sklaw dna yawllah eht ot snrut eh ,drow rehtona tuohtiW ".eruS"
.hcum oot elttil a noitnetta eht
.flesym fo duorp ylralucitrap gnileef m'I tub
.gniwollof m’I erus ekam ot kcab snrut eye elgnis a esuaceb ,wonk I
,efil ym tuohguorht lla skcits ti tub
.enim tsniaga spil sih secrof eh sa ti gnihcterts ,trihs ym fo ralloc eht no era swap sih fo htoB
rettiwT no etoyoCtriD ta mih dniF
dna ni tif t'nseod xof elbram sihT
.em rof wap a gnidnetxe ,syas eh
.ti ekat ot desoppus m’I wonk I dna ,em ot ti gnireffo s'eH
eno eht saw I woh gninoitseuq
,rettiwt no elbuort fo stros lla gnisuac ton s’eh nehw ,ohw ,etoyoC triD yb
rab ecaps a dnif I dna
,evael tsuj ot ydaer m'I
",dnoces a rof nwod elttes tsuj
.sevil emos evas ot ydaer m'I dna ,RE eht ni em tup yehT
ylleb ym no ruf eht htaenrednu yllausnes gnicart swalc eht tub
neerg dna ,wolley ,eulb ,egnaro ,der ni setaidar tI
strohs ograc dna
.od nac I tahw gniees ydaerla
.ti tpecca ot nrael yeht dna
.ti detnaw reve d'I sa hguor sa yltcaxe s’ti em sllet
,yawa selim noillim nezod
,em ecaf ot revo snrut eh nehw s'tahT ".flesruoy
.deb eht dna ruf ym gnirevoc erp
.sthgil gnitfihs eht htiw
.sdap sih no gnittis ti ees I dna
.erofeb naht rediw kcab gnillup si elzzum sih tub
ezag sih sa esuap a s'erehT ".ti
.ffo meht ekat em tel naht rehtar sehtolc ym derhs tsuj thgim eh taht dnoces a rof deirrow m'I dna ,cirbaf eht ta raet swalc siH
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
rood tnorf eht ot kcab kool I nehT
.mih ton s'ti tub
,ereh fo tuo kcuf eht teg
.yltneitap wap a no daeh sih gnitser
nwod selttes rab ehT
.yenruoj ym fo tser eht
.yldalg os od I dna
.thgir t'nsi sihT
stfihs yllaudarg moor ehT
.gnihton otni ylknalb gnirats
,retressid a delebal si dna
hsup dna llup hcaE
,erofeb siht enod reven ev'I
.ni tsixe I diov eht hguorht sgnilf ssensuoicsnoc ym sa em no tsol si flesti emiT
,wap eerf ym htiW
,deifirret s'eH .em ekil yob a
.retrofmoc eht otni peed kcab daeh ym nael I dna
,samohT sa ,sedart lla fo flow a ,traH ydrA morf pleh htiw
,em ta gnikool ton s'eH ".nisuoc ruoy
,ecno ,mih tsniaga tonk ym kconk I
,ylhsipeehs don dna setavirp ym revo liat ym kcilf I
.gnir sih tsap hsup ot hguone t'nsi tips eht tub
.mih pleh ot em sgeb dna mra ym sbarg ,ruf degnis sih rednu elbazingocer ylerab
,si dnim ot semoc taht gniht ylno eht dna
,I ezilaer I sa em sepolevne edirp fo esnes A
gniwollof ezag sih
ruf eht otni gniknis
,ksa I "?erus uoy erA"
denigami dna ,if-ics htiw detanicsaf neeb syawla d'I
,llub A .t'nac I ohw
enod ev'I tahw rednop I ,ssengnihton ni gnitaolf xof elbram a sA
.ylduol ffo sessa rieht gnihgual dna gnikoj ,em ot txen gnidnats tsuj syug fo puorg a
,ecafrus eht ot selbbub ekil pu esir yehT
,syas dna selkcuhc gnihT dliW ehT
,noitcerid rehtona
.rotcod a ton m'I
.esle gnihtemos saw I…ma I
,strohs ikahk sih fo tsom gnirevoc ,gnol os s'tI .sredluohs sih ffo gnignah ylerab s'taht pot knat gnittif esool a no tog s'eH