”?ereht tuo og ot tnaw d’uoy kniht uoy od
.syad esoht ni kcab suoregnad erew sgnihT“
.smotpmys reh eganam ot dengised gnihtemos htiw reh detaert dah srotcod ehT
,nevahdloC rof emoh rieht delf dah ylimaf reh nehw lrig elttil a neeb ylno dah ehs tub
,stluda redlo eht fo tsom gnoma nommoc saw roivaheb ehT
,ecracs emaceb dooF
.ti fo raelc ylluf eb reve ot ytic eht rof elbissopmi ti edam thgualsno tnatsnoc eht
,timda ll’I ,ylekilnu s’tI“  .sdnah denettim sih pu dleh ekiM  .deerga eoJ
.tnenopmoc degamad eht gnivomer tuoba tes dna lenap eht denepo eh ,sloot sih tuo gnilluP
.ytic eht fo egde eht dnoyeb s’tahw tuo dnif reven ew ebyaM
”?uoy dluow ,loot taht em dnaH“
,sreviR neruaL yb
.don mrif a htiw deerga eoJ
.secnatsmucric lla dna yna rednu kcolc eht dnuor gninrub ti peek ot boj rieht saw tI
”,sedaced ruof ni enoyna morf draeh t’nevah ew ,dah yeht fI“
.reh no pu evig reven dluow eh sseldrageR
”?ti ekam ot gniog er’ew kniht uoy oD“
.desuap eH  ”.hguone eurT“
.tsol dah yeht lla llacer ot lufniap oot ylpmis saw ti ebyam rO
seirots reh fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,dluoc uoy fI“  .dias eoJ
”,meht tuohtiw ti edam evah t’ndluow eW
,ytefas fo eetnaraug a snaem on yb saw tI
.tlem ton did yeht emit siht dna
,soidutS ecnecsedirI yb nooM eulB fo rohtua
,noitarud ni erom ro keew a netfo syenruoj rieht dna detimil saw deeps riehT
”.dlrow dlo eht fo tfel s’tahw ees ot tnaw d’I erus ton m’I emit emas eht ta tub
.lavivrus ni dia dluoc taht gnihtyna dna ,seilppus ,doof saw ytiroirp riehT
.desoppus eh ,rettam t’ndid ton ro eurt saw ti rehtehW
.sraey rof smaerd sih dellif dna noitanigami sih deleuf dah buc gnuoy a sa dessentiw dah ehs sgniht fo seirots reH
.retsasid larutan fo tros emos saw ti detseggus dah seiroeht ylraE
nosaer rehto emos ro egnar fo tuo raf oot ylpmis erew yeht esuaceb saw ti rehtehW
ytic eht fo egde eht dnoyeb ssap dluow ti stnemom wef a nI
.oga emit gnol a srovivrus rof gnikool neve desaec dah smaet noollab eht fo tsoM
.aedi tsethgils eht t’nevah I“
,pils gnihtemos tel dluow ehs emit ot emit morF
nevahdloC ni efil ot laitnesse rewop dna taeh eht deirrac sepip eht ,selim rof gnihctertS
nevahdloC fo syad ylrae eht ni ylralucitrap ,yrartnoc eht ot ecnedive on etipseD
.yrujni fo ksir tnacifingis ssel hcum a htiw krow ydaets saw ti tub
.lavivrus rof thgif etarepsed a ot yaw evag ylkciuq seiroehT
.tseb ta citamelborp saw lavivruS
,wons eht otni teef debbew sih desserp niugnep gnik ehT
smetsys gnitaeh rieht demlehwrevo dah dloc emertxe eht sa
.gnir retuo eht sdrawot deklaw yeht rehtegot dna
.saw ti sa hcus ,gnivirht dna evila ytic eht tpek dah reh erofeb tsop eht dleh ohw esoht dna ehs
.rewop fo tol a dah sgniht esoht thguoht elpoep neht kcaB
,derrucco retsasid eht nehw gnuoy yrev neeb dah rehtom sih ,deednI
.flesreh ronrevog eht yb boj sih nevig eb dluow nezitic gnuoy a nehw
,dlrow siht ni gnihtyna evreserp ot si ti drah woh nevig dna ti tnaw uoy dnif yam uoy yad eno ,sediseB
.trofmoc werc rof ssel dna ograc dna taeh ot detoved ecaps erom htiw
”?ereht tuo s’tahw tuoba rednow reve uoY“
.deggurhs ekiM .deksa eoJ
.noitseuq eht yb desirprus ylraelc ,daeh sih detlit ekiM
.dehgis niugnep gnik ehT
”.won ti no krow ot su rof hguone looc eb dluohs buh eht ,yawyna ,lleW“
,delevart yeht tuo raf woh rettam oN
.rentrap sih deksa eoJ
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
”,detrats dah ti erehw ro woh wenk eno on dna wons eht ni thguac erew yehT
,swonk ohw dnA“  ”.esoppus I ,haeY“
”.pohskrow eht ot ydenneK“
.tfird wons a ekil seiromem eht gniyrub
.ti nees dah taht esoht htiw gnola tsol saw deneppah tahw fo hturt eht ,sgniht ynam ekil tub
syad esoht ni tub
,snoitcerid lla ni noziroh eht dnoyeb delevart yeht nevahdloC revo thgis raluger A
.tinu eritne eht morf taeh eht gnitcerider saw pets tsrif eht ,sriaper tcudnoc dluoc yeht erofeB
,ereh thgir tuoba yrrow ot sgniht hguone evah I  .oN“
.lennahc desolc eht ot dias eoJ
”,ot desu yeht naht rehtruf tol a levart nac yehT
”?ereht tuo si kniht uoy od tahw neht ,llA tI wonK retsiM ,thgir llA“
,seirtsudni suoirav s’ytic eht fo sdnamed eht no tnedneped ylegral saw siht did ehs hcihw ta etar eht elihW
.sriaper rieht detelpmoc neve d’yeht erofeb demrofer eb dluow ti taht wenk eh ,yawa eno dekcik eh emit yrevE
.ytic eht fo egde eht edistuo efil fo ngis yna nees dah nevahdloC ecnis sedaced neeb dah tI
.ytic eht ni dnuof eb ot enon saw erehT
,nevahdloC fo elpoep eht rof doof edivorp ot elbissop sa meht fo ynam sa detavitluc dah yeht seiceps gnivivrus wef eht gnitcetorP
.dah yeht ecruoser evitcepser hcae fo hcum woh wenk tnemnrevog ytic eht ni esoht ylno ,sselehtreveN
,mlap sih tuo dleh ekiM
,sevisolpxe htiw ni yaw rieht decrof dah enoemos syad lanif eht gnirud tbuod oN
,erus rof wonk ew litnu tuB
”.taht evivrus ot dah ereht tuo erehwemos enoemoS
.desolc lennahc ehT
.elbazingocernu tsomla saw epacsdnal eht peed os eci dna wons ni derevoc sdleif neerg ecno htiw ,sselesu erew spam eht esruoc fO
.eoJ ediseb taes a koot eH
.deksa eh ”?repap yhW“
.buh maets eht desolc dna riaper eht dehsinif ekiM
.htaed dna efil neewteb ecnereffid eht naem dluoc gninraw syad wef a nehw syad ni gnimoc saw tahw dna
.ti daer ot hguone raelc saw ti siht ekil yad a no dna
:ereh yrots ruoy etsap dna ypoC  sreviR neruaL yb
”.ereht tuo yksir s’ti noitnem ot toN
.suorehcaert erom neve saw ti ereht tuO
.gnipoh deppots ecnis gnol dah elpoep tsom
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.ytic gnilggurts eht rof ecnereffid a hcus ekam dluow ti did yeht fi ,tey dnA
.neht ecnis srovivrus rehto yna deretnuocne ton dah yeht
,ytic eht ni esle enoyna naht ereht tuo saw tahw tuoba erom wenk smaet noollab eht taht eurt saw ti elihW
”?eciohc on dah I fi ekil naem uoY“
.lla ta siht erofeb dlrow a saw ereht tegrof ot hsiw ot demees ohw
.dednamed noitalupop eht ygrene dna stcudorp eht ecudorp ot desu elpoep sdohtem eht kcab elacs ot detpmetta elpoep sa dlrow eht dnuora depoleved dah stsetorp retsasid eht erofeB
”,ecnanetniam reporp eht rof elihw a ni ecno yreve nwod meht tuhs dluow yeht fi reisae tol a ti ekam dluow ti tub ,seY“
”.noos rotces rehtona ot no gnivom er’yeht raeh I“
,elbadart saw ti thguoht yeht fi dnuof yeht tahw kcab gnirb dluow yehT
.elzzum sih derewol eoJ
”?t’nsah ohw ,emit ot emit morf ti tuoba derednow ev’I ,timda ll’I“
”.emit eht lla ereht tuo og yehT“  .mraw oot llitS
,ytisnetni sti ni sseltneleR
,eruc a neeb dah ereht
.og dluohs eh thguoht rehtaf ym noitcerid emas eht daeh d’I sseug I
.niadsid emos htiw tnempiuqe fo eceip eht ta dekool eoJ ,hcnerw sih gnitfeH  .gninrom ralucitrap taht ereh tuo tnes neeb dah yeht nosaer eht saw eno siht ,esruoc fO
.dniheb tfel stnanmer eht morf rehtegot deceip tsom htiw
.deilper ekiM ”,ylsuoivbO“
syad lanif eht fo soahc eht ni tub sretlehs eht otni tel eb ot deggeb dah snezitic dekcinap ynaM
,nommoc erew smrotswons ,taht fo pot nO
,yltcerroc gnitarepo nehW
.elbissop sa noitalupop rieht fo hcum sa evas ot snalp ycnegreme detcane snoitaN
,evivrus ot elba eb reven dluow ehs dengissa saw ehs boj tahw rettam on tuB
teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.od dluoc eh elttil saw ereht ,elcarim a saw ereht sselnu teY
.eldnaC eht sdrawot gnirutseg ,dias ekiM
,noollab eht fo noitcerid eht ni pu dekool ekiM
,gnizeerf evoba gnisir syad wef htiW
.reh was eh emit yreve demraw eh
.snoitseuq erew tfel saw taht llA
yllacitamard deppord erutarepmet labolg ehT
.neeb dah eh ekil
.boj eht fo sdnamed lareneg dna ,snoitcnuflam ,stnedicca fo rebmun tnacifingis eht ot eud
”.wons fo sreyal sseltnuoc htaeneb deirub t’ndah eci eht gnihtyna
.reyal niht a ni gnihtyreve gnirevoc ecnatsbus etihw yredwop eht ta erats ot tnemom a gnikat
.ecnatsid eht ni rellams reve gniworg
.erofeb dlrow eht rebmemer ot hguone dlo neeb dah ehs tub
.ffuts eht htiw dellif ereht tuo secalp dnuof smaet eht fo emoS“  .deggurhs eH
.derit dna kaew yltnatsnoc tiebla
.sraey ytnewt naht erom ti gnikam srekrow wef htiw
,seirraH nomoloS yb uoy rof daer
.erots tnemtraped a dellac eb ot desu ni saw ti gnidliub eht taht em dlot eH
”.saw taht dlrow eht morf stcafitra nezorf naht erom gnihtyna dnuof t’nevah llits yeht dnA“ .dias eoJ
”etihW ehT dnoyeB
.doots yeht hcihw ni ytic eht ta derutseg eH
”.siht morf meht tcetorp dluoc ti thguoht ylbaborp neve emoS
.yruf sseltneler a htiw dlrow eht nopu nwod desserp dloc eht ,erew uoy ohw rettam oN
,suoiruc m’I  .wonk t’nod I“
tnemom gnol a rof desuap eoJ .deksa eh
ereht tuo dnaletsaw nezorf eht fo tser eht gninioj morf ytic eht gnipeek gniht ylno eht era sgniht eseht ,llew ,seY“
etarepsed rieht tsacdaorb saw od dluoc yeht lla strap yrassecen eht ecalper ot ytiliba on htiw dna
”,gnihtemos eb dluow tI“
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.nruter s’noitidepxe hcae retfa pu dehctans eb ot tsrif eht gnieb netfo
.mih fo tfel evah I lla s’ti tub
.su tsuj naht ereht tuo erom saw ereht eveileb ot desu syawla dad yM“  .deksa eh
.egamad eht gnitagitim saw laog ylno rieht noos
.sredro rof gnikool stinu yratilim neve semitemos ro
.tnemeerga sih dereffo sselehtreven eoJ tub ,yas ton dluoc eh
.thginrevo deraeppasid seirtnuoc elohW
gninetsil rof uoy knahT  .stsacdop ruoy
,lysaeW ,ytiniffaruF no
.tenalp eht depolevne taht mrots evissam eht evivrus ot
”.dehsinif t’nsaw I“
.retniw lauteprep eht tsniaga etauqedani erew stroffe rieht fo lla
,rewop dna taeh etareneg ot eldnaC eht tuohtiw taht nevig ylgnilliw os did tsom egral dna yB
.derewsna eh sa ylthgils gninepo kaeb sih ,sredluohs sih deggurhs ekiM
rewop sih ni gnihtyreve od dluow eh devil ehs sa gnol sA
”?ytic eht evael ot dah reve uoy fi od d’uoy kniht uoy od tahW“
.ytic evissam eht tuohguorht detuor gnieb erusserp fo slevel suoirav eht gnitacidni buh maets eht derevoc seguaG
.pord erutarepmet laitini eht gnirud ereht dna ereh thguac elpoep morf sllac ssertsid htiw dellif erew syad ylrae esoht fo tsoM
,etapissid ot emit fo tnuoma tnacifingis a ekat dluow sihT
”,ereht tnemugra oN“
.yllacirotehr ,deksa eh
dlrow eht fo tser eht yb stpmetta rehto fo srepsihw dna sromur llits erew ereht
.yfirev enola tel
.eb ot gniog syawla s’ti yaw eht si siht ebyaM“
,soahc daerpsediw
thgirb os saw tirips reh rof ,dereffus ehs wonk reven dluow uoy teY
,serusaemretnuoc rof hcraes ot detpmetta snoitan emoS
.owt uoy krow doog ,dootsrednU“
.hctaw tekcop sih htiw gninoitom ,dias eh
.redluohs s’dneirf sih no wap sih gnicalp ,dias eoJ
.wap detoob sih htiw wons fo dnuom a dekcik eoJ
,buh gnidneffo eht ot nwod ti worran ylno dluoc scitsongaid eht fo snoitatimil eht ,revewoH
,eciwt ro ecno reganeet a saw eh nehw ti tuoba reh deksa dah eH
”.gninrom ysae na rof hcum oS“  .dekrims eoJ
.egde s’ytic eht dnoyeb dnaletsaw nezorf eht sa sselefil dna dloc sa emoceb dluow nevahdloC
.maets otni detapissid dna sdnoces wef a retfa detlem tI
.ezeerF eht ot pu gnidael syad eht ni egatobas fo stca ot mitciv nellaf dah stnalp rewop dna seirotcaf wef a naht eroM
.ydnah ni emoc ll’ti nehw wonk reven uoY
.lennahc eht desolc neht eciov eninac ehT
,gnorts dna gnuoy eht naht rehto enoyna yb enod eb ton dluoc taht krow gnikaerb kcab ,drah saw tI
,smra sih ni reh gniyrrac sthgin ynam pu yats ot mih gnisuac
.etomer saw doohilekil eht emit taht lla retfa taht yned ton dluoc citpeks tnetsisni tsom eht neve ,revewoH
.setsaw nezorf tsav eht gnoma tuo snoitidepxe ylrae eht fo eno gnirud rehtaf sih tsol gnivah
.hcum ti tuoba kaeps ot ekil ton did ehs dna
:llafretniW“ saw sihT
.dias eoJ ”,egavlas rof gnihcraes ereht tuo tsuj er’yehT  .tsap eht rof gnikool ton er’yeht tub ,seY“
.no evil ot hguone saw tI
.rewsna sih deredisnoc ylsuoires eh sa
seitic rojam raen denoitisop erew meht fo ynaM
.erac dna noitarepo sti htiw degrahc esoht gnoma seicnacav llif ot dengissa eb ot dedeen elpoep netfo tsom
,noollab eht fo epahs gniraeppasid eht ta erom ecno derats eoJ
.neht kcab egnar rieht ni detimil erew snoollab eht tub ,eurT“
.ylyrd deilper eoJ
.emit siht lla retfa evila enoemos gnidnif fo doohilekil eht naht rewol neve ylbaborp erew erehwemos
.elbaraperri emoceb noos dluow ti tnemnorivne eht no tcapmi s’efil tneitnes ecuder ot stroffe tnacifingis tuohtiw taht detsisni dah ynaM
.erutarepmet tnerruc sti tset ot buh maets eht tsniaga wons emos dessot eH
.sllac lanoitidda on draeh dah yeht drawrof yad taht morf dna
.snoitseuq sih fo wef derewsna dna evisave erew sesnopser reh tub
”.siht sediseb ereht tuo gnihtemos saw ereht kniht ot desu syawla eH
strap ecalper ot ytiliba rieht taht gniton ,desum eoJ
.retsasid laitini eht evivrus ot deganam dah enoemos taht elbissopmi ton saw ti sselehtreveN
”?ereht tuo neerg gnihtemos dnuof yeht fi gnihtemos eb ti t’ndluoW“
.dnaletsaw nezorf eht otni erom ecno krabme dna
.ecafrus dehsilop eht no nrettap lufituaeb a htiw ,dlog saw tI
srekrow tnemecalper gnideen ylraluger ytilicaf eht htiw
.wap sih fo erutseg a htiw tniop eht dedecnoc eoJ
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.noitareneg ’stnerap sih ecnis nees ton dlrow eht tuoba ytisoiruc sih egludni ot ylno fi ,sgnireffo rieht esurep dluow eoJ emit ot emit morF
.egnahc etamilc gnisuac stroffe lairtsudni rieht dna yrutnec tsrif ytnewt ylrae eht demalb dah emoS
.deggurhs dna detseuqer sa did eoJ
,pu worg reh ees dna reh tcetorp ot
,ytic eht ni sboj suodrazah tsom eht fo eno eb ot nwonk dna
,sboj deulav erom eht fo eno ton saw tI
”…nehw ereht tuo saw tahw tuoba gnikniht deppots I“  .dehgis eH
,noollab eht etalfed dna dnuorg eht ot nwod rohcna saw od dluoc yeht llA
”,msimitpo ruoy ta peew I“
.dereffus ehs hcihw morf noitidnoc cinorhc eht emocrevo dluow ehs taht epoh tsniaga gnipoh
.rethgit taoc sih gnillup ,deerga niugnep ehT
retsasid eht retfa sraey xis saw langis dedrocer tsal ehT  .dias eoJ
”.repap fo pils yna naht erom htrow eb dluow taht ekil gnihtemos tub
.flesti niatsus ot yaw lanoitidda na htiw ytic eht dedivorp dna niatniam ot ysae erew yeht tub
”.41 gnidliub ni stinu gnitaeh eht fo eno htiw eussi na s’erehT
suoregnad saw tI
,did ohw enoyna ot noitacolla ecruoser rehgih yltnacifingis eht ot eud dereetnulov emos hguohT
enimreted ot tluciffid saw emit ni sretlehs eht ot teg ot deganam dah meht fo yna rehtehW
.stimil sti nihtiw emoh dna erutcurts yreve ot
”,ot no gnidloh htrow era sgniht emos
.evivrus ot stroffe etarepsed dna
.ti peek dluohs uoY“
.buc a saw ehs ecnis reh deugalp dah taht snedrub eht fo eerf eb dluow ehs yad eno ebyam dna
”.ti edam evah ot dah meht fo emos taht ezeerF eht erofeb ereht tuo elpoep eht lla htiw taht thguoht eH
”,oot uoy ot gninrom dooG“
”…ot naem t’ndid I  .nam ,yrros m’I  .tihs ,hO“
.stnatibahni sti dna ytic eht ot neppah thgim tahw swonk ohw ,os fi dna
.tiaw tub od ot elttil saw ereht neht litnu os
,yrartnoc eht ot ecnedive on htiW
.rettam rehtona saw ,wap rehto eht no ,rethguad siH
.ytic eht edisni sesuohneerg eht fo noitpecxe eht htiw tuo depiw tub lla neeb dah stnalP
,cinap gnisuac ecafrus eht ssorca erot smrots tneloiV
gnir laitnediser eht ni gnillewd tsedom a htiw emac ti tub
.troffe na hcus ni eulav yna ees yeht did ron
”,meht did ti doog fo tol taF
,dedeen yeht naht erom ylecracs netfo erew sdleiy rieht tub
,tnemom a rof desuap niugnep gnik ehT
,eb ot ti ekil dluow eoJ tahw reven saw ylppus eht elihW
.rettam ot desaec yrotirret dna ytilanoitan ekil sgniht sa llef sreirraB
”.naem I ,efil tneitneS“  .deksa eoJ
.ahplA 64 buh ta s’tI  .melborp eht dnuof ev’eW“
”.riaper dna esongaid nac ew os tinu eht nwod tuhs ot uoy deen eW
.tuo detniop ekiM
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.rehtaew digirf hcus ot demotsuccanu saera deirub dah wonS
,deddon eh dnah devolg sih fo hcuot thgil a htiW
.retnec ytic eht ta ecanruf evissam eht ot dengissa elpoep eht rof mret laiuqolloc eht saw maet nrub ehT
.emoh nruter ot secruoser hguone htiw mrots eht tuo edir ot gnipoh
”.eveileb ot drah elttil a sdnuoS“
.stfird wons eht ot tsol gnol dlrow a fo sciler nezorf saw dnuof yeht lla
,did eloC ronrevoG gnihtyreve htiw eerga syawla ton did eoJ hguohT
.rednow tub pleh ton dluoc eoJ ,llits teY
,yldas derrihc ekiM  ”.mih
.ees reven thgim eh gnihtemos fo smaerd naht erom elttil erew sgniht hcus ,won rof tuB
.dlrow eht dednuop taht smrots eht fo yruf eht yb demlehwrevo erew snoitidnoc rehtaew citamard hcus rof deraperp erew ohw esoht nevE
”.smaet noollab eht ksa syawla dluoc uoY“  .deggurhs ekiM ”.erofeb dlrow eht tuobA“
”.siht naht rehto gnihtemoS“
nepo os traeh reh dna
,erutan laitnesse ssel a fo smeti rof devreser syawla saw ecaps ograc eht fo tnuoma niatrec a ,revewoH
.mra eht no kcams a dneirf sih evag eH
,rehtom sih morf seceip dna stib denrael dah eoJ
.dias eh ”,nekorb s’tI“
.emit ot emit morf srovivrus dnif ot desu yeht snoitidepxe ylrae eht gniruD  .ebyaM“
,gurd eht tnarraw ot hguone hgih neeb dah maet ecnanetniam eht no noitisop siH
,was eh tahw wonk ot suoiruc si em fo trap ,gnorw em teg t’noD
.daD regdaB yldduC eht ,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR  .yrrufoS dna
ereht tuo gnivirht llits stnalp fo sddo ehT
.daeh sih koohs dna ti morf yawa dekool raeb ralop ehT
.ylno egavlas dna egavlas saw noissim rieht
,esu dluoc ew ecaps ,ecaps fo tol a pu sekat tI
.nwonk reve dah ti taht dloc lufrewop tsom eht fo ycrem eht ta flesti dnuof noitalupop eritne eht
.yks eht otni hcnual snoollab eht fo eno ees ot emit ni pu dekool dna etarc ybraen a no nwod tas eoJ
.owt rebmun saw eno ralucitrap sihT
,elpoep sti gnitcetorp fo elbapac regnol on saw tatibah eht
.wonk t’nod I“  .deddon eoJ
,gnola emoc ot mih rof derutseg ekiM
tnemom a rof derevoh noollab ehT
.sraey ytrof revo rof noitarepo tnatsnoc raen ni neeb sah tnempiuqe sihT“
.dedeen uoy revetahw teg ot repap fo spils elttil gniusrup fo ssensuoretsoperp eht dnatsrednu ot gniyrt
.tluciffid saw ti neht neve dna
,thgis eht yb decnartne yliratnemoM
,smeti ralupop erom eht gnoma erew gnihtolc dna ,syot ,skooB
”.stekcop rieht ni deirrac yeht repap fo seceip htiw siht ekil sgniht yub dna ereht og dluow elpoeP
”.gnitteg er’ew seruliaf metsys eht lla htiw yadot sdnuor ruo etelpmoc ot gniog er’ew woh ekil
.noitidnoc tnerruc reh ni deyats ehs fi ton
.dlrow taht fo srednow eht ot teg reve dluow eh sa esolc sa saw ti ,esruoc fO
.skeew ro syad koot srehto elihw stnemom ni ezorf seitic elohW
.snoitan depoleved tsom rof raey tsrif eht nihtiw despalloc erutcurtsarfni
”,strap eraps naht melborp reggib a evah ot gniog er’ew od ew fi tuB  .ebyaM“
.ytic eht ot nruter rieht litnu deriaper eb ton dluoc netfo metsys gnitaeh evitareponi na dna
.tsethgirb eht dna tseb eht dloh ot dednetni erew dna
,daeh sih koohs eoJ
.evas ot tnaem saw ti esoht htiw gnola deid yeht dna
.sretlehs ycnegreme mret gnol otni detrevnoc erew hcihw statibah dnuorgrednu lareves tliub setatS detinU ehT
”.sevlesruo rof ees lliw I dna uoy syad eseht fo eno ebyam
.noitanretsnoc fo prihc dlim a htiw tnempiuqe eht ta gnikool
ereht tuo saw tahw rof egdelwonk laitnesse dedivorp smaet noollab ehT
.maerd s’rehtaf ym saw ereht tuO
,waptsrif ti nees dah ohw elpoep eht fo tsom dellik retsasid ehT
.ruof fo ylimaf a ot pu rof doof dna
.tser eht fo tsom nekat dah retfa sraey hsrah eht dna
,seruliaf tnempiuqe lacitirc gnivah sa dedrocer neeb dah srehto lareveS
.daD regdaB yldduC eht
”.pu gnivig staeb ti tub ,gnihton s’ereht era sddO“
,derevocsid yeht secalp eht tuoba em llet d’eH
.deggurhs eh tnemom a retfA
.buh maets eht ta detniop eoJ
.hctaw llams a tuo dellup dna tekcop sih otni dehcaer eH
”.gnol siht detsal s’ti dezama m’I
.noitalupop sti fo ytilibavivrus eht derusne yeht tatibah evissam eht fo aera yreve ni slavretni raluger ta decalP
.eldnaC eht sa yllaiuqolloc nwonk ecruos taeh lartnec a fo noitarepo eht no dedneped nevahdloC fo ytic ehT .deilper ekiM
,gnihton rof neeb dah ti tub
.dehgis dna oidar sih pu dekcip eoJ
”,esoht fo tuo nur ot gniog er’ew syad eseht fo eno ,wonk uoY“
.spam dlo emos dna snoollab fo riap a naht erom elttil htiw dnaletsaw eht trahc ot detpmetta dah yeht esu fo gnihtyna rof hcraes ot dengissa sregavlas fo tes raluger a dah yeht erofeb gnoL
.ylwols deddon ekiM
”.emos dah uoy erus ekam ot detnaw uoy ezeerF eht erofeb taht si wonk I llA
.nepo yawflah nwolb srood eht htiw ytilicaf hcus eno derevocsid dah smaet noollab eht fo enO
.dlrow eht ezorf revetahw htiw od ot gnihtemos dah yeht dias neve emoS
tekram eht ta dedart erew hcihw fo tsom
.retsasid eht erofeb dlrow eht fo seiretsym dna serusaert htiw gninruter
.daeh sih gnikahs nugeb ydaerla dah ekiM tub ,detrats eoJ
delaes eb ot elbanu rood eht htiw sa
nevahdloC  .ereh er’ew taht lufetarg m’I ,gnorw em teg t’noD“
.evila ytic eht tpek yeht tub ,haeY“
.ecafrus eht htaenrednu slennut fo krowten evissam a hguorht taeh ssecxe eht detuor ti sgnir retuo eht dehcaer ti taht erusne ot tub
ton ro suoires gnieb saw noinapmoc niugnep sih rehtehW
”.decalper eb ot sdeen rotaluger eht ekil skool tI“
.dias ekiM ”,wonk t’nod I“
,srebmun der dlob ni nibac eht fo edis eht no detniap saw reifitnedi ehT
.os kniht t’nod I ,oN“
,noitaucave lareneg a yb dniheb tfel neeb ro
.gniworg dna yhtlaeh meht peek ot noitnetta tnatsnoc deriuqer dna sesuohtoh rieht fo ezis eht yb detimil erew yeht tub
,pord erusserp eht fo ecruos eht deedni saw siht taht demrifnoc gnivaH
.noitseuq eht gniredisnoc
.ezeerF eht retfa dlrow eht ni dnif ot drah neeb dah ti tub
,yldliw deirav ezeerF eht erofeb dlrow eht fo seirotS
,snoitcnuflam ot enorp erew yeht
.t’nac tsuj I  .ti hguorht og ot traeh eht dah reven ev’I  .emoh ruo ni derots ffuts sih evah I“
”.oga emit gnol a ereht tuo no pu evag tsuj I sseug I  .yako s’tI“
”.rof thgif ot elpoep evah I sa gnol sa toN  .pu evig reven ll’I“
.detaerc dah ti taht retsasid eht devivrus ton dah noitamrofni eht ,esuac eht revetahW
.ees dluoc eye eht sa raf sa wons dna eci tub gnihton fo seirots htiw denruter maet retfa maeT
.ronrevog eht fo pihsredael gnorts eht dna
.yrots emas eht evah syawla d’yeht tub
,tneve rojam a sdrawot dedaeh saw eldnaC eht taht etacidni ot demees srekrow lanoitidda owt fo ssol eht
”,teg ot gniog s’ti sa doog sa si siht taht tcaf eht tpecca tsuj llew sa yam uoy os
.maet nocer eht fo srebmem ylrae eht fo eno neeb dah rehtaf s’ekiM
.nees d’eh sgniht eht fo seirots htiw ekawa em tpek dad ym
:llafretniW“   yojne esaelP
.ecno ta erehwyreve morf emoc ot demees dah ti tsom oT
”?uoY“  .esuap rehtonA
.evitisnesni ylbidercni tlef eoJ tnemom taht tA
.ylppus doof rieht htiw egde s’efink eht no gnicnalab yltnatsnoc elpoep eht gnivael
”.nekorb s’ti yhw tuo erugif ot si boj ruO“
.wons dna eci fo thgualsno tnatsnoc eht tsniaga od dluoc yeht elttil saw ereht raelc saw ti erofeb gnol ton saw ti dna
.deilper eciov eninac ffurg a ”,ereh pohskroW“
.lufesu esiwrehto ro ,elbariaper
.weiv fo tuo detarelecca ti sa noollab eht fo thgis gnihctac ,tnemom a rof desuap ekiM
,krow suoregnad saw tI
smetsys gniretaw dna gnitaeh eht fo egatnavda tseb ekat ot gnir laitnediser eht ni erew meht fo tsoM
,tnemngissa fo ega eht gnihcaorppa saw sacuL taht wenk eH
.ti devivrus ew tuB
.wons eht otni tuo pleh rof esaelp
.sregnif sih neewteb senarbmem eht no gnillaf sekalfwons
,repap fo dnik laiceps a saw ti dias eH  .neht kcab erar saw ti ebyaM“
.etaf taht morf nerdlihc sih eraps ot
.egavlas fo hcraes ni dnaletsaw ywons eht ot tuo yenruoj sti no ytic eht revo yllufecarg taolf tfarc llams eht dehctaw eh
yltnacifingis deppord lavivrus fo sddo eht taht tnaem ereht dengissa gnieb teY
.esle lla evoba ytic eht fo lavivrus eht ezitiroirp ot meht dlot dah pihsredael s’nevahdloC ,deednI
.yretsym a niamer dluow ti fo hcum demees ti
”.ereh tuo htaed ot ezeerf ot ynitsed ruo s’ti ebyaM  .wonk t’nod I“
”.hguoht suoiruc uoy ekam seod tI“
”.tuo pohskroW  .nwod
.secruoser laitnesse rehtag ot sdohtem wef eht fo eno saw ti
.rentrap sih ta dekool dna dekwauqs ekiM   .denialpmoc eoJ
.sraey ytrof revo rof efas su tpek sah
”?thgir ,gnihtemos rof tnuoc ot tog s’taht dnA
,ybab a saw ehs ecnis lli neeb dah ehS
.dlrow eht derevoc ew ezeerF eht erofeb tuB
,yas stnerap nwo reh draeh dah ehs sgniht ot gnirrefer
,kcihc a saw I nehW“  .deggurhs ekiM
.gnol os rof sdik eht dna aruaL evael ot tnaw t’ndluow I tub
.level niatrec a dnoyeb erutarepmet ro erusserp ni spord yna derotinom metsys eht tuohguorht tliub srosneS
”.keew tsal maet nrub eht no srekrow fo elpuoc rehtona tsol eW“
,retsasid eht gnirud niatbo ot elbissopmi tsomla emaceb swen sa
.dekwauqs niugnep gnik ehT ”?seno thgir eht evah uoy fi wonk uoy od woH“
,ega dlo saw ti spahreP
,smrots laitini eht ni deid noitalupop eht fo erom dna erom dna detnuom seitlausac sa tub
.eurt s’ti tub ,os ebyaM“
.gniR lairtsudnI eht ot tuo no daeH
looc morf setunim 54 evah uoY  .stinu gnidnuorrus eht ot maets eht gnituorer ,ydenneK ,dootsrednU“
.dedeen tsom erew yeht erehw secruoser yrassecen detubirtsid yeht
.noisiv rieht morf deraeppasid gnol won
.deggurhs ylpmis ohw ,niugnep gnik eht ta ssorca dekool eoJ
.eoJ ot denrut eH
.erolpxe ot thguos yeht hcihw dlrow wen eht fo ytilaer eht rof deraperpnu yletelpmoc smaet laitini eht htiw retsasid ni detluser tsomla nocer ta stpmetta tsrif eht ,deednI
”etihW ehT dnoyeB
.ytilibavivrus fo egnar eht nihtiw ytic eht peek ot htmraw hguone dedivorp ti ,ecanruf evissam A
,maet ecnanetniam eht nioj ot nesohc eb dna sessalc sih fo lla hguorht ti ekam daetsni dluow nos sih taht depoh eoJ
”.enilno kcab si ahplA 64 buH“  ”.ereh pohskroW“
,ekil neeb dah erofeb dlrow eht revetahW
.deliaf dah tnenopmoc cificeps hcihw ton
.noitisoppus fo rettam a neeb gnol dah ezeerF eht fo nigiro ehT .dias ekiM
,hcum oot gnitalumucca morf ti tpek sepip maets eht morf taeh eht hguohT
,ezeerF eht erofeb saw dlrow eht woh tuo dnif ot gnikool ton erew yeht tuB
.reffo ot eulav fo gnihtemos dah ohw enoyna ot
.ees dluoc eye eht sa raf sa dnuorg eht derevoc taht wons fo reyal eht ta dnuora gnikool ,dehgis eoJ
.ezorf dlrow eht nehw tol a tsol eW“
”.seno thgir eht dah uoy fi ,detnaw uoy revetahw rof ti edart dluoc uoy yldesoppuS  .wonk t’nod I“
.daeh sih koohs eh esuap trohs a retfA
.serusaemretnuoc regaem rieht gnimlehwrevo ro
elpoep reh fo stroffe denibmoc eht ot sknaht evivrus ot deganam syawla dah tub sllac esolc emos devivrus ytic ehT
esruoc ffo snoollab worht ot gninetaerht
,gnorts ylbanosaer dna evila reh peek ot hguone tsuj saw ti tub
.evila noitalupop rieht peek ot gniyrt yznerf etarepsed a otni seirtnuoc tsom gnidnes
nalp lavivrus nwo rieht mrof ot detpmetta dah ohw elpoeP
.deralced saw wal laitraM
”,rehtie ,ereh dnuora efas yltcaxe ton s’tI“
ereht tuo evivrus ot gniyrt neeb d’ohw enoemos dnif d’yeht neht dna won yrevE
,ytissecen sti etipsed
neht dnA“  ”.ti teg ot tsuj troffe fo stnuoma elbaveilebnu hguorht og dluow elpoep taht tub fo tuo skoob ekam dluow uoy epyt eht ton
”.uoy erew I fi htaerb ym dloh t’ndluow I“
”.pohskroW eht ot hsuR“
.htron eht ot erehwemos ecalp deirub flah a ni siht dnuof yeht dias eH“  .mlap debbew sih ni ti dleh dneirf niugnep sih sa sdnoces eht yawa dekcit ti ylteiuQ
”?ereht t’nsi ,ytilibissop eht syawla s’ereht
,sreviR neruaL yb
”etihW ehT dnoyeB :llafretniW“
,sepip maets eht no wons fo dnuom rehtona dessot ekiM
.evila yats ot gnilggurts elpoep etarepsed ot mitciv nellaf dah meht fo wef a naht erom
.esruoc sti detneiroer ti sa
.wons eht ta derutseg eH
,elbatrofmoc ylevitaler ytic eht fo eroc lartnec eht tpek taeh tnaidar elpmiS
”.smetsys gnitaeh eht tuo derugif yeht litnu noitidepxe yreve tsomla no deid smaet noollab eht flaH
ebolg eht fo hcni yreve gnirevoC
,ti rof elbisnopser neeb dah yeht detsisni sromuR
”?ti htiw od yeht dluow tahw
.ti tnaem eh dna ,dias eh
,draeh dah eh os ro
,ytic eht fo edistuo evila werc eht gnipeek dna taeh gnitareneg ta evitceffe hguohT
”.erom emos gniklat ekil leef I  .yaw gnol eht ekat s’teL  .no emoC“
depoh eoJ sselehtreven tuB
.ti fo hguone dah uoy fi gnihtyna od dluoc uoy thguoht elpoep siht lla erofeb tub ,taht eveileb I hcum woh wonk t’nod I
saw taht dlrow eht nI
.lla ta meht dias reven dah ehs tsisni dluow ehs emit eht fo tsom tub
.ereht tuo morf deveirter saw revetahw htiw gnola ytic eht dnuora secruoser larutan fo ylppus eht no tnedneped ylegral saw
.deen s’ytic eht teem ot hguone neeb syawla dah ereht raf os
,sledom tneiciffe ssel erew snoollab ylrae ehT