.leehw gnireets eht ot kcab detaerter neht
.flesti wons retniw eht sa lufituaeb dna lufrednow sa si nosaJ
?no gniog saw tahW ? . . . tahW
.tesolc sih otni tnemrag eht dessot eh sa redrah gnihsulb
.cirbaf eht tsniaga htaehs sih fo eglub thgils eht ta nwod kool ot ton deirt I
,sdnoces wef a ereht doots I
,elzzum sih otni ti deppop dna nrocpop fo lufwap llams a debbarg nosaJ
azzip fo secils ruo ffo dehsinif ew retfA
.dias I ",uoY .etaH .I"
.delims I   .dias evoD .srM
,strap ynnuf eht ta gnihgual
.niks detaeh ym no htaerb sih leef dluoc I
,tsiaw sih dnuora mra ym depparw I ti tuoba gnikniht tuohtiw dna
.nrocpop taht fo erom emos gnivah tuoba gnikniht tsuj pu gniyrd si wam yM
.tuoba gnihsarht liat ypor sih
.yawa gniklaw detrats dna moorhtab eht ot og ot flesmih desucxe eH
.dedne eivom eht woh tuoba dessip m'I tuB" .dennirg I ".ti
.deb eht no sknird dna doof eht gnicalp
.kaeuqs em edam eh nehw gnihgual tuo gnitsub dna
".3 esoR ehT rof stekcit owT
".tey netae t'nevah ew ,oN
.ecnelis eht gnikaerb ,dias nosaJ ",wonk uoY"
? . . . em gniddik uoy erA" .detarepsaxe
.mih ot pu ti dleh dna raet elgnis a yawa depiw I ".skrow
,em degguh dna revo dehcaer eH ". . . xof ylliS
.allevon a otni dehsilbup seirots sih fo eno teg ot gniyrt no gnikrow yltnerruc si eH
.nwod nrocpop detlas-revo ytsan eht tup dna dehgis I
.kcab delggig I dna delkcuhc nosaJ  ". . . taeh
gab mraw eht otni delgguns I
?thgirla gnihtyreve sI"
detlem dna ekorb slatsyrc etihw tfos elttil
.niaga daeh ym koohs I  ".taert ym s'tI"
.egarag eht otni gnillup
,eltneg eb nac selcsum deppir sih ekil sdniw hsrah eht . . . lufituaeb os
"!uoy sevol toggaf gnikcuf ehT"
.og uoy ereH" ,dias dna em ot meht dednah ehS
.efil ym ni no gniog erew taht sgniht eht tuoba thguoht I
,ecaf sih ssorca tes yrrow
.reverof rof tuoba demaerd ev'I tac eht gnissik
.htmraw rof esolc em gnidloh mih fo gnileef eht deyojne tsuj dna thguoht eht dessimsid I .dnim reven
,cisum gnicudorp ni selbbad osla eh ,gnitirw sediseB
.em taert syawla uoY"
.ecaps eht deipucco taht sehcuoc eht fo eno no dediser dad dna mom sih erehw
,rednow dnim ym gnitteL
.yltneg dennirg eH
,em ot doog tub gnihton neeb sah nosaJ
.meht ot tuo emac I nehw tuo em dekcik stnerap ym nehw neeb ro enod ev'dluow I tahw wonk t'nod I
sthguoht ym morf flesym dellup noos tub
,tnemssarrabme htiw der dehsulf skeehc yM
,rehtnap etihw eht htiw ereh gniyal ecin saw tI
.ecnayonna kcom ni smra ym gnissorc
,dias I ",yrros m'I"
,yawa dekool neht dna ,sdnoces elpuoc a rof mih ta derats I
esuac' ,yawa nar eh yhw ylbaborp s'tahT
.reeuq a ;toggaf a—
.gnileef eht wonk I"
,tuoba dekcilf liat siH
.dlrow laer eht ot kcab em thguorb edistuo llihc yci ehT
.no trihs ym tfel tub
.edisni peed degdol tonk gib a htiw gnillews taorht
did I emit emas eht knird ruo barg ot revo dehcaer nosaJ
",evah syawla I !?ko ,uoy evol I"
.em nevig dah nosaJ wollip eht no daeh ym detser dna
.yltnelis yrc ot detrats I ,lliw nwo ym tsniaga dnA
.ot drawrof dekool I stnemom eht era eseht taht
.delims dna em ta nwod dekool eH
.emit gnol a rof dneirf tseb ym neeb sah nosaJ
,waprevliS rennaT yb
.derepsihw eciov s'nosaJ "!maS"
?eivom eht saw woH"
.yawa wap sih gnittaws ,delley I "!yeH"
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.denrut dna yawa tsirw ym deknay I
.seye god yppup tseb ym mih evag dna rehtegot swap ym dleh I
. . . xof diputs ,diputS .flesym dekcik yllatnem I
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.evol tsol sih revo gniyrc retcarahc niam eht was I ,pu gnikooL .deil I ".
".raewrednu ym hcuot t'nod dnA"
.gniliec krad eht ta gnirats
,sdap-sregnif ym ffo tlas derettub eht dekcil I
.dehsulb dna yawa dekool I
,nwod ruop ot nageb wons sa dehctaw I
.em dnuora delbmurc dah dlrow elohw ym thguoht I nehw pu em kcip depleh eH
dias nosaJ ",ereh er'ew ,yeH"
,ekops I nehw elttil a depmuj eH  .deksa I
,eno egnaro ym drawot tuo hcaer ot detrats wap ywons siH
;derepsihw nosaJ "!?maS"
. . . ev'I .enif si gnihtyrevE" .deil I ",seY"
.srexob sih ni ydaerla ,gab gnipeels sih tuo dellup dah nosaJ denruter I nehw dna
.pots lluf a neht dna
"?maxe yrotsih taht no did uoy kniht uoy od woH"  .deilper I "?seY"
.ti devol I ,haeY"  "?ti ekil uoy diD
enigne eht fo muh eltneg eht yb ffo derednow evah tsum dnim ym tniop emos tA
,redluohs ym dehcuot wap siH
ekawa llits saw eh fi ees ot nosaJ ta dekool I eivom eht hguorht yawflaH
.rellik tsuj si rehtaew dloc eht tub ,gnihtyreve sekam retniw lufituaeb woh ekil yam I
,pis a koot I sa ylippah htrof dna kcab deppihw liat yM
,flesym ot delbmurg I ".em
traeh ym lla htiw uoy evol I"
.taht dias eh nehw erif no erew yeht ekil tlef skeehc ym woN   .dias eh
.azzip eht teg ot nehctik eht ot deirruh nosaJ "!moM sknahT"
"!buc a ton m'I !taht od t'noD"
".emit siht su rof yap em tel . . . esaelP"
.gnihtyreve dias seye sih tuB
.deksa nosaJ "?maS ,yeH"
.elims gnirussaer a mih evag dna deddon I
.elims em edam sihT
. . . mmM" .tnev eht tsniaga swap gnizeerf ym gnivohs dias I "!dog knaht ,hO"
.gnirons tfos sih raeh dluoc I noos dna
".uoy era oS .uoy knahT"
.dluohs I naht erom mih tuoba gnirac rof trid ekil leef I dna
,wam ym otni deppils eugnot sih noos dna ,enim dnuora deniwtretni dna
.dekrep srae ;kcab dennirg nosaJ
,derettuts nosaJ ". . . knaht-
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
.pmad saw ruf ym tlef I ,seye ym ot wap a gnisiaR
.em ot derettam taht gniht ylno eht saw uoy gnitcetorP
,wodniw eht no dednal ekalfwons elgnis a dna
.dias ehs ",ris olleH"
.tsalb lluf ot taeh eht denrut nosaJ nehw
!taht ekil em eracs t'noD"   .delbmum I ". . . hO"
".wohs eht yojnE
,ti pleh t’ndluoc I tuB
"?uoy pleh I nac woH"
.noitnetta yap t'ndluoc I taht yrrow hcum oot htiw dekcar saw dnim yM .t'ndluoc
llihc neddus eht ta em ot esolc tekcaj ym dellup I ,edistuo ecnO   .derumrum I ",kO"
".thgim tsuj I .em ot naem yllufwa gnieb si wonk I xof sihT
,taes ym morf esor flah I
.lortnoc fo tuo gniog erew yeht ekil tlef snoitome ym
"?ko er'uoy erus uoy erA"
.eybdoog devaw dna sknaht dias I
.tcejbus eht gnignahc ,dias nosaJ ". . . oS"
.tuo teg ot nosaJ rof detiaw dna moorhtab eht raen hcneb a no nwod tas I
".skcid era stnerap ruoY"
.tsirw ym deppirg ylthgil sregnif sih dna pu tog nosaJ
.moorhtab eht ot og ot dah I taht ados hcum oot dah tsuj I .tluaf ruoy ton s'tI"
waprevliS rennaT yb
.uoy tsol I fi enod evah dluow I tahw wonk t'nod I
,delims I ",ko s'tI"
;tellaw ym s'ereH"
,yppah em edam tI
,peelsa llaf ot deirt dna dnuora denrut I ,flesym ot gnihgiS
.wap sih deppord dna deddon eH
.dezigolopa eh ",ssem eht rof yrros ,yeH"
.ylsuovren ti gnidaenk detrats dna pal ym otno liat ym dellup I
.gnilworg ,deralg I
yag saw I taht erac t'ndid eH
nwod dils swap sih tuB
"?uoy evol I tuoba woH"
.ykcul tsuj saw taht . . . tihS
.seivom ni etsat ym etarelot ot dneirf doog a hcus si eH
".gnihtemos era yllaer uoY"
.daeh sih fo kcab eht gnihctarcs
,rood eht drawot gnivom detrats dna pu tog I
,niaga retupmoc eht no yawa gnipyt detrats dna deddon ehS "!eruS"
efil elohw ym raeh ot gnipoh neeb d'I sdrow—
.dehgual eh "!thgirla ,hO"  .derepmihw I ",ris
.tuo deppop stekcit fo tes a sdnoces owt ekil nI
em dna uoy fo sehsalf tsuj saw tI"
,resolc em dellup dna redluohs ym dnuora mra sih depard nosaJ
em detcartsid skcud ria s'rac eht hguorht detsalb ria fo tej toh A
.enog saw ti litnu knird ruo fo spis gnikat yllanoisacco
,dias dna redluohs ym no wap sih tup nosaJ
.ecnelis htiw moor eht gnillif
. . . "   .pu meht mraw ot swap ym revo liat ym tpews I
.kcen sih fo wolloh eht delzzun dna
,ti psalc ot tuoba saw eh fi sa
.dehgis eh dna nwod tnew srae siH  .detats I
.delkcuhc nosaJ "!aH"
,dekaorc I ",yrros m'I"
.dehsurb sregnif ruo dna
.retaeht eivom eht fo ecnartne eht ot yaw ruo edam ew sa
.enim tsniaga gnihsurb
.keew a rof gniht nmad taht rof demmarc I
.hctac sih morf ffo gniyap eb yllaer tsum ecitcarp essorcal siH
".lliw syawla dna tuoba erac I eno ylno eht er'uoY
. . . ti gniod yllautca m'I eveileb t'nac I
sffup elbisiv ylerab ni tuo emac htaerb yM
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.tuo eugnot ym kcuts I ".tac diputS"
.esirprus ni pu dekool I  .nrecnoc htiw debbe eciov sih
.seivom evol ecnassianer/laveidem
elttil a ffo desod evah thgim I kniht I tniop emos tA
,detrotnoc ecaf sih
sdrow elttil eerhT
.yag gnieb em fo esuaceb pihsdneirf ruo tuoba seitirucesni elttil eseht dah syawla ev’I
.edistuo dloc nmad os s'ti . . . tihS
tsuj I .t'ndluoc I tub
.ydob erab sih tsniaga em gnillup
,nrocpop llams dna knird muidem a deredro eW
,dedne eivom eht emit eht yB
.mih ecaf t'ndluoc tsuj I
.enips ym nwod nar kraps a sa gniltsirb liat ym
deraeppasid eh noitcerid eht ta gnirats
.ekawa ylhguor em gnikahs swap gnorts fo riap a tlef I
.deb s'nosaJ fo toof eht ta gnittis
.ruf tessur ym rednu redrah neve gnihsulb
.hguoht em htiw meht hctaw ot dnats dluoc nosaJ woh wonk t'nod I
.ssendrawkwa htiw kciht saw su neewteb ria eht
,t'nod esaelP"
.srexob fo riap naelc a erew depoh I tahw pu dleh dna em rednu dehcaer neht
,tsehc sih tsniaga ecaf ym desserp I sa
mih tuoba ,gnihtyreve ,ssik ehT
.delggig I ",htob em dna uoY"  ".gniyduts taht lla morf deirf yllatot si niarb yM
.uoy esaelp ot tsuj lliw yeht erus m'I"
.gnidliub eht deretne ew sa taeh fo mraws eht ta ylippah gnihgis ,retaeht eivom eht otni deirruh I dna nosaJ
.retniw fo em dednimer
.llew did I epoh I .kniht I . . . dooG"
.delims dna em ta nwod dekool tsuj nosaJ tuB .raf oot enog dah I fi ees ot pu dekool I
rac eht otni deppoh I
.pu dooh ym dellup dna
sraet htiw doolf ot detrats seye ym noos dna ,eromyna kcab dloh t'ndluoc I
gnileef ,ffo deliart I ". . . haeY"
.moortser s'nem eht drawot delbma dna kcab tellaw sih koot eH ".nalp
,dnats eht dniheb esoognom gnuoy a saw erehT
.dias I ",ti wonk uoY"
.tuo dednetxe wap
.esimorp I .kcab thgir eb ll'I dna eivom eht hctaw dna tis oG
.tellaw rehtael nworb dlo na em dednah eH ".moorhtab
,edisni dedaeh dna rac eht fo tuo deppoh I
.eye eno htiw em ta drah nwod dekool eH
.yrrulf etihw a ni wons eht gnisiar
yawa htaerb ym koot ti sa ssik eht morf yawa ekorb I
.dlrow elttil nwo ym morf em gnikaerb
.detrats eivom eht erofeb sevil s'rehto hcae ni no gniog neeb s'tahw dna egelloc tuoba erom emos deklat eW
.enif er'uoy ,yltsenoH
lwarc a ot nwod wols ot detrats dah rac eht taht
.semitemos yllis os eb nac I
,siht ekil tuo gnah ot egnahc a dah ev’ew ecnis elihwa neeb d’tI
.swap ruo no gnitser selzzum
ymmut ym dekop dna revo dehcaer eH .desaet eh
.delims dna mih ta dekool I  ".eurT"
.yraet seye ym edam thgirla eb dluow gnihtyreve taht em gnillet
.siht no tlas dna rettub hcum oot yaw tup yehT" .denaorg eh
.wonk t'nod I" .deggurhs nosaJ
,wodniw eht dekcor dniw ehT
.ria thgin dloc eht otni detlem traeh yM
.yppah em sekam tsuj meht tuoba gnihtemoS
.delims dna em ta pu dekool ehS
".hguoht uoy evol llits I"
deciton I esuaceb ,syek onaip fo gnippat dna scitsuoca fo murts tfos eht dna
,revihs em edam sihT
.esae tuohtiw llab a teg ot elba eb d'eh taht hcum os mih htiw gnicitcarp neeb ev'I ;retteb d'tI
"?wonk uoy ,uoy tuoba yrrow tsuj I"
.gnitareggaxe revo tsuj saw eh gnikniht
teiuq yltnasaelp saw ecalp s'nosaJ ot kcab edir rac ehT
,eb lliw syawla dna won rehtnap etihw ym si eH
.em dniheb gniggaw ylizal liat ym
".erad t'ndluow uoY ".depsag I
".yrgnuh era syug uoy fi egdirf eht ni azzip s'ereht ,lleW
.etal oot pu yats ot ton su dlot dna thgin doog a su dehsiw dna ni emac rehtom s'nosaJ esuaceb
.rood sih nepo ot detrats dna tleb sih delkcub-nu eh sa
".siht od t'nac tsuj I . . . tsuj I"
,deksa nosaJ "?ydaer uoY"
.yag saw I esuaceb eromyna em tnaw t'ndid ylimaf nwo ym neve—hguoht ti evresed I sseug I
,seye ediw htiw em ta derats dna kcab llef nosaJ
,desimorp eh sa kcab eb dluow nosaJ taht gniveileb ,eivom eht ot noitnetta yap ot deirt I ,gnihgiS
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
.pis a koot dna riadim ni ti thguac eH .deksa eh
.wonk t'nod I tahw tuoba tub ,dessip elttil a dekool eH .nwod
.retaeht eht ot yaw ruo edam neht dna
",tnemtrapa ym ta er'uoy nehw dnuora raewrednu ym gnivael ym ees t'nod uoY !yeH"
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.sdneirf doog hcus er'ew yhw s'taht sseug I
?llew sa ti tuoba gnikniht nosaJ saw yhw tub
.owt ro dnoces a rof gnisuap ,yas ot detrats I ". . . lleW"
stekcit eivom eht rof yap syawla uoY .oN"
.kaerb traeh ym edam—
"?tuoba gnikniht uoy era tahW"
,wons htiw dnuorg eht gnirevoc
,rac eht dellif taht ssab gnislup eht ot denetsil dna
.ssik sih fo noitasnes emosewa eht ta deleer daeh yM
.yltnatsni dias I ",uoy evol I"
"?tuoba gnimaerd uoy erew lleh eht tahW"
?eivom eht fo kniht uoy d'tahW"
.ecaf ym was eh nehw dezigolopa eh ". . . gnikoj saw I"
.tac ralucsum eht rof nepo rood eht gnidloh
.erocdraH KU dna pU sdnaH
,knird ym fo pis rehtona koot dna tserdaeh s’deb eht tsniaga gnitser
.elzzum ym no detser swap sih htob sa ssik eht otni erom mih dellup dna kcen sih dnuora smra ym thguorb I
swap ym no elzzum ym detser I
,sthguoht ym ni flesym gnisol
moor ylimaf eht otni nosaJ dewollof dna taoc ym pu gnuh I
,redrah neve hsulb em edam sihT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.kcatta traeh a dah ylraen I deirrow os saw I
tac etihw gib eht htiw gniklaw detrats dna rac eht fo kcab eht ot tnew I
,nwod elzzum sih thguorb nosaJ
,ereht dial tsuj I
.rac eht ssorca redluohs sih depmub I
.raed ,kO" .deddon evoD .srM
.reeuq oot tsuj m'I
!?yag gnikcuf os eb ot evah I od yhW !tihS
",esaelp uoy dluow nac taht em ssoT"
",emit siht meht rof yap ot tnaw I
ruf sih rednu nosmirc dehsulb nosaJ nehw delggig I
.dnats snoissecnoc eht ot mih dewollof dna deddon I
.deciton nosaJ erofeb
.htoob tekcit eht ot deklaw dna dehgis I
em tuoba derac yllautca
.elzzum ym detfil dna nihc ym rednu sregnif sih thguorb eH   .redrah gnibbos
,daeh ym gnuh dna denaorg I
,esuoh s'rehtnap eht dehcaer ew ,emit trohs a nI
". . . yas ot tahw wonk t'nod I-I-
.seye lufituaeb sih otni derats dna dnuora denrut I !tihS  ". . . maS"
.yaw ym decnalg yllanoisacco tub
em dennuhs yllacitcarp ylimaf nwo yM
",eivom a dedne elpoep yaw eht gnitah rof rettel yrgna yrev a etirw ot gniog s'taht xof eht diaS"
;saw eh ,esirprus ym ot dna
.em drawot si eh ecin woh teews tub ,ynnuf fo dnik s'tI .delkcuhc dna
.ecnelis eht kaerb ot tnaw yllaer t'ndid dna
.kcab dellup srae
"!esaelP !pu ekaw ,maS"
.desufnoc ,nosaJ ta pu derats I seye ym morf peels gnibbuR
.wons gnillaf eht morf yawa seye ym gnidleihs
taht ereh enoemos saw ereht wenk I esuaceb ,stnerap lufetah ym htiw laed ot evah t'ndid I
?em gnivael peek evol I elpoep eht od yhW
,llew sa thgin taht ot kcab gnikniht saw I ,uoy dniM
.stnerap gnirac sih gnidulcxe—
,seirots ecnamor yag gnitirw syojne yltsom eH
.noisserpxe ciots sih daer t'ndluoc I tub
.dias eh ",tuo uoy dekcik stnerap ruoy thgin taht tuoba gnikniht tsuj saw I ,hO"
".emoh kcab klaw gnol a s'ti . . . luferaC"
.derumrum I ",sknahT"
.thgindoog a em dehsiw dna
.dekrep srae ,denetfos neht
.moorhtab eht ot daeh I sa stekcit ruo yub og
.ko dias dna dehgis yllanif eH
,moor s'nosaJ ot sriatspu nar ew
.em morf rettel yrgna yrev a gnitteg eb lliw yeht ;doG em pleh os ro gnidne retteb a htiw eno rehtona ekam retteb yehT
.llef wons eht sa gnihctaw deunitnoc dna pal ym no swap ym dedlof I
,gnirac dna eltneg erew yehT
.dennirg nosaJ ",fooG"
wonS retniW“   :yojne esaelP
.peels ym morf em detloj taht dna ekahs rehguor neve na tlef I
,deksa dna redluohs ym no wap sih detser enilef eht ,tuo yaw ruo nO
.thguoht ni tsol saw eh sa erecnis dna
. . . das os tsuj si enecs sihT .doog m'I"
.noisses dipar ni yawa kcurts swalc reh sa dekcilc syek eht
",dnuora gniyl ti evael t'noD" .denworf I
.lluks ym ot kcab dellup srae enipluv ym
.niht dna kciht eht hguorht
srae sih ,dehgis dna seye sih debbur eH
". . . hturt eht tuo dnuof uoy retfa em tfel uoy taht
.lamron mees tsomla efil ym sekam tI
”wonS retniW“ saw sihT
.rufdaeh ym delffur neht
.moM ,taerg saw eivom ehT"
.eugnot nwo ym tsniaga gnitser
,nwod kcab tas dna ffo deliart nosaJ ". . . yakO"
. . . I taht uoy llet I nac woh ,nosaJ hO
gnihtemos eb nac taht rednu tub
?eno siht thguorb tahw rednow I
erom pu meht mraw ot rehtegot swap ruo debbur htob eW
"?tey tae syug uoy diD
. . . em tuohtiw ffo retteb eb dluow nosaJ ebyaM
.enigne eht fo gnigguhc tfos dna oidar eht rof tpecxe
.aera eht ssorca delwarps was I elpoep wef eht rof tpecxe ytpme hcum ytterp saw retaeht ehT
,deb eht fo retnec eht ot pu dellup I
,sraey rof rehto hcae rof ereht neeb syawla evah eW
.nos a sa rekcuskcoc a tnaw t’ndid yeht taht—
,der gnihsulb llits ,em morf yawa dekool eH ". . . emoclew er'uoY"
.em ot derepsihw eh ",ko s'ti . . . hhhS"
,rednow etihw ni tsac dlrow eht tfel tI
,eivom eht fo tser eht rof ecnelis ni ereht tas eW
.retniw devol syawla I
.ypsar saw dna derettuhs eciov siH ".kcatta
.em ta nwod denworf nosaJ    .dias I
.tuoba demaerd dah I tahw derebmemer yleugav I
.gaf a em llac dna em fo tuo tihs eht gnitaeb trats ot mih rof—trats ot swolb eht detcepxe I
.lla s'taht ,s’yduts ym htiw ysub neeb tsuj
ffo thgil dnatsthgin sih dekcilc nosaJ
,feiler :snoitome fo sevaw htiw koohs ydob yM
.tuoba gnikcilf pit liat
,seirots lanoitome dna xelpmoc erom ot ttums gnitirw morf gnignar
.pu em taeb ot gniod yllautca saw eH .dehcnilf I dna
.pu eb llits ot mih tcepxe t'ndid I
.deksa I ",peelsa saw I
.nwod kcab ruf ym dettap dna derewolg I
.dekcap saw ti esuaceb tol gnikrap eht fo dne eht raen krap ot dah ew ,yletanutrofnU
",uoy evol ,moM kO"
,llaf ot detrats sraet hserf
,dias eh ",daeha og ,yrros m'I !spoO"
.etanoissap dna teews saw ssik siH
.iH" ,dias dna kcab delims I
,od ot retteb gnihton evah ew ecnis sseug I tub ,ksa ot gniht driew a ekil demees tI ".keew
",maS thgindooG"   .dias nosaJ
.pu mraw ot detrats rac eht sa
.mih ta regnif a detniop I  ".eniF"
.ti no teef ruo tser dluoc ew os egdel a raen staes fo wor a dekcip eW
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.ruf nehsa sih rednu der gninrut ecaf sih
.dias eh ",ko s'tI"
.tuo dellac eciov a "? . . . maS
,flesym emos deirt dna delggig I   ". . . wE
".nrocpop retaeht teg reven I yhw si siht dnA"
.enim tsniaga dehsam yltfos spil siH
.trats ot eivom eht rof gnitiaw ew sa etsat eht ta gnirevihs
yppah htob erew eW
.deb ot gnidaeh erofeb eivom eht dehsinif dna nac ados tsal ruo ffo dellik I dna nosaJ  "!thgiN"
.rehto hcae tsniaga gnihsurb dna gniggaw sliat
.yhtapmys ebyam ro—
dna erom elttil a denediw seye s'nosaJ   ".uoy . . . devlovni tI"
.elims em edam sihT
.deerga nosaJ ",gniddik on ,haeY"
.skrow retaw eht nettog evah dluow uoy esle rO !dooG"
.aes gnigar eht ekil em no nwod hsarc ot detrats dah gnihtyrevE .detuohs I
".emoclew yrev er'uoY"
,llew sa srexob ym ot nwod deppirts I
,neht kcab ylthgit em gnidloh mih fo gnikniht tsuJ
;tsaf taht peelsa llaf ot mees t'ndluoc I tuB
.yawa sraet eht depiw dna deddon I  "!?ko uoy erA"
.noitautis elohw eht dna flesym drawot dertah ,regna ,yrrow
,pis a koot dna knird ym debbarg I
.retupmoc a no yawa gnipyt
. . . . gnirons etuc s'nosaJ ot gninetsil si rebmemer I gniht gnitsal eht esuaceb did I tniop emos ta dna
.detuohs tsomla nosaJ "!pu ekaW"
.noitnetta gniyap ton rof revo nur nettog evah thgim I
I" .sselhceeps ,ereht doots tsuj I
.niaga sgniht gniknihtrevo tsuj saw I taht ,lanoitarri gnieb saw I wonk I ,nwod peeD
,nageb eivom eht dna nwod demmid ylwols sthgil ehT .ecin saw siht os
.elbatrofmocnu nosaJ edam dah I deirrow
.dnim ym ni hserf llits  yromem taht ,emit siht lla retfa nevE
.deilper I ".enif m'I ,seY"
,edistuo gnirats ot kcab tnew dna
.kcab tellaw eht dednah dna daeh ym koohs I
.guh rehtona em evag dna ,revo dehcaer dna denaorg eH ". . . dog hO"
.sraey wef a rof gnitirw ni gnilbbad neeb sah ohw flow yerg a si waprevliS rennaT .waprevliS rennaT yb wonS retniW
.reven ro won s'ti . . . lleW
llew sa thgindoog a mih dehsiw I
. . . mU"   .niaga delims eH ".esimorp
;yltneg enim otni gnikool mih was dna seye ym denepo I
.dias ehs ",syob olleH"
".su rof nrocpop emos dna knird a rof yap nac uoy ,tnaw uoy fI"
cisum eht ot denetsil ylteiuq dna oidar eht no denrut I ,doom yppah a nI
.regnif ym no dekooh tnemrag eht mih dewohs I "?siht gnissiM"
.etsat gnirewoprevo eht ta deltsirb ruf yM . . . doG .yM .hO
"!ekas tsirhC rof peels ruoy ni gnibbos erew uoY
.wodniw tnorf s'rac eht tih yeht nehw
.mra sih no wap ym tup dna mih ta delims I ".em
,em ta gnirats rehtnaP etihW gib eht dnif ot denrut I
.esnecs ycuas emos ni gniworht llits elihw
?gniod uoy era tahW"
.dekniw dna niaga dekop eH ".em
.mih depmub dna delims I
fo erneg eht ni gnicudorp yltsom
.ydob eligarf ym dnuora depparw erew smra gnorts esohT
.nosaJ tespu evah thgim I gniyrrow ,riahc ym ni dnuora gnimriuqs tpek I
.htoob tekcit eht rof dedaeh dna
.loohcs ssucsid llew sa thgim
eseht rof rekcus a fo dnik m'I
,ados fo snac tsrif dna
".uoy evol I" .dias eh ",maS"
.taht dias eh nehw deltsirb ruf yM
.noitcefrep ni su dnuora dlrow eht gnivreserp
,nac ados a dna swap ruo ni azzip fo lluf setalp htiW
.elbatrofmocnu yrev
ht-hT"   .wap ym morf raewrednu eht dehctans dna
.nalp a ekil sdnuoS" .dennirg eh "!eruS"
.esuoh s'nosaJ ot yaw eht no tnelis tpek dna
.elzzum ym no elims a
;em ta kcab dekool nosaJ sa denedder hsulb yM ".lla
.lufituaeb os lla saw tI
htmraw htiw dellif saw ezag sih
.em evol uoy . . . esaelP"
.neercs eht gnicaf
moortser eht esu ot flesym desucxe I
. . . . em rof ereh eb syawla lliw retniw sa elims em gnikam
?no ti thguorb tahW
.rettam eht no rehtruf yna hsup t'ndid tub ,eil ym eveileb ot mees t'ndid eh
".syad elpuoc tsap eseht delbuort . . . demees ev’uoY
.delims dna pu dekool evoD .srM
,tsehc ym dnuora depparw dna
.won sraey rof evah I—
.erom neve yrc em edam sihT
,gniod saw nosaJ woh ees ot revo decnalg I yllanoisaccO
,deb eht no nwod dial ew dna eivom a ni deppop nosaJ
.em htiw ereh t'nerew uoy fi lla ta dlrow eht enrob evah dluoc I kniht t'nod I
.smra ym ni retniw nwo yrev ym
.elzzum ym dnuora ruf eht dna eson ym no htaerb sih leef dluoc I dna
.llits tis t'ndluoc I tuB
.seye sih dellor nosaJ  .kcab tohs I
?od ot gniog I saw tahW .thguoht ni tsol
,daor eht ot noitnetta diap dna drawrof decaf eH
.yawa meht gnittup dna pu sgniht gnikcip moor sih dnuora delffuhs nosaJ
roiretxe hsrah a evah nac retniw woH
.daeh ym gnikcoc ,nosaJ ot revo dekool dna tuo dehcterts I
",hgU" .ados eht fo emos knird ot dehsur dna esion detsugsid a edam neht
.mih tsniaga em dleh dna dnuora em denrut eH
,nwod kcab tas dna delbmum I ". . . ko
.yltnelis revo dehsur nosaJ  .dekaorc I "?nosaJ"
;redluohs ym no elzzum sih detser eH
.gab gnipeels eht otni dehsur I os
.nworf a otni nwod deggut sworb sih
.sthguoht sih fo tuo mih gnignirb ylgnimees
,niatrecnu dekool dna em ta nwod dekool tac gib ehT
.nosaJ retfa desahc neht ,evoD .srM dna .rM ot olleh dias dna delims I
dnuora emac liat siH
.ruf der ydaerla ym rednu der peed hsulb ym edam sihT
.yltfos derepsihw eh ",em ta kool ,yeH"
;enola os tlef I dna ssenkrad ot dedaf gnihtyreve noos tuB .seiromem yppah—