.ssengnihton eht ni erugif dionamuh a ekil dekool ,tnemom a rof
,taht ekil tsuj dnA
.deggurhs llaH tnanetueiL
siht sa hcus saera hguorht niart eht wollof ot demees yeht taht tcaf eht
.setanidrooc detacidni eht ta detniop ehS
,niart eht no gnivres morf emac taht sdnegel fo tnuoma riaf a erew ereht draeh dah eillE
.setunim fo rettam a ni enoz daed eht retne ot tes saw niart eht
,detseggus dah eh sa tub
.tey nekops t’ndah ohw puorg eht fo rebmem ylno eht saw egdirb eht fo tnorf eht ta detaeS .dias eillE
.puorg eht fo rebmem hcae ta dekool ehs ,slortnoc reh morf yawa gninruT
,sgnidaer emas eht nruter ot deunitnoc nacs yreve teY
.noitamrifnoc tnatiseh a evag ehs pu gnikrep srae reH
.esruoc egnahc ,asiL
”.su ni detseretni tsuj er’yeht kniht I ,yllanosrep eM
”,gninoitcnuflam eb ot sraeppa elosnoc ym ,llaH tnanetueiL“
,atad drocer ot deunitnoc srosnes ehT
,elzzum a fo epahs eht tuo ekam dluoc ehs thguoht tsomla dah ehs ,eno fo espmilg a thguac dah ehs nehW
.daeh sih detlit eh ,dnuora gninruT
”?gnikool enog reve enoyna saH“
”.yaled ruo fo nedraG eht gniyfiton fo yaw on evah ew tub
,srats eht ni snoitalletsnoc dnuof elpoep woh ekil
,no erew uoy edis tahw rettam on tub
.esirprus ni dnuora gninrut ,deksa llaH tnanetueiL ”?enoz daed eht fo elddim eht nI  ?ereH“
.snoitarepo noissim dna niart ot dengissa lla erew srac drawrof ehT
”,liah ruo ot ylper t’ndid yeht yhw snosaer fo rebmun yna eb dluoc erehT“
,erew yeht revetahW
.gnitroper htrow elttil yrev htiw ylwols dessap os ro ruoh txen ehT
htron tnatsid eht ni erehwemos tniopyaw a saw noitanitsed reH
.retniw lauteprep fo pirg eciv eht ni dleh saw dlrow eht taht tcaf eht saw etupsid ni ton saw tahw nigiro sti ot sa seiroeht gnitepmoc erew ereht elihW
.dnammoc hguorht noisiced yreve nur ot lacitcarpmi demeed saw ti
.noissimsnart gnimocni na gnitacidni pu til elosnoc reh nehw peews rosnes sseltniop rehtona tey nur ot tuoba saw ehS
,dedeen erew yeht nehw rof ylefas yawa dekcut eb dluoc erofeb dlrow eht fo sehcir eht erehw ecalpemos ,toped sulprus a rof nesohc neeb dah noitacol siht yhw saw taht spahrep teY
.ereh ni thgir krow ot mees t’nod srosnes ehT“
,llet dluoc ehs tahw morF
.aksalA fo snoiger reppu eht ni peed saw noitats ehT
.smra sih dedlof llaH tnanetueiL ”?snoinipO“
.seitud rieht tuoba gniog sreciffo suoirav eht tsap deklaw ehs sa nwod daeh reh tpek ehs ,llaH tnanetueiL gniwolloF
.dlrow eht fo tser eht morf raf siht evil ot nesohc dah ohw elpoep wef erew ereht retsasid eht erofeb nevE
.slegna wons llac ew nonemonehp a eb ot sdnet ereht htron raf siht teg ew emit ynA
.niart eht fo tnorf eht sdrawot derutseg eH
.flesmih ta delkcuhc eH
”.dnoces a rof ylno tub
.gnitavitpac saw nonemonehp lausunu eht yned ton dluoc eno
,seilppus fo sehcac ,stnemelttes no noitamrofni dah semitemos yeht
.daeh reh detlit ehs ,roirepus reh ta pu gnikool niagA
.drawrof denael adnap der ehT
.erofeb drawrof raf siht neeb reven dah ehs skeew fo rettam a rof niart eht no devres ylno gnivaH
”.elosnoc ruoy ton s’tI  .yrrow t’noD
.dednammoc adnap der eht
.sey hA“  .deddon eH
,era yeht revetahw ,yawynA“
ngisnE“  .elims thgils a dereffo ehs ,ti gnikahS
tsetrohs eht taht demialc neeb sah tI
.spetstoof gnihcaorppa fo erawa emaceb ylneddus ehs ,noitcelfer ’swodniw eht ni mrofinu reh gnitsujdA
”.ydaer noissimsnarT“
”.enoz daed eht fo elddim eht ni kcams thgiR“
.uoy tuoba kool taht dah uoY  .os thguoht I“
.selosnoc evitcepser rieht no stuodaer eht denimaxe llaH tnanetueiL dna eillE ,enigne eht fo sedis etisoppo no detaeS
.aksalA sa nwonk noiger remrof eht fo epacsdnal nezorf eht otni noitidepxe na tnarraw ot ytilibissop hguone tnacifingis a demeed saw ti ,sselehtreveN
.noissimsnart rof atad eht gnitpyrcne dna gnisserpmoc ,noitamrofni tnaveler dna stroper sutats eht fo lla detcelloc ehs ,tekcap noitamrofni eht gniraperP
.nacs rehtona tcudnoc ot detpmetta ehs ,dexelpreP
.denoitseuq erah eohswons gnuoy eht ”?tahw roF“
”.niaga revo dna revo egassem emas eht naht rehto gnihtyna gnitteg ton llits m’I tub ,gniviecer era yehT“
.ebolg wons citnagig a otni dlrow eht denrut dah taht retsasid eht tuoba wenk enoyrevE
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.goD fo tsohG ehT ot
.ezeerf eht fo tuo ti ekam t’ndid taht elpoep er’yeht yas emoS“
.gniees saw ehs tahw nialpxe ton dluoc ehs ,niaga ecnO
.deksa eh ”?setanidrooc tnerruc rieht ot sa sseug tseb ruoy s’tahw ,repraH ngisnE“
.sneercs s’llaH tnanetueiL fo tsegral eht no deyalpsid pam eht ,setanidrooc s’niart eht pu gnillaC
.seiroeht lausunu rehtar emos ot ecnederc tnel
.noitalpmetnoc ni elzzum sih derewol yrollaM niatpaC
.ereh dnuora stros fo noitaitini na fo tib a s’tI“
.ekops neht dna tnemom a desuap eH
,sreviR neruaL yb
seegufer pu dekcip yeht nehw snoisacco erar eht nO
.wodniw drawrof eht sdrawot decnalg eH
nedraG eht morf esnopser a eviecer ot koot netfo ti emit eht dna ecnatsid eht neviG
.dloc elbatipsohni eht ni dnuora ecnad seirrulf eht gnihctaw ,ssalg eht ot esolc denael eillE
”.llac ruoy s’tI“  .deggurhs eH
.nottub eht revo regnif reh dleh ehs ,dehsinif saw ehs ecnO
,soidutS ecnecsedirI yb nooM eulB fo rohtuA ,sreviR neruaL yb
.elihw a etiuq rof dnes dluow niart eht egassem tsal eht saw tI
a fo smret nI .elbatibahninu dna dloc
”.nedraG eht ot kcab etadpu sutats a dnes ot eraperP“
,enoz daed eht morf gnigreme etal saw niart eht fi noitadipert emos eb dluow ereht elihW
epacsdnal a ’,dlrow‘ eht rof ,werc reh
.tsal ot dengised smetsys yratnemelppus rehto dna
evah t’nod ew dna detimil era seilppus ruO  .noitnetta lacidem eriuqer dna lli era puorg ruo fo lareveS  .aksalA nrehtron ni erehwemos noitats hcraeser cifitneics a ni egufer nekat evah srehto lareves dna ylimaf yM  .lennahc ycnegreme eht no tuo gnihcaer yrraP nayR si sihT“  .ssenkrad eht morf tuo dellac eciov a sa efil ot delkcarc tI
.goD fo ecioV ehT no goD fo tsohG ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
”.selibomwons eht no yaw eht fo tser eht og dna esolc teg ot evah d’eW
.esira ot erew taht snoitautis rehto yna rof noitercsid s’niatpaC eht ot pu syawla saw ti snoitarepo egavlas rof saw evitcerid yramirp rieht hguohtlA
.eillE ot derutseg dna smra sih dedlof yrollaM niatpaC
.elcriC citcrA eht hguorht dehsup niart eht sa swodniw eht no detcelloc wonS
”?noitisop tnerruc ruo s’tahW“
,niart eht dnuora aera eht fo speews rosnes raluger nur ot deunitnoc ehs ,dexelprep llitS
.sdnah sih pu dessot llaH tnanetueiL
.emit tsrif eht rof edisni deppets ehs sa htaerb reh dleh ehs ,enigne eht gniretnE
,tnemom a rof emit ot emit morf raeppa dluow sgnihT
,gnihtemos fo psiw a ees nac uoy netfo os yreve tub ereht tuo dnuora gniwolb wons tsuj s’ti ,yllaeR
.wodniw eht tuo kcab decnalg ehS  ”.repraH
”?ti t’nsi ,ruot tsrif ruoy si sihT
rac noitautis eht otni dessap yeht sA
”?gniyas erew uoY“
.lla ta tnerehoc ton erew gnitteg saw ehs sgnidaer eht fi sa tsomla saw ti ,revoeroM
”.tnatsni na naht erom rof ereht reven er’yeht dna tnempiuqe noitceted yna no pu wohs t’nod yeht
”eliM kraD ehT :llafretniW“
”.nigiro fo tniop sti enimreted ot yrt I emit yreve gnirettacs s’ti tub aera lareneg a ot nwod ti worran nac I“
,ti revo dessolg tsomla ehs moderob reh nI
.emit fo tol a
.gnihton saw ereht won ,epahs elbitpecrep ylerab taht saw ereht erehw tub wodniw eht ta kcab decnalg ehs ,mih sdrawot ylprahs gninruT  .enog saw ti
,emit fo doirep degnolorp a rof srehcraeser fo tnegnitnoc llams a troppus ot hguone egral saw ti esoprup sti gnitacidni sdrocer eht ni gnihton saw ereht elihW
.stluser suolamona emas eht nruter ot demees ti
.tsixe ot nwonk llits secaps neerg wef eht fo eno ,ecalp a hcus ni nrob neeb dah eillE
.revo detrats egassem eht sa emulov eht decnelis eillE
.retsasid eht desuac revetahw rof tnemhsinup ruo er’yeht kniht srehtO
mrofinu ytud dradnats s’niart eht ni desserd enilef ednolb A
.aera dnammoc eht dnuora tiucric sih edam eh sa selosnoc rieht fo lla gninimaxe
,enigne eht fo htgnel eht decap eH
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT        .deilper eh ”,ris
.langis eht ni segnahc yna rof gnirotinom peek ,repraH
.slegna wons eht tuoba reilrae reh dlot dah llaH tnanetueiL tahw ot kcab thguoht eillE
,nihc sih debbur adnap der ehT
”.stsohg er’yeht ekil s’tI  .kcehc ew nehw ereht tuo gnihtyna reven s’ereht od ew tahw rettam on tuB
.demrifnoc ehs ”,si tI“
.ti tliub taht ynapmoc eht ot nwonk saw tahw ot detimil dna etelpmocni netfo erew sdrocer eht ,ezeerF eht erofeb retupmoc eht ni derots atad ot detimiL
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.noitazilivic fo sngis rewef neve dna efil fo sngis on htiw
selosnoc lortnoc eht morf gnitaname sthgil eht rof evas krad saw egdirb eht
”.revO  .sutats tnerruc ruoy htiw dnopser esaelP
.noitanalpxe fo tros yna rof ssol a ta ,dias ehs
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’thginoT dna
emit txen ni enuT .dad regdab yldduc
,thgil deudbus ni deduorhS
srotareneg rewop ycnegreme lareves htiw deppiuqe saw noitats eht ylekil tsoM
nosrep tsal eht :swollof sa sdaer yrots rorroh elbissop
.noisufnoc ni pu dekrep srae reH
.sgnidaer reh ot denruter ehs ,tnemom eht rof derewsna noitseuq reH
,eliM kraD eht nihtiw gnilevart erew yeht sa gnol sa sselesu yllacitcarp erew srosnes reH
.ereht pu seilppus gnitteg ni yaled a saw ereht esac ni tsuj ylekil
,noititsrepus sa seirots eht dessimsid srehto elihw
.arbez eht ot kcab denrut ehs ,pu gniviG
.otni gnikool htrow s’ti kniht I ,thgir llA“
.evah ew ygolonhcet nwonk yna hguorht elbbub eht etartenep ot elbanu era slangis lacirtcele ,erauqs selim derdnuh evif revo aera na gnirevoC
.ytiniffaruF no seirots reh fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
,’nosrep tsal‘ eht rof ,niart sti dna evitomocol a etutitsbus ’moor a‘ rof
.eci eht ssorca syenruoj sti ni deggol niart eht taht sgniht rehto ro
.noziroh eht sdrawot detniop eH  ”?eeS“
.reh no skcirt gniyalp erew yeht spahreP
,eyA“ ”.maet yrevocer eht dael ot uoy tnaw I ,llaH tnanetueiL
dne eht ta stiawa tahw tuo dnif ot
”.smrahc kcul doog ruo meht redisnoc fo dnik ew taht meht nees evah su fo hguone tniop siht ta tub
.noitatiseh ni gninettalf srae sih
.deneppah tahw detapicitna reve yeht ylekilnu saw ti hguohtla
.sgnidaer reh mrifnoc ot nwod dekool eillE
.ecnelis fo tnemom rehtonA
.stluser emas eht nruter reven dluow yeht ,sgnidaer reh mrifnoc ot tpmetta dluow ehs emit yrevE
”,gnihtyna fo hcum llet ot drah s’ti puos siht ni tub ,gniyrt m’I“ .deksa yrollaM
.snoitavresbo nwo sti morf saw detcelloc niart eht ecnegilletni eht fo tsom ,deednI
”.lausunu gnihtyna troper dna srosnes lla rotinoM
.riahc reh no wap a gnicalp ,dniheb morf devresbo yrollaM  .ycneiciffe mumixam ta gnitarepo saw gnihtyreve mrifnoc ot citsongaid smetsys a nar ehs ,tcepxe ot tahw niatrecnU
.nwo ruo no er’ew neht litnu ,nemeltneg dna seidal ,thgir llA“
,soahc eht ni snrettap rof gnihcraes sgnieb tneitnes naht erom elttil erew yeht denigami ehS
dessimsid dah ehs ylkciuq os enog dna emoc dah ti tub
.noitcerid siht ni skcart eht ekat ew emit yreve hguorht ssap ew enoz daed fo tros a si daeha pU“
,seirraH nomoloS yb uoy rof daer
”eliM kraD ehT :llafretniW“
.deksa eillE ”?evila yeht erA“
”.edis rehto eht tuo emoc ew litnu tcatnoc fo tuo eb ll’ew eliM kraD eht otni ssap ew tnemom ehT“
”.eliM kraD eht morf egreme ew litnu sruoh xis tniop ruoF“
.deksa eh ”?slegna wons eht ta kool ot emoC“
.semit fo ytnelp ,eruS“
”.gnitiaw si niatpac eht ,no emoc woN“
:noitarobale na ,mialc taht fo tnemssessa nI .rood eht no kconk a saw erehT .moor a ni
tas dlrow eht ni
”?langis eht fo ecruos eht ezilacol uoy naC“
.snoitanigami rieht ypucco ot gnihtemos rof gnikool sreciffo yratilim derob naht erom gnihtyna er’yeht erus neve ton m’I  .wonk I fi denmaD“
.drawrof reh degru eH
.noitacol esicerp ruoy yfitnedi ot elbanu era tub uoy etacol ot gnitpmetta era eW
”…snaem taht nehT“  .desuap eillE  ”.evah
.sruoh ynam sa ni owt retnuocne ot tuoba saw ehs won tub
,ytiruces fo daeh s’niart eht ot degnoleb eciov ehT
.staerht laitnetop rof trela niamer ot deunitnoc ehs os neve tub
.citats otni gnivlossid erofeb detats eciov elam a
.wodniw eht tsniaga denael llaH
.deilper ehs ”,ris ,seY“
.secruoser fo elipkcots elbissop a detneserper noitamrofni rieht ot gnidrocca hcihw
2 fo 1 traP ,sreviR neruaL yb ”eliM
”.nwo ruo no er’ew ,ereht ni teg ew ecno ,yltcaxE“
,niart eht morf langis eht fo noitacol tcaxe eht tniopnip nac ew taht hguone esolc su teg ylbaborp nac I setanidrooc s’repraH ngisnE no desaB“
.emit emas eht ta reh no saw eye yrevE
,sgol retupmoc eht ni dnuof dah ehs tahw morF
.niart eht morf selim wef a naht erom gnihtyna no yler ot hguot s’tI
ton naht netfo erom dna stneve erar ylriaf erew sllac ssertsid
”.gnipool speek egassem ehT  .esle gnihton s’erehT“
,ew rood eht no kconk
,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR
”.sruoh evlewt tsael ta yb dniheb su tup ll’ti ,niatpaC ,langis eht etagitsevni ot og ew fI“
.gniees saw ehs sgnidaer gnisufnoc eht rof tnemom eht ta edivorp dluoc ehs esucxe ylno eht saw ti
.llac ssertsid ruoy ot gnidnopser yrollaM newO niatpaC si sihT“
sselehtreven tub
.sucof otni kcab reh deppans rotacidni til eht fo noitazilaer eht tub
.yaw sti no saw noitamrofni eht dna desserp saw nottub eht retal tnemom A  .deredro eh ”,dneS“
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.dnah sih tuo dehcaer eH  ”.llaH tnanetueiL
,stirips lautca erew yeht deveileb elpoep emos
*	      *	      *	                                                           .ssenevitceffe rieht esaercni ot did ehs tahw rettam on
.stsohg rosnes sa ebircsed ylno dluoc ehs seilamona lausunu htiw
.ecnerrucco modnar a naht erom elttil sa ti
”,snoitats ruoy ekaT“
,sgniht gninigami erew sklof thguoht elpoep ereh pu erew ew semit wef tsrif ehT
.rekaeps eht detavitca ehs ,nottub gnihsalf eht rof gnihcaeR ”.ti raeh s’teL“
.erah retrohs eht sdrawot daeh sih detlit arbez ehT
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
”?em esucxE“  .llaH tnanetueiL
,ereht tuo er’uoy fI
.redro na reh evig ot enoemos rof detiaw ehs reciffo roirepus arbez reh dniheb gnidnatS
gnitteg saw ehs sgnidaer eht ni tnemevorpmi lanigram a naht erom hcum ekam ot deliaf noituloser rosnes eht evorpmi ot stpmettA
.raeppa ot desufer yeht ,dehcraes ehs drah woh rettam on tub kcab dekool eillE
noitisop tnerruc ruo fo htron erehwemos noitats hcraeser cifitneics a pu kcip od I retsasid eht erofeb morf evah ew sdrocer no desaB“
.niart eht htiw ti hcaer t’nac ew tub
.nevaeh eb hcum ytterp dluow taht ekil ecalp a
.niart eht edisgnola delevart slegna wons yna fi ees ot gnikool wodniw eht ta ecnalg erom eno tsac ehs
,yats ot ecalpemos dedeen dna aksalA ni tuo dednarts erew uoy fi ,taobefil fo tros yna eb ot dednetni reven saw ti elihW
.deilper ehs ”,ti nialpxe t’nac I  .stupni lausunu emos gninruter peek srosnes ehT“ ”?gnorw s’tahW“
.elbmaerp tuohtiw dias eh
,tuptuo eht tcerroc ot detpmetta ehs semit ynam woh rettam on tub ,scitsongaid lanoitidda nar eillE
.gnihton saw ereht
,htron raf siht gnihtyreve no pirg sti denethgit evah ot demees ti ,wen gnihton saw dloc elihW
.erew yeht sa hcus ,senoz efas wef eht fo eno ni eb ot enutrof doog eht dah ro tpada ot denrael dah gnol siht devivrus dah taht esohT
.deraeppa ti tahw naht rehto gnihtyna saw siht taht noitacidni on dnif dluoc tub sgnidaer reh dekcehc elbuod eillE
”.eliM kraD eht gnihcaorppa er’eW  .enigne eht ni su stnaw yrollaM niatpaC“
”.rewsna ot ereht eno on s’ereht etacidni dluoc esnopser a gnitteg ton er’ew taht tcaf ehT  .wonk t’nod I“
.gnidnatsrednu ,deddon eH
.noitacol tnereffid yletelpmoc a ni eb dluow txen eht dna
”.lennahc a nepO“  .deddon yrollaM niatpaC
,tnemtnioppasid reh oT
.daD regdaB yldduC a
.flesreh rof ees ot tnaw ot ytisoiruc eht dah dna ereht tuo saw tahw fo seirots no pu nworg dah ehS
”.ot klat ot enoemos tnaw tsuj yeht ebyaM“
.yllamron gnitarepo erew smetsys lla taht detsisni yldetaeper retupmoc eht scitsongaid eht morF
.tnemmoc tuohtiw srac drawrof eht ot yaw eht fo tser eht deklaw owt ehT
.troper reh dereffo ehs ,redluohs reh revo adnap der eht dnif ot pu gnikooL
.sraey lareves tsal eht rof niart eht fo tolip yramirp eht neeb dah ehs
.remit eht detavitca llaH tnanetueiL
.eliM kraD eht fo
.deddon yrollaM niatpaC ,yllaniF
”,deredro sa gnitroper repraH ngisnE dna llaH tnanetueiL ,yrollaM niatpaC“
.ti nialpxe ot woh ro ti sesuac tahw swonk eno oN“
.noitamrofni ro ,lennosrep ,seilppus rof ecruos laitnetop a
.rehto eht ot etartenep ot elba eb ot mees ton did ti ,no saw ti enoz daed eht fo edis revehcihw taht deraeppa ti tub
.noitacol s’niart eht morf ecnatsid eht retaerg eht elbailernu dna railucep erom emaceb sgnidaer eht
.degnevacs eb nac tahw ees ot evah lliw ,werc eht ekil
”.semitemos etihw eht ni ereh tuo teiuq yllufwa steg tI
.enoz daed eht otni gnissap nopu ylthgils koohs niart eht dna derekcilf sthgil eht sa pu dekool enigne eht ni srebmem werc eht llA
”,ycneuqerf emas siht no esnopser ruoy dnes esaelP  .pleh ruoy deen ew
kraD ehT :llafretniW“   yojne esaelP
tahw was ehs ,gnikool pots ot tuoba saw ehs nehw tsuJ
”.noissimsnart a detceted ev’ew ,niatpaC“
.gniliec eht gnola sthgil tnecca wef a dna
”?eliM kraD eht s’tahW“
”?noitcerid a em teg neve uoy naC“ .deilper eillE