.deraeppasid ti emit yreve noitacol tnereffid a ni gnieb syawla
.efil fo sdnuos rof gninetsil pu dekrep srae reH
”.sruoh owt ni lavirra detamitsE
.selibomwons eht ot yaw rieht edam yeht sa redluohs eht no eillE deppat llaH tnanetueiL ,taht htiW
.deggurhs ehS  ”.smaerD
.retne ot nepo ti gnillup erofeb llaH tnanetueiL morf don a rof detiaw dna rood eht dehcaorppa ehs ylsuoituaC
.yalpsid sih ot noitnetta sih denruter arbez ehT
”.ezeerF eht devivrus reven yehT“
emos elihW .mudnedda na ,noitcudortni suoiverp ruo gnidrageR  .daD regdaB yldduC a
.dnopser dluow enoemos taht gnipoh
”.gnisaercni dna egassem oidua eht naht regnorts s’tI
.enoz daed evissam a fo elddim eht ni langis ssertsid a deretnuocne niart eht
.ekops ehs erofeb yltneg gnirrup ,slortnoc lareves desserp asiL  2 fo 2 traP ,sreviR neruaL yb ”eliM kraD ehT
.uoy tsniaga tes flesti tnemnorivne yrev eht htiw
,llac a hcus rewsna dluow enoyna taht eci eht no tuo epoh elttil saw erehT
.snoitacinummoc hsilbatse ot stroffe reh neewteb ni speews rosnes nur ot deunitnoc erah eohswons denimreted eht
”.llaH retsiM ,taht naht etamitse retteb a deen I“
.tsaehtron eht sdrawot ffo detrad dna niart eht morf yawa dellup yeht
.aococ toh eht fo pis a koot eillE
.ecalp ot ecalp morf gnicnuob speek langis ehT  .ris ,evitageN“
.noitnetta lacidem eriuqer dna lli era puorg ruo fo lareveS
.emit fo tol a evah t’nod ew dna detimil era seilppus ruO
,efil fo sngis on was ehs kcab gninruT
.dias yrollaM niatpaC ”,su ot pu hctac srediar esoht erofeb setunim neetfif naht ssel evah eW“  ”.ris
.trop seerged ytriht morf gnihcaorppa gnihtemos pu gnikcip m’I ,no dloH“
.mra reh dehcuot arbez ehT  ”.og ot deen eW“
.srehto eht ta pu dekool ehS
.daeh reh koohs eillE ”?srovivrus ynA“
.eye reh thguac roolf eht no tcejbo na tub
.tsap gnol syad gnirud dedrocer ecno sdrow nettirwdnah eht ta gnikool lanruoj eht hguorht deppilf eillE
.edom nacs eht degnahc dna elosnoc sih no lortnoc a desserp eH  ”.raf os toN“
”…saw ti revetahw os tnempiuqe eht fo yna htiw gnorw gnihton dewohs scitsongaiD
”.did I  .mih ot deklat I“
.deksa adnap der eht
,deretne tsuj dah yeht erehw morf etisoppo ngis llams a yb deifitnedI
,stnetnoc sti nopu noitcelfer reh ni dessorgne os saw ehs ,revoc eht no wap reH
”,esolc teg ew nehw em yfitoN“
.meht dnuora devom taht wons fo spsiw eht ni detseretni eb ot demees esle eno oN
.deddon eh ,retal tnemom A
.deredro eh ”,ti oD“
.noitisop lanif sih ni nezorf yal flow eht
,sreviR neruaL yb ”eliM kraD ehT
”.ti fo selim owt nihtiw uoy teg nac I“
,lli nellaf evah tsum puorg rieht fo eno ,yenruoj rieht gnirud tniop emos tA
.dnim reh htiw skcirt gniyalp ,enoz daed eht tsuj saw ti ebyam rO
.skcart dehctiws dah yeht detacidni niart eht fo lluh eht dna dniw dna wons eht yb delffum ,kcalc latem duol A
.roolf nezorf eht no yltneg dekcalc sevooh s’llaH tnanetueiL  .gnihtyna
”.rekaew gnitteg s’langis eht ,niatpaC“
.tsud fo etom a ekil gnitapissid erofeb niarb reh yb elbazingocer eb ot hguone gnol tsuj raeppa dluow nosrep a fo epahs a
sa rorroh tsetrohs s’dlrow eht daer
.wons eht ni deirub flah erutcurts latem llams a edistuo tsuj pots a ot emac selibomwons ruof eht sa dewols maet ehT
lanruoj eht ssorca dnah reh nar ehs ,sthguoht tsal s’yrraP nayR ta nwod gnikooL
,nwo rieht no niart eht ot regnad on detneserp yeht hguohT
”.kniht ot tahw wonk t’nod I“
”?langis taht nwod gniworran kcul yna ,eillE“
rohtuA ,sreviR neruaL yb
.rehtag ot meht egaruocne ot dednet doolb fo pord elgnis a dna
”.noitats gnihctiws txen eht ta esruoc egnahc nac eW“
,moor eht dnoyeb gnivoM
,langis tsohg a tsuj saw ti fI
.eirever reh gnirettahs ,detuohs llaH
.yrassecen snaem yna yb os gniod eunitnoc ot dednetni gnol siht detsal ohw esoht taht naem ot dednet ti
,smoortser fo riap a htiw denil erew sllaw ehT
.eliM kraD eht fo tuo dna enoz daed eht fo egde eht sdrawot meht gniyrrac drawrof degrus niart eht ,draob no maet eht htiW
.meht neewteb elbat eht no ti gnittes ,knird eht detpecca ehS
.spets reh htaeneb dehcnurc dloc fo reyal niht
.nwo reh naht ecnerefretni eht hguorht tuc ot ylekil erom erew srosnes lacitcat siH
”.CPA rediar a eb ot hguone egral s’ti tub si ti tahw llet t’nac I
.goD fo tsohG ehT ot
.nacs rehtona nar ehS
.serutaerc tneitnes wollef rieht fo thgilp eht rof nrecnoc elttil htiw
”,tsew eht morf meht fo erom pu gnikcip er’eW  .langis rediar eht ,niatpaC“
.noitats s’eillE ot noitnetta sih denruter niatpac ehT
eW‘  .esnopser ni egassem rehtona gnidnes ,desuap eillE
.llaH tnanetueiL dna renruT ssiM ot atad ruoy lla eviG“
.ecnerefretni eht htiw noitamrofni hcum evah dluow eh tcepxe ton did eillE hguohtla ,deksa eh ”?sisylanA“ .deralced arbez eht
.eliM kraD eht ni neppah dluoc gnihtyna ,lla retfA
.ruoh tsekrad rieht ni meht evas ot emoc dluow enoemos taht sepoh eht ni dam enog dlrow a delf dah yeht
.emoc reven dluow taht pleh rof llac dlo sedaced eht gnidne dna ffo noissimsnart oidar eht gnittuhs
.sepoH  .seirotS“ ”?ti ni s’tahW“
”.rehtruf yna nwod ti worran nac I kniht t’nod I  .tneserp ta elbadaer ylerab si langis ehT“
,esoprup lanigiro rieht revetahW
.emit yna etsaw t’nod dna ,gniog teG“
”,ris ,enoz daed eht ni od nac I tseB“
.noitcerid thgir eht ni su ediug ll’ti tsael tA
.niaga deggurhs eH
.lasopsid rieht ta erew secruoser revetahw htiw os enod dah retsasid eht ecnis sraey gninevretni eht devivrus dah taht esohT
,soidutS ecnecsedirI yb nooM eulB fo
,tuo dna ni dedaf ti sa rotacidni der eht dehctaw ylsuovren ehS
”!liat ruoy evom ,repraH“
:daer daetsni dluohs mrof eurt sti deniatniam evah
.taorht reh ni thguac htaerb reH
,noissim ycrem eht nodnaba ot esoohc thgim niatpac eht ,tnacifingis oot saw regnad eht fi wenk eillE
,muimerp a ta yltnatsnoc seilppus dna snoitpo detimil htiW
.dnif lliw uoy tahw wonk reven uoy
.eromyna toN  .t’nsaw eH“
.langis taht fo ecruos eht nwod worran ,eillE“
’.uoy dnif t’nac
.puorg sih dna yrraP retsiM etarepsed eht gnidia saw ehs os gniod yb fi sa
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.deksa ehs ”?su ot gniklat ereht kcab stsohg erew esoht taht em gnillet uoy erA  ?tahW“
.ylno txet ,erehwemos morf noissimsnart a pu gnikcip m’I kniht I
pleh rof llac ot htiaf fo tca emerpus a saw ti gninaem
,sesab elibom sa meht gnisu dna sreirrac lennosrep deromra gnireednammoc yb gnivivrus ot nekat dah spuorg fo rebmun a ,ezeerf eht retfA
”.eciton lliw ereht enoemos dna ykcul teg ll’ew ebyaM
”.enod s’boj ruo erofeb og ot yaw gnol a tog ev’eW  .peels emos teG“
.meht ediseb gnicnad slegna wons eht fo erom was ehs raews tsomla dluoc ehs seirrulf eht hguorhT
.srelevart daed fo tnuoma riaf a naht erom ni detluser dah meht gniretnuocnE
*	      *	      *	                                                            .dewollof dna tekcop reh otni ti dekcut ehs ,don a htiW
.aksalA nrehtron ni erehwemos noitats hcraeser cifitneics a ni egufer nekat evah srehto lareves dna ylimaf yM
,elbuort ruoy rof uoy llik dna dah uoy seilppus yna laets ot ylekil erom eb dluow ereht tuo esoht fo tsoM
.srelevart drawyaw rof yrautcnas a sa devres won ti
.daeh sih koohs arbez ehT
.dniw eht fo edis etisoppo eht no neeb gnivah raelc saw rood ehT
,ereh tuo dnuof yeht sgniht tsom rof hctam a naht erom yllareneg saw ygolonhcet rieht elihW
,god.ecioveht ta
”,taht ot su del ti dna enoz daed eht fo elddim eht ni
elttirb os mees mih gnikam ruf desopxe sih detsorf ecI
.sreksihw reh dehctiwt ehS
.yalpsid sih no langis tnettimretni eht detacidni arbez ehT
.niart eht fo llaw eht hguorht deraeppasid eh ,don a htiW
srehto ’,rood eht no kconk a saw ereht
,reh ot gnillac fi sA
.segassem eht ekil tsuj ,enoG“
.nerdlihc sih rof dah eh smaerd eht dna srobhgien dna sdneirf sih htiw ylippah gnivil ecno flow a fo yrots eht dlot yehT
.ezeerf eht erofeb emit emos retpocileh yb ereh detisoped ylekil stnemtrapmoc raludom llams wef a saw tI
.evitanretla eht etalpmetnoc ot tnaw neve ton did eillE dna
.reh erofeb neercs eht ta niaga dekool eillE
,ydaets saw langis ehT
.erutseg ot raeppa ot hguone gnol tsuj demrof htruof a dna tnemom rehtonA
.hctiws mocretni eht desserp asiL  ”.trop
.meht deviecer reve ew taht ecnedive on sah retupmoc eht tuB  .uoy eveileb I“
.noitautis rieht deredisnoc adnap der ehT
.deksa eh ”?yrraP retsiM morf esnopser ynA“
recuas a reh gnireffo
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si
”.etelpmoc noitcerroc esruoC“
.ti tuoba gnihtemos od ot snaem eht dna lliw eht evah dluow yeht taht deviecer saw ti fi neve dna
,dias eh ”,sthguoht ruoy rof aocoC“
”.ecnedicnioc tsuj naht erom saw ti ,saw ti revetahw tub
…erofeb dlrow eht morf mih htiw ekat ot detnaw eh gnihtyreve s’tI“
.edisni sehcneb fo riap a htiw sllaw eht denil raeg retniw yvaeh rof srekcol dna skooH
.egassem gnimocni na dah ehs gniciton neercs reh ta nwod dekool ehS
.tuhs nezorf yllaitrap gnieb ,detsiser hctah ehT
”?su gnisahc erew taht slangis rediar esoht tuoba tahW“
.desuap neht tub htuom reh denepo ehS
.detats llaH tnanetueiL
.dehsinif niatpac eht
”?resolc yna su teg uoy naC  .noitats hcraeser ruo eb ot tog s’tahT“
”.dootsrednU“  .dias yrollaM
.deddon adnap der ehT
”.langis ycnegreme eht gnitteg ylno llits m’I ,evitageN“
.ecaps eht fo retnec eht pu edam
.noitanitsed rieht sdrawot resolc eunitnoc dna snoitcerid tfihs elcihev evissam eht tlef eillE retal stnemoM
,llah ssem eht ni detaeS
,llits dna dloc saw ria ehT
,retal owt ro dnoces a enog saw ti deraeppa eno emit yreve tub daeh reh koohs eillE
.yrraP retsiM no dael a evah yam I langis eht nwod gniworran elbuort gnivah llits ma I elihw ,niatpaC“
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
”.ereht tuo esle gnihtemos pu gnikcip m’I ,niatpaC“
.egassem wen a dah ehs detroper rotacidni ehT ’?uoy era
.detrons dna daeh sih koohs arbez ehT .deksa eh
.enoz daed eht otni repeed reve meht gnikat dessap setunim ytrihT
.noitaterpretni ruoy ot evael ew ,kconk a ro
”,meht fo eno naht erom eb dluoc ereht rO“  ”…ro ,eliM kraD eht eb dluoc ti woN
seirots reh fo erom dnif nac uoy dna
.noissimsnart fo smrof rehto tsom naht ssel koot segassem txet
.lanruoj eht ta gnitniop ,dias eh
.reh erofeb gnidnats mih denigami dna
.tuo dellac eillE ”?yrraP
.tca eht morf deniag eb ot erom elttil saw ereht taht llew lluf gniwonk
”.ot evah I naht ereh ni erom dnoces a dneps ot tnaw t’nod I
”.noitcerid thgir eht ni su gnidiug meht tuohtiw noitats eht dnuof evah dluow reven ylbaborp ew ,si gniht ynnuF  .ecalp tsrif eht ni ereht tuo neeb reven d’yeht fi sa saw ti ,dniheb eliM kraD eht tfel ew tnemom ehT
”.su knalf ot gniyrt er’yehT  .slangis rediar erom pu gnikcip m’I ,riS“  .denworf llaH tnanetueiL  ”.noitcerid
.gnihtyreve gnirevoc tsorf fo reyal niht a htiw
,dnuob yllufituaeb dna nworb ,lanruoj llams a pu dekcip ehs ,nwod gnihcaeR
.rebmahc noitatibah niam eht otni eillE dewollof eh
,emit tsaL  .ton dluohs hcihw gnihtemos fo ecneserp
,dne dluow wons eht yad eno taht epoh sih fo dlot yrtne tsal siH
.tnemelttes ybraen a hcaer ot gniyrt neeb dah ylimaf sih dna yrraP nayR ylekil tsoM
.aera gnivil eht eb ot deraeppa tahw desuoh noitces siht ,noitats hcraeser llams eht ot edon lartnec ehT
,pleh rof llac eht ot netsil ot gnitrofmoc ti dnuof ehs wohemos teY
.niart eht edistuo erew uoy nehw esrow neve saw ti eliM kraD eht ni yaw rieht dnif ot drah saw ti thguoht dah ehs fI
,ecalp suoregnad a saw esnapxe nezorf tsav ehT
si sihT“  .gniyas saw eciov eht tahw raeh won dluoc ehs ,nepo rood eht htiW
ecnereffid eht fo ,spahrep ,noitseuq A ”.rood eht no
.elbissop sa evila meht fo ynam sa gnipeek fo sepoh eht ni retlehs rof hcraes eht gnitatissecen
.setunim owt ni noitats gnihctiws eht gnihcaorppa eb ll’eW“
”.stsohg era ereh s’taht llA  .oN“
.riahc sih ni dnuora nups llaH tnanetueiL
”.noitisop tcaxe sti gnitacol elbuort gnivah llits m’I“
,esnopser a rof tiaw ton did eH
.dad regdab yldduc
.gniraeppasid dna gniraeppa speek tI“
,sselesu ylralimis devorp lasopsid sti ta dah niart eht seitilibapac suoirav eht hguorht stluser eht retlif ot stpmettA
,rood eht no kcol a setutitsnoc derevocsid evah yeht tahw rehtehW
.daeha pu morf gnimoc eciov a fo dnuos tsetniaf eht raeh dluoc ehs ,desiar srae reH
erehW‘  .ylper reh tnes ehs ,esnopser a ni gnipyT  .dias ti ,su pleH
.dnaletsaw nezorf eht otni eciov gnidaelp sih tnes
.eliM kraD eht ni gnihtyna fo niatrec eb ot tluciffid saw ti tub
.oidar lanoitcnuf a htiw noitats hcraeser a ssorca emac yeht ,snoitpo fo tuO
”,ereht tuo gnivom erutangis taeh a ekil erom si eno sihT  .os kniht t’nod I“
.rettam eht ni eciohc elttil dah eno semitemos taht wenk ehs
.enigne eht fo tiucric raluger sih ot gninruter daetsni
.segassem eht deciton dah meht fo enoN
”.noitcerroc esruoc rof eraperp ,lennosrep llA“
,ybraen deldduh seidob fo noitcelloc llams A
.citats otni gnivlossid erofeb detats eciov elam a
.deddon asiL .deksa eh
”,su no ni gnisolc era slangis esohT  .niart eht no kcab uoy
.rednerrus ni sdnah sih pu werht eh ,gurhs a gnireffO
.denworf yrollaM niatpaC
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.slegna eht wolloF .tnemom rehtonA
:llafretniW“   yojne esaelP
”.dedne sah thgin gnol ruoY“
.resolc gnitteg erew yeht ,sdrow rehto nI
.stros fo kcolria na naht erom elttil eb ot deraeppa hcihw
lavirra rieht fo syad eht ecnis dah taht hctiws eht morf yawa sehcni yal mra rehto siH
”.nettogrof eb ot evresed t’ndid eH“
”eliM kraD eht :llafretniW“
,seY“ ”?em raeh uoy ,kcab dna erehT
,liah eht deunitnoc ehS
.derewsna eb reven dluow taht llac a saw tI
.sgnidaer reh mrifnoc ot detpmetta ehs sa gnisuap
,gnikool peek uoy sa gnol sA  .gnihcraes peeK
kcol a saw erehT“
.nopaew reh werd dna elibomwons reh ffo debmilc eillE
.knalc latem emas taht niaga ecno dna ,kcart rehtona otno niart eht dehctiws ehs ,taht htiW
.deppots dah ti etad eht htiw reverof nezorf
”.noitisop ruo fo tsaehtron nacS  .llaH tnanetueiL“
.llaH tnanetueiL ot dekool yrollaM niatpaC
.elbarenluvni ton saw niart eht
.evarg yci na ni sevlesmeht dnif ot dednet spuorg yrotaderp erom regral morf sevlesmeht dnefed ot htgnerts eht dekcal ohw esohT
”.regnol yltnacifingis ekat ll’ti noitcerid ruo esrever ot tpmetta ew fI
,nacs rehtona nar ehS
.sedaced rof ereh neeb dah yeht gnitacidni sehtolc rieht
.niaga devom rotacidni elitsoh eht sa pu dekool ehS
yrots s’thginoT dna
”.segassem esoht was I  .sgniht gninigami ton m’I“
.deksa eh ”?llac ssertsid rehtonA“
:llafretniW“ fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
selbat wol no smeti lanosrep detrossa dna ,sriahc wef a ,sehcuoC
.deggurhs llaH tnanetueiL sa tcerroc devorp sseug reH
.shtap rieht ssorc ot hguone etanutrofnu esoht dna
.niaga neercs eht ta dekool ehs ,stuodaer eht gninimaxE
.sneercs rehto eht no pu ti thguorb eH
.ecnartne eht yb hctaw tpek maet rieht fo srebmem owt rehto eht elihw
.elzzum sih delknirw eH
.gnitapissid erofeb elcric a ni gnicnad
noitacol sti nwod worran ot deirt ehs dohtem wen yreve sa
.esruoc no yats dluoc ehs arbez eht ot noitaler ni noitatneiro reh ot eud ylno saw tI
,ereht tuo er’uoy fI
.daeh reh koohs tac esemaiS ehT
”.tpecretni ot setunim ytriht detamitsE“
.setunim neetfif yreve langis ruo timsnart ot eunitnoC“
.wodniw eht edistuo epacsdnal nezorf eht ta derutseg eillE  ”.siht
”?ereh fo tuo teg ot deen ew fi etuor tseb ruo s’tahw ,asiL“
.erehw erus toN  .ybraeN
.detats eciov s’yrollaM niatpaC
,erom netfo erew ereht eno saw ereht erehw
.yawa deklaw dna deddon eh ,redluohs eht no reh gnittaP
,seirraH nomoloS yb uoy rof daer
.noitatiseh fo tnemom A
,etihw fo sekalf eht morF
.srehto eht ta kool ot dnuora denrut ehS
.dias eh ”,noissimsnart laitini taht naht rehto segassem yna fo drocer on yletulosba saw erehT
.daeh reh koohs ehs ,gnirruP
.edisni pets a koot dna nepo rood eht dellup ehs htgnerts reh fo lla htiW
.noitats s’llaH morf yalrevo lacitcat eht pu thguorb ehs
”.erutangis rewop evitca na htiw tub ,llams ,erutcurts a ekil skool tI  .gnihtemos tog ev’I“
,enoz daed eht hguorht gnilevarT
.noitavlas kees ot yenruoj sih dna ,detrats wons eht yad eht fo etorw eH
.eno ylno eht ton er’uoY
regnad fo meht nraw ot srosnes eht neve tuohtiw dnilb eb ot suovren eillE edam syawla ti hguohT
deen ew ,llaH“  .efil ot gnurps oidar s’llaH tnanetueiL
.elosnoc reh fo ecafrus htooms eht tsniaga swalc reh derab dna dessih asiL .deilper eh
.resolc gnitteg saw ti ,ereht tuo saw revetahW
,rood eht dehcaorppa ehs sa decar traeh reH
.egassem rehtona tey was dna yalpsid eht ta nwod dekool eillE
.stluser evisulcnocni erom edivorp ylno ot demees
syovnoc rellams gnikcatta
,moor a ni tas dlrow eht ni nosrep tsal ehT‘
.pleh ruoy deen ew
,nos sih dnuora depparw mra tfel sih ,taoc eulb yvaeh a ni desserD
”?noitcerid sti ot sa aedi ynA“
.goD fo ecioV ehT no goD fo tsohG ehT ot gninetsil er'uoY
.tuo dellac eh ”,ecnatsiD“
,etarepsed dna denethgirF
.egassem eht fo gnidrocer sih gniwollof tuo dessap dah eh ylekiL
.lennahc ycnegreme eht no tuo gnihcaer yrraP nayR
,seirraH nomoloS yb daeR  .ytiniffaruF no
,dedarged langis eht tneve eht ni taht wenk ehS
.reh fo tnorf ni thgis eht dleheb ehs sa ,sselnoitom ,yawrood eht ni doots eillE  .dnuorg eht otno gnillaf wons fo stib htiw
.deksa eh ”?htap tnerruc ruo ni ynA“
llac ssertsid dlo raey ytrof a pu dekcip ew wohemos si wonk I llA  .aedi on evah I“
,eci gnirettahs fo kcarc eht htiw nepo ti gnillup
.daeh sih koohs llaH
.renwo gnivol ecno sti yb deirrac smeti wef eht fo eno
.eb ot desu ti sa dlrow eht kcab gnirb dluow enoemos taht dna
.tuo dna edisni metsys eht dekcehc reenigne feihc ehT“
.mih dehcuot ehs fi rettahs thgim eh deraef ehs
,morf gnimoc erew yeht reverehW
.deggurhs eH  ”.uoy ot sknahT
eht dna ,ereht eb dluohs hcihw gnihtemos fo ecnesba eht neewteb
.gnihton morf gninnur yllaitnetop eb dluow yeht
”?snoitpO  .ecnahc eht gnikat ton m’I tub ,oN“
,hctiws eht deppilf dna drawrof deppets ehS
.dniheb morf dehcaorppa llaH tnanetueiL nehw eciton ton did ehs
.niaga nageb egassem ehT
,hctawtsirw a saw tsirw sih dnuora deppartS
,stuodaer eht ot noitnetta reh gninruteR
,moor eht deretne eh reh dniheB
retsiM“  .nehctik eht dnoyeb tsuj doots moor oidar eht
.mra reh no wap a tlef ehs sa gnisuap
,esle gnihtyna ro slegna wons eht ro stsohg saw siht fi wonk t’nod I“
.srae reh denettalf ehS
.dnah a pu dleh llaH
,evael ot denrut ehS  .deddon eillE
.elcihev evissam eht fo thgis tsol ehs erofeb etunim a naht ssel ton saw ti yawa gnilluP
?yaw ruoy no uoy erA
,deksa llaH ”?ereh enoyna sI“
”.era yeht tahw s’taht erus eb neve t’nac eW“
.stegrat dednefed llew ssel fo hcraes ni dnaletsaw nezorf eht demaor taht lareves erew ereht seitic regral dnuora eb ot dednet yeht hguohT
.nonemonehp larutan elpmis a tsuj eb ot evila ot esolc oot demees yeht taht yned ton dluoc eno teY  .noisulli rehto ro egarim a ekil ,noitanigami eht fo skcirt tsuj erew yeht reh dlot cigoL
.noitats hcraeser eht ot yaw eht lla meht denodnaba reven yeht was ehs ynam woh rettam on tub
.ylsuoiruc deinnihw dna doots ehs erehw ot pu deklaw llaH tnanetueiL
,mils erew meht gnidnif fo sddo ehT
.yrassecen naht regnol yna aera eht ni niamer ton yeht evitarepmi erom hcum taht ti ekam dluow ti meht gnitnuh srediar erew ereht fI
”,ycneuqerf emas siht no esnopser ruoy dnes esaelP
.saw ehs spahrep dnA
lavivrus nwo rieht rof gnithgif eci eht gnimaor spuorg rehto dna srediar erew ereht nehw
.taht naht cificeps erom teg ot tluciffid saw ti tnaem enoz daed eht fo erutan eht tub
,ecno ta deraeppa slegna wons eerht sa desuap dna saremac lanretxe eht detavitca eillE
.stnemtrapmoc rehto eht ot ffo gnidael srood dna ,aera nehctik a
.laturb dna demra llew netfo erew yeht elpoep ytnewt naht erom ylerar hguohT
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
,staebtraeh ,gnihtaerB
.emac ew yaw eht kcab og ot gniyrt naht esruoc tnerruc ruo no eunitnoc ew fi retsaf s’ti tniop siht ta ,niatpaC“
.puorg s’yrraP nayR morf eb ot dah ti
eht edisni wap toof detoob reh gnicalP
.daeh reh koohs eillE  .diuqil nworb toh fo puc gnimaets a htiw
.etagitsevni ot enog evah yeht ,ytilibissopmi eht yb deugirtnI
.desuap ehs ,pu ti gnignirB
,niaga langis ssertsid eht ot denetsil eillE