,emit tsrif eht did eh ekil tsuJ
,hcT“ .strohs s’reviR fo tuo wap sih dils dna erutcip lluf eht tog god eht
.erow yeht strohs dna strihs tenhsif rieht hguorht
”?ti dekil eh yas eh diD“
”.ereh llits m’I .em tuohtiw ti od nac uoY .ecnad ot ekil yllaer t’nod I wonk uoY“
.semit hguone kcehc elbuod t’ndluoc eh
.erehpsomta eht yb derutpac sa etiuq ton ,dias rotciV
ruf sih otni gnibbur deppots namrebod ehT
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,detuohs ylraen reviR
,seitilibisnopser htiw delddas won ,sdneirf dlo sih fo llA
.ti ta gniog yllaer eb ot dekool eh
,mra s’deR deppals eH
”.semag dnim gniyalp eno eht er’uoY .elohssa ynroh emos tsuj s’eH“
.ytic detaidar thgil eht ni
”.tey tnorf eht ta ton er’eW“ .meht fo
.won neve noitisop tcaxe taht ni llits erew
noisses snokroD & snoegnuD thgin yadirF sih pu evig ot dediced dneirfyob sih
,mih fo tuo tib elttil a koot enil ni gnitiaW
.rethgual htiw bulc eht fo tuo gniraor emac puorg egral a
.nirg ykcoc sih revo gnikcil deR saw ti
.rehto hcae ees dluoc yeht litnu
,yad ot yad etautculf secirp tekciT
.enil eht ni ffo tfel d’eh erehw gnillorcs ,no ti dehctiws dna
.meht dnuora lla ksud gnihtoos a ni netfos ot sllaw eht denil
,enil eht ni mih gnivohs rof seigolopA
mih tem reven eh hguohT
,dias eh ”,gnicnad rof pu m’I fi erus ton m’I dna yad a neeb s’yadoT
,dellab tsif ,gnihsal liat ,denettalf srae
elttil a neeb evah thgim tI
”ecnaD eM hctaW naC uoY“:yojne esaelP
.keew a rof deppirts semag oediv dna noitneted htiw emac ti ,delffucs eh emit tsaL
.mih fo tnorf ni nwod ti demmals yllacitcarp knuks eht sa
.stnerap s’teneg eht htiw tsafkaerb tsuj naht erom eb ot desoppus saw worromoT
ecnalab-ffo mih tes ylraen ot hguone drah eno
”.knarf eb ot ,ti dekil uoy ekil dekool tI“
”.ecnad taht evol yllaer d’I
.ediskcab dna ymmut sih no ruf eht tsniaga ria dloc tlef eh sa noos sa nwod kcab meht gnikcud
redluohs sih no gnola deggat ylno nagidrac allinav tsedom siH
,taes sih otni delttes eh sa denialpmoc rotciV
erehps tnecsednacni detum tub egral a rednu tsuJ
,demihc rotciV ”,edur saw taht
gnileef saw eh gnihtyreve ffo gnikahs fo yaw sih saw tI
.repmihw saw od dluoc eh lla taht
”,dnoces a ni edisni eb ll’yehT“
.sretcarahc ssa gnirob dna ,gnikam noisiced xam/nim ,nuf dengised
.teg annog saw eh tseb eht saw tahT
.eye sih thguac eh thgin tsrif taht ot kcab nekat teg flesmih gnittel
”?ecnad em hctaw tsael ta uoy naC“
tsirw s’namrebod eht dnuora depparw liat gnol siH
,luos sih fo ssendoog eht fo tuo ,yllufknahT
.elbisivid ylisae t’nerew taht erutinruf fo htrow sraey neves dna
.syraM ydoolB sah taht erehwemos tuo og ll’eW
.emit eht lla ti raeh ot gniyonna fo dnik dna enilef a ton ,tsrif ,yakO
,thgin nwo sih niur ot ton gniyrT
”?yas annog er’uoy lla s’tahT ?ti s’tahT“
rettiwT no etoyoCtriD ta mih wolloF
,esirprus s’reviR ot ,rehto eht ni dna
.elzzum sih fo edis eht pu gnipeerc elims llams a kcab peek t’ndluoc rotciV
.diputs ton er’uoY
,deniur gnieb saw thgin s’ohw eno eht ,dneirfyob sih ,elihw eht llA
.setadpu erutuf rof
hguone gnorts erew egats eht raen srekaeps eht morf gnitsalb esaB
.seye sih otni kool ot daeh sih tfil t’ndid reviR
,suoretsiob dna gnilimS
.ecnereffid eht llet ot elba eb t’ndluow reviR dna won thgir edisni egrab dluoc enil taht ni ydobyreve ,tcaf nI
.sdrow sih sa swap sih htiw hcum sa tsuj deklat eh sa dnuora debbob ydob reppu eritne s’namrood eht
?ti eveileb uoy naC“
,snaej sih nrow d’eh fI
”?ydaerla ecnad tsuj ew naC .ebab ,ti tegroF“
,riahc sih morf gnidnatS
”?syawyna sknird eht rof su eguog ot gniog er’yeht fi eef ecnartne eht gniyap neve fo tniop eht s’tahW“
,meht fo owt eht neewteb ecnalg s’namrood eht tA
tnorf ni snoillats eht sdrawot gnitniop
,won rof tub ,ebyaM“
t’nerew uoy fi reippah eb d’yehT
,doog saw yllaer tI
drac eht koot enirevlow ehT
.mih rof tib elttil a tsuj pu ti ecips dna yrt ot detnaw eh fi mih deksa reviR retfa
,snoillats ,snoil ,sregit ,sexof ,senimre ,sknuks ,shateehc ,sevlow ,seiksuh ,sexoF
,rumrum ot ni gninael erofeb mih detadimitni rotciV
.llac tsal erofeb ruoh na roolf ecnad ytpme raen a no dnuora gnigniws teneg eht dehctaw rotciV
.desufnoc taes sih ni kcab dellup rotciV ”?tahW“
,levon a gnidulcni stcejorp gnitirw suoirav no skrow
.elzzum sih fo egdirb eht no thgir ssik rehtona gnitnalp dias rotciV
taes sti ni tis ot riahc eht elacs yllacitcarp ot dah teneg trohs eht ,gnilbmurG
,htiw gnitautcnup erofeb drow tsal eht gnitagnole
eh taht rotciV llet ot gniog saw eh erofeb tsuj dna
flesmih ekil tsuj sdik erew rab eht gnidnuorruS
,egdun rehtona mih denrae tahT
!kcabtes rojam a toN
gnissarrabmE .daeh sih revo selcric ni dnuora pot knat eht gnigniws pu wap a htiw
.deb ni ekil kool d’yeht tahw ezisatnaf ot evah t’ndid eh
.rehtegotla enil eht fo tuo dna
,pleh sih tuohtiw pu saw tahw ezilaer ot gniog ton saw rotciV taht gniwonK
.niaga pu gnitrats skrowretaw eht
.enohp sih ot kcab gninrut erofeb teneg ta daeh sih dekcoc eh
.revoc d’eh snalp levart eht tuoba meht fo lla ot ecnuonna dluow rotciV ,uoy knaht a sA
nwod mlac ot mih teg ot hguone erew sessik erom wef A
.strohs sih htaeneb gniraeppasid ylgnisaet erofeb pu yaw eht llllllllla dellevart dna skcos kcalb sih evoba tsuj detrats yehT
dnoces a neercs sih revo pu dekcilf seye s’rotciV
,knird sih fo pis gnol a gnikaT
,hsoohS“ .mih ot gnizigolopa saw
srednetrab eht htiw trilf ot revo tneb sexof dna ,seinnub ,sterref ,sdrapoel
.devom eh yaw eht tuoba railimaf gnihtemos rof teneg eht dehcraes rotciV ,ni gninaeL
.htiw ni deklaw eh gnatsum dna eladsedylc eht neewteb noitnetta sih gnittilps saw
.dnim ot emac sreeb owt htiw kcab gnimoc dneirfyob sih fo thguoht gniyrrow A
.mriuqs a teg ot hguone mih gnilkcit ,kcarc s’reviR hguorht regnif retniop sih desserp neve eh ,tcafnI
,derepsihw god eht erofeb srevihs ni ruf s’reviR gniltsirb
,neeb dah s’namrebod eht erehw wap sih gnidilS
,dneirfyob sih ot detniop saw elzzum sih hguohT
.flesmih knuks eht dna ,stnerap rieht
,tekcop sih otni enohp sih deffuts rotciV
,ylgnihtoos liat nwo sih gnikortS
,hgU“ .dneirf sih ot kcab gniklaw ydaerla
.yrots detfarc ylluferac eht ot egamad eromyna gnisuac morf reviR tneverp ot
,won rof tub ,tluciffid os thgin siht gnikam rof dewo eh nwo sih fo seigolopa noillim a dah eh wenk eH
,srae eht neewteb skcep ot devom tsuj rotciV
,ti tuoba yas ot tnereffid gnihtyna dah sdneirf sih fo yna fi dna
,deksa rotciV ”?mih ta ,ekiL ?daM“
,rac rieht ,sdneirf rieht ,tnemtrapa rieht ,sllib dah yehT
.swalc sih tsniaga kcab dehsup eh dna
.ssalg gniyfingam a ot dleh gnitteg saw esle gnihtyrevE
.sregrub gnippilf dna ,seirf gniyrf ,sehsid gnibburcs llits saw eh dna retal sraey ruoF
.deltrats dnuora dekool dna
,emit morf emit detapicitrap ylsuoiruc dneirfyob sih erofeb
”.elohssa namrebod taht fo tuo tihs eht kcik em hctaw nac uoy ,rO“
,looc flesmih gnipeeK
DI sih ees ot dedeen rednetrab dna recnuob eht ylnO
,evohs a dna ,trons a mih denrae tahT
.ydaerla fo kniht nac I sgniht owt s’ereht ,daeh ym fo pot eht ffo thgir ,ekiL“
,ecnalg desufnoc a htiw ti koot knuks ehT
,enil eht dna krow morf eros llits ,ylwols doots eH
,moor eht fo renroc dedulces a sdrawot ylefas erew yeht litnu ti gniod saw eh gnizilaer neve ro gnikniht tuohtiw ,niagA
.ot desu saw eh tahw fo ynotonom llud eht dnoyeb raf mih deticxe osla tub
eson sih morf yawa enohp eht dellup rotciV
.ti sserpxe ot teltuo na evah t’ndid eh nehw
dna snedrag elbategev gnidnet ni
.sgel nat sih dnuora depparw stops etalocohc sih fo nrettap eht derimda evah dluoc eno on
,tfel ygrene yna evah ew fi dna
elzzum sih no noisserpxe suoregnad a htiw elbat eht revo gninael ,taes sih fo tuo s’reviR
,lworg wol a tuo tel deR ,revo gninaeL
.reilrae skeew owt tsomla spuc gniddup gnorw eht emoh thguorb rotciV nehw dam gnitteg dna ,liam eht barg ot gnittegrof
.nuf gnivah eb ot desoppus saw eH
.regnarts eht naht erom sraet eht gnithgif
.krow ffo llac ll’I
.dluoc eh tseb sa mih gnisserac
.evom a ekam ot namrebod eht rof gnitiaw dna nwod ti gnittes erofeb pis kciuq a koot dna
ti depiws eh sa deddon dna
”.irodiM fo tohs dedda na htiw dnalsi gnol a s’tahT“ ,denialpxe eh
.syawyna owt-ytnewt llits saw teneg eht ,deksa enoyna fi dna seitnewt ylrae sa emas eht erew seitnewt etaL
hguone nwod mih delttes noitcurtsed emoS
”,deniur s’gnihtoN
,egelloc fo raey tsal eht depleh dah yenom ehT
,enohp sih ni detsevni oot llitS
,erats sih dekcol eninac ehT
,del eb ot flesmih dewolla teneg ehT
.gnivaw regnif a dna
,shtnom neeb d’tI
bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoY
”,ro ,ecnad em hctaw rehtie nac uoY
.swalc kciht sih htiw doow eht hguorht senil wen hserf gniggard
.eciuj egnaro fo ssalg a neeb tsuj evah dluoc ti ro ,tahT
”?moorhtab eht ni mih pmuj ll’ew
,mih eporg ot namrebod eht gniwolla
.mih tcidartnoc ot dneirf ssel eno evah d’eh
?tuoba taht saw kcuf gniylf eht tahW ?kcuf eht tahW
.ecaf sih no elims ediw a htiw teneg eht ta gnitniop
.eromyna s’yttaP dereppeP rof gnikrow eb ot desoppus neve t’nsaw eH
”!aeT decI oykoT ruoy rof srallod gnikcuf ytnewT
?tuoba gniklat uoy era taem tahw ,dnoceS
,dias reviR ”,thginot deniur I yrros m’I“
.kcehc noitutitsnoc a evlovni t’ndid taht sneeuq dna seiriaf htiw ffuts od dluoc yeht os
nwod ssalg sih tis ot mih rof yltneitap detiaw reviR
,dluoc eh sa gnorts sa deyats reviR
.smra sih gnidlof elihw dehgual rotciV
.neeb dah ti erehw yltcaxe wap sih tfel eh
,werc eht fo rebmem gniknird wed niatnuom no lluf yllautneve dna
,derepsihw rotciV ”,hsoohs ,hsoohs
,tif dliw emosenol sih
.daetsni sbat hguorht deppilf dna elims eht dessim rotciV
.revirdwercs a saw demussa eh tahw saw
warts eht dnuora spil sih gnipparw erofeb rits a ti gnivig ,ssalg eht pu dekcip reviR
,yldeticxe nwod dna pu daeh sih gniddoN
.no kcab pot knat sih tup dna
sllor niatrec tuoba eil dluow eh taht hguone gniyonna saw ti semitemoS
.noitcif yrruf citore trohs dna ,allevon a
.ti tuoba deticxe gnitteg tsuj saw dna
,snoitome war htiw gniwolfrevo llits dna redlo sraey neves
.mih egnellahc ot rotciV gnicaf nirg sih
.aera gnitaes eht ni
.erew snaej eht naht yxes erom neve ton fi yxes sa tsuj tlef strohs ograc eht taht thguoht eh ,yllautcA
.sriahc tuohtiw elbat a revo gnidnats snamrebod owt erew mih ot tsesolC .syob
.dneirfyob sih fo tnorf ni thgir deldnof eb ot deunitnoc eh elihw ti gnippis dna
.esruoc fo ,seye wolley gnicreip dna elims enitsirp sih sediseb
,laitnetop s’nos rieht tuoba gniklat fo thgiarts raey a tsomla retfA
,ohw ,etoyoC triD yb
.meht revo yletelpmoc ydaerla ,namrebod eht ot regnif a gnitniop
gnitseretni yletomer gnihtemos fo kniht neve ot gniyrt deretsulf tlef eh semit lareveS
kcab dehcaer eh sa dias reviR ”,draC“
,erac ot ton gnimeeS
?tuoba ffo dessip os eh saw tahW
.rehtegot erew yeht langis ot rotciV dna mih neewteb debmuht dna tuo drac tiderc sih dils eH
.repaehc teg reve d’yeht eetnaraug on dna won thgir wol ytterp erew yeht ,rewol meht nees d’eh hguoht dna
.tnar sih htiw gnola deunitnoc tsuj rotciV sseleulc ,tcaf nI
derettum reviR ”,hctiB“
,seohs sinnet elbatrofmoc erom sih rof edart t’ndid knuks eht taht erus edam d’eh taht niatrec rof wenk eh hguoht nevE
,s’yttaP dereppeP ta hsid tsal eht gnibburcs dehsinif eh sa noos sA
,tif meht ekam ot gniyrt ruoh na flah retfA
pu saw gnihtemos wonk ot demees deR elihw eht llA
,dnoces a rof elbmuf sdrow eht
,etihw nrut ot nageb yeht taht ylthgit os rehtegot spil sih gnisruP
.esolc oot nettog d’eh fi mih morf yawa pets ot deeh koot selpuoC
,dik a saw eh nehw ot desu eh ekil tuo gniog laeR
.mra tnanimod sih htiw mih ekahs tsuj t’ndid eh yhw ees ot dekcehc eh elihw ti otno gnidloh
,hguoht thgir dna tfel gniylf smrA
gniknird ton esohT
,dereviuq spil s’reviR
?stenhsif gniraew obmih emos htiw lwarb a otni teg ot gniog saw eh taht kniht yllaer reviR diD
,eulc eht gnitteg tsomlA
,enoyreve fo tnorf ni ereht thgir ssem a gnimoceb fo tnemssarrabme mih gnirapS
,flesmih gnicudortni dna wap a gnidnetxe
.eugnot sih otno nwod delbbird pord tsal eht litnu kcab yaw eht lla ssalg eht deppit eh sa hteet tnorf sih tsniaga dekcilc ecI
.em tuohtiw tratS“
.retcarahc ym dellik uoy ,hcum oot knard I taht emit tsal eht esuaceb tsuj s’taht dnA
.gniporg eht morf delzzarf llits saw eh tub nwod flesmih looc ot deirt reviR
”!bulc thgin a fo edisni tuoba dna tuo er’eW
,elbat eht htaenrednu tnew wap s’rotciV
hcuot deticilosnu s’regnarts a fo noitasnes eht dah d’eh ecnis gnol os neeb d’ti tub ,yas dluoc eh dehsiw reviR sgniht erew esohT
,won thgir ecnad tsuj su fo htob tuob‘ woH“
.sedapacse thgin etal sih dna mih gninioj enod erew dna pu derentrap dah sdneirf s’teneg eht fo llA
.ni drow tsal eht gnitteg tuohtiw ton tub
.sroloc dna snrettap fo epocsodielak a ni gniwolg rab eht saw
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.knuks eht fo tnorf ni thgir gniod saw eh tahw laecnoc ot stnemevom kciuq yna morf deniarfer eh tub pots eh did tniop on tA
.rehtegot hctaw t’ndid yeht taht wohs a t’nsaw ereht dna syad rieht revo enog ydaerla d’yehT
,mih thgif ot neht hguone llew wenk rotciV ”.esaelP“
”,diputs os m’I .taht naem t’ndid I .yrros os m’I .yrros m’I“
.egelloc fo tuo weivretni tsrif sih dah d’eh nehw mih rof thguob dah reviR srefaol rehtael kcils eht gniraew saw yllaer eh ,yllufknahT
dnah rehto eht no ,yksuh a dna naitamlad a ,syob tarf owT
”?ecnad ot tnaw t’nod uoy dna tuo era eW“
.niaga noitnetta s’rotciV rof dehguoc eh os ,hcum siht ti gnikil rof ytliug leef ot gnitrats saw osla tub
.sknird eht evas ot tsuj enohp sih nwod tup ot decrof saw rotciV dna ylsuoregnad tuoba decnuob yeht tub ,deppit rehtieN
.tuo ruop ot denetaerht taht gnihtyreve edisni dloh ot thgit os dezeeuqs seye dna ,pil tib
.eno t’nsaw llits eh taht ton
.sruf yerg yarts yna fo dekculp neeb dah kcen dna smra sih no stops eht sa llew sa
.htap sih raen gnidnats eb ot hguone etanutrofnu enoyna gnippihw liat
.tuo reviR nekat dah enoyna ecnis ,shtnom
ti gnisu mih ees dluoc eh erus ekam dna niaga enohp sih llup tsuj ot detnaw mih fo trap ,ylgnittimdA
,meht htiw gniklaT
.elbat eht ssorca egar teiuq eht eciton neve ot enohp eht otni detsevni oot saw rotciV
,detrups eh ”?tahW“
:gnicnad dna aeT oykoT naht erom devol eh gniht ylno eht htiw flesmih detcartsid eh ,tnemugra eht fo ffo dnim sih ekat ot gniyrT
.saesrevo noitacav ot stnerap rieht htob dna mih rof thgilf esirprus a gnisahcrup saw eh elihw hctib a ekil gnitca neeb dah reviR ,thgin llA
,erusaem doog rof mra nwo sih tsniaga gnipiW
wap a rof detiaw eH
enil ni mih ot txen doots rotciV
,dluoc eh sa gnimrasid sa eb ot deirt reviR
.tuons sih ni tfel gnihtyna pu delffins dna
.bulc eht ssorca reviR no sucof yllautca ot hguone tuo mih dewollem tI
ees t’ndluoc yeht srats eht ekil kool gniliec eht edam slenap kcalb morf gnuh sblub enillatsyrC
.nottub ”won yub“ eht gnisserp fo trohs tsuj saw eh taht dalg elttil a saw eh
.telbat a delruc rehto eht elihw dednetxe wap eno htiw reviR deksa eh ”?drac ro hsaC“
.feilebsid ni dekcoc daeh sih
,shtnom neeb d’tI
.roolf ecnad eht fo ffo
.mih derussaer rotciV
.ti rof diap eh srallod ytnewt eht htrow neve ebyam
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.teiuq ti peek dluoc eh tsael ta hguoht
.krap tnemesuma na ta buc a ekil tuoba gnihsal liat sih
elihw tnatsid saw flesti cisum eht tub ,elbat eht etarbiv ot
.slaoc toh revo saw eh ekil dnuora ydob sih dekrej ti
rotciV .erutan suoregnad sti fo stnih on gnirahs ,teews saw tI
.tub gnihtyna neeb sah thginot dna
,ykSkcalB eht ot klaw ot meht koot ti naht enil ni regnol detiaw yeht tcaf eht etipseD
.rab eht ta kcab detniop eh dna
.enif er’uoY .taht rof deen on s’ereht ,hhhS“
.tixe eht ot gnitniop ,dehsinif eh
.daeh sih evoba hgih smra sih hcterts t’ndid eh sa gnol os ylleb sih pu derevoc llits ti
,elbat eht no stsif sih gnimmals
?emoh kcab mih ees d’eh dna bulc eht evael ot gniog saw eh ,ekiL ?evaeL
”.elbisnopser yrev ton s’tahT“
,tnetxe emos ot ti yojne tub pleh t’ndluoc reviR
,nihc sih debmuht reviR
.detutitsbus strohs ograc etihw fo riap
.ees ot mih rof tnappilf dna citsalp yldetniop saw s’reviR hguoht neve
.flesmih rof ylno saw ecnad s’teneg eht taht dootsrednu eh thguoht eh
wap sih htiw elzzum sih detfil tsuj rotciV tub
.ti tuoba gnikniht neve tuohtiw stsirw sih yb yob rehto eht debbarg dna revo deklaw rotciV
mih evig ot mih rof gnitiaw saw deR taht ees dluoc eh ,mih ot dekool reviR nehw dna
.suoires saw tseuqer s’reviR gnizilaer won
.thgif a detnaw eh ekil mees t’ndid knuks eht fi neve ,noisnet emos saw erehT
.hguorht kaerb ot deganam d’eh
sebut tnecseroulf eulb miD
.ffo ti deggurhs eh tub yletaidemmi gnikcilc t’nsaw teneg yttuls gnihton toof evif eht htiw
reviR morf kaeuqs a decrof hcnip A
”?anoroC“ ”?thgir ,emil htiw thgil anoroC
.pis rehtona rof knird sih gnibbarg dna seye sih gnillor
.mih kram ot desu eh taht pot knat wolley eht dnif ot elbanu
.stnerap ot stisiv dna ,serohc ,sllib ,krow sa suoidet sa tlef lla tI
.tnaem reviR tahw tuo erugif t’ndluoc eh tub
”,m’I .si taht tahw wonk I ,mmm ,—I ,oN“
.kcehc ot mih rof tuo DI sih dah teneg eht
.sucof sih fo tuo yletelpmoc saw teneg eht
,gurhs a htiw dewollof dna aera elbat eht sdrawot kcab detniop knuks eht ,dnoces a rof gniliart
”.uoy rof kool ll’I ,pu hsinif I nehW“
”—gdew emil yek elttil eht htiW
,hE“ .noisulcnoc a ot gnimoc erofeb dnoces a rof ti tuoba gnikniht
,pu-trats a rof ysserd
,elbignat enoemos no desucof erom erew ohw esoht ot lanoitnetni
,eromyna dda nac rotciV erofeB
.sesiurb suoiretsym dna srevognah naht rehtar sbuc ysion
.nuf gnihtyreve revo teknalb tew a ekil tlef knuks eht won dna
.sbos hguoht reviR sa flesmih decudortni teneg eht elihw
detseretni erom erew yeht ,woN
,tnemeticxe sih kcab dloh t’ndluoc llits reviR tub
erom ecno yllufyalp mih devohs reviR erofeb ,guh a dna
.tcefrep neeb evah dluohs tI
”.dam eb ot desoppus s’taht eno eht er’uoY .ton ro ti deyojne I fi rettam t’nseod tI“
.nwod edispu ekahs ot deirt yldrawkwa dna wap tfel sih htiw pu dehcaer eh ,ssa s’teneg eht gnidaenk eunitnoc ot gnitnaW
etilop deniamer elims siH
”.otni knis ot taem emos htiw seittik ym ekil I“
.drac eht no ecaf s’reviR thguac eh litnu dednah gnieb saw eh tahw erus etiuq ton ,denoitseuq enirevlow eht ”?mmH“
.ylthgit stsif sih dellab eh sa smlap nwo sih otni gud swalC
,gnittap eht pots ot tsuj tuo enohp sih evah dluoc
,sraet eht fo tsrow eht hguorht gnieb etipseD
,rettiwT no elbuort fo stros lla gnisuac t'nsi eh nehw
!thgin D&D no—“
,flow ehtil a rof detepmoc
.nwo sih no bulc eht fo tuo klaw tsuj ot ton
sregnif sih sa ylisae sa dnim sih htiw ti gniliart ,ruf nworb dna kcalb trohs eht ni koot reviR
.roolf ecnad eht fo retnec eht otni kcab rotciV gnidael erofeb pu flesmih denaelc eh
.tellaw sih tuo dellup dna
,retaw ekil mih hguorht gniwolf cisum eht fo daetsnI
.strohs sih fo kcab eht nwod dils wap a
.reisae deppuc eb dluoc eh os taes eht ffo flesmih detfil eh ,yllarutaN
,t’nsaw eh raelc saw ti nehW .lavorppa deerga
.tons dna sraet ni cirbaf dna snottub gnikaos ,tsehc s’rotciV otni gniruop emac seigolopa noillib A
.yadirF no sanoroC knird syawla uoY“
,sdnamed teneg eht ”,aeT .decI .oykoT .A .tnaW .I“
.hsirevef naht citnarf erom saw ecnad siH
,ekops eh sa tcatnoc eye ekam ot
.emag eht rof evol sih detingier ti
.deciton dah wolleY erofeb ton dna gnirats saw eh taht ezilaer eh did etal ooT
,sdneirf D&D ydren s’rotciV erew tfel dah eh taht elpoep ylno ehT
.tuo tog rotciV nehw laer gnihtemos eusrup dna egaw muminim tiuq dluow reviR taht deerga d’yeht tub
,laidroc tub deyonnA
,ylyls dias deR
.rood eht ot txen gnidnats enirevlow eht ot sesroh eht tsap tsuj gnitniop ,denihw reviR
.erats ot hguone dlob enoyna ot sdoog eht gnitneserp osla elihw
,wolley eno dna der eno ,meht revoc ot spartskcoj rieht ylno htiW
,llits tpek traeh sih ,dnoces a roF
demees evah thgim sevom sih elihW
”.elbatneserp er’ew erus ekam dna su egrahc tsuj ot si boj sih kniht I ,ebaB“
,worb sih gniworruF
.sknird htob su teg ot gniog saw I gniylpmi saw I ,hgu -naem I ?tahW“
.wap desiar a htiw mih dessimsid eh ,gnikool tuohtiW
,elbatneserp gnieb fo noitnem eht tA
.gnippohs yrecorg morf emoh gniklaw oyorf fo puc a gniggans ro seivom eht ot tuo gniog ,ekil ,toN
sekorts htiw dewollof saw ecnetnes yrevE
.mih ta dam eb ot desoppus saw eh taht flesmih dnimer dna nwod ti hsauqs ot troffe fo tib a koot tI
nwod mih mlac ot edis eht ot mih koot eh
.gnilwab neewteb tuo tel eh
gniod saw eh tahw fo suoicsnoc-fles nettog evah tsum eh ,niaga stops sih gnirevoC
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
esool A .regnol hcum tiaw ot dah eh fi edisni yats ot denetaerht rotciV
”,ecnad em hctaw rehtie nac uoY“
.pu dewohs reviR erofeb tlef D&D sa suonotonom sa tsuj emaceb lla ti
,ecnad sih hguorhT
”?ylsuoireS ?aeT oykoT A“ ”.aeT
,elbat eht ssorca dehcaer eh
,siht derebmemer rotciV
.yleritne revo ti gnippit tsomla ,kcab dekconk tog riahc eht taht tsaf os dnuora nups eh sa mih degdelwonkca liat sih ylno tub
.enif eb ll’daD dna moM
.etib yna dekcal sdrow sih hguoht ,deksa eh
.teneg dekcinap eht ot suoivilbo
,ylhguor os mih gnihcnip saw god eht taht tib elttil a truh tI
dneirfyob sih saw ti taht ezilaer eh did roolf ecnad eht no gninepo eht was eh litnu ylnO
.pis tseinit eht gnikat dna ssalg sih gnibbarg
.od ot tahw gnikniht thguac saw namrebod eht dna
,gnihcnurc rebmun emoceb dah gnihtyrevE
.hcamots sih morf yawa mih llup dluoc eh os
,egats ot revo decar teneg eht sa tsaf sa decar dnim s’rotciV
,kcab sraey wef a ti thguob eh nehw sa llew sa etiuq gnah t’ndid pot knat wolley sih hguohT
.noitartsurf ni dneirfyob sih ta deralg reviR
,noitnetta rof ysuolaej poleved ylluf neve dluoc reviR erofeB
,mih fo tnorf ni gnittis enohp eht pu kcip dluoc eH
.redro ym gnikat neve erofeb esle enoyreve tuoba tsuj sevres rednetrab eht dna dnuora gnidnats yug tsellat eht m’I ,esruoc fo dnA“
,ecneserp-flah gnikcom ot demrofsnart ytisoiruc s’reviR nehW
niaga enohp sih tuo dellup eh ,taht htiW
.niaga kcab drac eht dnah ot gniyrt erofeb htrib fo etad eht ta ecnalg ot gnidneterp ,ylduol oot elttil a demialcxe eh ”!thgir ,hO“
.nuf gnihtyreve gnikam edis sih yb ereht thgir saw reviR nehw saw puorg dneirf sih htiw sthgin tseb eht fo emos ,kceH
.sliat detfil fo eireganem a saw erehT
.doom sih did os dna dloc yllarutannu tlef raer sih ,wap a tnesbA
.detrats tsuj s’thgin ehT .nuh ,ebab ,ebaB“
.syawyna meht gnitteg saw eh taht ecin tlef yeht
:sngis gninraw eht lla ees dluoc eh
.kniwt eht gnirahs ni detseretni rehtien
.nwo sih no tuo og ot ekil t’ndid eh esuaceb saw gnol os ni tuo enog ton d’eh yhw nosaer ylno eht ,tsenoh gnieb ,yllautcA
,gniksa erofeb dnoces a epag wam sih tel reviR ,dehsinotsA
.ssalg eht ot stnerruc gnidnes llab amsalp a ekil reviR morf detpure ygrene eht fo llA
.ecnad wols a fo elddim eht ni erew yeht ekil kool ot hguone esolc ,thgit tpek yehT
erow eh tiftuo emas tcaxe eht tsomla gniraew xof A
.taorht sih deraelc dna yltnatalb dehguoc reviR ,rab eht ot nrut ot deirt eh nehw tub
”,evael em hctaw nac uoy rO“
aeT oykoT eht debbarg eh ,revirdwercs eht naht redrah elttil a gnihtemos gnitnaW
.teef s’rentrap sih ot keep a dekaens reviR
.roolf ecnad eht ot gnitfihs regnif sih ,dekrab reviR
.mih rof pu elims a dekrow neve dna
.sknird eht elttar ot elbat eht tsniaga hguone drah stsif htob gnimmals erofeb
,deruos dias eh ”,esaet ’nikcuf
,buc dedlocs a ekil nwod daeh sih tpek tsuj eH
.enohp eht ot kcab seyE
noom eht eb ot tnaem
.eson sih ot pu thgir regnif a dah eh erofeb ni drow a teg mih tel neve t’ndid reviR tub ,tsrubtuo s’teneg eht tuoba dnim nwo sih evig ot ydaer tuoba dekool ,suoiruf ,rotciV
skcals egieb emas eht no dah knuks ehT
,riahc sih ni depmulf dneirfyob sih elihw
.srentrap rieht htiw emit rieht gnikat
,seigolopa dedeen taht eno eht saw eh ekil leef t’ndid eh hguohT
.mih rof tuo dial eh snalp eht niur ot gniog saw reviR taht nwonk evah dluohs rotciV
,dne s’thgin yb dneirfyob a evah d’eh fi erusnu saw eh elihw ,woN
”,tib tsethgils eht toN
.gninrom taht krow ot nrow d’eh
.gnidnesednoc gnikcuf os t’nsaw ti fi gniraedne eb dluow tI
.loohcs ot kcab og ot mih ecnivnoc pleh ot desimorp d’yeht
.enecs a diova ot cisum eht ot emit evitaler ni stnemevom rieht tpek eh ,htrof dna kcab mih gnildarC
”.esle gnihtemos od dna emoh og tsuj nac eW“
,ecin eb dluow taht ,oN
.thginot tiftuo sih no tuo lla tnew eh tsael tA
,mih ot drow a dias neve ro
.edistuo enil depmarc eht naht elbatrofmoc erom ylbaredisnoc saw edisnI
”ecnaD eM hctaW naC uoY“
”.won thgir gniporg er’uoy dneirfyob ym s’taht ,mU !hO...hO“
.sucof fo tuo saw gnicnad mih ,rehtaR
.hsif a ekil rednuolf mih gnihctaw fo daetsni
na fo daetsni ,hguoht daeh sih denrut eh nehW
.ydaerla detsuahxe gnikool
.llew os deil devom eh yaw eht tuoba gnihtemoS
trihs drofxo eulb thgil dna
.rehtegot erew yeht mrifnoc ot wap hgih tsiaw a devaw dna elims etilop a delims rotciV
.worromot stnerap ruoy htiw tsafkaerb gnivah er’eW“
.knird a teg ot gnilbmarcs
spil sih ot knird sih thguorb rotciV
,derepsihw reviR ”,ebaB“
.flesmih pu lla ti gnah ot tuoba saw rotciV
,flesmih taht ta retteb hcum t’nsaw reviR
,nat sih ni neddih skceps yerg ssel elttil dna ,reinniks elttil A
,ecivres gnimaerts a dna dneirfyob sih htiw hcuoc eht no gnilruc naht erom gnihton tuoba dezisatnaf rotciV sa hcum sA
,ria eht otni smra sih werht yllacitcarp reviR
”,ti sekil eh sraeppa ti ,lleW“
.namrebod eht sdrawot decnalg dna taorht sih deraelc reviR
gnirb ot desimorp eh aeT eht saw wap eno nI
,saw ti sa hsidlihc dna
sgniht esoht fo yna t’nsaw reviR
,etoyoC triD yb ”ecnaD eM hctaW naC uoY“ saw sihT
.snoillats owt eht htiw noitasrevnoc yldneirf ylevitaler a ni degagne saw enirevlow eht ,gnikcinap s’reviR ot yrotcidartnoC
.ega fo saw knuks eht fi ees ot gnikcehc fo aedi eht gniromuh neve tuohtiw dias eh
.staes dah dna llat saw taht eno gnittops
.ssenittep sih htiw egagne naht rehtar ti derongi rotciV tub ,kcehc taoc eht tsap deklaw yeht sa
”.evif a mih deppit llitS
”.enohp ruoy no emag a gniyalp uoy ees annaw t’nseod recnuob ehT“
.taorht sih ni kcab dekohc bos a
,god.ecioveht ta
.boj doof tsaf elttil yttihs sih htiw nwo sih no evil ot droffa neve t’ndluoc reviR
.edis sih ta knuks eht ot egdun dna hguoc a gnivig
”.thgin a rof em tuohtiw evivrus ll’yehT
.rotciV tsap deppils gnihton
,reviR ot drac eht nruter dluoc eh erofeb tub
”.ni daeh nac owt uoY .hguorht tneW“
.teneg deriw eht htiw pu peek ot ygrene ro emit evah t’ndid
.emag eht revo koot yletelpmoc dna D&D otni thguorb eh taht gniht fo tros eht saw ssenillis tahT
.sknird owt ta deppac stimil sih togrof eh nehw semit hguone reviR deucser gnivah ,hguoht retteb wenk
.kcab eht sdrawot tuo dah yeht tahw gnikahs
”.trihs eciN .rotciV .iH“
selbat dna rab eht tsap erew
.hguoht syadawon gnihtyna tuoba pu gnikaeps enoyna tuoba yrrow ot dah reviR taht toN
,revognuh leef llits I fI
detsiwt elzzum s’rotciV ,desufnoC
,teneg sih del dah rotciV
,knuks suoenatnops yllausunu
,hguoht ti tuoba gniknihT
.dnuora thgin eht gninrut no sucof ot detnaw eh
.eporg eht otni gnisserp elihw elbmum saw od dluoc eh lla dna
.bos teiuq a trats ot thgis fo tuo ylefas saw eh litnu hguone gnol kcab gnidloh
,aera delbat eht sdrawot yaw sih gnikrow saw rotciV
.stnaw nwo sih gnigdelwonkca tuohtiw mih rof tseb thguoht eh taht sgniht gniod syawla saw knuks ehT
.metsys sih fo tuo gnihtyreve dekrow reviR elihw gninetsil
,flesmih bulc eht ta enolA
!tuo enog dah reviR ecnis ,shtnom
,elzzum trohs prahs sih no sgnikram kcalb ehT
.ruf sih morf esaerg dna tnegreted eht tuo naelc ot emoh decar dna reganam sih yb welf eh
.edisni snoillats eht gniddon erofeb rood eht hguorht meht gnittel ,puorg eht ot daeh sih denrut recnuob ehT
saw esle enoyreve elihw tuoba dehsarht eh ,cisum eht htiw gnibiv tsuj dna desolc seyE
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.enips dna epan sih nwod gninnur
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.pots ot mih llet ot mih gnirad dehcra worbeye na
.dias t’ndah eh taht sgniht eurt eht wenk rotciV
.dworc eht fo tser eht sdrawot noitnetta sih denrut ,gnirats thguac nettog d’eh taht dehsaba elttil a ,reviR
.tfel saw taht noitrop eht dehsinif dna
”.tfihs gnisolc a evah llits uoy ,taht retfa dna revognuh
.deidaets tlef eh litnu warts sih fo pis gnol wols a koot eh
.meht neewteb ecaps fo ytnelp dna nepo selbat lareves erew ereht
decI oykoT a tnaw I“
ssalg eht fo mirb eht revo dehsuls aet emoS
.bulcthgin ykSkcalB eht fo tnorf ni ereh etairporppa erew yeht tub
,srekam yenom laer sih erew sgel s’reviR
”,knird a teg annog m’I“
.meht ni enohp a t’nsaw ereht nehw swap sih htiw od ot tahw erus etiuq ton ,skcals sih ta dettap yllacimhtyhr rotciV
.sessalg sih htiw tcatnoc gnikam fo trohs tsuj enohptrams sih htiw
knuks ydren llat toof xis desserd yltsedom eht tuoba gnihtemoS
rentraP yM roF   etoyoC triD yb
deb eht no tuo dial d’eh snaej ynniks fo riap ehT