.sdrow ekil ylbasingocer gnihtemos deganam llits ew tub
,ytnewT ot pu thguac I
,dexaler erom gnileeF
.dne eno ta senigne htiw sgnir fo kcats gnol a saw pihs ehT
.tcatni dna elbats erew erus ekam ot
,netfo os yreve hguone eciN
.levart fo noitcerid eht ni detniop saw ti yenruoj eht fo flah rettal rof hguoht
.neeb reve dah ti sa doog sa saw gniraeh reh taht
.niaga nwod kcab wols ot gninrub tser eht dneps dna pilf neht dna
,nesneJ arhtruT rinieL naD yb
.ograc erew ytirojam eht dna
.noitanitsed ruo ta retnuocne ot ylekil erew ew snoitidnoc eht rof
,eb thgim ti swalc esohw tceted ot deirt eson ym sA
,epahs ni dna tif su peek oT
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
deksa eh sa denworf dna
.dnammoc fo ertnec eht ot gnir eht dnuora dna
,yerg denrut dah seye reH
.gninnur ti gnipeek fo ksat eht dah ohw did snaicinhcet ew tsael ta
buh lartnec a dna sebut ruo yb detcennoc tub
.kciuq nur lleT .teg dias enO"
.enihcam eht morf tuo yaw eht lla flesym dellup dna deilper I
.rats rehtona ot og ot efil gniniatnoc pihs tsrif ehT
,dedaeh dna kced dnammoc eht deretne ew sa mih ta dekool dna dias I ",oN"
,dnammoc saw dnammoc esuaceb snet eht dna sralugniS ehT
.mrala lleT .uoy teg ,og dias lortnoC"
,level ekil htraE na ta ytivarg etalumis dluow noitator eht tuo rehtruF
,renaelc ylbaredisnoc dna
.ria eht ta deffins dna
,reh sdrawot ria eht deffins I dna ytnewT htoB
.em dlot t'ndah yeht
.enod ylraeN .K"
.yranidro eht fo tuo yltcnitsid gnihtemos saw ti ro
.gninibmoc dna gnittilps
,pihs eht fo dne etisoppo eht ta neeb I dah ylno ton oS
.ecnatsid a ta elbisiv saw eh
.htraE ot rats tseraen eht ta neve saw
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ma I dna ,taerg er’uoY
,gnidnet deen dluow taht tnempiuqe htiw smoor fo tol a gnitcepxe
,edisni saw tahw wenk enin ytnewt rehto eht fo yna fi tuB
esac tropsnart eht fo tuo deppets tsrif I nehw saw tahT
.sdloh ograc ynam eht fo weiv a hguorht gnilcyc
,enod dah ertosnuheS sa ylivaeh sa gnitnaP
"?neppah tahW .xaleR .roinuJ"
.yawa sraey thgil laretil eb ylbissop yrev thgim eno tseraen eht esuaceb
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
,won gniod saw enoemos yaw eht
,pihs eht fo ertnec eht ni orez htiw ,elddim eht morf derebmuN
su detaerc dah hcihw maet eht fo redael eht dna
?roinuJ" "?trela orez gniR
pihs eht fo elddim eht ni ,orez gniR
.dnammoc kciuq nuR"
,pohs a morf stib wen emos ni redro tsuj t'ndluoC
,pihs eht gnitroppus su
,ygoloisyhp namuh eligarf eht rof troppus ni tif ot deen on htiW
,tpada ot su thguat dah rotaerc ruO
,su ,werc sti sa llew sa
rebmun eht ,eman ym gniyas ot teg ot elba saw eh tseraen eht ,niaga dias eh ",eertnewT" .seitud ym mrofrep ot dlo oot emaceb yllanif I nehw
.ylreporp ,yltcerid erom em ta dekool dna seye sih denepo eH
.ylevitisiuqni mih ta deffins I sa worb ym no nworf thgils a
,gnol yrev rof yhtlaeh t'nsaw ti tub
,pirt eht otni sraey neethgie yad eno ,yllanif litnu
ti ni sdnuos fo rebmun egral ylgniyonna na dah eerhtytruofdnaderdnuhneveS
noitats hsaw noitcesretni eht morf ebut yrrucs ediw eht pu yaw ym edam I
.no gnikrow neeb dah I tinu eht ot eson sih detniop eH ".kciuq
,nrob erew ew morf dlot neeb dah ew gnihtyrevE
,edisni peek ot detpmetta I yrrow eht deyarteb sreksihw gnihctiwt yM
.smelborp owt fo ressel eht nesohc dah ew ,egaugnal ydob dna gnirutseg elttil a ni gnidda ,os dna
.dnammoc morf yaw eht lla nur ylekil dah eh thguoht I dna
.buh lartnec eht ot sekops eht fo eno ni gnikrow neeb dah I erehw neeb saw ,esruoc fo ,sihT
eliforp sdaeRdooG rieht no dnuof seigolohtna eht ni seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy
ygolohtna tenalPruF eht ni dnuof eb nac
.eno lanif reh tub tfel seciohc on dah ehs
,pihs eht deretne dah eW
fo lluf ,sknat egral ni derevoc saw gniht eritne ehT
",enod nehT .od ot naelC
.od ot dah I tlef I gnihtemos saw ti
stfihs gnitator no
,noisiv gnizama yltcaxe ton ruo htiw nevE
.redro eht no dessap dah
.setampihs ruo naht
,saera cer eht ro gnireenigne ekil
.enola ton er’uoy taht wonk esaelp
.saw pihs elohw eht yaw eht
,ebut eht morf nwod morf eciov railimaf a emac "!eertnewT"
.neppah ot dah sdeef ygrene eht fo ecnanetniam lareneg
.ecudorp ylisae ot em wolla ton did pil tfelc s'tar a taht
,edis eht ot gnicnalG .devirra dah eW
pihs eht otno dna seitilicaf gniniart eht morf thguorb neeb dah
,ruf sih ni etihw naht rehto ruoloc a htiw su fo wef eht fo eno saw eH
.ti fo noitubirtsid ssam eht wonk ot dah ew os dna
,detcennoc demees syawla taht sgniht owt
,sdrow ot did shtuom ruo naht
,su dlot dah srotaerc ruo os
,ecap mlac erom a ta
noos dluow hcihw dna
.ytiradilos ni gnihctiwt sreksihw nwo sih
eerhtytruofderdnuhneveS nehw
srae ym dekrep yletarebiled I
,niart depleh dah I esoht fo enO
stsen mraw ni pu deloh ylbatrofmoc star egral dnasuoht A
,uoy rof ruoy fo emit tluciffid a si siht fi dnA
.ti desolc dna ,llew sa saw enim desilaer I dna
.detsixe wonk ot desoppus saw elpoep eroc wef a fo edistuo ydobon taht gnir eht saw
,stenalp elbatibah htiw srats lareves erew ereht taht yrevocsid eht fo tnemeticxe eht gniwollof ,deeps taerg htiw tliuB
,dias ehs ",wonk uoY
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,wonk ot dedeen I gnihtemos t'nsaw tI
,esuaceb ,sevlesmeht og ton dluoc yeht desilaer dah snamuh eht wenk eW
,gniteerg ni rehto hcae ta deffins eW
dlrow taht fo seitilaer eht deraps neeb dah ew erus edam dah rotaerc ruO
,fo erawa saw ydobyreve ton taht
,dnuos eht fo ecruos eht rof dehcraes ezag ym
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
ralucitrap ni yrots sihT .riniel/moc.sdaerdoog ta
,wenk ew sa raf sA
,etsah edam I tnatropmi yldediced demees ti esuaceb
.rehtegot su tcurtsnoc ot ytinutroppo eht nekat dah yeht taht dna
,siht su dlot dah pihs eht dna su htob detaerc dah ohw esohT
pihs eht fo strap erew ereht wenk eW
",enod nooS .ksat yM"
.lufesu erom tsuj erew sdrow semitemos tub
.ytilaer otni su thguorb taht dlrow eht tuoba thguat neeb ton dah eW
,deeps ot pu teg ot gninrub
.B amixorP rof dedaeh eb
.werc taht rof dengised eb nrut ni dluoc hcihw pihs a tif taht werc a ngiseD
,llew ,deniatnoc ti ssam hcum woh fo edistuo
,did ew esruoc fo hcihw ,egaugnal ydob hguorht deyevnoc eb dluoc noitamrofni fo laed taerg A
,pihs eht fo edistuo eht nees reven dah eW
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I  .goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.tnatropmi saw erusopmoc esuaceb
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht eht saw sihT
.pihs eht fo sedisni eht hguorht
pihs a dliub dah yeht
.ylwols delahxe dna ,desolc seye
.aedi tseb eht saw metsys desolc a sa troppus efil gninnur taht dediced neeb dah ti
,tpada ot thguat neeb dah eW
,elttil a tsuj elzzum ym desiar ylmlac dna
.htraE tfel dah ew erofeb tsuj
.regnol niart ot elba neeb dah su fo tsedlo eht tub
,roines ym sraey neetfiF
hguorht repmacs ot su rof srodirroc fo snur sseldnE
.werc dnammoc ruo morf stnemtsujda thgils ylno htiw
.drawkwa saw ti semitemos ,neht nevE
,serots tnempiuqe eht fo yna raen erehwon saw noitacol ruO
flesmih demlac tar gnuoy ehT
”taobefiL ruO erA uoY“
,gnixif fo deen ni tnegru gnihtemos saw ereht fI
,neetenin hguorht orez derebmun erew sgnir ehT
,yas dluoc I lla saw
.morf emoc dah draeh dah I dnuos eht noitcerid emas eht
.sdaehklub retuo kciht yb
,neeb dah reve ti sa prahs sa saw
,tnempiuqe eht niatniam ot dedeen slliks eht su nevig dah gniniarT
.tuo dial neeb dah snibac gniniart ruo yaw eht
wap emas taht htiw detniop dna dias ehs
,orez gnir otni og ot desoppus saw ydobon ecnis ,lla retfA
.eerht ytnewt
.dlo sraey ytruof revo llew
tnemssarrabme ni teef sih dnuora liat sih gnilruc
.no krow ot sgniht fo ytnelp dah I dna
,secalP weN gnirolpxE
.yako kciuQ" ".yako epoH
.deen siht gniyevnoc fo elbapac ytnelp saw mocretni s'pihs eht
edam ehs eciohc ehT
”taobefiL ruO erA uoY“
.setamwerc ym fo eno fo epahs derruf-etihw ,gnirepmacs eht dna
gnihtemos gniwohs saw
.dewolla ytiroines dnarg reh noihsaf dexaler erom eht ni
.gniteerg ni elzzum sih fo pot eht bur ot rebmemer ot gniganam llits tub
regral hcum tsuj
hsilop walc emos rof ereh mih tnes dah roirepus a rehtie
.kced dnammoc eht hguorht yaw ruo edam ew sa moor eht ssorca morf ylduol dias enO ",llet I"
,htraE tfel ew nehw dlo sraey net neeb dah I
.krow ot dednetni neeb dah ti woh si siht
.niaga nwod mlac ot traeh gniremmah ym dna gnihtaerb ym gniwolla fo tceffe edis eht dah tI
.thgiled dna tnemeticxE  2 fo 1 traP ,nesneJ arhtruT rinieL naD yb
,spup sa hguorht nur dah ew taht snur nuf eht
,yllacisyhp su troppus ylpmis ton ot dengised neeb dah
,otua no yleritne tsomla nur dah tI
.ycneculsnart raen ypsihw a ot etihw lausu ruo morf dedaf dah ruf reh dna
.erew ereht yltnerappa tub ,pihs eht edistuo
.etulas ni selzzum dna srae ruo gnibbur dna
.terces orez gniR"
,stsen ’star-ecaps eseht sa guns dna yzoc dna ysub sa eb ot tnaw d’uoy nehw
.dluow ti detcepxe dah I naht yklub erom tahwemos
,sruof lla no nwod kcab tog dna
detaerc eb ot derdnuh evif tsal eht fo trap a neeb dah eH
,ereht yaw flah tuobA
,sehcnuah sih no pu tas dna
dnammoc neewteb noitcesretni eht ta devirra I
.oga sraey thgie ytnewt esoht em dnuora wolf ot demees hcihw gnileef eht saw tahT
.reh ediseb syalpsid egral eht fo eno ot
.dah uoy tahw htiw laed ot dah uoy ,ecaps nI
,roinuj a saw eh elihw dna
.kced eht no swap ym tup dna
.pihs eht fo tnorf eht ta
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
secnatsmucric gnignahc dnatsrednu ot su deniart
.secalp wen fo yteirav ediw a erolpxe dna tuo og elpoep lamina fo yteirav a erehw
deyolpme snoitaerc 'srotaerc ruo fo emos
.ti fo laed taerg a ton saw ereht
smetsys eht fo ecnanetniam cisab did werc ruo fo tsoM
.enim ni did ylerus eh yaw eht
.yad tsrif taht su ot demees dah ti sa yenruoj eht hguorht su ot lufrednow sa deniamer lla tI
.saw ti tahw wonk yllaer ton did
,ylpeed ni dehtaerb eH
,tfel ew nehw seye sih tog tsuj ylno dah dna
.tfel ew erofeb hcet no gniniart fo sraey evif dah dna
,sebut gnitsiwt fo ezam a htiw tem neeb dah ew daetsnI
,noitaidar morf pihs eht edisni seititne lacigoloib etaciled eht gnitcetorp ,retaw
.fo erawa ton erew uoy gnihtemos ot tpada yldrah dluoc uoy tub
.ot dah ew nehw snoitces ytivarg wol eht ot og ylno ot deirt ew os
,roinuj neeb evah llew thgim eH
”taobefiL ruO erA uoY“   :yojne esaelP
,kaeps ot os ,raer ehT
owt dna eno gnir neewteb spam eht ni pag a tsuJ
.hsilop walc oN .deriuqne I
.seitud ecnanetniam ruo mrofrep ot elba eb dluow ew os
star rekaterac dereenigne
egaugnal ngis eht ot ssel neve sevlesmeht tnel swap ruO
,sih ni yrrow fo hcuot a detceted I dna
no gnikrow saw I tinu gnilcyc ria gnimmuh yltneg eht htaenrednu morf tuo flesym dellup I
.sdloh erutuf evitcelloc rieht tahw dna
.noitautis eht ta yrrow ym fo dlot sreksihw gnihctiwt ym dna nworf nwo ym erus saw I hguoht
,enO teem ot dedaeh saw I erehw gnireenigne dna lortnoc deniatnoc neetenin gniR
.kciuq deirT .ereh teG"
,enO gnieb siht dna ,tnatropmi gnieb ssenilnaelc tub
,tnorf eht dellac eb thgim hcihw
ylnommoc erom ro
,sevil nwo rieht fo revocsid sdneirf tar gniraf-ecaps ruo tahw tuo dnif ot emit txen ni enuT
.ton saw thgiseye reh sa etuca sa gniraeh reh dna
,eno kciuq a saw hsaw ehT
.dias roinuJ .enO eeS
edaced a fo tsom tsal eht no gnikrow neeb ev’yeht cipe if ics taht em llet yeht dna
?ereht saw ti wonk ydobyna dluohs yhw
,thguoht I ,dekool tI
yaw sti dekans hcihw ebut tisnart eht fo enil gnipeews ,tfos eht gniwollof
.esle gnihton detseggus dah sreniart ruo dna shcet eht gnihtyreve
.no krow ot su rof tnempiuqe htiw dna
.raer raf eht ta saw dna
.wenk I gnihtyreve mih gnihcaet sraey neetriht tsal eht tneps d'I
,revewoh ,su ot detacidni ehs eno ehT
.buh eht ot yawflah neeb osla dah I
,sraey wef riaf a rof yaw ruo no eb dluow ew ecniS
,snoitarepo rof desu werc egdirb eht taht stuptuo rosnes fo xim a dewohs yeht yllamroN
.nwonk evah ew dluoc woH
,reh dehcaer ew sa dias I ",riS ,yrros mA"
sehcnuah ruo no pu gnittis
.draob no tar tsedlo eht morf noissim a no tsegnuoy ruo fo eno
.enog sgniht tnatropmI
",ertosnuheS" .desivorpmi ew os
,nepo ediw gnignah htuom s'ytnewT deciton I
"?mrala orez gniR"
,neetenin gnir ni noitces gnireenigne regral hcum eht dna
,B amixorP no eb llew sa thgim uoy fi sa leef won dna
,drah gnitnap saw eH
,doof suoiciled yllausu gnikooc neewteb emit rieht tilps yeht erehw
.sebut yrrucs naht rehto ti ni gnihtemos dah wenk shcet wef a ylno taht
,ylefas dna ylideeps htob gnola su leporp ot swap ruo fo swalc eht dewolla osla tI
,tpada ot elba eb dluow ew derusne dah
.tcejorp EDK eht ni erawtfos ecruos nepo dna eerf gnitaerc ro
,siht desilaer dneirf gnuoy ym sseltbuod dna
,mih tuoba ria tnedifnoc erom a htiw dias eh tsal ehT ".relcyc eldnah I"
.dne enigne eht sdrawot erew sgnir derebmun nevenu eht
.pihs eht dna su sa dengised sa airetcab dna stnalp fo noitceles a dna ,su tsuJ
"?won od tahW .ediced eW
ecaps ytpme yb detarapes erew sgnir ehT
,tnecs sih hguorht yrrow fo tniat gnorts a gnitceteD
pirt eht fo flah tsrif eht dneps dluow tI
# .nwo ruo fo eno su evig ot saw
;ti fo tuoyal eht denrael noos ew ,dedraob ew nehw tub
fo werc gnorts-dnasuoht eht fo tser eht dna I yad ehT
.sraey neethgie rof eno neeb dah eh
tlef dah I sa desufnoc sa tuoba gnidnuos
,saera lanoitaercer ruo ekil erom hcum neeb dah tI
.terces emas tI .won raeH"
pirt a fo htrow sedaced owt ylraen eht rof eb ot emoh ruO
.tik fo seceip neewteb teg ot
.em sa delliks sa yllacitcarp saw eh tub
.mih pleh ot trap ni
,maet rieht fo tser eht htiw gnihgual yltnerruc saw dna
.uoy erofeb naicinhcet roinuj deticxerevo na htiw yllaicepsE
.tib a pu flesym naelc ot noitats hsaw a ta pots kciuq a edam I dna
em rof revo ekat dluow ohw dna
pihs eht fo smetsys eht tuoba erom nwonk dah eW
stcapmi morf detcetorp
,sevil eritne ruo niatniam ot deniart dah ew
,rehto eht fo tnecs eht htiw railimaf su fo htob
,semitemos ,rebmemer ot tluciffid saw tI
",wonk toN" "?neppah wonk"
,revewoh ,dnim reH
.htooms neeb ylpmis ti dah naht
,llew esuaceb seitnewt su dna
.doom sih deterpretnisim evah thgim I desilaer I dna
,flesti werc eht niatniam ot enod eb ot dedeen hcihw sgniht ynam rehto eht fo yna ro
.su fo lla gnitroppus pihs eht dna
,su gnitroppus airetcab dna stnalp ehT
.meht htiw laed ot dna
dias eh ",wonk toN"
.remrof eht eb ot ylekil mees ton did tI
buh eht ot raen taht tub
.morf emoc dah eh noitcerid eht ni ffo gnidaeh erofeb hcet gnuoy eht ot deddon dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
:srebmem dellortnoc ylthgit htiw
nrut ni sknat eht dna
.seye ruo tog dah ew ecnis dneirf doog a dna ,hcet dael
eerhT dna owT ,enO erehw dne raf eht ot revo
,erehpsoib deifilpmis A
saera s'pihs eht fo strap suoirav gniwohs saremac morf sdeef dna
,ytud no erew yeht nehw dial
,hguoht ,taht naht eroM
,dnammoc sdrawot deunitnoc htob ew sa dias eh ",eertnewT oL"
,tneicna ylevitisop eb won llew thgim enO
.citsalp tsniaga yldipar gnikcilc swalc dna gnitnap ekil dednuos taht gnihtemos ta rae na dekcilf I
ecnelubrut ssel htiw levart ot ria dewolla ecafrus ylbbon ,tfos ehT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
,emit emas eht ta neppah eerht lla semitemoS
,noisserpxe nwo ym xaler ot gnitpmetta ,dias I
,hguorht ssap ot dah I erehw dna
.ekops eh sa thgil eht ni gninetsilg seye der ,thgirb sih
,ecnatsid riaf a nur tsuj dah eH
.esruoc fo ,deksa dah I taht toN
".mrala orez gniR
,siht ekil gnitnap ereh saw eh fI
.resolc delwarc dna
:lamron gnihtyna eb ton dluow tI
.derahs su fo owt eht yrrow eht fo tnih tsethgils eht ylno reh ni detceted dna
.noitsuahxe drawrof thgiarts tsuj spahrep sa yrrow hcum os toN
.cificeps erehwemos eb ot deriuqer ylneddus era uoy nehw noitacol tneinevnoc a ni flesruoy dnif ot mees reven uoY
.hcae sekops ruof yb
.egnahc locotorp dnE
saremac erew ereht taht aedi on dah I .tnereffid yrev
.tatibah ruo saw pihs eht fo pit eht ta neethgie gnir dna
,mlac nwo ym niater ot tseb ym did I
.nevig eW .orez gnir sihT
dne eht sdrawot edam neeb dah ohw esoht fo eno ,hcet roinuj A
.eligarf erew yeht
gnillortap snrut koot su fo dnasuoht eht hcihw sdloh reniatnoc fo hcnub gib a tsuJ
wap a htiw rae eno debbur ehs sa su ta gniffins ,dias ehs ",htoB
,nesneJ arhtruT rinieL naD yb
,dne rehto eht sdrawot erew sgnir derebmun neve ehT
.llew sa yllatnem su egnellahc tub
,sdnaldiM hsilgnE eht ni gnixaler dnuof eb yllausu nac ohw ,riniel tsuj ro
,ytivarg wol eht ni swap dnih ym no thgirpu dnats ot devom I
"?tahw trela orez gniR .wonk toN"
,ograc sti eraperp dluow hcihw
.yenruoj a hcus fo niarts eht ekat ot elba yllacisyhp saw namuh oN
,ti dah srekam ruo yaw eht hceeps rof dengised yldrah erew shtuom ruO "!kciuQ"
rats tnatsid taht ot
,tnecs eht yb dewollof yldipar saw eciov ehT
.pu gnipparw ot resolc gnitteg si
.pihs eht draob no pu nworg dah dna
,dekrep ylneddus srae sih dna pu tohs worb sih sa deksa eh "?orez gnir wonK
,noitcif ecneics dna msilaer laicos fo stib suoirav gnitirw
,shtaerb neewteb dias eh ",riS ,esucxE"
,flesti pihs eht fo ytirgetni larutcurts eht no tcapmi na dah tI
.deddon htob ew dna
.detsixe ti wenk neve ytriht tsrif eht ylnO
egdelwonk hcus detnarg neeb dah ohw ew neve tub
.pilc riaf a ekil dednuos tahw ta em gnihcaorppa
.rae deppit-nworb eno
esoht fo tseraen eht taht dna
,eno siht retfa erom ekil dluow uoy fi ,dnal ot taht rof gnitiaw elihW
.sdnah efas ni saw relcyc ria tahT
.pihs eht evoba ecaps nwerts rats eht ni gnignah saw tahw saw