.tnorf reh dnuora kcab delruc liat reh dna
htraE tfel dah ew ecnis nees ton dah I ecaf A
,aera lortnoc namuh eht ot
"?sey ,llacer uoY .lenap ddo
,pirt gnol a saw ti esuaceb ,sU
,erehwyreve tsud saw erehT
gnidrocer siht ees uoy nehw dna
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.em rof noitcerid eno ni evom ot gninnigeb saw
.nwod dekool I dna
.dlrow llamS .wonk ew pihS
em ot nellaf dah tI
.yas ot gniyrt saw I tahw gniwonk etiuq ton ,deppots dna ,detrats I ",sihT"
.htraE tfel dah ew nehw
,noihsaf siht ni etaf ruoy fo nrael dluohs uoy taht yrros ma I ...tey dna
,eldarc a no gniyal saw ohw
.deunitnoc ehs sa noitanimreted htiw daeh reh gnikahs ,seye reh desolc dna
.ygoloib skcal tub
,niaga seye reh desolc ehS ".evivrus dna
.su gnillet saw ehs tahw gniredisnoc
ecaf s’enoemos no elims a gnittup ekil yad ym snethgirb gnihton tub
,oreZ fo yrots eht taht desimorp dah ,yromem gnivol fo ,enO .oreZ ruo
.enO fo taht sa delknirw sa saw niks reh dna
.em sdrawot kcab denrut daeh sih dna
",emas srood kcolnU
.erofeb naht ecaps eht fo esu retteb hcuM
mrala orez gniR .no peelS
.snamuh tuohtiw pihS"
.regna tnaem seiceps elbanosaer yna ni taht seno yhtoot ,gnitairufni esoht fo eno
ecapS dna ,lufetsaw saw tI
.uoy ekat lliw pihs ehT
.meht ot gniklat spots pihs eht nehw siht fo nrael lliw htraE
,ssendnik fo sdrow wef a htiw
tatibah namuh remrof eht retne ot saw nevig neeb dah ew ksat ehT
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
”taobefiL ruO erA uoY“   :yojne esaelP
.tenalp elbatibah ylbissop a htiw
gniyas saw enO tahW
".noitpeced siht em evigrof ,emit ni
.sseccuS .eruliaf ton ,oN"
,pihs eht su nevig dah ehS
.emoceb evah uoy tahw ekil ton yam ohw
,namuh neeb dah ecnetsixe ruo derusne dah ohw ehS
.taerg toN .nwonknU .regral
.mih dnuora gnivruc lanimret retupmoc eht gnitarepo
htraE ot kcab og neht dna ,kooL
,su sa nosrep a hcum sa ,elbillaf saw ehs wenk eW
.noitces namuh eht fo pam a pu dellac dna
,demees ti ,deracs neeb dah snamuh ehT
,emoceb thgim ew tahw rof sehsiw reh dna
",ti tnaw uoy fi won sruoy si orez gniR"
,ni saw ehs taes eht ni kcab denael ehs dna
.draob no namuh tsal eht saw I litnu uoy llet ton dluoc I tub ,seman evah uoY
,meht ot erew ew tahw dna
,noituacerp artxe na erew slaes daehklub ehT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.thgil eht ees dluow yehT
.hctef ot enog dah eh eno dlo
.ylreporp eybdoog uoy llet dluohs I taht thguoht ylpmis I
.tenalp eht no nwod tnemelttes gnivirht eht ni mih dedeen ylimaf s'dneirf dlo ym
,edis eno ot gnihsiws liat reh
,ytilanoitcnuf sti llA .taht ekil tsuj
.ecalp eno ta deppat dna
.won ediced eW .dlrow ruO
,nosaer emos rof ,dluoc I tub
.tnes ehs tnemucoD"
.lufsseccus yletelpmoc naht ssel neeb dah ssecorp gninaelc eht fi
,won pu su fo owt eht dellac dah enO yhw saw sihT
,tnegru erom dna reduol
.siht wenk naicinhcet latnemnorivne nA
.stnetnoc regnol oN .snamuH
.dap atad a dial hcihw ediseb
.kcehc eht mrofrep ot smetsys rieht esu dna
.lirep taerg fo erew seirots esoht semitemoS
.noitpmeder rof ecnahc ruo era uoY
,won ti wenk su fo lla dnA
.su nevig dah oreZ seman eht fo eno ekat ot dediced
hcuM .B amixorP
".ecaps ni ygoloib htraE fo sniamer taht lla eb lliw uoY
,ecnelis ni orez gnir ot yaw ruo edam eW
,uoy tuoba wonk t’nod I dna
.erofeb naht remlac ,dias ehs ",won thgir toN" ".knihT
.kaeuqs ot nrut ym saw ti dna
.snamuh tuohtiw B
,ydaer saw tsrif eht taht woN
,gnuoy fo rettil a derehtaf neve dah eH
.ees lliw htraE morf eno on taht
.pihs eht fo noitces namuh eht fo srosnes lanretni eht ot
.detnaw I tahw si sihT
,spahrep ,neeb evah ot demees ssecorp gninaelc eht taht saw dnoces ehT
.mih ta dekool I nehw rosiv s'tius eht dniheb nworf a deirrac ecaf siH
".flesym ti od ot dah I dna
enod evah dluow ew gnihtemos erew taht hguoht sA
,hcum eb dluow sgniht
.gnorw ygoloiB .lavivrus oN
.evivrus ylbissop nac nosrep lanoitar on erehw
.mih ot nwod dekool I sa
.siht no ssecca toN .ereh lortnoC"
.oga sraey net yad taht deirrac dah eh yrrow fo tniat eht tuohtiw dna
.riahc eht otno pu em depleh ytnewT dna
.ecaps ni eunitnoc eW
.devomer eb ot melborp a era uoy taht ediced thgim yeht ro
.pu gnipparw ot resolc gnitteg si
,os ro raey tsael eht revo seirots eht deyojne ev’uoy fI .kcab gnivig dna
,nwo ruo morf trapa tnecs fo kcal rettu gnitartsurf eht morf trapa ,ni deklaw ew sa deciton ew gniht tsrif ehT
erutseg eht denruter I dna ,elzzum sih debbur eH
,seno nevig gnieb naht rehtar ,won tub
,tcaf ni ,saw ti taht erusne dna
.tenalp taht ta ,ylesolc yrev ,kool ot
"?tahw stnetnoc orez gniR ?enog sgnihT"
,dnuof eb ot gnihtyna saw ereht fI
,gninruter erofeb ,yliratnemom deppots gnituohs eht dna gnipmuht ehT
,sdnaldiM hsilgnE eht ni gnixaler dnuof eb yllausu nac ohw ,riniel tsuj ro
.su ot no dessap dah ehs egdelwonk eht dna
ebut tisnart eht ot mih wollof ot tropweiv eht tfel dna dnuora denrut I ".gnitiaw yehT"
,htraE yb detisiv eb ylbissop dna
,noitautis tsehguot eht ni ,woh tuoba klat dluow yehT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.emas eht deniamer tluser eht dna
,ti retne ton dluow srehto os ffo ti gnikcolb
,don a htiw dias eh ",K"
,emit emas eht ta neppah eerht lla semitemoS
,swap dnih ym no gnidnatS
,eertnewT saw I ,oN
noissapmoc tahw fo nrael dluow ytinamuH .su meht wohs dluow ew dna
.gniroolf eht no gnikcilc swalc ,em ediseb pu deklaw dah ohw
".hguoht ,llew sa eunitnoc nac pihs ehT
.traeh gniknis a yb tnaem srelletyrots esoht tahw dootsrednu I taht dnuof ylneddus I
,enog sgniht tnatropmi lareves htiw
,elbats dna efas si tI
ynoloc-otorp a pu tes dluow ew esuaceb
.ti derebmemer I naht redlo ylbaredisnoc gnikool eno tub
.draob no esle ydobyna ylraen dluow ron ,ti ees ton dluow I .sraey ytriht
,regnol tiaw ton dluoc I
.yaw rednu llew erom ynam htiw ,ydaer won saw meht fo tsrif ehT
,pihs eht rof detaerc erew eW
.desilaer evah dluohs I .desilaer evah dluohs eW
orez gniR .uoy ksat giB
srood eht denepo ylpmis evah dluow ew
.tcejorp EDK eht ni erawtfos ecruos nepo dna eerf gnitaerc ro
,daeh ym ni revo ti thguoht I
",eertnewT esucxE"
.pirt nruter a neeb reven dah erehT ".retal
.taht fo erus erew ew
.ecnetsixe eritne ruo dewo ew mohw ot esoht ot
,dias ehs ",nigeb ot tuoba si elcyc ehT"
.eviP ikiR dna uoS ikiR ,eerT ikiR
.eb dluohs ti sa demrofni ,llew
,noitats ecaps wen siht ni llah noitaercer dna noitavresbo eht emoceb dah yab scinopordyh ehT
,gnidrocer eht no dnuos gnipmuht a eciton ot nageb I ".uoy
.ydaer eb dluow nerdlihc s'areiK .revocsid ot su rof gnihtyreve dekcolnU
,os od ot wolla dluoc ew draob no ecalp ylno ehT
.ybraen selip erom wef a deciton dna dnuora dekool I
,egnahc rotinom eht no egami eht edam eH
.erus eb ot detnaw I esuaceb pu naelc ot gnol siht detiaw ylno I
.dnuof dah ytnewT taht lenap eht denepo neht dna
.noitanimreted htiw gnihctiwt sreksihw reh dna dekrep srae
,B amixorP morf yawa pihs tsrif eht dael ot
.ynam os fo esopsid ot sdohtem esrow desu ohw esoht ot layol elpoep rof
saw ta doots erew su fo owt eht tropweiv eht edistuo weiv eht dna
snamuh edisgnola evivrus ton dluoc eW
.srehto eht gnillac erofeb
ralucitrap ni yrots sihT .riniel/moc.sdaerdoog ta
emit siht hguoht
.ezag gnimaor ym wollof ym naht rehtar mih fo daeha gnikool
egassem lanif taht gnidnes neeb dah taht snoitcnuf segassem eht gniwohs llits saw eno tfel ehT
,su nwohs dah ehs ytilaer eht
daeh sih koohs ytnewT
.naelc os eb ot dah esle lla esuaceb
.ta gnikool saw I tahw ees ot daeh sih denrut dna
,taes ytsud eht no pu doots I sa ylteiuq dias ytnewT
.tcefrep naht ssel neeb dah snoitca s'rotaerc ruo fI
ograc fo stnuoma taerg eht dna
?taht denigami ylurt evah ew dluoc ,tuB
.ecafrus yreve gnirevoc
,moor eht fo raer eht sdrawot dedaeh dna
,elbavlosernu ti kniht dna riapsed dluow yeht woh
.su tif ot depahs ylraelc dna ,rellams hcum erew yeht tub
.snamuh htiw B amixorP .su llik dluoW
.won dlrow rieht toN .sediced namuH
,yltnecer os nosrep a neeb dah hcihw
dne gnittif a smees tI"
etalp ecaf eht dniheb yldeticxe gnihctiwt erew sreksihw siH
.su dnuora daerps dah hcihw ecnelis eht ni dias enO ",daer I
,sgnir ruo ni sa niaga ezis emas eht ylisaE .suomrone saw tI
.enO htiw nees dah ew taht
,ycagel ruo era uoy fI
,noitats ecaps a sa desopruper neeb dah oreZ gniR s'pihs dlo ehT
.yletelpmoc gnippots erofeb
.sebut yrrucs desu ssel eht fo eno ot su gnidael ytnewT
,ytnewT ta gnikool dias ehs tsal ehT
.skeehc deworruf ylpeed reh nwod nar sraet fo skaerts owt dna gninetsilg erew seye reh
,tsixe ot su wolla ot efil reh nevig dah ehS
,nesneJ arhtruT rinieL naD yb
,rehto hcae ta dekool eW
.egral yltnasaelpnU
.pihs eht fo tser eht morf ,ylnommocnu
.meht tsniaga tlover wohemos dluow ew taht dna
,etihw tnaillirb denrut dah riah kcab dellup ,gnol reh tub
.neeb evah dluoc reven erehT .su rof toN
.gninaelc reggirT"
.suoires elttil a naht erom saw siht desilaer I dna
,ereh emoc dluow snamuH
,draob no snamuh erew ereht wenk neve reven uoy esilaer I
.srieht sa dlrow a hcus ni neve
.lla ta ereh erew ew yhw saw tI
,tsud fo elip eno dnuof eW
,won su dlot tsuj dah ydal dlo eht tahw htiw gnirrulb
.trop gnikcod pihs ot pihs eht ot del hcihw
,owT ikiR ,enO ikiR
.emulov ni gniworg saw hcihw
metsys ria eht fo muh eht ylnO
,lairetam fo tnuoma egral a hguorht hguoht sa
tsap eht ni esoht ot pu kool ohW
.desu neeb dah ti yaw eht
.rats rehtona gnitibro dlrow a ,nosrep ni
.deirrow saw ehs em gnillet seye gnitrad reh dna ecaf reh no noisserpxe eht tub
.ereht eb dluohs ew taht eerga ton did ohw
.srats eht ot sdrawno eunitnoc dna
pihs eht hguorht yaw ruo edam ew sa dnuora gnikool ,deyalps srae
.pu koot ynoloc a rof slairetam cisab eht lla dna senigne
,rotaerc ruo htiw tcatnoc raluger ni neeb dah enola ehs
dias eh ",pihs og emiT"
.liaf ot detaerc neeb ton dah eW
,tlef I sa deirrow sa gnikool ytnewT
.si erehw wonk newT .rooD .nepo won
werc egdirb eht fo eno ot deddon enO
,B amixorP ot ereh emoc dah ew rof
.derdnuh tuoba werc namuH .detsaW"
.tpada ot su thguat osla dah ehS
.puorg dezis noitasinoloc a enola tel
.dnuof dah ew tahw elpoep llet ot
.htraE tfel ew nehw su dlot dah ehs tahw htiw ti gnirapmoc
,su ,spilb owt tsuJ
su dlot dah enO .efil fo ytpme
,neercs eht no weiv otni emac
.hguone dlo erew yeht nehw seman nwo rieht esohc dluow yeht
.kciuq thgir su lliK
,dias areiK ",eertnewT"
,eettimmoc lartnec eht yb dekcip dnah lla erew yehT
strap lanif dna dnoces eht eht saw sihT
,em tel ton dluow yehT"
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er’uoY
.sgnik ekil evil dluoc eW .ecaps hcum oS
.niahc dnammoc orcam a dewohs rehto ehT
.moor eht fo dne rehto eht ta rood eht denepo ew ,stius elbatrofmocnu eht ni derittA .ni deklaw dna
.wols eciohc ekaM .wohS
.siht morf gnihtyna ees ton lliw sredael taerg ehT
,doof suoiciled yllausu gnikooc neewteb emit rieht tilps yeht erehw
.won yawa raf oot era eW
,delffum ,seciov rehtO
.srosnes eht ssecca ot deirt ytnewT elihw sehcnuah ruo no ti erofeb tas dna
,daehklub a tsniaga pu ti depporp eW
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
amixorP" .meht deniatsus hcihw ygoloib eht dna
,emit tsrif eht sa tnatropmi sa tsuj gnihtemos rof emit sihT
noihsaf lausac oot raf a ekil demees tahw ni gnihctiwt sreksihw reh htiw dias ehs ",won neppah toN
.secalp wen fo yteirav ediw a erolpxe dna tuo og elpoep lamina fo yteirav a erehw
.neercs etihw a tsuj saw ti litnu rethgirb gniworg erutcip eht
gnola gnimoc eb dluow eh
,pihs eht htiw neppah thgim sgniht elbirret detseggus yeht semitemoS
,egdirb eht sa deifitnedi dah ytnewT hcihw moor eht dnuof yllanif eW
,sa noisiced eht ekam ot dedeen noitamrofni eht lla enO evag ydaerla I"
.tuohtiw dluoc ew naht retteb noisiced eht ekam ydobyreve pleh dluow oreZ gniR edisni dnif dluow ew revetahW
.niaga B amixorP hcaer ot tpmetta dluow snamuh
,htrof gnirb dluoc
.srosnes lanretxe eht ot ssecca derahs
,siht dias ehs sa pu flesreh desiar ehS ".tnatropmi sihT
.nruter oN .rehto nalp pihS
htaed lufniap dna wols a naht elbatrofmocnu ssel ylniatrec erew yeht ,neht nevE
,pihs eht no evil osla nac uoY
,evitcepsorter eht htiw tneitap saw tar gnuoy regnol on won eht
",noissim siht fo eruliaf eht fo snrael htraE erofeb sraey ytnewt eb lliw tI"
.meht ot og dluow ew esuaceb ,erus erew eW
moor lortnoc rieht ot og ot dah I dna ytnewT
orez gniR ni tfel rettam lacigoloib on eb lliw ereht
.eb dluow nerdlihc riehT
.retal terces ton ,won terceS .siht
,esle gnihtyna thguoht ew daH
htraE ot denruter ew nehw teg thgim ew emoclew eht tuoba dna
?ereht erew esoht fo erom ynam woH
,pihs eht denaelc dah oreZ
,nwo ym sa railimaf sa tnecs sih
tenalp eht no edistuo gnirutnev enoemos ebircsed dluow yeht semitemoS
.noitces namuh eht ni esle gnihton dna
.yas ton dluoC .yrros mA"
,ssentiw ot srats eht neewteb ecaps fo ytimrone eht ssorca dellevart dah ohw
.nesohc erew yeht
.tsrif ruo neeb llits dah ehs tub
,elcyc noitasilirets lluf eht detaitini evah I"
,ti derebmemer I sa mlac dna raelc sa gnidnuos eciov reh
,areiK fo eciov teiuq eht emac
.gnorw ygoloiB .lavivrus oN
.erom ynam ,ynam emoceb dah dnasuoht ehT .dah ew dna
".dlrow etaerc eW .rehtO
.hguoht ,yrots a ton saw
,ot elba neeb dah ew sa tsuj taht os derebmuN
,srerolpxe taerg sa
.noitpo reveN .htraE nruteR"
.neppah ti gnihctaw fo rorret eht yb dellud
nevig neeb dah ew taht eciohc ehT
,rehto hcae ta yltfos deffins eW
.sreksihw ym dehctiwt dna dias I
rats rehtona rof gnidaeh
.sniamer lacigoloib yna rof kcehc lanretni etelpmoc a nuR
,noitcif ecneics dna msilaer laicos fo stib suoirav gnitirw
saw ti ,ecaps fo tnuoma eht tsuj ton saw tI .egdirb eht
.esnes ssel dna ssel edam yllaer tI
,dias I ",ecapS" ".ereht og deeN
.yaw eht fo emos tsael ta
.ylreporp taeb ot deliaf traeh ruoy hguoht sA
.elbatius si dlrow wen sihT
,ecaps egral rehtona otni
.tuo krow ot tluciffid erom hcum
,htraE tfel ew erofeb nrow dah rotaerc ruo dna sreniart eht seno eht ekil hcum erew yehT
.suoirolg saw ti tuB
.sevil eritne ruo detcetorp neeb dah eW ".kciuq
,meht ot ,ylpmis erew uoy taht uoy llet ot flesym gnirb ton dluoc I
.saw ti taht demees ti rood erusserp eht gnihtyreve saw ti taht em dlot esion gnikcus eht dna
.noitautis elbavlos a ton saw gnorw enog locotorp dnE
.B amixorP dnuora tibro otni devirra dah ew ecnis edaced eht ni naicinhcet tnedifnoc a otni
smetsys ruo morf ssecca on saw ereht taht saw tluser dne ehT
,seman ruo gnieb srebmun eht ot desu nworg dah eW
.erom hcum os dna desimorp neeb dah ew lla saw ti dna
,os gniod morf snamuh eht gnippots ni deeccus ton did yeht fi dna
ygolohtna tenalPruF eht ni dnuof eb nac
.niaga deef aremac a yb decalper neercs eht no egami eht
,dias ehs ",elbissoP
.dlrow wen etaerC .og eW
# ".su ylnO .snamuh erom oN"
,B amixorP no evil nac uoY
.kcolria lanretni kcolnu yllanif dna
.tixe eht sdrawot deklaw dna dnuora denrut eH
,star dnasuoht a taht ecaps a ni
,tser eht ot derapmoc llams ylddO
.pit liat ot eson morf gnol saw tar nworg ylluf a sa llat sa semit eerht erew snamuh taht nettogrof dah I ,sraey neethgie retfA
.enO neve erofeb emac ohw ehs ,oreZ ruO
,saw ti hguoht lufetsaw ,ecaps sti fo lla
.ydob eht ni dnuora devom ti taht naem ton did tI
su was snamuh rehto eht woh
,desilaer I ,dlo neeb dah ehs tub
smelborp eht xif ot woh tuo dekrow yllanif yeht erofeb
.moor eht edisni ees dluoc I taht tsud fo elip ylno eht dah hcihw noitats a ot
?dedeen eb dluow ti niatrec ton erew ti fi ,nwonknu
,rehto hcae demoorg dna ereht pu deldduc ew sA
,dluoc ew won tub
.thgir lla ti ekam dna
.thgir neeb dah enO taht desilaer I elihw a retfa tub ,tsrif ta pihs eht no yats tsuj ot lla su detnaw I
.esoprup hcum evres yllaer ton ot tsuj demees syawla dah ,llew ,hcihw eno detacol ylddo ylthgils A
sruo dna rotces namuh eht ni smetsys eht taht dna
tar on saw erehT
,ereht srehto gnidnif dna
,thguoht dah yeht naht regral hcum pihs eht saw ylno ton taht derevocsid star gniraf-ecaps ruo ,emit tsaL
.tneserper uoy tahW
.dlot erew yeht nehw gninetsil pots ton
,pot eht ot thgir ytivitisnes eht dehsup I
,knis dluow traeh s'oreh eht
.tol siht yb naht ,nerdlihc ym
.su dnuora gnihtyreve fo elacs eht saw
.su dloT .did yehT
.yllanrete ton esruoc fo tub ,ew naht regnol hcum os devil snamuH
.sevlesruo rof detcurtsnoc dah ew spihs wen eht fo eno fo epahs keels eht fo
,hgis a htiw niaga nwod kcab dial ehS
,rehtom rieht rof erew spup ruo lla sa demaN
.niaga kcab daeh ym gninrut erofeb
,nwodkcol morf snoitcnuf lla esaeler
tuoba ni rats ruo hcaer dluow eW
,elims namuh a nees dah I ecnis sraey neethgie neeb dah tI
ereht og dluow eW
.evol dna egaruoc ,rednow
yromem reh htob ruonoh ot ,taht od ot yaw tseb eht dna
.elbissoP .evivrus eW
,tnatropmi era uoy fo llA
,mih dniheb gnitser ylizal liat sih dna dexaler seye dna srae siH
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.su dnuora daerps taht ecnelis eht debrutsid sneercs dna snottub tsniaga stigid dewalc fo pat eht dna
.dias enO .terces giB
.nwo ruo fo wef a dedda neve dah eW
.thgir saw lufetsaW
.nerdlihc ym fo tsrif eht erew
.ti ot dehcatta tatibah namuh eht dna
.revo lla snoitatskrow gnivruc htiw
.eerht ytruof dna derdnuh neves rebmun regnol on saw ohw
.eciohc ruoy si sihT"
.serutnevda taerg fo selat evaew dluow ew
,pihs dlo eht morf desilabinnac slairetam morf tliub erew spihs wen ehT
.gniht eno fo erus ma I dna sraey neethgiE
,ezag yduolc reh dewollof I sa dna
.sterces dna sterceS .don mih was I
,krow rieht deyojne ohw redaer a morf gniraeh ekil yad s’retirw a snethgirb gnihtoN
,noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m’I
.rehtona ro dnik eno fo stnemegduj ni seruliaf gniwohs sdrocer dah lla ew dna
,evael dna nrut ot edam ew sa
,su no seye yduolc reh denrut ehS
.hturt eht dlot dah ehS
,B amixorP ot tog ew nehw dnif thgim ew tahw tuobA
.god.ecioveht ta bew eht no dna
.tsrif erew uoy tub
noitats eht otno pu delwarc I .sruo saw
,ebut taht fo sdne eht
.ti tsniaga dediced dah seno redlo rehto eht fo ynam dna I
.elpoep nwo reh ot ti llet dluow ew nooS
,yamsid ni deyalps srae ym ,yas ot deganam I "?tahW"
.ereh erew ew yhw si sihT .hsA
,uoy yb detneserper retteb raf eb lliw htraE
.ereh emoc lla ksa I
.ralimis esiwrehto tub ,lenap weiv dezisrevo na ekil erom
,nesneJ arhtruT rinieL naD yb
seton wohs eht ni rohtua s’edosipe hcae dnif nac uoY
.mlac ylddo gnikool dna ,edis eno ot gnikool
,dewob daeh reh htiw deunitnoc ehs
,stius esoht ,ruf ruo tsniaga yklub dna tnasaelpnU
nworg dah retsgnuoy ehT
"?ohw esilaeR .sihT"
.su dellik evah dluow dlrow eht ,detcetorpnu pihs eht edistuo deppets dna htraE ot denruter dah ew fI
,secalP weN gnirolpxE
,yracs erew seirots esohT
.enin ytnewt hguorht enO
,elihw a retfa dias areiK ",og tsum eW"
.htraE nruteR .nalp pihS"
,evitca llits saw noitats ehT
,dlo woh nwonk reven dah I
trap lanif dna dnoces eht si yrots s’yadoT dna
sdaehklub eht dekcol eW
.smelborp yna erew ereht fi ,efas erew yeht depoh I dna
.ecaps taht ni eb thgim taht stnecs eht fo yna hctac ot ytiliba ruo dekcolb ylrettu yeht dna
"?won nepo sseuG" ".nepo ton I
.emoh fo ylgnorts os dellems hcihw ecaps ylevol taht ni
,eno siht retfa erom ekil dluow uoy fi ,dnal ot taht rof gnitiaw elihW
.noitces lortnoc nwo ruo fo noisrev pu delacs a ssel ro erom demees ti dna
,pihs eht no worg ot ecaps eht dah reven dah eW
,ti fo dne eht eb dluohs siht taht ediced thgim yehT
.eciohc ekaM .elbissoP
.eciohc a su nevig dah ehS
,tsud fo elip enO
.stnetnoc orez gniR .deen oN"
.ssenlufetsaw ekil ton did
”taobefiL ruO erA uoY“ fo
,su dlot dah oreZ elat eht wonk ton did ohw
,seman dah evah dluohs uoY"
.atad eht lla su tfel dah ehs tub
.elpoep eseht rof pihs a nar hcihw yrenihcam eht fo trap a
tbuod on dah ew
.sredlo lla wohS
.noitpo rehtona tseggus ot niaga gnihsiws erofeb
.smroftalp dna syawklaw htiw dellif secaps egral sti
tsud fo elip egral a hguorht yaw ruo dehsup ew dna
.ytnewT ot elosnoc eht fo egde eht revo gnikool ,dias I
enO ot elif a tnes evah I tub
,uoy erongi ylpmis dna
",won sruo llA .pihS"
,tnemirepxe deliaf a si htraE
.retal sredlo rehtO .won uoy llaC"
,snamuh derdnuh A ".ecaps
,niaga denepo rodirroc eht ot rood s'egdirb eht elihW
.eciohc eno ylno ekam ton ot saw
em ta yltcerid dekool dna dias ehs ",eertnewT"
.meht fo hcae rof gnir eno
eliforp sdaeRdooG rieht no dnuof seigolohtna eht ni seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy
noitanitsed rieht ta devirra osla dah yeht
— setiruovaf ruoy fo emos tisiver ot tnemom a ekat ebyam
.ikiR gnieb rehtom rieht
,htraE ot nruter ot denitsed erew spihs eht fo owT
.tropweiv eht no wap a tup I
,rethgirb worg ot demees sthgil ehT .delims dna
dias ytnewT ",erom on wonK .lla sihT"
,egrup lacigoloib etelpmoc reggirT
evif sgnir ni revo sdop egarots eht fo wef A
.niahc loot eht fo trap rehtona tsuj sa ti rof detaerc yllaretil
.terces eunitnoc ton sihT"
.tug eht ni dehcnup neeb dah uoy hguoht sa tlef tI
,desuap neht dna dias ehs
,dias ytnewT ",ereH"
.worb reh no nworf a
.epoh tsal eht era uoY
.sedutitlum sseldne ot esrow did ohw
.stius htiw denil moor a saw rood eht dniheB
.ylpeed ni gnihtaerb ,dias ehs
,rotaerc ruo fo elpmaxe eht wollof ylippah dluow yehT
.elbatcetednu saw ti
,su dniheb rood eht desolc eW
”taobefiL ruO erA uoY“ fo
.snoitpo eht neewteb esoohc ot ton nesohc dah eW
.siht ni thgir saw enO
.rood eht edistuo eno egral a htiw
.em erofeb yalpsid eht ta dekool I sa dias I
.terces a niamer dluow ti fo enon taht
,rorroh fo hcuot a htiw desilaer I tsud ton ,oN
.ksat ruo ni liaf lla dluow ew taht dna
.spihs eht etaerc ot ,su fo lla ,rehtegot dekrow dah eW
.sgnilbis ruoy ot nevE
B amixorP ot gniog erew ew dlot neeb dah eW
,sretsgnuoy rehto eht fo ynam ekil ,dah eH
"?edisnwod enog newT"
,ffo egdirb eht gnikcol dna rood eht gnisolc erofeb ton tub
.ti htiw laed ot dah ew dna ,deneppah ydaerla dah tI
.su llik dluow yeht ro ,nepo ot wolla ton dluoc ew hcihw slacigoloib deniatnoc
,areiK sa ylduorp sa eman ym erob I dna
,gnivig fo emit a si siht elpoep ynam roF
",em tel t'ndluow yeht tub
,gnidrocer eht no dias ehs ",yrros ma I"
,ylwols erom emit siht
.tnaw uoy fi ,ereht evil nac uoY
,enin ytnewt hguorht eno ,uoY"
,aremac eht ot kcab ecaf reh desiar ehs nehw dna
,thgim uoy taht epoh I dna
saw ti fi lairetam hcum os gnirb ew dluow yhW
.eerht ytnewt rebmun decnuonorpsim eht regnol on saw I
.saera egarots eht tuohtiw tub
,stsen eht ni rehto hcae ot seirots llet dluow ew ,emit ot emit morF  2 fo 2 traP ,nesneJ arhtruT rinieL naD yb
etacoL .oga sraey ynaM
,desu yllamron ew seno eht ot derapmoc dezisrevo yletelpmoC
,eybdooG .duorp eb nac ew
.ecaps hcum ooT .llams rebmuN
.elbissoP .taerg toN
.eno elgnis yreve stsilayol
,em ediseb dias ytnewT ",seY" ".gib ooT"
.ydaer eb dluow nerdlihc ruo llA
,draob no erew snamuh revocsid dluohs ew taht
edaced a fo tsom tsal eht no gnikrow neeb ev’yeht cipe if ics taht em llet yeht dna
.ti tuoba od ot tahw fo eciohc a htiw decaf sevlesmeht dnuof dna
.lenap dniheb rooD
.lla meht od dluow eW
.tsen ot ekaT .egdelwonk ekaT"
.wonk srohtua eht tel ebyam dna
.desilaer I ,gnilims saw ehS
,treni yletelpmoc tub gnihtyna saw tsud siht fI
.lenap eht nwod tup ew sa
detfil waperof eno htiw gnidnats mih ees ot daeh ym denrut I dna
.tcefrep etiuq ton
,snoitces lla kcolnu reggirt
.slenap daehklub fo kcats a ekil
.srosnes lanretni eht pu dellup dna
.tiaw ot gnivah tuohtiw retal emoc dluoc elpoep os ,thgir erew snoitidnoc eht fi
,meht dekil reven dah I dna
,namuh a rof gnol ton saw sraey neethgiE
,derebmun erew htrib morf neeb dah ew sa tsuj ohw spup evif
.evitamriffa na dekaeuqs eh dna ,deksa I
.klat dluoc uoy dias ehs litnu ti tuoba mum tpek uoy ,gnihtemos tuoba mum peek dias enO fI
,lla uoy htiw emit hcum os tneps I