,denepo seye sih ecnO !sixelA
fo htmraw ehT .tcatnoc edam stuons ehT
,dnif uoy tops hguone etavirp tsrif eht ni ti od
,swolb lareves deppots dleihs sih hguohT
,seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
.niap emaceb ecnelis eht dna ecnatsid eht tub
shgis sa tuo gnimoc ekoms rieht
neerg sredlo ehT
,hguone esolc saw eh ecnO
.teiuq denrut ecalp elohw eht
.snaom s'dal eht fo emulov eht desiar osla tnemercni ehT
.kcab s'lakcaj eht ot
.deidaets yletelpmoc pirg eht ,hgis a htiW
,evird fo kcal a rof ton
sdaeb desselb reh dloh somarA zoriP
.duht cillatem duol A
.stneve gnideecorp eht dellacer eh ylwolS
.eert a tsniaga mra na htiw flesmih gnitroppus doots ,gnilahxe
.thgin doog a evaH
.aera ydnas eht nihtiw dnats dluow detaudarg yltnecer eht dna sreidlos
,redluohs s'lakcaj eht no sdnah sih fo eno tup eH
.ecnelis suoixna ni tcere
.dnuos rehtona pu dekcip ,doots eh sA
.tsehc s'lakcaj eht
.peels t'ndid enola sixelA
shtuoy wollef sih yb detaerc noisufnoc eht ot kcab denrut sixelA
.evitisnes oot ,hserf oot saw dal ehT
?ereh gniod uoy era tahW
.sselhtrow htuom sih
.doots zoriP dna lareneg eht erehw
,noitisop rieht morf nevE
.sdnim rieht ni gniht ylno eht saw
,naom eninac regral eht edam tahT
.deppord ecaf siH
,seye sih denrub mih evoba thgil gninrom eht tey dna
?mih tnel yeht raeps ehT
.mih ediseb yltaen gnittif
.selballys derruls dna
.oot ,ti deyojne I .dooG
,cinut dna etik s'niatpac eht detfil ti
.sehsub eht fo tuo pmuj mih edam
.srebmem htob debbarg dnah s'flow eht
.ezoob naht erom saw hcnets ehT
.noitautis eht denesrow ylno
.htraeh gnitrofmoc dna
,raeh yltniaf dluoc eh
.lakcaj gnuoy eht rof hcum oot saw tI
.redluohs sih no thgiew eltneg tlef lakcaJ eht
.foorp etamitlu eht saw
.ti tsniaga gnilzzun
depoord srae dna ecaf siH
,cinut sih desserac sdnah woh tuB
.tnet s'niatpac a ni steehs eht htaeneb dekan gniyl saw eh taht llet ot elihw a mih kooT
.htgnel s'mra ta lakcaj eht tpek eH
.daerpsediw saw melborp eht os ,dehsinup tnew ylerar
.ymene na tem reven drows sih
.dehsirep evah dluow I
.tnatropmi gnihtemos derebmemer eh nehw evael ot tuoba saw flow ehT
,resolc yltnatsnoc werd eH
.msagro neddih dna
tsew dehcram sixelA
.mra ynwarb taht depsarg dna
.nirg ythguan a htiw stigid esoht no gnikcus saw tub
.tfola sdaeb eht dleh ohw floW deR eht no noitnetta tup eH
,dleihs sih evom ot yrt dluoc eH
.tug eht nwod dils sdnah s'lakcaj eht
ydob s'rednes sih ot welf ti sa denetsilg diuqil etihw ehT
.degilbo niatpac ehT .em dael
.niaga teem lliw eW .yrrow ton oD
.ssik rehtona rof flesmih decarb htuoy ehT
.ygrene dna htgnerts htiw dekrej lakcaj eht
.sknurd eht htiw ecaps gnipeels a gnirahs ot drawrof gnikool ton saw eH
noisiced ym detpecca sah ehS
.seciov tnenimorp htiw nam eht desiarp stnadnetta tsoM
.mih del flow eht sa
.eninac redlo eht deifsitas naht erom dliub sih tub
,mih taoc mreps s'oreh sih tel sixelA
roirraw wen a htiw su desselb sseddog eht rof ereh dnats eW
,noinapmoc sih ot meht evig llahs dna
.soriP niatpaC ,seY
.mih truh yllautca evah thgim taht naht regnorts gnihtyna htiw gnitratS
.deppord tuons dna srae siH
,eromyna edih ot gnihton did flow der eht noos dna
.eninac eht fo kcab eht no ruf der eht til noom eht fo thgil elap ehT
,hcnilf dna egnirc dluow eh emit hcae dna
.luferac erom elttil a eb ot dah ehs os ,raw ot amozirep reporp a thguorb ton dah sixelA
?dnatsrednu uoy oD
.rethgif deniartnu eht ot gnihton devres snalp dna seigetarts esoht llA
.revo eb dluow efil s'lakcaJ eht dna drows sih fo evom enO
,noisufnoc otni nellaf evah dluow dnim s'sixelA
ewa ni dehctaw flow ehT
.sixelA ,yad taht ecnis uoy tuoba thguoht evah I .soriP niatpaC
.dedaf hcuot mraw eht sa mih gnittih noitautis eht
.uoy esuor ot tuoba saw I
derodA recnaL ruoY
,dezilaicos ylerar si xelA
.llew sa ni devom dna
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
,ytilaer ot kcab mih decrof eninac redlo eht ,erofeb ekiL
.pleh ot nrut sih saw tI
.flow eht sdrawot depmil tub
.gnihcuot niaga erew stuons riehT
.kcab gnilims saw eh
.tsrif ekops htuoy eht
.slarotcep eht teem ot degnulp ecaf suoiruc siH .emosdnaH
,eno siht ot sleuqes gnidulcni
?elbatpecca taht saW
.setunim rof dedeecorp
.reidlos4102u\a ,won ereh er'uoy
mih woleb maerts suounitnoc ehT
.enola seigetarts no sucof dluoc dnim sih taht elbissopmi saw ti
.rovaedne na evorp dluow ti htiw gnilaeD
,noitazilaer taht nopU
,shgiht nwo sih no ssenivaeh sih lla tup ot luferac saw flow ehT
.wolb-htaed eht rof tnew nam redlo ehT .kcab dloh t'noD
?eman siH .sixelA ,sixelA
.ti dekil nem woh yltcaxe wenk flow redlo ehT
,sorygrA fo elttaB eht ni yrevarb rieht roF
.daeh s'nam ypeels eht ni deyalper dna deyalp
,kaeps eciov peed eht draeh sixelA .nus a htiw
.seitilamrof elpmis eht tpoda ot derehtob sreidlos wollef sih fo wef demees tI
.ssenisword sih ot detubirtnoc ylno
,noon erofeb ailoA fo etats-ytic eht ot denruter
tnemhsinup gniraes
,ecaps eht fo hcum os dellif yehT
.lliks fo kcal a rof tub
.flow eht desirprus yleniuneg rewsna regae ehT
.uoy morf raeh ot evol d'I dna
,sretnuocne tsap sih retfa ekiL
,sreidlos gnihcram eht fo elddim eht ni dednal worra elgnis A
.htuom s'nam der eht ni demrof elims eniuneg A
,yracs saw hctiws kciuq ehT
.ygrene htiw ti gnilkcus yb dednopser sixelA
.mih desirprus flow ehT
eseht piks nac uoy
.raw ni detsissa ynapmoc detpircsnoc eht fo raey lanif eht fo srebmem eht ylno sa
.dnim s'sixelA ni dna dleifelttab eht ni dengier soahC
.ytic gninim eht otni gnidael
.dia s'floW deR eht emoceb ot ecnahc eht dleh nem lla ,nwod peeD
.tabmoc ni sehsiw reh dloh llahs taht
.tsiaw eht yb eninac gnirewot eht gnikat ot devom dah dnah s'htuoy ehT
,dworc eht ekilnu ,nem ymra gnuoy ehT
detehcocir dna dehsalc lateM
.floW deR eht yb del dnab sih dnif ot hguone yppah tsael ta saw lakcaJ ehT
.depsag dna denaom ylwols nam gnuoy ehT
seninac eht fo ecarbme rettew ,regnol ehT
.dessap dah yad eht dnatsrednu dna kniht dluoc eh
.ecaf sih ot dewolf emahS
.ailoA gnivael erofeb nem gnuoy eht detcurtsni yeht sa
,floW eht rof gnignol dna
!ytisoiruC !esirpruS
,flow eht dias ,lleW
.repeed og ot dah eh wenk flow der eht ,kcab dellup ecaF
.eciov sih yb htuoy eht hsiugnitsid ylno dluoc eh ,detanimulli yleraB
.thginot wols ti ekat lliw eW .sixelA ,oN
,emit gnol a ni ecno roF
erusaelp eht ot derednerrus dna
,dehcuot yllanif seitiliriv riehT
.tleb rehtael s'htuoy eht dleh taht sparts eht didnu dna warts eht hguorht gud sregnif s'eninac ehT
ekops flow eht tub
.dor eht deppirg ylregae dna flesmih niatnoc ton dluoc nam gnuoy eht
.ecrof ton tub ssentcirts htiw tluassa eht del eugnot s'flow eht
.emas eht emaceb gnihtyreve
,roolf 'stnet eht no gniddeb warts eht tsniaga nwod tup yltneg ydob siH
.rewsna ot stnemmoc on dah htuoy ehT
?pleh deen uoy oD ?truH
.esle elttil od dluoc tub
.tsehc sih ot dnah sih thguorb eH
,yas ot fi sa ,stnemevom siH
.trats wols A .zoriP dias
.noitanalpxe rehtruf on dedeen eH .eurt era yehT
.oot ,ecnatsid trohs a hcus ta
flow eht erimda dluoc eh
,deggard syad gniwollof ,lakcaj eht oT
flow eht troppus ot devom stigid derevoc-avilas sih nehw nevE
.draeh reve dah wef dnuos a
.ymra htuoy eht fo esoht gnisuba
?sgnileef wen sih nopu tca ot hguone gnorts eb eh lliw
.esolc era sniatpac rehto ehT
.daeherof sih no emit taht
.s'flow eht cimim ot devom
.owt eht neewteb deneppah reve dah taht erofeb gnihton ekil
,pmac eht ot tog yehT
emit tsal eno sixelA otni decnavda zoriP
?recnal ym eb uoy lliW .noitome fo lluf
.trofmoc ylno ,tnemhsinup oN
,uoy ediseb nam eht drauG
,gnimaerdyad elihW
.seye s'lakcaJ gnuoy eht erofeb dehsalf gninrom dna nwaD
.gnisselb reh nekat evah I sa
.soryP otni yarts flesti yb dluow
.ylluftnevenu ton tub
.trapretnuoc regnuoy sih dewodahsrevo stohs sih ,rewop nI
.taeh 'srehto eht neewteb ni gnihton
,llew os sretsgnuoy eht detaert ohw ,sorygrA fo elpoep eht roF
s'zoriP .htuoy gniyl eht delddarts ,desopxe yletelpmoc
.htuoy dezilibommi eht ot dednetxe mra na sa
,rethgif gnuoy a gnisiar reniart a ekiL
,sgnaf s'flow eht decreip eugnot siH
.spsag pmad neewteb dias flow ehT
,tcatnoc fo ngis tsrif eht tA
.scep tif eht desopxe os dna
.teiuq eb tsum eH
.ekawa ediw saw eh litnu dnim sih dellif esion ehT
.ymra htuoy eht fo srebmem tnapicitrap detaudarg licnuoc eht
,niaga yawa sehcnI
.ekatsim sih dnema ot devom eh
,romra sih tem reve nopaew on taht hguone yltnailav draug sih desiar eH .gnilbmert
?thgir lla ,retsaf tib a og s'teL .taerG
kcab ydob sih werht flow ehT
yrots s'yadot dnA
.srebmun 'stnegrusni eht detanimod snailoeA eht tub
.tcilfnoc ysae na ni efil tsol ylno eht neeb evah dluow ti
flow eht ot dnah sih dednetxe eH .htgnerts
.mih dlot dah soriP tahw
,evitpac hsubma eht rof elbisnopser slebeR
.retrauq on roirepus sih evag htuoy ehT !sixelA ,hO
.mih ecaf ot htuoy eht detpmorp hcihw
.gniwolfrevo fo egde eht no saw retsgnuoy ehT
,ygetarts lavivrus doog a devorp dleihs a dniheb gnidiH
denokceb won
.meht thguac enoemos erofeb yawa kaerb ot dah eninac redlo ehT
.nwot eht fo dloh tog sleber eht ecno
.mih degguh flow eht sa slarotcep esoht no dedilloc sdnah s'lakcaj ehT
.lakcaj eht morf elims a htiw mih dedrawa tahT
.did esoht ekil mih htaeneb nam gnuoy eht fo tuo emoc dluoc sdrow hcus taht feilebsid reehs fo tub
,yltcaf-fo-rettam niaga ekops eH
,ymra htuoy eht fo hctapsid eht deriuqer elttab on ,sraey eerht roF
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na si retrap-owt s'keew sihT
.sorygrA edistuo tsuj
.taht tnaw ton od I
,oreh sih tuohtiw teY
.tabmoc ni ecnamrofrep ym dehctob I
,niaga detca ecrof ehT
.sleber yb deipucco ytic eht ,sorygrA ot
.mih no doohnam yrd fo llems tcnitsid eht llems dluoc eh dna sffins owT
.tseug devoleb a otni denrut rebmem gnidavni ehT
.tser eht naht reduol saw naom enO
,tcnitsid werg eciov ehT
.ti eveileb ot tnaw ton did eH
.yllufrednow did uoY .sixelA ,tseR
,hgih taht hctip a dehcaer eciov peed sih yaw ehT
,ti ees ton dluoc lakcaJ eht
.wollof ot dnammoc hguot a
.seirujni rof nam eht deziniturcs seye s'sixelA
.deppirts lodi sih
.snoitcaf owt eht neewteb hsalc elpmis eht dnoyeb gninnalp tnaillirb on saw erehT
.ti edih ot kciuq saw flow ehT
.reidlos ,yadot llew did uoY .esae tA
.revewoh ,ti pots ot ereht saw zoriP
.decnad seugnot stuons esoht neewteb dna nihtiW
.lareneg eht dewolleb
,derusaelp gnieb saw htuom siH
.ssik dnoces eht detrats lakcaj ehT
?thgir lla ,sreidlos rehto eht nioJ
,ecnedac htiw detca ohw ,flow eht ekilnU
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m'I
.yad gniwollof eht emoh nruter dluow yeht erofeb
,wolgretfa na ni saw sixelA .oot ,ytsaT
.thguoht eh ,tabmoc taht morf ytlausac ylno eht neeb evah dluow eh
.daetsni stsurht civlep demrofrep dna skcoc htob no dnah sih dellits eH
.ylwols sehsub hguorht gnikaerb dna seert gnigdod ,htlaets
sgnileef diputs sih morf nrob maerd A
,roirraw ot rethgif deniart
.renokceb eht was dna burhs lanif eno hguorht ekorb eH
,smra sih ni llitS
.sseddog eht fo tfig eht gniraeb emoc I
,yellov ylrae eht edistuO
.noitautis eht fo ytilausnes eht ot gnidda
.sruoy em ekaM .zoriP ,em ekaT
.reidlos4102u\a ,boj taerg
.reidlos ,tey emit ruoy ton s'tI
.zoriP saw ti tbuod oN
,noitisop sih morF
,sgnileef wen ,toh eht yb deL
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer ,nagidraC yb
.redluohs sih ta dednal dna
tsehc s'nam gnuoy eht no
.esruoc fo ,tnew sixelA
,meht eveileb ot detnaw eh ,esimorp taht ,sdrow esohT
.dehctef I htolc dna tekcub taht esu
.raelc emaceb repsihw eht ,emit nI
.revewoh ,mih ediseb ton saw roirepus siH
.flow der ehT .mih was eh
.digirf nrut ot tey saw ydob ehT
,feirb saw sorygrA fo elpoep eht gnitsissa dna dednuow eht gnilaeh tneps emit ehT
nwo sih tsap welf daeh s'eninac regral ehT
,yrc gnicreip a htiW
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.denruter sesnes sih sa daeh sih koohs eH
.eciffus ot evah dluow htmraw rieht
.sroirraw nailoeA eht elcric ot esor seof
.dnim s'sixelA dessorc dah srotca dab hcus yb detegrat gnieb fo thguoht ehT
,delttes yeht ecnO
.ti dewollof htuoy eht
,noitca sih fo ssenevisarba eht gnicitoN
.elbmarcs a otni nekorb saw xnalahp eht saw taht retsnom dezinagro ecno ehT
,ris ,pleh ruoy rof ton ti ereW
,xnalahp eht fo elddim eht ni noos saw eH
.slairub reporp daed wef eht evag
,esproc a gniveirter htiw deksat
,nem gnuoy fo gnireehc dna gnitnahc hsiroB
decalp neeb dah taht ograbme utpmorpmi eht yb demmid srebmun rieht nwohs dah letnI
?uoy t'nera ,esolc er'uoY
.dnim sih fo seloh eht ni ylsseldne deohce esarhp taht sa
.zoriP dias ,pu teG
,yrekcom fo tuo ton
.devas yeht steerts eht gnoma tuo dessap dah srethgif ynam ,yaw sih nO
.hsalf a ni mih ot denrut
,hgis peed a dna ,reyarp tnelis a ,esuap a retfA
.enog saw dnuorg pmad eht ot mih dexif taht thgiew ehT
,mih fo tnorf ni doots ydob der evissam eht dna
mih hcaer ot deliaf dah ecno taht dnah ehT
.deyojne eh slian demmirt ylluferac s'flow eht neve
.ssik a otni dehsiruolf hcuot eht nooS
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy
etarbelec ot tfel erew sreidlos eht nwodnus erofeb os dna
.thgin taht reilrae eno eht
silop eht ta gnivirra
,dias eh ,lufituaeB
.raw saw taht tub
,shtuoy ydwor eht morf yawa flesmih tog yllanif eh ecnO
.moc.yrrufos.nagidrac ta
,thgif eurt a nees ton dah sixelA
.erusaelp otni mih dael lodi sih tel regnuoy ehT
.emit on dah eh wenk tub
,dereviuq shtuom riehT
,htuom s'eninac gnuoy eht derettibme raw lautca fo etsat tsrif ehT
,taebtraeh s'flow ehT
,dehsinotsa ,flow ehT
,tfihs tpurba na nI
?pu gnidloh uoy era woH ?woH
.mrofrep ot evom tsal eno dah eh
.noitnetta werd seirrauq fo yellav evissam eht
shtuoy eht ,dennalp dna delbmessa ymra gnidnats eht fo srebmem rehto dna sniatpac eht elihW
.noitcif evitcaretni dna
delcric sdnah ynwarB
,noitale dna tnemssarrabme fo xim a htiw detaeh ecaf s'sixelA elihW
,raef nI .sevlesmeht ylno
.gnihtyna roF .saw eH
,dniw keem eht ni gniltsur sevael eht gnomA
,thguoht eh ,tnatsid fi nevE
.nworb diviv s'htuoy eht tem
,erahs ot ekil d'uoy yrots a evah uoy fi dnA
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht si
.ydob nwo sih lios mreps fo dnelb eht gnittel
.elzzum s'lakcaj eht desserac dnah ynwar eht fo kcab ehT
,nagidraC yb derodA
ydob ybbuhc tey ralucsum sih
.elur eht ecrofne ot flesti nopu koot ylerar
,seno gniknar-hgih yllaicepse
ydob s'eno rehto eht
.nihc s'dnal eht desiar eH
.hguone raf yllanif saw eH
.nirg der taht htiw dehsinav lla
.sorygrA fo yellav eht dednuob tserof llams A
.taht fo enon tlef nam gnuoy eht
yromem neht dna noitanigami sih
,dnuorg eht no dezad deniamer evah dluow eh
,sgnimoctrohs sih fo erawa ylneek ,htuoy ehT
nwot revlis eht fo steerts gnipeels eht hguorht
,eslaf yllohw ton hguohT
noitavreserp-fles ekasrof oT
.stohs gnihcaer-raf dna lufrewop htiw mih dedroffa htuoy fo ytiliriv euqinu eht sa
.mih rof klat dluow snoitca sih ,ecno roF
,raw fo thgiew eht
,meht pots ot gnihtoN
.ruf nedlog eht deziniturcs slirtson nwo s'flow eht sa
.lohocla gnimusnoc morf dewollasid yllaiciffo erew sreidloS
.eno naht syaw erom ni zoriP ot esolc ytterp
.oreh sih ot ytitsahc sih esol
.ris ,uoy knahT
htob meht revoc dluow dleihs evissam siH
,soriP niatpaC .htuoy eht
.ris ,uoy knaht ,seY
,raw fo ssenhguot eht wenk ohw ,ymra gnidnats eht ,licnuoc eht fo ecneserp eht tuohtiW
.doog os sleeF .dooG
.anera eht ni swen eht evig dluow zoriP
.thgin eht otni etal
.lodi sih dniheb dehsur eH .niatpac ,seY
deborp sdnah derruf-der eht
.dnah s'eninac eht yb desuod
.sregnif owt fo pit eht ta delbbin nam gnuoy eht
,sixelA ot ,wohemoS
.dehctamnu erew ssentfos dna taeh ehT
.won evael tsum I .netsil
.sedis htob no desolc seye
.thgin reilrae eht morf snoitca s'elpuoc eht noitnem ot derehtob ro deciton eno oN
.troffe on koot noitautis eht gnidnatsrednU
.flow der eht ot ron flesmih ot ton degnoleb sthguoht sih
,deniamer yeht erehT .zoriP ,seY
.lakcaJ eht revo welb tsug A
.seilla nellaf ot nrut ot xelfer eht thguof sixelA
.htolc fo eceip niht a dniheb dih noitcere deniatnoc ylerab sih oS
.dedaeh-ytpme ssenisub sih did dna dettauqs htuoy eht ,ypeels yltsoM
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.ti htaenrednu sgnileef eht delaever sredluohs s'htuoy eht no smlap gnilbmert eht tub
fo trap lanif dna dnoces eht saw sihT
syad dab ynam nO
,ymra htuoy eht fo pleh eht htiW
,dleihs s'htuoy eht tih stcejbo weF
.tsehc s'dal eht gnirevoc knups fo erutxim eht revo regnif sih werd nam eht ,oS
,deltserw sesinep dna seugnot rieht sA
lakcaj eht fo smra depoord ylsuoiverp ehT
,nekat dah eh sevil ehT
.eerga tonnac I rof ,ris ,em evigroF
,erob eh edalb dna dleihs ehT .tsol gnoL
.ymra suoigitserp rieht fo srebmem tsewen eht ees ot gnitiaw ,gnireehc
.eman ym gnillac dna truh si eH
,tnet taht edistuo enod lla ecno
,lakcaj eht yb gnittauqs elihw dias eh ,sixelA
,rehto hcae ni deltsen
,erofeb taht ekil mih dehcuot dah eno oN
gnitser snrut koot
.ysub saw dnim sih tub ,tuons s'sixelA saw oS
.won thgir daeh taht hguorht gniog era sthguoht fo dnik tahw wonk I ,netsiL
shtuom rieht fo ecarbme teews ehT
.thgin taht rouqil detsat tsrif sixelA
.ekawa lakcaj eht deciton eh nehw elbatneserp gnitteg saw flow ehT
,ydob s'flow eht fo tnempoleved eht hctam dluoc sixelA yaw oN
flow a fo dnah gnitatiseh eht
,ymra gnidnats eht fo srebmem fo seirotS
.esnefed dna esneffo tuoba saw raw tub
.sretsgnuoy fo poort hcae del ymra gnidnats eht fo sniatpac gniknar-hgiH
tog sixelA ,emit tsaL
.erusaelp fo eno tub
.pu ekow lakcaj eht neht saw tI
muidop llams a delcric shtuoy ehT
.roolf eht ot lakcaJ eht dehsurc ecrof a
,srotciv eht dessap eH
.denruter ,edacaf eht ,kool suoires ehT
.mih yb shgiht ytaem esoht gnibbur yltnatsnoc yb flow eht deknaht lakcaj ehT
.ti ees ot hguone esolc yllanif saw eH
,tuons ecnal eht no detaeh sdrow esoht fo hcaE
.flesmih detcerroc yldrazahpah eH
,egalliv taht fo enilefil eht ecno saw neerg ehT
,elpoep sih rof thguof deedni eH .rekatefil
?kcatta esirprus A
,ecnatsid eht ni zoriP was eh nehw hserf llits saw retnuocne eht fo yromem ehT
,deppots niar yldaed eht retfA .revaw ton tub
.htolc a ni seidob denibmoc eht derevoc dna
,eciov ytluaf a ni ,dias eh ,etar yna tA
.lakcaj eht dednahnu dna taorht sih deraelc eH
.tnelis yleritne deniamer eh thgin tahT
,mih derebmemer yeht fI
.ytuaeb laerrus eht yb
,peels ot flesmih hsiuqniler dluoc eh erofeb tub
sgnileef hcus dehsiuqniler eh tub ,deniamer raw fo raef ehT
,esirprus sih nI .sixelA dias
.dedne yllufecrof efil s'nam a tub
nrecsid dluoc eh yleraB
.stnet laudividni rieht dah sniatpac eht erehw
denaom lakcaj ehT
.suoirotciv degreme snailoeA ehT
,nam gnuoy eht no ssik rehtona decalp flow ehT .esimorp a s'tI
.eciohc sih ot devom eh
,laecnoc ot deirt flow eht tahW
.rehto hcae otni denaom yehT
.peels ot sixelA del taht yballul a
?truh uoy era ,zoriP niatpaC
,oot ,sdnuos eht htiw detsissa tI
,mih morf yawa ecnalg a floW eht htiW
,nam redlo eht fo riah hsinworb eht ot decnavda eson s'htuoy ehT
,ni evag tsuj nam gnuoy ehT
.erutraped eht rof gniraperp era sniatpac ehT
.tsud fo aes ymrots a otni denrut yeht ,hsarc eht retfA
,nemyrtnuoc wollef ruoy tsurt yldnilb dna
.zoriP dias ,tiaW
thgin suoiverp eht fo stneve ehT
,syawla sA .noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
,scifironoh dna setulas gnisu
,mih revo derewot emarf
,dleihs sih dniheB
,gniciton tuohtiW
.stnemragrednu sih edisni dehctiwt ytiliriv nwo sih
.dah reven eh sa emac eH
.lluf os erauqs eht was reven sixelA
.elkcuhc a htiw zoriP dias ,taht ekil uoY
,ssenkrad ni detaoc ,yletanutrofnu
.efil nailoeA rehto on koot yeht
enohs sdnah sih no senots neerg dna eulb fo noitanibmoc ehT .dednetxe dnah
.noitcaer s'nam gnihcaorppa eht gnimoclew
dluohs uoy ,dehsulf ,dias eh
eerced yloh eht derruls sniatpac ehT
.yletaidemmi lakcaj eht gnikaw
,tnemhcated fo noisulli eht rednu
,evom eht no seimra esohT
.dnuorg eht no mih dah ymene ehT
,egami eht ta derevihs eH
.ytilaer ni deneppah dah gnihtyrevE
,fo locotorp eht wollof ot etilopmi ti dnuof sixelA
.htuom taht revo mlap sih gnittup yb dal eht tuhs zoriP ,noitarepsed nI
,thgin taht sgnileef esoht no tca ton dluoc eh hguohT
dehctam ylno eulav sti
.daed ro ,evitiguf
.ylsseltroffe eriuqs sih ot enileeb a edam zoriP
,elkcuhc thgil a otni denrut tnemhsinotsa sih ,tniop eht oT
.sixelA ,gninrom doog ,hA
.derevoc cinut eht tahw dnoyeb ydob sih ees ot tey saw nam redlo eht tub
.flesmih morf mih detcartsid dah gninrom taht fo stneve ehT
.dees fo naelc ti gnikcil ,ecaf sih ot dnah eht thguorb neht dna
,anera eht ni yad taht noitcaer ehT 4102u\I4102u\I .tsrif
?sromur eht wonk uoy oD
.noitommoc yrotarbelec a otni mih dellup smra ngierof
.zoriP niatpaC ,od I
.ecap eht pu dekcip eH
,mih dniheb tub ,wonk ton did eH
.soriP ,taerg saw tI
.deneppah taht erofeb niaga ekops flow eht tub
?ti ekil uoy did woH
lakcaj eht yb thguoht tnatsni ehT
,reidlos ,evael uoy erofeB
,ymra eht fo redael eht morf noitom a htiW
.ezag s'lakcaj eht did oS
.ecarbme tsemraw ehT .zoriP em llaC
.etulas dna etteuqite reporp htiw flow eht sserdda t'ndid eh
.seimene rieht htiw yrtnasaelp hcus htiw rehtob siloB did modleS
,ris ,eman ym llac uoy draeh I
.skcarrab tfihsekam rieht ni dial sdal eht nehw emoc ylerab dah thgiN
.spoort rehto eht gnoma niatpac sih yb del gnieb
.skcarrab tfihsekam eht ot tnew eh erofeb
,htaeneb rehtael eht tlef seot pu-delruc sih
morf tnew lakcaJ gnuoy ehT
.erofeb mih koot smaerd sih ylno erehw saw eH
daor nedal-llih eht no tem seitrap htob ,nooS
,yad taht mih dellac esle enoyna fI
.ylrae peels ot thguat erew sreidloS
.dessarrabme ,denrut eh
,noitamrof esnefed ni sroirraw eht esuor ot kciuq erew sniatpac ehT !hsubma nA
.egnar sih ni neht saw ,derujnoc ylno noitanigami sih tahw
.raw dezinagro fo seirtnasaelp lausu eht fo enon degnahcxe yehT
.lamron sa dedeecorp yad ehT
,ti tuoba kniht ot emit nekat ton dah eH .rewop eht
.eciov ytluaf a ni derewsna yllanif eh ,seY
,flow eht htiw etamitni tahwemos emoceb dah htuoy eht neht yB
,niap fo ecruos a toN
,dehcnuh flow ehT
.flow eht fo ecnesba suoiretsym eht rof truh dna
,doohnam taht lla ekat dluow eH .tsrif sih
.gninrom gniwollof eht ylraed yap dluow yeht wenk lakcaj ehT
.epac a ,htuom sih ot kcoc eht gnimia
.esruoc fo ,tegrat eno htiw devom eH
,erom yaw siht yojne ot gniog er'uoY
raw rof detius-lli tlef eH .sixelA ton tub
.sredluohs sih fo hcae no sdnah ylnam
.ni sregnif sih fo erom detresni eH
.yrotciv dna lavivrus rof delwarb nem sa
,dedeen yeht redro ylno eht detuohs sniatpac ehT
,ylimaf sih fo edalb dna romra detirehni eht htiw dettiF
sdaeB dercaS eht fo dnaB eht fo rebmem tsewen eht taht dias tnemecnuonna cilbup A
,srehcaelb eht dekcap snailiviC
recnaL ruoY :yojne esaelP
.nwot fo strikstuo eht no noitacol suovzedner eht ot ti edam yeht erofeb raw was nem ehT
.dehcaorppa ylidaets xamilc fo tniop eht sa
.srettam tahw si tahT
.nruter ni maeb yllanif dluoc sixelA
tib a rof ti desserac flow ehT
.noitamrofni hcus wenk ymra eht morf enoemos ylnO
.nwod wols eh did ,mih revo ylivaeh hgis dna
.siloB eht ot deilla egalliv a no noitcerrusni na tuo tup ot tcilfnoc rellams a
,roolf nedoow detavele eht morf dednecsed
,maercs yreve htiW
.llew noitisop eht wenk seninac htob
,spoort ymra gnidnats fo lufdnah a tpecxe ,ymra ehT
,sega rof fo demaerd dna derimda dah eh nam eht ,lodi siH
,margeleT dna rettiwT no yggodikahk@ m'I .wonk em tel esaelp
snoitca hcus fo srotartepreP
,flesmih gnihtolc morf eerf saw eh woh neht dna
.ssentew emos dewohs thgilnoom eht ni denetsilg ti yaw ehT
,yhw llet ton dluoc lakcaj ehT !tsuL
.noitacol rehtraf a ot deklaw eh os
.neeb syawla dah eh lodi eht sa
.noinapmoc sih nesohc dah
.nwod demlac yllanif nem gnuoy eht nehw thgin eht fo elddim eht saw tI
.kcoc sih ot tsiaw s'eninac eht morf tnew dnah sih
.ti yojnE .llew yreV
.selitcejorp rehtruf morf tcetorp ot pu sdleihs
,sleber tsom devalsne yehT .daed on tub
,ymra gnidnats eht ni noitisop a ot dedeecorp ynaM
.maerd tew diviv yrev a neeb evah dluoc tniop taht erofeb gnihtyreve
,trofmoc emoceb dah eciov s'zoriP tub
.enot nwo sih desiar eh
,ecap sti pu dekcip dnah ylnam ehT .did eh os dnA
seirots trohs setirw eh woN
.detcepxe sa secrof leber eht dehsurc snailoeA ehT
,sgel sih neewteB
aera detagerges eht ot ti edam lodi sih sa hctaw ylno dluoc lakcaj gnuoy ehT .ris ,oot uoY
mraw A .selbram neerg esoht niaga tem dna
.gnihsalc sevaw egral owt
,gninim esnetni eht morf etihw denrut sniatnuom sa
.etelpmocni erew ti dniheb tnemitnes eht wenk htob
.ecaf s'eninac eht tih retaw dloC
.dlo fo reidlos eht did sa
,detarepsaxe tsomla
,tabmoc ot dellac erew ailoA fo sreidloS ~ .2 fo 2 trap
htiw ecruos eht dehcaorppa eH
.seye sih desolc eH .ti saw tahT
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er'uoY
,sniatpac eht rof stnet fo aes eht ot dna
.lesaew gnuoy a gnirujni
,elbativeni saw taht ,snailoeA dednuow ynaM
,mih fo daeha tsuJ
.gninaom yb ssik eht ekorb yehT
.keew txen uoy rof seirots wen eb ll'ereht dna
.sseddog eht fo eerced yloh eht
snaom dna stnurg
.tsehc taht deporg dna
.mih delcric taht nem gnuoy fo dworc eht otni evod dna
.suoivbo saw ti zoriP ot dna
,citoahc denrut sthguoht s'zoriP
.slevon lausiv yrruf fo noitcifnaf tluda htiw 0202 etal yrev ni gnitirw nageb eH .nagidraC yb derodA recnaL ruoY
,niaga mih steem eh nehw ,won tuB
.noitatiseh dna ezis htiw degrahc eciov sih ,sixelA
.sffuh duol htiw dellif ,ylnam dna peed
.dessarrabme teg ro dnopser dluoc lakcaj eht erofeb niaga nam eht dessik yehT
.sehctorc tnioj eht morf dnah sih devomer eninac redlo eht ,dedne tsalb eht retfA .ecaf dna
,elddim eht ni loop egral eht no eulb enohs yks noonretfa etal ehT
,niaga sdnah sih devom zoriP .sixelA
.pu denaelc flesruoy teG
.egac taem sti gniodnu erofeb
.noitasnes lautca eht dih htolc tew tahT
.elpuoc eht no tceffe on dah dniw llihc ehT
.sesnes sih detanimod enola flow eht fo htmraw ehT
.noitartnecnoc sih lla koot srae derruf
,ailoeA fo elpoeP
.stnemevom eht gnisae sdor htob morf ssentew emos
.flow eht saw yad taht enod dna nees dah eh tahw fo tceffe eht desae taht sthguoht ylno ehT
.enon mih no dehgiew tub
,desaec flow der eht ecnO
.laer hguorht gnineppah saw tahT
,yltcaf-fo-rettam gnikaepS
,mih ta demaeb elims
.dedraug eb lliw uoy dna
,reidlos sih degguh niatpac ehT
dnah sih desiar sixelA
,eninac redlo ehT .mih roF
,lairetam s'tnet eht hguorht ekorb esirnus fo stib tseilrae ehT
.ycavirp dnif dluow sixelA erehw eb dluow ti thgin taht tub
.roirepus sih dehcaorppa nam gnuoy deirrow eht
,wonk ton did htuoy ehT ?toh taht saW
,snailoeA eht oT
.gninnalp yad-flah eht fo tsom tneps
.sliated sti fo tsom delaecnoc ssenkraD .emahs sih
,cinut s'htuoy eht gnidloh snottub eht odnu ot kciuq saw eH
.spil dna htuom s'nam rehto eht desaet dna decnad
tsehc sih no daeh s'sixelA tup soriP
.ksat ylno sih saw em ediseb xof siht tcetorP
,seninac eht edisni reip emaceb sgnileef ehT .dne ot dah
.mih elosnoc ot redluohs sih teem ot deliaf
.dnim sih tfel ylurt rehtien tey dnA
,noitnetta elttil meht evag
.mih dellac erutaN
,derit ,eciov s'nam a
,gniddeb eht no lakcaj nedlog eht denioj eh ,deifsitas htob
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
,gnol s'lakcaj ehT
.semalf eht yb debrosba ailoeA fo dradnats eht htaeneb eryp larenuf eht dehctaw eH
!airotciV ailoeA ,em ediug O
.derussa saw yrotciv
noitcerid eht demrifnoc
.mih revo derewot ecneserp rehtonA .denepo seyE
,tuons s'lakcaj eht morf yletelpmoc dnah eht koot eh erofeB .em evigrof ,hA
.stnatabmoc ecalp driht dna dnoces ,tsrif s'tnemanruot eht did oS
?ydaer uoy erA .mih sserdda ot
.semit rehto ynam os yrotciv meht thguorb dah taht yhposolihp a hcus saw ti
.noitisop s'dal eht fo suoicsnoc
.ykcul os ton erew sdal esoht tub
.pmac dnuora gnipleh dna
.degrahc sleber eht
.sllih gnidnuorrus eht ni esor seimene sa dnuorg eht ot llef dal ehT
,neerg eht fo kciht eht hguorhT .desolc seye
.rafa morf gnihctaw ylno