”?feeb denroc emos tnaW“
”?gnileef er'yeht tahw tuo erugif em pleh uoy naC
.tneitap wen reh htiw deipuccoerp oot t’nsaw ehs fi ,hcnul fo tser eht revO
.goD fo ecioV ehT no htnoM edirP ot gninetsil er’uoY
.cigam tseroF fo sdnarts dediarb ekil dekool tahw htiw ereht deruces dna kcab s’flow eht ssorca suoicsnocnu delwarps ,regnessap a eb ot tuo denrut ograc ehT
.ti deveileb yltsom dna
.guh a rih evag dna aifoS ot pu thgir delbmarcs rehtsE
”.vokaY ,taht ekil eb t'noD“
”.niaga emoh emoc annog m’I taht dnatsrednu ot meht deen tsuj I ,won thgiR
”,gnuoy uoy detrats yehT“
.snoitseuq rih lla ksa dna pu hctac ot tseroF eht ot yaw eht lla nur dluoc eis ekil tlef ylneddus dna ,gnidnuop traeh ,klawedis eht tih eiS
.taht ot dnopser ot woh erus etiuq t’nsaw aifoS
,ssorC yb daeR   .denifed si
”?taht retfa yawa uoy tpek yeht oS“
”.taht htiw depleh adnik uoy ,haeY“   .devresbo leirA
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil rof uoy knahT dna
.redluohs eno otno ti tfil dna lehctas a otni meht kcap ot yawrood eht ni desuap neht ;tuo kcehc ot rehtom s’mairiM rof ksed eht ot meht thguorb
”.rehto hcae fo deracs ssel gnieB“   ”?tahw gnioD“
.flow eht retfa spets eht nwod gninnur ,dellac eis ”!tiaW“
,ti fo kniht ot emoc dna
si yrots s’yadoT dna
.spets eht ta nwod dekool aifoS   ”?naem uoy od woH“
.dewollof leirA dna ,sevlehs eht otni ffo derettulf ehS
”?sevlowerew tuoba deklat yeht woh tuoba kniht yllaer dna ,aes eht ssorca morf scimoc esoht daer reve uoy diD“
.flah ti dereffo dna hciwdnas reh depparwnu aifoS .sriats eht no gnitiaw tas flow ehT
.tseroF eht morf fle laer A“
,edyaz s’rehtsE ot neeb dah tsrif ehT
.klawedis eht no tlenk dna hcrop eht ffo nwod deppets leirA
”.emoclew er'uoy“ yas ot hguone stiw reh rehtag dluoc aifoS erofeb enog erew dna
.yllacificeps reh ta gnikool saw ti taht noiton eht epacse t’ndluoc aifoS
”eniM dna ylimaF ruoY“
”?won tsuj tuoba yrgna os uoy erew tahw tub ,ksa ot diarfa tsomla m’I .mU .oot eM .haeY“
284 ydaL ruO fo raeY ehT yrarbiL gnidneL cilbuP hpmuirT
?detrats d’ehs taht won ,yas ot gnorw tsael eb dluow tahW
.taoc etihw yssolg s’leirA ekil gnihton nworb ytsud a ,ruf yggahs ni derevoc erew smra rih dezilaer eis ,pu gnidnatS
.rehtO ehT fo raef ot ,dne eht ni
.thguoht eis ,pu nworg erew yehT
.dnuorg eht ot desserp spitregnif rieht htiw tnemevap eht no tlenk neht ,eybdoog evaw ot kcab denrut yeht ,klawedis eht dehcaer leirA nehW
”.rehto hcae fo deracs ssel elpoep ekam dna swal eht egnahc ot gnikrow sevlowerew erew meht fo ynam os dna ,ereht elpoep lufrednow emos tem I
.ti htiw sgnikrow renni eht fo tser eht nekat dah dna ,gnitsiser saw ereht ni gnihtemoS .tnemngila otni
.noon drawot edils ysaenu sti no wodniw nehctik eht fo tuo dna pu deyesom nus ehT
.derepsihw rehtsE ”,woW“
”.tseroF eht ni ekil saw efil tahw ees ot ,yldab os uoy htiw og ot detnaw I
.eciton ot ysub oot neeb syawla d’ehs esuaceb t’nsaw taht ebyam taht reh ot derrucco tI
.sraey wef tsrif eht rof em no eye esolc a peek did yehT
;tnecs fo dna htgnerts fo hsur eht ,gniyfirret regnol on ;ruf htiw deltsirb smra reh taht kcohs a regnol on saw tI
.detnaw ti tahw tuo dnif tseb d’ehs ,lleW
.elbat eht no nwod koob a tes yehT
.pu dekool aifoS
.emoh wen rieht ni ecived gnivas robal tsrif eht sa eno siht dellatsni dna
.secaf htiw em pleh t’ndluoc yeht tub ,drac yrarbil a em tog dna ,terces ni ereh tuo em thguorb dah nisuoc yM
.yawflah flow eht tem dna teerts eht pu edorts ehS
.sgniht fo esnes ekam ot gniyrt dna daor eht ta gnirats ,regnol elihw a spets eht no tas ehS
uoy did tahw ,aifoS“
.tey taht dnuora daeh rieht nettog yllaer sah emoh ta ydobyna erus ton m’I dnA .haeY“
”.llew os tuo dekrow s’taht dalg os m’I
”.sknahT“   ”.kcul dooG“
”?dluoc yeht kniht uoy oD“
.pu doots dna riahc rieht kcab dehsup leirA ”.lufrednoW“
.edyaz s’rehtsE fo yromem a dias ?hturt eht tuoba woH
?ot klat ot rih nesohc yeht dah yhW
nosnogarD .T xelA yb
.aifoS ta pu kcab dekool dna ti fo tuo flesmeht dellup neht...epahS
.tnemom yreve flesreh erom dna erom gnileef dna wohemos teef reh otno kcab gnillaf
.lla ta krowemoh ekil kool t’ndid taht koob emos ni peed kaeb reh ,riahcmra na ni pu delruc saw mairiM ,epoN
.tsrif krowemoh rih hsinif ot gnivah tuohtiw scimoc daer dluoc eis fi oot retteb gnidaer ekil d'eis ebyaM
.)leirA eb ot dah yletulosba ti won( dias leirA
.nairarbil eht saw rehtom reH
.daeha thgiarts desucof neht ,ylsuoituac tuoba dekool tI .drawrof dekcirp srae s’flow ehT
,elap os saw niks riehT
,tseroF eht fo egde eht gnola dna daor eht pu neve ro ,nwot ssorca gnidir rof tcefrep ,yad gnirps ylevol a saw tI
.onnud I“ .deggurhs aifoS
”.edyaz reh htiw gniyduts saw I elihw reh fo erom tol a ees ot tog I .semitemos enileert eht ot yaw eht lla klaw ot desu I dna rehtsE“
.yad taht neeb dah vokaY sa latnemegduj dna deracs sa ,nwot eritne na enigamI
retal sraey 22   ”.edyaZ
?yad taht reh fo diarfa neeb vokaY t’ndah
draoh a pota morf
,peekpu dedeen ecived yrevE
.egaugnal ydob s’elpoep ruoy daer ot nrael ot gnitrats tsuj saw I
?enod eis dah tahW
”.esimorp a ekorb eh ekiL
,ereht revo laer era seirots esohT“   ”…yllaer ton ,hU“
.yhtapmys emos evah dluow mairiM ebyaM
”.tsrif acirbmunO ni gnignahc era sgniht woh tuoba erom wonk ot deen I
?rof tluciffid saw siht eno ylno eht aifoS saw yhW
.enog shtnom owt ylraen saw hcihw ,tekram ecitsloS eht edistuo detnedecerpnu ylrettu rehto eht dna—wodahs s’ydaL eht tfel ylerar sretseroF peeD—lausunu saw eno ehT
”.sevlowerew gnieb rof tsuj ,meht denwosid stnerap esohw sklof tem ev’I .yltsom
.sdleif kcab eht tsap tuo sgnineve remmus gnol gnirebmemer ,delims ehS
”…gniod saw I tahw wenk I ecno tuB
.hpmuirT fo elpoep eht rof reisae elttil a gnivil fo krow eht ekam ot senihcam nwo reh gnidliub nageb dna s’irO morf teerts eht ssorca pohskrow nwo reh denrae ehs litnu tnempiuqe mraf nacirbmunO detropmi gnixif dna sesroh gnieohs ,htimskcalb eht rehtom s’irO ot ,taht retfa dnA
.railimaf dellems flow egnarts eht
.dessap yeht emit eht yb sklawedis eht ot detaerter dah dworc ehT
”.su erih t'now taht snoisseforp elohW .yduts t'nac ew stcejbuS
.egnahc a rof secnailppa s'esle enoemos xif ebyam dna drawretfa pohskrow nwo reh yb pots dluoc ehs dnA .krow ta hcnul htiw efiw reh desirprus tsal aifoS ecnis elihw a neeb dah ti ,tcaf nI .senihcam tsuj ton dnA
”!era yeht erehw wonk I“
.srae rieht tuoba ddo
.hciwdnas nwo reh tae ot spets tnorf ynnus s’cinilc eht ot detaerter ehs os ,ecaps emos ecitnerppa reh dna rehtsE evig saw won od dluoc aifoS gniht tseb ehT
,edirP yppaH .stsacdop ruoy
”.enog erew uoy tub ,tnew I nehw yrarbil eht ta eb ot demees syawla sdneirf ruoY
.suovren ylneddus ,dias eis ”,aifoS m'I“
”.deirrow mees t'ndid rotcod ehT“   ”?yako eh sI
,ti fo kniht ot emoC
”.ysub em gnipeek spihsecitnerppa dah tsuj I sseug I ,taht retfa dnA .ecalp tsrif eht ni ereht eb ot detnaw I kniht t’nod I ,yltsenoH
”.taht gniod enim dna ylimaf ruoy enigamI“
.meht htiw gniugra em ro uoy tsuj naht erom ekat ll’ti tuB
,ksa dluoc uoY“
?ti gnivael tuoba meht thguat stnerap s’leirA dah tahW
.tsrif ta nosrep emas eht erew uoy erus neve t’nsaw I“
,dias eis ”,yako m'I .haeY“
”.gnidaer m'I gnihtemos htiw em pleh dluoc uoy fi gnirednow saw I“ .dias leirA
.thguoht ehs ,deddon flow ehT
.havztim’b reh ot loohcs hguorht reh yrrac ot yromem dna cirotehr fo skcirt hguone
,ti saw ,elbissop t'nsaw taht dna—efil rieht ni edistuo neeb reven d'yeht ekil dekool yeht
.ylsuoires em koot ohw elpoep wef yrev a fo eno erew uoy dna ,dnuora ksa ot dah I
***   .siht t'nsaw erus ti tub ,detcepxe d'yeht tahw wonk t'ndid aifoS
.aneyH desopmoC a
.yawa dekool ylkciuq dna gnirats saw eis dezilaer aifoS dna ,dias regnarts eht ”,iH“
.ksa t'ndluoc eis tuB
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif
.sevlesmeht yb noissucsid elohw eht gnivah ylbaborp ,htiw gnilggurts saw aifoS egap emas taht no desucof yletelpmoc ,elbat renroc eht ta ffo erew vokaY dna rehtsE hguoht nevE
.elbats saw nam eht erus saw ehs sa noos sa tae d'ehs desimorp dna ,detaicerppa ehs ,doof ehT
teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
.no devorpmi eb dluoc metsys yna dna
?rih fO ?deracs eh saW
.eno txen eht rof eraperp ot wol gniyal erew srepeekpohs s’hpmuirT ,gnihtyna fi dna ,oga syad evif tsael ta saw siloporteM htroN morf ni pihs tsal ehT .yadot ysub taht lla t'nsaw teertS niaM
.gnidaer saw mairiM eno eht ekil revoc a htiw ,koob cimoc a saw tI
?ograc htiw ereh gniod yeht erew tahW
.won evael t'ndluoc eis tuB
.deksa ehs ”?rotcoD“
,relevart wollef ruoy ,floWcaM boR si sihT
.taht retfa hcum kcab og t’ndid I ,haeY“
”.nwod ti etirw ot evah t'nod dna gnihtyreve rebmemer tsuj sevle syas amaM“
.eugoganys eht dniheb nedrag elbategev eht gnideew ekil ,yrrow stnerap rih ekam t’ndid taht gnihtemos gniod eb neve dluoc ehS
;dnah ni skoob fo kcats a ,sevlehs eht morf degreme leirA sa yltnelis dehctaw aifoS os dnA
.ti tuoba thguoht eis tahw deksa rehcaet rih nehw worromot yas ot gniht elgnis a htiw pu emoc ot elbanu ,seirots trohs fo koob a ta gnirats ereh kcuts t'nsaw eis tnaem ti fi tniop siht ta sehsid hsaw ot gnilliw tsomla saw eiS
”.gniyfirret sdnuos tahT...“
.enog ton tub ,tniaf--eslup rieht kcehc ot tlenk aifoS
...“ .tnenitnoc eritne na ,oN
.truh ti deticxe os dekool ehS .srehtaef eulb dna der fo remmihs a ni deraeppa mairiM
”eniM dna ylimaF ruoY“yojne esaelP
.wohemos stnerap s'aifoS ot kcab ti ekam dluow ti dna ,nairarbil eht llet dna ,eciton dluow rehtsE
stnecs eht ,resolc ylthgils saw dnuorg eht ,meht denepo eis nehw dna ,ssenizzid eht ffo ekahs ot seye rih desolc eiS
,dedaf dah ezeerb eht no
eis tub ,thgis fo tuo saw leirA
.rih retfa gninnur vokaY dna rehtsE dna
.gniyas rehcaet rih derebmemer eis ,seulc txetnoC
.rehtsE htiw revo ti klat retteb d’ehs desoppus ehS
.seert eht otni deraeppasid daor eht erehw dnoyeb yal tahw gnirednow dna trapa sgnos drib eht gnillet gnicitcarp
.etiteppa reh tsol d’ehs dezilaer dna ,hciwdnas reh fo tser eht ta nwod dekool ehS
.oga sraey esoht lla yrarbil eht morf derebmemer aifoS fle tnagele taht emaceb dna ,detfihs flow ehT
.reh gniees tpek ev’uoy ekil sllems ti dnA“
.hctaw ot aifoS dniheb pu emoc dah rehtsE
yhtapmys ni epahsflow nwo reh fo og tel aifoS
kcab syellup sti elttes ot yrt ot rehsaw-hsid dlo eht fo edis eht no degnab aifoS
.enummoc eht morf m'I ,seY“
--ebyam ,sruof lla no nar eis fi retsaf meht wollof dluoc eis thguoht eis dna ,tnew yeht yaw hcihw llems dluoc
”.retsis gib ym dna edyaz ym ekil ,flowerew a tsuj s’eiS“
.etisoppo eht tsomla ,oN“
gnihtemos saw ereht dna
”.em wolloF .thgir llA“
?secaf tuoba snoitseuq htiw ereh emoc d'yeht taht ,tseroF eht tuoba tnereffid os saw esle tahW
.ylprahs dias leirA
.elbat rih ta nwod tas dah enoemos taht ezilaer ot tnemom a rih koot tI
.nekat dah aifoS emit eht flah ekil tlef tahw ni egap elohw eht dennacs rehtsE
.eugoganys ta sredle eht morf draeh reve ylno dah aifoS sseniraew-dlrow fo tros eht htiw dehgis leirA
.ti ssorca dehsalps deunitnoC eB oT dah eno txen eht ;egap eht denrut yehT
.wenk eis enoemos t'nsaw ti dnA
.reh rof dnuora dekool aifoS
.yrarbil eht ni devil stnerap s’mairiM neve ton
.dneirf rieht eb ot desu yug dab eht tuo derugif tsuj ev'yehT“
.erehwyreve lufwa t’nsaw ti ,si gniht ehT“
”.uoy ekil yeht ekil dekool tI“
.stuc dloc rof derewoprevo ylssorg regnol on hteet htiw hciwdnas fo etib a koot dna—erutseg tnereffid ylthgils a ,reyarp emas eht—
.erofeb ecaf taht ekam enoyna nees reven ev'I“
.deyarteb si taht rof drow eht kniht I
.seye rieht dniheb gninrub gnihtemos esnes dluoc ehs tub ,degnahc t’ndah noisserpxe riehT
,oga gnol reh thguat dah ,ecaep ni tser eh yam ,edyaz s’rehtsE ngis dnah eht edam dna ,mra eno rednu ot hcnul detfihs aifoS
.emoh teg I nehw tae ll'I ,sknaht oN“
,sseug I ,oS .egdelwonk taht tuohtiw acirbmunO ni gnol devivrus evah t'ndluow I
”?eman ruoy s'tahW .leirA m'I“
.elcycib rih no krap eht ta tuo ekiL
.siht yrt ot dnim fo ecneserp eht htiw eno ylno eht ylraelc saw ehs tub ,ereht flowerew ylno eht t'nsaw ehs erew sddO
...mmmH“ .kool resolc a teg ot taes rih no tlenk aifoS
”.ereh gniod er'yeht tahw rednoW
.ecnatsid suoiruc a ta dewollof sdneirf rih dna aifoS dna ,yrarbil eht tfel leirA
.nwot fo tuo daor eht gnola ffo tes dna ,sgel sti dehcterts ,kcen sti dnuora llits lehctas ,tops taht morf esor flow etihw citsejam a dna ,degnahc yeht ,knilb a fo ecaps eht nI
,kcolb eht nwod yawflah flesrih dnuof dna ,kcab dekool dna deppots eiS
.golb gnidliubdlrow rieht no seirots rieht fo erom dnif nac uoy dna ,nray yzoc fo
,yrgna dna deracs kool yehT...mmmH“
snray yzoc fo edroh a snips ohw
rehto eht woh tuoba selbbiuq si tser eht llA
.kcab sti no tuo ekam etiuq t’ndluoc ehs gnihtemos gniyrrac ,ruf etihw yssolg htiw flow egral ylbaborpmi na saw ,bruc eht ffo deppets ehs sa tuo dnuof ehs ,gnihtemos tahT
,emit eht fo tsom nus eht ees ylerab dluoc uoy taht tseroF eht ni peed rehtegot esolc os werg seert eht taht ecno lla meht dlot dah narg s’mairiM
”.detrats teg em gnipleh rof sknaht
.hpmuirT ni klof tseroF fo sgniog dna sgnimoc eht fo erawa taht lla neeb yllaer reven dah aifoS
.ylniatrecnu gnirettum ,reh dnuora detrap dworc ehT
nac uoY .aneyH desopmoC a ,ssorC yb
.daor tseroF eht nwod gnihcaorppa gnihtemos ta gnilevram dworc llams a ni flesreh dnuof ehs ,hcalegur nomannic dekab-hserf fo xob a dna sehciwdnas lausu eht htiw iled eht tfel aifoS nehw ,llitS
.yrarbil eht naht eb rehtar dluow aifoS secalp ynam os erew erehT
.yas ot lufpleh gnihtyna fo kniht t’ndluoc aifoS ”.lleW“
.kaerb hcnul reh gnirud ni thguorb tneitap ycnegreme na evah ot yppah oot enon saw rehtsE
.dias leirA ”,hcum os uoy knahT“
,nosnogarD .T xelA yb
”.yaw sihT“   ”?em wohs uoy naC“
.gnihtyreve tuoba ,mrofsnart meht tel taht cigam eht tuoba ,emoh rieht tuoba ,leirA tuoba--wonk ot detnaw aifoS hcum os saw ereht ,ecno ta llA
.derepsihw eis ”,yako er’uoY“
,rehtsE rof tfig pihstruoc a sa rossecederp sti edam d'ehs erofeb gnol ecnis ,sedaced owt tsomla rof enihcam gnihsaw-hsid a fo aedi eht htiw gnireknit neeb d'ehS
,epahsflow rieht otni kcab dexaler yehT
”?dneirf ruoy htiw eerga uoy oD
.ereht tog neve meht fo tser eht erofeb tuo nettirw snoitseuq reh lla dah ylbaborp ehS
.wohemos thgir mees t'ndid tsuj tI
.noitseuq s’rehtsE yb derehtob mees t'ndid leirA
.lenap a ta detniop dna dne eht raen kramkoob a ot ti denepo yehT
.saw ehs esruoc fO
.gniht doog a ylbaborp s'tahT“
”.kcab gniog er’uoy oS“
.worg sgniht lla stel dna dlrow eht sniatsus ohw ,ydaL eht ot esiarp ,ti htiw tnew taht reyarp eht dehtuom dna
.lenap rehtona ni enil a ot detniop neht ,egap eht fo tser eht hguorht daer eiS
”.sneppah tahw ees ot eno txen eht dnif ot evah ll'I esoppus I“
.emit tsrif eht rof detfihs I yad eht saw...uoy tem I yad ehT“
.niks elap yltsohg tsomla dah srehtaef ro ruf evah t’ndid dna ereht devil ohw enoyreve os
.elbat renroc eht morf meht gnihctaw saw vokaY ”.aifoS
”eniM dna ylimaF ruoY“ saw sihT
.esoprup no tfihs ot woh em thguat ohw ,s’rehtsE fo evitaler a ,rotnem a em dnuof yehT
.eye eht ni rih kool ot kcen rih gninarc regnol on saw rehtsE dna
.evil ot dewolla t'nera sevlowerew secalp era ereht acirbmunO nI“
uoy rof daer ,nosnogarD .T xelA yb
...epahS noitamrofsnart rieht otni nael ot detrats yehT
.rellat daeh a ylraen saw eis dnuof aifoS ,rih dehcaer rehtsE nehw dna ,eb dluohs ti naht yawa rehtraf saw dnuorg ehT
,niaga reh htiw yawa gninnur morf ti peek dna luos reh ni flow eht dneirfeb ot gninrael snoonretfa reh gnidneps ,ecaep ni tser eh yam
”?uoy t'nera ,tseroF eht morf er'uoy ,yeH“
.tseroF eht morf yawa denraw gnieb doohdlihc elohw reh tneps d’ehS
.tuo dedaeh dna xobloot reh pu dekcap ehS
.edyaZ ot klat og s'tel woN .os uoy dloT“
,tem tsrif ew nehW“   ”?tahw roF“
,kcab rieht nwod yaw eht lla dediarb saw riah riehT
.dias yeht ”,uoy knaht ot tog yllaer reven I ,wonk uoY“
.ediw seye ,kcab gnuh vokaY ”?od
”.thgir sdnuos deyarteb ,haeY“
.egnarts dekool regnarts eht yhw eb dluoc taht ,ti denoitnem eis taht woN
”,sega ni uoy nees t’nevah I“   ”?huH“   ”?yako uoy erA
,nwod sliob yrtogib llA
,yaw eht gnola dna ,liaf tuohtiw emoh yaw reh dnif dna efas rehtsE peek dna tnuh dna tnecs a wollof ot
.sregnif rieht neewteb sepahS eht fo emos dezingocer ehs thguoht tsomla aifoS ;sdnah rieht gnurw leirA ”.saw tI“
.eman rih dellac enoemoS
.wen gnihton saw taht ,lleW
”.gnirob era skoob tseroF ebyaM
”?desirprus ebyam dna
.dluoc yeht kniht I“   .deksa ehs
.derednow rehtsE ”?tseroF eht ni skoob evah neve yeht oD“
”.yako er'uoy dna ,evarb yrev neeb ev'uoY .skniht eh tahw tuoba yrrow t'noD“
,yawa deniard enilanerda eht sa gnillaf tsomla flesrih tlef dna ,guh eht otni niamer ot nageb aifoS
.tseroF eht drawot pu decnalg yehT
.niart raeg wen a rof emit yllanif saw ti ebyaM
”,aifoS ,uoy teem ot ylevol s'tI“