,htuoy fo egaruoc dna
.retaw eht ni htolc eht dessot flow ehT .uoy knahT
,boj retteb a gniod tnaem noitnetta gniyaP
.hcamots s'suidanneG ot ttubdaeh a demrofrep soriP
,dnim sih no dehgiew tneve eht hguohT
.tcaer ot ytiliba sih htiw gnirepmet syad eht
.eciov eht fo renwo eht saw
emaceb stnemevom sih
ssennrobbuts dna edirp sih tub ,sroirraw decneirepxe ynam dedesrepus
.htuoy eht ot tuo yaw eht deifiralc eh noitasrevnoc kciuq a ni dna ,hcneb eht morf doots flow ehT
,hctam eht fo trats eht delangis seerefer eht retfA
.teef eht ta detrats eH
,elkcat rehtona od ot emit on koot raeb ehT
eseht piks nac uoy
.raef I ,gar dna tekcub rehtona hctef ot thguo uoY .deednI
.oot enog saw snoitca revo elur sih tub
,gniht eno saw sehcneb tnatsid eht morf lodi sih fo ydob emosdnah eht gnitcartsbA
eninac redlo eht ot yrujni lautca fo ksir eht dna
,morf emac gnileef eht erehw ton wenk eh
.kcab ym htiw trats yam uoY
...ot detagilbo leef ton oD
.detnurg dna seye sih desolc yllanif eH ...I
.maerd a saw taht yleruS .gninrub
,aet fo puc ruoy ton s'taht fI
.suorepsorp tsom eht saw
.flesmih neve desirprus deneppah dah tahW
,naelc ot sixelA rof reisae ti ekam ot saw noitnetni siH
,trap ydob ylggij
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy ,ikahK m'I
hguone mih detcartsid ecneserp riehT
,dnoces tsal eht tA
,selur eht gnikaerb ot denrut raeb eht ylisae woh
,dnab eht nioj ot flow eht dellac yeht nehW
...os ,niap rehtruf diova ot ekil dluow I
.nwonk eb ot emac ti redael eht neeb syawla ton dah ailoA
.sisonpyh s'htuoy eht ekorb niaga ecno eciov gnimoob ehT .boj dooG
,soriP tnemilpmoc yllanosrep ot ecnahc ehT
eye sih thguac yltsal tahW
.rewop dnuofwen deniag osla yeht tnaem
,emarf s'rethgif eht gnizylana ecneirepxe fo laed doog a dah htuoy ehT
.anera eht hguorht deohce taht dnuos a detaerc tcapmi eht tub ,wols erew yehT
.swodniw llaw pot eht hguorht gnimoc nus eht yb detanimulli
,erofeb semit ynam ekiL
,ikahK yb uoy rof daer
.dal eht gnisaeler
.htuoy eht desserdda niaga eh ,ytinecsbo ronim emos gnirettum retfA
.lautir wen a ni desselb sseddog eht
,elggurts a saw tfola ti gnipeek fi nevE
,tnacav yletelpmoc emos ,sevlehs nedoow
.rewsna s'oriP did esuap a retfa ylno ,dekcohS
yvaeh gnihtaerb sih dna
.gnihton naelc ll'uoy esiwrehto
,slakcaj eht ta ylelos dekool seye sih dna
.won smra ym no krow dluohs uoY .ris ,seY
,ffo tcapmi eht gurhs ot kciuq saw suidanneG
.ton dluoc raeb ehT
.deil stekcub fo seires a erehw
,htolc eht deciton eH
noitamalcxe siH !luferac eB
htuoy eht ot esolc os saw flow eht tub
ytic eturb eht gnilppot
dnuorg dleh eH
.htolc eht dnoyeb htaerb sih tlef flow der eht
.mih deliaf dnim sih
.doog kool meht gnikam otni erac tup enoemoS
.keew txen uoy rof seirots wen eb ll'ereht dna
.ydob ybbuhc tey ralucsum eht fo kcen eht dnuora gnuh htolc fo eceip llams A
.sreidlos fo gniknar etile eht nioj ot sraey derdnuh a ni tsrif eht eb ot
,did eh ekil deffuh soreP
,ecaf sih ot esor tnemredliweb s'sixelA
.ymra eht ot gnidrocca tcepsersid tsomtu eht
,dnim sih evael ot desufer soriP tub
secrof drazahpah rieht fo redael eht
,detnawnu yltsom saw taF
.mih htiw noitcennoc a tpmetta ot ytinutroppo tcefrep eht saw ti
,mih dnuora dlrow eht gnivresbo rof noitanicsaf ehT
.yllanif ,sixelA dias ,ris ,loof tsol A
ti gnippop mih fo dnuos ehT
.lacismihw tsomla
,tfos eht fo erutxim a ,ruf ehT
.won sgnileef s'lakcaj eht edih dluoc troffe oN
,dehgis lakcaJ gnuoy deveiler ehT
.tessa tsetaerg sih sa ti detpecca tub
.niaga sucof dluoc eh os gel sih esolc dluow flow eht taht saw epoh siH
,nwonk lavorppasid fo lworg sih edam suidanneG ,esor eh retfA
.enigami neve dluoc dal eht naht niap fo erom hcum wenk flow eht tub
desseug evah ton dluoc sixelA .noitcennoc A
goD fo ecioV ehT ot
.kcen sih morf htolc eht devomer eninac redlo ehT .ees I
,ailoA ,meht gnomA
,neht dna won htolc taht tuo gniR
gnipsag ot nika ,tuo emac
?ereht kcab enod uoy era ,hO
dnab eht nioj dluow rebmem wen a
.taews yksum s'flow eht fo ruodo gnirulla tub gnitaesuan eht pu kcip dluow eH
,srodirroc sseldne eht ta ecnalg A
.dluoc eh sa hcum sa gninrael no desucof os dna tuoba emoc ton dluow taht ekil ecnahc rehtona wenk eH
.desaet gnieb saw eh fi llet ton dluoc eH
.tlef eh lufniap woh raelc saw ti
.noon fo thgilnus dlim eht ni gninetsilg
.ytinasni fo knirb eht ot lakcaj eht evord egami ehT
,dereffo yrotciv eht sedalocca eht ton saw
.smraerof sih htiw ti kcolb ot hguone kciuq saw eh ,yletanutroF
.ytnelp mih dezitonpyh selcsum kcab gniglub eht
.niw a hcus ni edirp on saw erehT
,slworg raeb kcalb ehT
.srenetsil erutam rof yrots tluda na si retrap-owt s'keew sihT
,scifironoh tuohtiw ekops eh
.rood eht rof tfel dna
recnaL ruoY :yojne esaelP
hguone lliks sih deulav yehT
lanoisseforp morf
.flow eht fo naf a fo ssel yna mih ekam ton did tahT
,slarotcep sih yllaniF
,hpmuirt taht retfa sraey derdnuh A
.ecnelis ot mih rof erafnaf on saw ereht fi neve
.noitartnecnoc htiw dnas dna lio fo kcab sih gniddir ot denruter eH
,esae htiw degdod soriP
,laer eht yllaudarG
,niaga teem soreP dna sixelA woh tuo dnif ot
ega fo ecneirepxe dleiw
,erutalucsum eht ot ssecca on dah seye siH
.mih htaeneb wodahs peed a gnitsac osrot evissam sih
.snoisiced roop ot del netfo sgnittes tnemom-eht-fo-rups htiw gnilaed ,noitasnepmoc nI
,stnemhsinup detcepxe yllaitrap eH
,dnah sih desiar htuoy ehT .gninaom ro
.ecaf s'soriP drawot welf hcnup s'raeb ehT
,sdnas eht ot llef ydob evissam siH .elggurts oN
,spets eerht rehtonA
,ymra reporp a gnikcaL
,ydob taht ni debbaws gar eht sA
,drows dna sdleihs eht koot redlo eht
.hcneb eht no tekcub eht decalp eh sa
.detiefrof dah suidanneG
,raeb derruf-kcalb eht emac edis etisoppo eht morF
.mih ecaf daeh s'flow eht edam
,liap eht ni retaw eht
ailoeA nar taht licnuoc eht ot dna
.wob a dna raeps a erob regnuoy eht elihw
.yrotciv fo ngis a sa hcum os tuohtiw anera eht tiuq soriP
.seye sih ni eb ot emaf eht mih evag
.ecnart s'sixelA ekorb ylerab eciov gnimoclew dna peed siH
.smra sih htiw mih dehctulc dna
,srethgif hserf fo reniart ,namelbon A
.elbatciderp saw ti
,ti derevoc amozirep ehT
.spets 'srethgif eht dehctam gnihtaerb s'lakcaj eht ,tniop eht ot gnitteG
,ydob reppu sih gnitsioh yleraB
.tsugsid dna yruf htiw tnenoppo sih ta gnikool elihw
.elbarisednu saw rieh na ecudorp ot elbanu gnieb
.soriP deman flow a
.emas eht lla laiceps tub
.lasrod s'assoreiP ot ssecca gnitteg
,seirots sih fo erom dnif nac uoY
,mih fo tnorf ni ytilaer eht ezingocer ot desufer lakcaJ gnuoy ehT
.soriP rof tniop eno deralced egduj ehT
.detcirtsernu gnivom lodi sih gniees
.saw eh erehw regnorts tlef llems enilucsam eht nevE
,tfel ecalp eno ylnO .doog yreV
.hctam eht degnarra os dna
.snoissucreper sti evah dluoc
.stnemevom tsethgils s'rehto eht deiduts
,snoitome esoht bruc ot deirt yehT
ylio sa ton erew esohT
.ti did yeht os dnA .deilper ehs
s'flow der eht revo lla
.tsal ton did elggurts ehT
,ylio ylthgils llits ,erugif siH
,swodniw eht ta kool dluow eh fi ,tey dna
,ekops eh semit rehto ynam morf dereffid
,ydob sih ni detsefinam ylerar hcihw taf fo tnuoma doog a deirrac flow eht ,ralucsum hguohT
,mra sih gnitsioh nehw eligarf os demees eH
.hgis yvaeh a htiw yawa daeh sih dellup eH
,sdohtem sih wenk flow eht ylnO
,noitisop dexaler erom a detpoda dah ohw rethgif eht ot denruter sixelA
flesmih gninoitisop ot yaw eht no saw soriP
.dezitonpyh saw eH
raeb eht fo ydob ralucsum tey taf eht
,gnir eht fo tuo raeb suoicsnocnu eht yrrac ot sdraug ralucsum eerht koot tI
.rekciht tog noisnet eht dna
.soriP rof tniop rehtonA
.noitnetta sih thguac slian ehT
?elahni ot eh ereW
.flesmih ta deppins eh ylekilnu si tI
.ydob s'flow eht no boj sih fo tser eht rof os did dna ,gnivol ot
.ris ,erusaelp ym eb dluow tI
.seilop laitneulfni erom eht fo
,elggurts lanif taht tub
.mih nekasrof dah dnim siH
,yawa kaerb ot meht dellac retibra eht hguohT
.mih dnamirper ot kciuq saw flow ehT
.roolf eht ot dna ecnalab ffo raeb eht werht eH
tseb saw ti dezilanoitar eh dna
,dnab eht otni dratsab a fo ecnattimda eht denoitseuq ,lareneg eht fo nos ,suidanneG
.ecnad suounitnoc a demrofrep sgel rieht sa ydob s'rehto eht nwod dna pu devom seye riehT
.og tel flow eht retfa
.kcab thgif dluoc eninac eht taht
.selitxet dna skcas htiw gnitsrub srehto dna
.yob eht ekil desylarap ,soreP dias ,I .ton did osla tub
.ycamitni hcus htiw reven tub
.flow eht dias ,tleb tahT
tsom eht eb dluow tug eht taht esnes ekam dluow tI
,erid tsom denrut noitautis eht nehW
.noinapmoc ediserif lufhtiaf ruoy
luferaC .nips dnim sih edam stnemragrednu esoht ot esolc os gnieb niaga tuB
.dnim s'dal eht deppirg llits eriseD
,mih ot tsnwonkebnU
.gnir eht fo segde etisoppo no doots stnatabmoc eht
mrof s'flow eht gnirimda morf tnew dnim siH
ruf der sih detaoc taht lio gnithgif ehT .flow eht ,tsriF
.yrassecennu dna evititeper
secaf suoires riehT
sixelA demusnoc evah dluow kcohS
.mih tih noitazilaer a sa
,elbissopmi saw tI .neerG
derevaw sevom siH
.suidanneG tsniaga demmals eH
.gnihtaerb yvaeh sih laecnoc ot luferac erom nevE
.esora melborp rehtona
.oot ,selppin eht ,esruoc fo ,saw erehT
tsif a desiar ylno raeb gnigar eht
.cirbaf eht htiw liap eht debbarg htuoy ehT .ris ,tcerroc era uoY
.elbatciderp oslA .deniartser erom
,ruf der eht revo delevart htolc eht sa
.niap fo ngis on deyalpsid eninac redlo eht
?ris ,won sgel ruoy ot ecnavda I llahS
mih dellac ohw eno ehT
.detcepxe ydaerla soriP gnihtemos ,ecnavda eht egdod ot gniyrt yb
.sgel sih denepo eh nehw
.rehto yna naht erom stnemevom sih dellortnoc thguoht suoixon tahT
,edutitrof dna amsirahc
.ylisae ffo meht deggurhs
.ecalp htfif ylno mih denrae stroffe siH
,pu noitautis eht kaerb ot detnaw eH
roirraw gnilgdelf a sa emahs tseggib s'lakcaJ eht spahreP
,htamretfa trohs eht yllaicepse
,tuo yaw eht ton saw ylraelc taht ecniS .ti fo hcum gnirucsbo llaw-flah a
.moor eht otni rehtruf gnivom
,meht detarapes gar tew eht hguohT
,tniopweiv doog a ot tog sixelA ecnO
.dehsinif dah eh decnuonna dna
.krow sih rof liap eht morf htolc eht desu eH
.ruoloc eye sih nrael ot
.yniturcs fo mrof emos ot tcejbus osla saw lakcaJ eht
.noitnetta s'lakcaj eht fo tsom demialc dah taht ruf der lausunu sih ro
.rehto hcae morf yawa sehcni stuons rieht dnif ot ylno
.yleritne ezag s'lakcaJ eht dellif
,emit tsrif eht roF
.htaeneb ydob eht leef ot elba llits saw eh
,megairaC yb derodA recnaL ruoY
.tuons 'sixelA morf yawa mlap a
ti gnihcuot edam taht ssenihsuc a htiw deriap saw ytidilos hcuS
.seiroeht sih fo emos evorp ot demees egnar esolc ehT
.sixelA tih s'yad rehtonA
.tug sih desserac dnah ynwarb s'soriP
,ffo ti gurhs tsuj dluow eh yllausU
,es rep gnitseretni neeb ton dah thgif ehT
.thgil ot emac sliated wen
.daetsni mih deknaht neve
.gnizad morf lakcaj eht pots eciov sih did
.anera eht fo llaw eht tih eh litnu nar raeb eht dna
.mih llarhtne ton did enecs eht fi
htolc regral a htiw nevE
,noitcartsid a hcus desuac tI
yrots s'yadot dnA
,htolc eht gnisuod dna gnisnir fo elcyc eht ni deretlaf reven eH
sseworp roirraw sih ton saw tI
.tnemevom sih deppots eciov eliriv a fo llac ehT
.etats ralimis a ni ti gnidnif ,rehto eht ot deunitnoc dna
.ris ,llew yrev ti deldnah uoY
.sselnoitom yats ton did secaf riehT .esuap rehtonA
,lacinahcem emoceb dah snoitca s'sixelA
.meht fo eno emaceb tsuj sixelA dna
.nwod mih gnilddarts
.deneppah dah gnihton fi sa
.sllaw eht ot esolc htob ,edis thgir dna tfel sih ot sehcneb gnol owt was eh ecno tA
.os emaceb ti ,neht yb suoivbo ton saw demrofrep lakcaj eht gnisserac eht fI
.elbarusaelp yrev
,eno siht ot sleuqes gnidulcni
,ailoA rof yrotciv ot del noitanibmoc tahT
,ytilaer saw tahT
.sllaw evititeper yb decudni ,ogitrev eht yb desserppus
.noitavlas rof ytied naidraug rieht ot deyarp
.skeew ni meht derewoprevo ymene eht
.ecnats evisnefed a nekat ecnis dah ohw
,srumrum fo aes a ni tfel seednetta ehT
,suidanneG no noitnetta sih fo tsom tpek sixelA
,noinapmoc sih dekcip ton dah soriP
.dnas fo lluf erew yeht sa
.pu flow eht pleh ot rehtona
s'flow redlo ehT
,yrolg eht etarbelec oT
.luftsul yllohw ton erew skool ehT
.ylsuominanu erocs eht ta dereehc ecneidua regaem ehT
.sthguoht luftsul erom sih dedavrep taht nam eht gnildnof dna gnihcuot ylworran saw eh
,ydob s'rethgif eht ni detsixe ssentfos taht denrael dah sixelA .hcamots gniglub
.ediskcab s'flow eht ot esolc yllufwa dekrow eH
.ydob sih fo tsom ekil ,hguot dna
,ees nac uoy sA .thgiR
nem gnuoy eht no thgiltops a tup ot noititepmoc esoidnarg A
,thgilp lufitip s'sixelA ot hguone citehtapmys dednuos tnemetats A !rehtaeH
.boj taerg a did uoy kniht I
.ydaets mra ruoy dloh nac I
.tuo ti gnitsiwt dna elitxet eht gnihcnerd emit sih koot sixelA .esae tA
euqisyhp gnipparts 'soixelA rehtien ,salA
gnitapicitrap rof nosaer siH
.flow eht ta degnul dna hsalf a ni toof sih denruter eh
,sreirrab trohs eht gnissaP
.ydob desopxe dna amozirep 'soriP morf noitnetta sih trevid ot stnemom sixelA koot ti
.boj suolirep a saw ymra eht gninioJ
tneve launna na edam yehT .srecnal
.tnemssarrabme ni detaeh ecaf sih sa
.htuoy eht derulla
.moc.yrrufos.nagidrac ta
,oS .ris ,uoy knahT
bmil ralucsum eht fo thgiew eht gnidloh elbuort dah lakcaJ gnuoy ehT .uoy knahT .taerG
.lakcaj eht rof sthgin evitca ynam ot gnidael
.ecnelis ni dereviuq lakcaJ ehT ?ereht seog ohW
tsrif eht emaceb poort tahT
.rehto hcae delcric yeht
.elbaeciton tub ,feirb saw swap s'flow ehT
.emac reven sdrow tub
,sseddog eht yb dehctaw ytic taerg eht
,maercs lufhtarw a ot snrut
selballys owt emas eht ylnO
,srebmem redlo ehT
,mih etareb ot ton esohc s'oriP
.enivid erew selcsum sih ,esolc pU
,edistuo morf tnerruc ria eht fo dnuos eht wollof ot tpmetta lacigol ynA
.ylio nworg dah sdnah sih neve dna
.shgiht sih ta yllanif saw eH
,hcneb eht fo elddim eht ni hcnuh tas eH
.tixe eht drawot anera eht fo sllah enihtnirybal eht hguorht edam eH
eno htiw dehsinif eH
.erow eh sladnas eht fo rehtael eht leef dluow eh ,seot sih pu delruc eh fI
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht saw sihT
,mra sih detfil flow eht yaw eht yB
deralced eerefer ehT
,saw soriP ekil rehcaet a emoceb oT
cirbaf regral a htiW
.moor eht fo dne eht ta seno regral dnif nac uoy dna ,emit ruoy ekaT
.stsacdop ruoy teg uoy reverehw wohs eht dnif ro
,god.ecioveht ta bew eht no seirots erom dnif nac uoy ,syawla sA
.dnim sih ni slriws desuac dednamirper gnieb fo aedi ehT
.netfo slian mirt ot ,selbon gnoma neve ,nommocnu saw tI
.trap denot tsom s'eninac eht yletinifed
,niaga ekops eh ,esuap tneced a retfA
.egamad gnitsal reffus dluow kcatta taht ni thguac enoynA .egrahc laturb A
.tsirw sih depsarg dnah ralucsum A
etinuer dluow yeht nehw ro erehw
,flow eht nees dah lakcaj eht secnatsid eht morf
roirepus sih deknaht sixelA
.sesnes lla ot tsaef A
noitpecrep s'htuoy eht thguac esle gnihtemoS
.krow ot tog dna cirbaf eht htiw scep eht derevoc eh ,salA
,neerg enohs seye esohT
.ti diova ot deen ton did flow der ehT
.tuo detrulb tsuj lakcaJ eht sdroW
.kcab detlit daeh sih
.tnemgduj fo tib a deirrac ti hguoht neve
,nottoc eht wollof ton did
.gnitaeb eht etiuq koot smra yM
,noitamrofni hcus llet ot deriuqer ssenesolc eht wenk weF
,mih ekil selbon rof tub
.srotciv s'tnemanruot eht fo eno eb ot gniog ylbaborp saw ti tub
.niaga soreP ecaf ot denrut lakcaj ehT
.evom yreve htiw lodi sih tuoba erom denrael eh
.ti tfil ot deen oN
.raeb eht laets ot detpmetta dna sdnas eht deretne sdraug
.ylraelc kniht ot yticapac sih deduolc lla
.flow regae eht rewsna ot sdnoces koot eh ,ynam oS
.ymra gnidnats eht ni noitisop a ron
seitilibapac tabmoc 'suidanneG
,deroda sixelA taht sgniht elttil ehT .sliated ehT
.sgel esoht esuod ot eh saw
.seednetta eht morf dnuos yna gniffuns
.erimda ot nworg dah eh eutats ciots eht fo noisulli eht decalper mih evoba nam tfos
teef sih ot esor sixelA
.niaga eciov eht draeh eh mih evoba tsuJ
.tniop taht ot pu tniartser emos htiw demrofrep dah eH
,strapretnuoc rieht eb ot yhtrow demeed yeht htuoy yna kcip dluoc ,sdraw
.yltnegilid demrofrep eh ,sseldrageR
.mih fo tnorf ni ylleb eht yb dellarhtne ,esor eH
gnileenk llits saw htuoy ehT .flow eht dias
.stnemragrednu esoht htaenrednu eil dluoc tahw fo egami na detaerc dah noitanigami s'lakcaJ ehT .noitnetta sih werd ylralucitrap osla amozerep s'zoriP .gniees fo maerd reven dluow sixelA sliated artxe deniag flow eht fo eceip desopxe yrevE
.rebmahc eht ta kool doog a tog yllanif lakcaJ eht
enot s'flow ehT .sixelA .sixelA
llaw flah eht ot detniop eH
.hctorc sih ta gnikwag lakcaj desuora na dnif dluow eh
.pils tel ton dluow eh
.naicitcat delliks a mih edam sliated rof ytiniffa larutan siH
!dratsab gnitsugsiD
hcihw setats-ytic otni dedivid saw akiteT fo alusninep eht ,semit tneicna nI ~ 2 fo 1 traP ,nagidraC yb derodA
.ydob eht fo serutaef eht ni gnikat osla tub
,htuoy fo telbog eht deciton dah flow ehT
.detnaw eh tahw dah yllanif eh
.sbmil eht htiw dehsinif eh litnu niarb sih detaemrep rebilac hcus fo sthguohT
,enips eht fo dne eht gnihcaeR
,srae sih dehctiwt eh yaw eht ro elims sih ekil sgniht elttil
poort taht ot seit hcus htiw enoemos yb egnellahc a gnitcejer tub
,ytilibaborp tsehgih eht fo eno gnieb ton nevE
,htruof sih etelpmoc dluow suidanneG erofeB
,moor eht fo tuo ylkciuq saw htuoy ehT .ris ,uoy knahT
.tbuod dna erusaelp neewteb dnim sih
.weiv retteb a teg ot srehcaelb eht hguorht gninnur
nwo sih no ecnart eht kaerb ot elba saw sixelA
.eciov ytluaf a ni ekops dna dehgis dna
,ydob ralucsum sih fo yromem eht
.deyebo eh noitamrifnoc lacov a retfA
.rehtegot selzzum rieht deggard ecrof elbisivni na fi sa saw tI
dna yrotirret rof thguof
.esor eh hcihw htiw etsah eht edih ton did eH
,epaga saw htuom siH
.derrucco noitcaer rehtona tub
,sdrow sih lortnoc ot elbanu ylno eh saw regnol oN
.tsol erew uoy dias uoy
,sega etarapsid fo nem rehtegot tuP
,hcneb eht dniheb gnivom
elggurts s'lakcaj eht ekorb flow gnirewot ehT
gninnalp ta dellecxe eh yaw eht ron
deplug lakcaj ehT
.ymra nailoA eht fo hcnarb tnatropmi tsom dna
,redro eht deyebo lakcaJ ehT
nwod dekool soriP fI
,tnahpmuirt doots ailoA sa gnol sa roF
.eciov s'flow eht ni tluaf A .neht ,llew yreV
.ti detbuod eh fi neve
.ris ,raey laniF .ris ,seY
.sllah eht ot nruter ot thguos sixelA
.dnuor txen eht rof flesmih denoitisoper ohw
.selcsum gel esoht ot ssendrah a saw erehT
.elzzum sih ekirts dluoc reidlos eno nehT
?lodi sih ekil eb ot lla ti saW
?ymra htuoy eht fo rebmem a uoy erA
.lwarb eht ees ot emit ni ti edam ylerab dah lakcaj ehT
.dnim s'htuoy eht fo tuo dna ni deppop sthguoht ynaM ?eman ruoY
,eninac der eht dennip eH
.rednet etiuq llits era yeht ,eraweB
.eninac eht fo ruf deroloc-der eht detcelfer thgil fo syar ehT
,derettu htuoy eht lla saw tahT ?riS
.tlep sih yb neddih sracs
.flow eht drawot ti gnilleporp ot dnuorg eht ffo ydob sih gnisiar morf tnew sgel s'suidanneG
.delbmert ti woh deciton sixelA
.goD fo ecioV ehT ot gninetsil er'uoY
.ereht did eh ekil ti tlef reven dah eh tub
.erimda dluoc htuoy eht hcum saw erehT
.derettam ti taht toN
.ti eveirter ot em wollA
.emoctuo eht wenk yeht esuaceb ylekil
.dessap dah taht noitautis eht retsiger eh did mra sih gninaelc detrats eh nehw ylnO
soixelA fo eman eht yb lakcaj a
,taht lla hguorhT
?pu naelc em pleh uoy dluoC
,ymra eht fo noitamrof eht etarbelec ot
.sgnileef wen esoht htiw od ll'yeht tahw dna
,thgif eht dednetta enoyna ylerab
.ymra eht ni ecalp s'sixelA fo lobmys
.snoitca nwo sih no noitcelfer a ot
htgnerts evissam siH
.noitcif evitcaretni dna seirots trohs setirw eh ,woN
.ti dnatsrednu ot gniyrt no neek etiuq erew srerimda diva tsom eht tub
.regnol rof gnirednop tas ohw ,sixelA tpecxe
,moor regral a ot tog eH
,saw evom eht sa lufrewop sA
.tca na no tup dah rethgif ehT
.taht lla denrael dah sixelA
fo strap owt fo tsrif eht si
.dezad saw raeb eht dna
.sdaeb fo tes a gnitirehni tuohtiw
.tseuqer rehtona evah I ,salA
.ris ,em evigrof ,hA
.egnirc ot lakcaJ eht desuac
tnenoppo sih dekcimim eH
,tnelis yltsom saw eh hguoht dna
.seye sih ni nrub dluow thgil eht
.txen sevlac eht no dekrow eH
.sdaeb dercas eht fo dnab ehT
?tcerroc ,thgif eht nees evah uoY
,rehtona ni raeps a dna dnah eno ni dleihs a sdleiw reidlos a ekiL
,nosaer revetahw roF
.citsitra saw epahs riehT
gnilbmert werg sdnah sih tub
derodA recnaL ruoY
,kcab yrev eht tA
snoinapmoc regnuoy rieht detfig srethgif redlo eht
,nam eht tcetorp ot noitarepsaxe sih nI
.detceles eb ot dehsiw ohw
?eciohc dnuos a neve ti saW
emit driht a roF
.noitcerid fo esnes roop sih saw
tsehc s'flow eht no selcsum deffup eht dekcehc lakcaJ ehT
.rehtie ti edih ot tpmetta on saw erehT
sroines eht yb detceles eb ot deirt nem gnuoy ynam
.detrats dnuor dnoces ehT
.roirp sraey hctam noitibihxe na ni mih was eh ecnis dnim 'soixelA ni neeb dah nam tahT
.tiaw ot mih dellac eciov peed A
,neddibrof ton erew sgnileef esohT
niap fo hceercs A
seye s'lakcaJ gnuoy ehT
emit txen ni enuT
.laitnetop sih nwod dehgiew
.deen yna detnemelppus llew yrev sdnah sih tub
?tekcub taht em hctef uoy oD
.dewollof sehcnup rehto ynaM
,ereht saw epahs raelc eht tub
.llew yllaer euqinhcet 'soriP wenk eh sa
.tsol gniniamer revo pleh teg ot
,rethgif eht rof noitarimda eht decnahne taht erutaef a ton
tsellams eht neeb dah ti ,ecnO
.ti troppus ot tsirw s'nam eht ot sdnah sih devom yllacitamotua sixelA
.esaerg ni derevoc llits m'I
.reverof efil sih egnahc dluow yad taht tub
.flow eht yb dniheb morf dennip
,sixelA neve desirprus tI
.slevon lausiv yrruf fo noitcif-naf tluda htiw 0202 etal yrev ni gnitirw nageb ohw ,nagidraC yb
.noisivid suoigitserp eht denioj dna
.ton saw eh fi emas eht eb dluow tluser ehT
.ssentfos laiceps nwo sti dah ereht ruf eht neve tub
gninetsil rof uoy knahT
.sehcneb eht no enola saw eh ,ot emac eh nehW
.ydob eninac eht gnirimda ot kcab saw eh ylhsilooF
.daeh s'flow eht hguorht tnew taht snoitaluclac tsellams eht enigami dluoc lakcaj ehT
.efil sih gniksir evlovni ton did taht noitisop a teg dluoc eh ylerus
,yltcaf-fo-rettam ekops htob yehT
,ti fo lla ,ydob sih
.pu gnidnats saw raeb eht emit eht ta
.ylreporp dedrawer era uoy taht ees lliw I
.neht egrahc ot eno eht saw flow ehT
,llac eht gniwollof ,nehw
.doog rof raeb eht tuo dekconk tahT
.anera eht fo tuo snoitcurtsni eht ot sknaht dna
cirbaf eht dednetxe eH
.mih ta gnurps tuoba thguoht modles nam gnuoy eht taht liated a
.yad taht gniwollof
.amozrep eht ta ylno derats seye eht tub gnikrow erew sdnah siH
,wonk ot tey saw eH
.gnir derevoc-dnas eht deretne srethgif eht ,nwod tas eh sa noos sA
.pu doots eninac eht ,eerefer eht morf tnemecnuonna eht retfA
.ecno ta ydob sih fo erom hcum debbaws eh
,soriP no dekcol seye s'sixelA tnelis
,dlot sa did sixelA
.noinimod deniag yeht taht srobhgien emoselbuort erom sti fo eno htiw tcilfnoc a retfa saw tI
.sdaeb eht fo pihsnoipmahc eht
eninac eht ot daeh sih gnippans
.tnemanruot eht ni detepmoc
,hcamots eht ekil
,gninetsil sretsgnuoy era ereht ro
.noitcerid yrartnoc eht ni ydob sih ecrof ot sgel sih fo eno desu eh ,raeb eht yb gnissap retfa
.ecnamrofrep tabmoc sih fo yaw eht ni teg secnegludni tel reven ot erus edam syawla soriP
.snoititepmoc dna sraw ni seirotciv niag ot dah eno
.s'oriP fo tnorf ni gnileenk saw noos dna ,dlot sa ,did eH
.tug gnidurtorp sih rof evas
.dleifelttab taht fo serohs eht no dnuof senots gninihs fo edam stelecarb
,emoC ?tsoL
,ereht derats dna gar eht gnivom deppots tsuj htuoy eht yllautnevE
,sekats hgih sti etipseD
.nwod sroirraw tsom wols dluow ti sa
.htuoy fo gnisselb dna esruc eht si hcuS
.thgif a ni lodi sih ees ot anera eht ot enog dah eH
.ecnart a ni liated hcum sa ni gnikat
.snoitasucca hcus ot remocwen on saw soriP
,bmil eht gnisnir trats dluow eh erofeb tsuJ
.zoriP naht rehto enon saw
,dnah yb serehps otni dedlom ,selbbep ehT
.ecneulfni
.tseuqer a tub redro on si tI .reidlos ,esae tA
,ecnats evisnefed a nI